<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=451'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=426&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=476&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>451</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1489722036892878933</id><published>2017-08-30T14:09:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2017-09-05T15:55:56.840-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Homeostasis</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I made this joke about &quot;home me-o staying&quot; (having some down time). I&#39;m reading about Proxemics, a discipline founded by Ed Hall (anthropologist), which is the science of how humans and other animals co-organize in space.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For example what&#39;s the plan of an ideal house, what are the rooms for, and how close should you stand to someone you&#39;re addressing? What level of voice is polite. I just read a chapter comparing Brits to USers, in very broad brush stroke.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He takes Americans for having automatic neighborliness, a &quot; kids will play with your kids&quot; egalitarianism, whereas a British family has no expected obligations, no lending of a cup of sugar, now over the fence camaraderie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Having lived in many parts of the US, in several states (New Jersey, Florida, North Carolina... Oregon), in many zipcodes, I&#39;d say many neighborhoods, including suburban, are just as isolating and foam-like (Sloterdjik) as the urban.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not that urban villages don&#39;t exist.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We don&#39;t all live in Twin Peaks, that&#39;s for sure.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s David Lynch week in Portland, unbeknownst to me when Melody made a pit stop and reminded me of that heritage.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m well into Season Two, after seeing the pilot after Season One.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re talking about a series made over twenty years ago, but recently resurrected.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m striving to catch up.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1489722036892878933'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1489722036892878933'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/08/homeostasis.html' title='Homeostasis'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3028205816824096683</id><published>2017-08-21T19:06:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2017-08-23T07:30:06.139-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Eclipse Day</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/35917189293/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Monitoring Eclipse&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Monitoring Eclipse&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4363/35917189293_a1f439023c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Oregon has been girding for today for some time.&amp;nbsp; I didn&#39;t have specific plans until my assignment came through to do computer camp in Lake Oswego, not quite in the path of totality (99.4%).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
All the kids had eclipse glasses but I didn&#39;t.&amp;nbsp; One of them kindly shared.&amp;nbsp; The eerie low light (never completely dark, no stars) was likewise spectacular.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We had three classes going simultaneously today, though with only two instructors.&amp;nbsp; Jeremy was covering both Little Coders and Minecraft Modding, which I consider a feat.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My stint was longer, 9 - 4, but only one camp at a time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
An added stress factor came after camp was over:&amp;nbsp; my car decided to throw a fit when I tried to start it, sounding the alarm.&amp;nbsp; I couldn&#39;t think of anything to stop it.&amp;nbsp; Should I call AAA?&amp;nbsp; After a brief conversation with mom, the Nissan started with no problems.&amp;nbsp; Weird.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I headed to a nearby McMenamins (&lt;i&gt;John Barleycorns&lt;/i&gt;) to unwind and finish paperwork.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s where I am now, having a Hammerhead and a Dungeon Burger.&amp;nbsp; I parked in a far corner of the lot in case the car throws a fit again.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Followup: no Torture Taxi tantrum this time; I swung by &lt;i&gt;PDX Code Guild&lt;/i&gt; on the way home to Asylum District, in case Flying Circus was happening, traffic light.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Business Accelerator building (2828 SW Corbett) was a ghost town, however.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I made it home in time for all but the first five minutes of the CBS Evening News with Anthony Mason anchoring from Carbondale, Illinois. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/36587686251/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;After a Tantrum&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;After a Tantrum&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4354/36587686251_1c0d81c919.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: in the corner ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3028205816824096683'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3028205816824096683'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/08/eclipse-day.html' title='Eclipse Day'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-885953978075208656</id><published>2017-08-17T01:08:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2017-08-21T20:21:44.496-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Atomic Blonde (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Wonder Woman remembers the mission, which is to save humanity from corruption by the devil (aka Mars). But in attempting to save us, she has to join the fray, a Joan of Arc figure, with knights ever eager to serve under her command.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fast forward to Lorraine, two wars later (really one) and now at a signature apex, the convergence of the two Germanys as symbolized by a wall-divided Berlin overcoming its internal divisiveness.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As the opening narrative makes clear, this story explores a violent underbelly of this convergence chapter, through a favored lens when exploring this era:&amp;nbsp; that of the spy thriller comic book genre. &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/10/john-le-carr-on-bush.html&quot;&gt;Le Carr&lt;span class=&quot;cauthor&quot;&gt;é&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uses a similar backdrop sometimes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some will raise their eyebrows at my use of &quot;comic book&quot; and ask what&#39;s so funny about all that head bashing, more like &lt;i&gt;Streets of New York&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I think because of the superpowers on display, an ability to play these violent games that shows some purpose and intent, not just people caught up willy-nilly in awkward conditioned-reflexing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The martial arts make for some bloody ballet, with protagonists appearing somewhat in control of their own destinies, more as predators in the know than as helpless victims. They serve and protect the rest of us, if cast as heroes (heroines).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Both &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/06/wonder-woman-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Wonder Woman&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Atomic Blonde&lt;/i&gt; use similar wartime spy thriller motifs, with their focus on Amazons (female warriors).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/11/spectre-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Rome, Italy&lt;/a&gt;, where I was during early Cold War years, was another hotbed of intrigue and secrets, with all the high fashion and flashy cars to match.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was too young to pose as an adult of any stature, but I soaked up some of that James Bond culture at the English language movie theaters, the Archimedes especially (near Piazza Euclide).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Berlin over ten years later was more into grunge and proto-punk from the looks of things here recreated.&amp;nbsp; Disaffected youth didn&#39;t want to grow up with some Iron Curtain through their psychology.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/06/songs-from-north-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;The Korean DMZ&lt;/a&gt; stands out as another Berlin Wall of today.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These spies did not have the Internet, nor much in the way of social media.&amp;nbsp; The film takes us back to when people used ordinary landline telephones and didn&#39;t have to deal with strong encryption.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I most recently saw John Goodman in &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/04/a-code-school-evening.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;10 Cloverfield Lane&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and couldn&#39;t quite shake the idea that this was a flashback to before his retirement to that bunker, just a passing thought.&amp;nbsp; American dads can be pretty crazy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lorriane smokes and drinks and lives a punishing lifestyle, which will catch up with her later.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was interested to learn that Charlize Theron, who plays Lorriane, is natively Afrikaans with American English her second language (IMDB). I wonder if she knows Yolandi Visser.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I did make it to Berlin before the wall came down, took the tour. &amp;nbsp;Our train was actually East German, terminating on the east side in Berlin, starting with a ferry trip from Sweden I believe it was. We were unusual for American tourists, not the first time. &amp;nbsp;Dad liked to plan interesting trips.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/885953978075208656'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/885953978075208656'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/08/atomic-blonde-movie-review.html' title='Atomic Blonde (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1346335637458971111</id><published>2017-08-15T10:29:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2017-08-15T10:32:44.356-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Chain Reaction</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;402&quot; src=&quot;//scratch.mit.edu/projects/embed/171289585/?autostart=false&quot; width=&quot;485&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
At first I didn&#39;t like that the timer was running even if I&#39;d not signaled my willingness to begin, by punching the green flag.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d have the option to turn that off, given the See Inside powers conferred in a copyleft economy.&amp;nbsp; I didn&#39;t write this game, merely remixed it and value added.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The point is to keep going to the next level, by setting off chain reactions that consume tiny sprites. The surface area of the target area is variable and rises as more sprites are consumed, before falling again. You anchor the target initially and then sit back to see if you&#39;ve won the round, so it&#39;s basically a one click per round game, a feature, a kind of minimalism.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Note the timer resets on each explosion. The sprites are all clones of the main ball, which spawns multiple copies of itself, shrunk to 15% of original size.&amp;nbsp; The number spawned is three more than the level number.&amp;nbsp; Notice you have less time as the level number rises.&amp;nbsp; But then more explosions per time unit would be expected.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
All in all, I consider this a handsome little game, elegantly implemented.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll plan to show and tell about in at summer camp today.&amp;nbsp; I actually found it in the official handbook, so it&#39;s not like I&#39;m straying far from my ken.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1346335637458971111'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1346335637458971111'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/08/chain-reaction.html' title='Chain Reaction'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6291486999933138682</id><published>2017-08-10T11:46:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-07T17:45:01.284-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Banning Nukes</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157684980151720&quot; title=&quot;Banning Nukes&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/4382/35665744613_421db36a80.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Banning Nukes&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Portland has joined a lot of cities, as cities stand to lose the most.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The uber-cowards plan to head for spacious luxury apartments in various gated mountain suburbs, there to send out hapless journalists at the point of a gun to see whether &lt;i&gt;Planet of the Apes&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;12 Monkeys&lt;/i&gt; has come true or not.&amp;nbsp; In the meantime, they&#39;ll eat nachos and swill Bud.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Portlanders don&#39;t savor that genre of science fiction as a their real future and so push back, joining a broad alliance of city mayors and others, signalling in the history books we were never on board with the selfish oligarchs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The oligarchs have various pretenses or ploys they float as trial balloons, trying to gauge the public mood. Recent results have been disappointing from their point of view.&amp;nbsp; A nuclear conflagration is harder to get started even if the UN Nuclear Weapons Ban Treaty is just something on paper.&amp;nbsp; So are a lot of things &quot;just paper&quot; (like money for example, other entitlements?).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This year, our memorial event (remembrance ceremony) featured a Buddhist invocation, several speeches, and a second indoor event in nearby NW 70 Couch Street.&amp;nbsp; We were permitted to take pictures, and indeed spreading visualization memes was part of the intent.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I fought rush hour coming home from the day job, where mom was waiting.&amp;nbsp; My mistake to think the Hawthorne Bridge could be any better, now that Morrison is one way each way, but no way from the east side, short of joining I-5 somewhere north, which is crazy.&amp;nbsp; But then traffic-wise Portland has succumbed to North America&#39;s chief ailment:&amp;nbsp; addiction to one-driver commute lifestyles (leads to opium addiction, heart disease...).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Usually, with no evening events pending, I don&#39;t have to fight rush hour.&amp;nbsp; I know a friend with a swimming pool just off Boones Ferry, plus have Lake Oswego friends scattered around I can visit.&amp;nbsp; The game around rush hour is to avoid it completely.&amp;nbsp; Fortunately the day job starts around noon, and the drive is then typical, at posted speed limits.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Cross references:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2016/08/hiroshima-day-august-6.html&quot;&gt;2016: Hiroshima Day&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/08/disarm-day-2015.html&quot;&gt;2015: Disarm Day 2015&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/08/remembering.html&quot;&gt;2013: A-Bomb Day&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/08/hiroshima-day-2010.html&quot;&gt;2010: Hiroshima Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/08/remembering.html&quot;&gt;2007: Remembering...&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6291486999933138682'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6291486999933138682'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/08/banning-nukes.html' title='Banning Nukes'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5838321666866650269</id><published>2017-08-06T19:57:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-23T22:33:38.259-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Visiting Vancouver</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157684852773550&quot; title=&quot;Visiting Vancouver&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Visiting Vancouver&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/4411/36367997616_7d0e60bed3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Vancouver, Washington is an important port and way station, a gateway to Oregon. People complain the I-5 draw-bridge is a choke point, however Oregon State Senator Lew Frederick says the studies he&#39;s seen point to replacing the rail bridge instead, re-routing trucks to their own deck.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In some simulations, this redesign would do much more to alleviate the problem than replacing the I-5 bridge, especially if people enjoy reading and social media enough to prefer taking mass transit, even high speed rail in some possible futures.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sam Lanahan has view property overlooking the Willamette-Columbia confluence, though from a safe distance away, which explains the telescope. Freight traffic is fun to watch.&amp;nbsp; Glenn and I got to see the hexagonal flextegrity table, which Glenn had helped build in my garage, amidst other marvels, on our car trip there today.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For those of you into intellectual history, when &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/02/octet-truss.html&quot;&gt;Alexander Graham Bell&lt;/a&gt; had the command of vast resources, post inventing the telephone, he plowed time and energy into what he called &quot;kites&quot;, and which today we might call an &quot;isotropic vector matrix&quot; if into Fuller, or perhaps an &quot;octet-truss&quot; if aware of the patent literature.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sam&#39;s matrix is no mere knock off of Bell&#39;s solution as the tension and compression forces get distributed by a different strategy.&amp;nbsp; However it helps to see it in the lineage of space frame solutions, in this particular family of lattice structures.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the latest incarnation the basic &quot;brick&quot; is a soccer ball of hard plastic made of six base parts, hence the name C6XTY, all identical, with eight screw-in disks to secure each assembly.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Armature members with their own smaller screws then fix these spherical components in place, creating the Bell-like lattice with the ball centers in CCP or FCC positions, for those of you schooled &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2017/02/class-notes.html&quot;&gt;in crystallography&lt;/a&gt;, or willing to watch a few Youtubes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Standing in the courtyard at his house, Sam had a prime example of the kind of sculpture one might create from C6XTY, given the liberty to explore the IVM &quot;in vitro&quot; so to speak, as an organic pattern.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He&#39;s working on and/or commissioning several more examples for an upcoming photo shoot.&amp;nbsp; My backyard is one of the construction sites.&amp;nbsp; We returned with a portable gazeebo on the roof of my car. I excavated and removed the brick fire pit to make room for the new work area.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I need to study &lt;i&gt;Quantum Mind&lt;/i&gt; again tonight, a book by Arnold Mindell.&amp;nbsp; You&#39;ll find Jungian psychology a recurring theme in these blogs.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m thinking Bell, Bucky, Lanahan and others were attuned to resonant frequencies in a collective unconsciousness that surfaces in their cases.&amp;nbsp; Something deep within us wants to get it out there.&amp;nbsp; The zeitgeist is making waves.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5838321666866650269'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5838321666866650269'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/08/visiting-vancouver.html' title='Visiting Vancouver'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4299702664372349130</id><published>2017-08-03T06:14:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2017-08-21T20:32:31.296-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Leaving Terrebonne</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/35545654533/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Madras Airfield&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Madras Airfield&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4342/35545654533_1470d4e9a6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: airfield, Madras, Oregon ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I&#39;m preparing to jet out of here, with &quot;jet&quot; more a metaphor as I&#39;m driving the Maxi Taxi. Yes, there&#39;s an air transport connection from PDX to Redmond, and car rental solutions, however I&#39;m partial to taking my own wheels over the mountain on Hwy 26, then down Hwy 97, through Madras, which also hosts a substantial airport.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m thinking ahead, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/08/international-school.html&quot;&gt;about Earthala&lt;/a&gt;, with roots in Terrebonne (Good Earth), science fiction at the moment, though others might call it investment memory banking.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I took down the campsite, and was never far from coffee nor WiFi, so I wouldn&#39;t exactly call what I did &quot;roughing it&quot;. Rather I was joining over forty others in a memorial service for Sam (my brother-in-law) at Haystack Reservoir, a special place for Sam &amp;amp; Judy, as is the whole of this area, where they&#39;ve lived since the 1970s, having met in Florida as college students.&amp;nbsp; I always feel a part of a tribe, an extended family, when coming over here, this time especially given so many reunited to pay tribute (heartfelt complements) to wise man Sam.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sam&#39;s sister Dawn (Carla later) also sought wisdom, as she was much on the same path as her bro. They grew up together in Ohio, Nashville, and later in Satellite Beach, Florida after the marriage was dissolved (Carla stayed with Don). She took the name Wicca, as in Dawn Wicca, to give herself a high bar to live up to, a constant reminder to seek wisdom. She was not establishing herself as a Wiccan per se, a specific invented religion you may wish to read about in &lt;i&gt;Triumph of the Moon&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/12/heptagons.html&quot;&gt;about Gardner&lt;/a&gt; and so on.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;re enjoying a global warming heat wave in 2017, with temperatures in Portland staying in triple digits for longer than we&#39;re used to.&amp;nbsp; I don&#39;t use air conditioning in the car and like to keep things cool and less trafficked, so chose an early departure time both coming (4:15 AM) and going (6:45 AM).&amp;nbsp; Carol (mom, 88) is back in Portland with Melody (passing-through house guest).&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2017/06/family-reunions.html&quot;&gt;Last time&lt;/a&gt; we came over, Tara joined us.&amp;nbsp; Alexia came over with Elise, whom Dawn was living with on a horse farm when we first met.&amp;nbsp; You&#39;ll find her elsewhere in this Russian &quot;novel&quot; (in quotes because I&#39;m doing non-fiction here).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fires are a big fact of life around here.&amp;nbsp; Orchards burn, other cultivated lands, even homes.&amp;nbsp; Firefighters can&#39;t reverse the irreversible. Mother Nature is not intimidated by humans, even a little. They&#39;re her creation after all. Planet Earth has a long history of creatures coming and going. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4299702664372349130'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4299702664372349130'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/08/leaving-terrebonne.html' title='Leaving Terrebonne'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5440571477201329444</id><published>2017-07-31T10:24:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2023-06-26T17:16:14.551-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Persia Power</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
There&#39;s a lot of truth to the idea that a sorry-ass &quot;deep state&quot; (a clique) is pushing to make Iran the uber bad guy again, in the wake of funding the Iraq side for many years, then turning on Iraq and making it the enemy.&amp;nbsp; Make up your mind?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A problem with &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/12/world-pax.html&quot;&gt;Kissinger-style real-politik&lt;/a&gt; is once you cut loose from meaning what you say, on the record, you may lose your moorings. The District of Columbia is somewhat adrift.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Making Russia the arbiter of the last presidential election (or why all the fuss) is a feeble call for help?&amp;nbsp; Maybe Russia will take it that way; NATO&#39;s bluster as an empty search for meaning on the part of some neocons hoping to play hero against some invented geopolitical backdrop requiring much suspended disbelief (most of us are not buying).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The bigger news is Persia&#39;s collaboration with India in competition with China&#39;s collaboration with Pakistan.&amp;nbsp; The journalistic class wants to keep it either/or (contrary to fact) and play up the India-Pakistan rift (e.g. Kashmir), but the engineer class, more globalized, is less impressed by the tabloid press (or tabloid politics).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Two ports, not far apart, feature in this so-called competition, with India shipping to the one in Iran, China using the one in Pakistan as a springboard to the Indian ocean, bypassing the Malaysian Straits. A lot of new infrastructure is coming together.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The nation-state terminology still helps us talk about the world geographically, as states themselves disappear into the global circuitry.&amp;nbsp; We all know where Israel / Palestine is, in the context of Mesopotamia.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I see global trade route planning as an application of graph theory in a lot of ways, as in networking on a sphere.&amp;nbsp; The&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2017/07/more-manicuring.html&quot;&gt; international school curriculum&lt;/a&gt; I&#39;m co-developing gives ample airplay to graph theory and global planning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Where do the airlines go?&amp;nbsp; I have a database of world airports, incomplete but at least on topic.&amp;nbsp; We use pandas, SQL, JSON... what they call &quot;computer science&quot; in English, somehow not statistics or math (&quot;data science&quot; maybe).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Is English broken?&amp;nbsp; I think the linguistic turn combined with basic self-critical reflection, puts English-as-a-first-language folk in a front row seat regarding the efficacy of this mother tongue.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m glad many diverse traditions continue feeding in to this meme-chest, as at the very least it&#39;s a language that&#39;s ripe for continued overhaul.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Iran&#39;s leading role in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/07/ban-treaty.html&quot;&gt;Nuclear Weapons Ban Treaty&lt;/a&gt; has not yet worked its way into the narrative as the &quot;cynical journalist&quot; culture doesn&#39;t really have a narrative and looks to politicians to carve out the talking points.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Politicians, not being engineers for the most part, may not have much insight into investment banking either.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re on the take, more than willing to take campaign contribution bribes and spout lobbyist language in exchange, but as originators of policy.... I&#39;m not thinking the District of Columbia is any longer original in that sense. DC is a district of followers, not leaders.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5440571477201329444'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5440571477201329444'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/07/persia-power.html' title='Persia Power'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3792542438156821761</id><published>2017-07-24T09:58:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2017-07-24T10:05:07.412-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Does Your School Have a Charter?</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vhubtPygTcA&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
[first posted to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/01/forum-206.html&quot;&gt;Forum 206&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I just waded through a few Youtubes on the charter versus non-charter school debate.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s a sloppiness to it all in that everyone starts by saying charter schools are public schools and then a sentence later it&#39;s back to &quot;public versus charter&quot;.  Silly right?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The mainstream discourse seems to have settled on &quot;traditional versus charter schools&quot; or &quot;district versus charter schools&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What an amazingly narrow and ill-fitting vocabulary, is my thought.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/vhubtPygTcA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://youtu.be/vhubtPygTcA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Charter Schools Are Overrated, IntelligenceSquared Debates&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
was interesting, a hosted debate between two teams, an ongoing show that seems to think &quot;IQ&quot; is something real and therefore square-able.[1]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What many debaters miss, in my view, is the passion some have, in every generation, to create new schools, not just join existing schools.  Any healthy society has its pioneers and reformists.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We should accept that as a built in feature of human nature, and so the debate should begin with that premise:  that the public sector, however designed, needs to facilitate (not stifle) turnover at the institutional level, meaning public schools, charter or no charter, will continue to come and go.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of schools going, I think it&#39;s more than obvious we need to physically close a lot of schools that are simply beyond repair [2]. Trying to coast on clearly broken buildings, full of lead or whatever, is just lazy, the opposite of innovation, and proof we have little imagination.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m one who thinks a central government (of any nation), if there&#39;s one in the picture, should have the where with all to create its own flagship schools.  These could be boarding schools for future diplomats, deliberately open to students from other countries.  We might also see more experiments with same-sex schooling, for those wishing that option (choice).  Let NASA do more than just summer camps, NSA too for that matter.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But then I&#39;m one who thinks any government worth its salt should run a number of showcase institutions designed to provide work to a nation&#39;s citizens, including roadside lodging (motels), an airline, maybe a rental car company.[3]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What better way to stay in touch with the people than to run and manage some example enterprises.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Something other than war machines (and a few camp grounds), which is currently the main endeavor for which the weakest governments (e.g. the US) are allowed a sandbox (the war machine includes government labs such as Sandia and Los Alamos -- not much research on  how to help with refugee camps -- just on how to create them in the first place i.e. by turning cities to rubble, per the 1900s, a century of barbarism).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Governments are permitted / coerced into serving as clients to a weapons-oriented private sector (Raytheon, Lockheed-Martin...). That&#39;s their major role (subsidizing the most sociopathic).  Greece, broke, buys submarines from Siemens. [4]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How we tax and spend today is income redistribution, like they say, from the defenseless and over-taxed to oligarchs with off-shore investments (Russian or otherwise, what does it matter at that level?).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A truly American run boarding school might even teach some of the heritage I&#39;m most interested in, namely this &quot;geometry of lumps&quot; I keep talking about (Karl Menger et al) wherein we experiment with axioms other than those inherited from ancient Greek metaphysics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/03/res-extensa.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/03/res-extensa.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The way things are going, with Uncle Sam broke, and more a hired gun than anyone&#39;s idea of an emperor, I don&#39;t think it&#39;s a given that these dreams will pan out.  We appear to have drifted into oligarchy and plutocracy with democracies fading.  The politicians have the job of telling us something different i.e. they comfort us with their fairy tales.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Kirby&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[1] (dig way back in the math-teach archives if you can figure out how, takes IQ, and you&#39;ll see we discussed the &quot;g factor&quot; for like forever that time).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[2]  Beyond repair... or not (in some cases):&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://prospect.org/article/fixing-our-infrastructure-how-about-schools&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://prospect.org/article/fixing-our-infrastructure-how-about-schools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[3]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Spain has a chain of state-run luxury hotels:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parador&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parador&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:Government-owned_companies_of_the_United_States&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:Government-owned_companies_of_the_United_States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[4]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/1.801881&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/1.801881&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
(similar to the scandal in Greece)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/08/world/europe/so-many-bribes-a-greek-official-cant-recall-all.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/08/world/europe/so-many-bribes-a-greek-official-cant-recall-all.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3792542438156821761'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3792542438156821761'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/07/does-your-school-have-charter.html' title='Does Your School Have a Charter?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/vhubtPygTcA/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2417387952389842817</id><published>2017-07-08T17:57:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2017-07-08T18:06:14.264-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Ban Treaty</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/InWkGyEIMiI&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Per &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2017/06/wanderers-20170613.html&quot;&gt;Carol Urner&#39;s presentation&lt;/a&gt; to Wanderers at the Linus Pauling House, the UN Nuclear Weapons Ban Treaty has passed the General Assembly, by a wide margin, as expected.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The loser nations know the ban need not apply to them.  Why?  Because they have nuclear weapons and no one tells Nuke Head Nations what to do.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Nevertheless, we patriots who care about reputation have some cause for celebration this July 4th, and &lt;i&gt;Tillamook&lt;/i&gt; butterscotch ice cream is being consumed in the Urner household.&amp;nbsp; The draft was actually adopted on the 7th, but we knew it was a done deal so were already waving the flag.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Good job Iran in helping to steer the process.&amp;nbsp; DC&#39;s mythology desperately requires Iran to be desperately seeking nuclear weapons.&amp;nbsp; Here&#39;s another nail in that narrative&#39;s coffin.&amp;nbsp; No one I know expects DC (not a US state) to ever reform its thinking. We expect it to remain a backwater.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2417387952389842817'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2417387952389842817'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/07/ban-treaty.html' title='Ban Treaty'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/InWkGyEIMiI/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3329385074136373950</id><published>2017-07-01T13:02:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2017-07-01T19:29:39.213-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Rajneeshpuram (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Rajneeshpuram was an attempt to found a new town in Oregon, in land zoned for farming.&amp;nbsp; Oregon has some strictly enforced land use laws.&amp;nbsp; That said township was so religious, and not Christian, didn&#39;t help.&amp;nbsp; Not that Rajneesh professed a religion exactly.&amp;nbsp; For years he wisely kept his mouth shut, went for a ride, then he gradually took control back, wresting more steering power to a point where Madam Sheila felt obliged to get away.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The folks of Antelope went to heroic lengths to not lose their cool, and played with Oregon State by the only rule book they could think to follow:&amp;nbsp; Oregon&#39;s.&amp;nbsp; That starting a Puram in the heart of Oregon by aggressive tactics ends up backfiring is hardly a surprise in retrospect.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I borrowed this OPB Oregon Experience episode from the Multnomah County Library system and today will return it, along with some books on CSS (Cascading Style Sheets), and another on SVG (Scalable Vector Graphics, another front end Web technology).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A man who fascinates me even more than the Baghwan here, is/was Father Divine, the short African American king of His jungle, as a God in his own way.&amp;nbsp; Lavish feasts were provided by the disciples, the fans, and the gatherings were by many accounts convivial and of &quot;melting pot&quot; ethnicity (an all-kinds stew), and all back when MLK was still a young man.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My overlap with the Father Divine community was when I scored a job teaching high school at St. Dom&#39;s (Catholic), exactly what I&#39;d been looking for, within walking distance. The circumstances of my hiring were tragic in that Sisters had died in a car crash.&amp;nbsp; My willingness to dive in under those circumstances was appreciated.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
An old Father Divine hotel was just kitty corner and offered a good breakfast served by Sister Grace.&amp;nbsp; I studied the literature and grew intrigued.&amp;nbsp; Other faculty would join me from time to time, or go there on their own.&amp;nbsp; Why not?&amp;nbsp; Great place.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Maureen (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/02/methodist-morning.html&quot;&gt;Methodist&lt;/a&gt;) and I got to talking on the phone through some of this film, which I screened while folding laundry, pacing about.&amp;nbsp; But then I&#39;ve been through the story before, in other media.&amp;nbsp; I never got to visit said Puram myself, even though I&#39;d returned to Oregon in 1985, having left in the 1960s at the end of 2nd grade (my 3rd grade would be first forum in the Junior English School of Rome).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As someone with a long term interest in student exchange programs, organizing opportunities for faraway urban kids to experience some ranch living, I&#39;m sensitive to locals not wanting to feel invaded.&amp;nbsp; Our placements will have advance training in sensitivity to community values.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In terms of setting up campuses, the ecovillages (picture boarding schools), I&#39;m interested in what Props has to offer, thinking lower barriers to entry (to year around camping and village building) has everything to do with technology, from transportation networks to radio stations and runways (landing pads or whatever).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d like to see more train re-development, for the express purpose of bringing students in to their remote bases, which may not stay put for long in some cases.&amp;nbsp; Exploring ecosystems means leaving them as they were by default.&amp;nbsp; However, where railways are concerned, we&#39;re talking about a longer term commitment.&amp;nbsp; Railway work is maybe for college credit, trucking too. That&#39;s how it works in the Global U.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3329385074136373950'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3329385074136373950'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/07/rajneeshpuram-movie-review.html' title='Rajneeshpuram (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6685325589638716087</id><published>2017-06-27T08:28:00.005-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-27T08:41:45.408-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Catching Up</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
We&#39;ve been over the mountain (Mt. Hood), my two daughters and I.&amp;nbsp; Alexia went earlier in her dad&#39;s late mom&#39;s Buick.&amp;nbsp; Sam, Tara&#39;s uncle, was in hospice, at &lt;i&gt;Partners in Care&lt;/i&gt; in Bend, Oregon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Last night, back in Portland, we visited &lt;i&gt;Atlas Pizza&lt;/i&gt;, Tara and I, Patrick joining us.&amp;nbsp; Patrick has been contracted to dig down into command line Python minus any IDE.&amp;nbsp; A paying client likes it that way. He&#39;s using Wing&#39;s debugger in another class, a habit I&#39;m likewise gradually acquiring.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve completed a first Arduino course, a Coursera MOOC, and now I&#39;m wading more deeply into that &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.sparkfun.com/tutorials/how-to-read-a-schematic&quot;&gt;world of programmable circuits&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Tonight I&#39;m teaching Python to adults, and next week to kids as well.&amp;nbsp; Mark me as firmly planted in tech.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, American Literature (we might call it that) is on my mind, and I wonder about standards.&amp;nbsp; How much are able to build immune systems, as we might call them, if following a &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/german-philosophy.html&quot;&gt;more German philosophy&lt;/a&gt; of bubbles, globes, foams.&amp;nbsp; To what extent will we stay prey, to &quot;false news&quot; in whatever guises?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Judy and I visited the funeral director while Alexia and Tara went on ahead. They ended up test driving a &lt;i&gt;Ford Fiesta&lt;/i&gt; in Madras.&amp;nbsp; No memorial service has been scheduled yet; a way will open. This journey has been a part of it.&amp;nbsp; Remembering Sam is a new theme now, one I&#39;ll treasure.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol has done her share of road trips recently, both east and west, and flew &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/02/surgery-on-blue-house.html&quot;&gt;the Blue House&lt;/a&gt; solo while we were gone.&amp;nbsp; Temperatures soared to record highs this weekend.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re glad for the break in the heat wave, with overcast skies, now coasting in the seventies (Fahrenheit).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve been showing Tara the latest PR around &lt;a href=&quot;http://c6xty.com/&quot;&gt;C6XTY&lt;/a&gt;, including my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/&quot;&gt;4D logo&lt;/a&gt; in the mix, next to the link to &lt;a href=&quot;https://synchronofile.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Synchronofile&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6685325589638716087'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6685325589638716087'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/06/catching-up.html' title='Catching Up'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5715661374884138815</id><published>2017-06-17T17:44:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-17T17:45:37.194-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Building Fractions</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
The code below shows a way of teaching operator overloading in Python.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Even
 though the standard library includes a Fraction type, it can&#39;t hurt to 
recreate it in a lesson, drawing on our knowledge of how fractions 
should behave.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Notice the embedded _gcd() method 
employs Euclid&#39;s Method to reduce fractions to lowest terms on 
initialization.&amp;nbsp; Since multiply and add operations, and their inverses, 
all end up creating new Q type instances (fractions), no attempt at 
reducing is made until then.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Hit the Run button to run the script.&amp;nbsp; Output appears at the bottom.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;//repl.it/embed/H7VF/18.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5715661374884138815'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5715661374884138815'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/06/building-fractions.html' title='Building Fractions'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-9139707968535369154</id><published>2017-06-14T23:05:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-14T23:18:20.958-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Circuit Rider</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/5288270273/in/photolist-Pd7jnT-GFzRTn-dvssnT-dvsspp-bdBrUr-bdBrip-94iLvF-8WW2GD-8WZ3xm-8y8b9A-5EXANd-5EXDEj-2yuiiu&quot; title=&quot;Uncle Lightfoot&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Uncle Lightfoot&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5206/5288270273_4a9cb2eb44.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Bill Lightfoot in 2010&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At age 92, my uncle (dad&#39;s mom&#39;s sister&#39;s son) Bill Lightfoot has the baud rate to negotiate Amtrak on his own.&amp;nbsp; He escapes his comfy quarters in Seattle to be with his grand nephew.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s eager for pictures of Jack, my dad.&amp;nbsp; They weren&#39;t much together after their chance meetup in Alaska, in the summer of 1947 I think it was.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Jack studied International Relations in DC, then went into regional planning under Dick Meier at the University of Chicago. After a strong on ramp performance, stateside, practicing planning in Portland, he went to nation-state scale, where you&#39;re looking at zoning and freeways, big picture infrastructure, less at individual housing or office complexes.&amp;nbsp; The latter is architecture and city planning, and more detailed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I brought along some C6XTY as I&#39;m timing myself to build a tetrahedron with four of them.&amp;nbsp; By &quot;them&quot; I mean soccer ball looking things, each assembled from six identical plastic parts, hence the name. The hexapent C60 is a meme, and a chemical (a carbon allotrope, a family of cages, then come the tubes and of course graphene, full circle, graphite, diamond and plain old soot -- carbon powder -- being the earlier discoveries).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol was also routing through downtown this same afternoon, and it worked to drop her at 10th and Taylor, park in a garage, observe some Flag Day childrens performance (a traveling troupe), then retrieve the car and head to Union Station, where the Coast Starlight has just arrived.&amp;nbsp; Bill and I headed over to &lt;i&gt;Ringlers&lt;/i&gt;, where we enjoyed the usual great food and service (I&#39;m a loyal customer). Thank you Bill, for making these forays.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll get you some more pictures, of dad.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This was the &quot;short format&quot; visit where we cut it pretty close.&amp;nbsp; The Coast Starlight is often late, getting here from California, but today was right on time.&amp;nbsp; I had Bill back at the station with only minutes to spare, whereas on another occasion we waited some hours.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On his previous visit he did &quot;long format&quot;, coming a train earlier and leaving a train later.&amp;nbsp; That gave us time for Pittock Mansion, Kell&#39;s for lunch, visiting with Carol at &lt;i&gt;Bagdad&lt;/i&gt; out my way, with time to spare getting back.&amp;nbsp; That was pretty exhausting though, for a ninety-two year old.&amp;nbsp; Did we get many pictures of Bill with his Aztecs (those were cars many considered rather funny looking, Bill loved &#39;em)?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Howard and Wilma came with Bill on one of these outings.&amp;nbsp; Bill and Barbara Hancock on another.&amp;nbsp; Amtrak:&amp;nbsp; keeping families together.&amp;nbsp; Bill wore his Northern Pacific hat.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.american-rails.com/images/northern-pacific-railway-herald.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://www.american-rails.com/images/northern-pacific-railway-herald.jpg&quot; data-original-height=&quot;200&quot; data-original-width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9139707968535369154'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9139707968535369154'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/06/circuit-rider.html' title='Circuit Rider'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8495709253346965687</id><published>2017-06-12T16:38:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-12T16:39:54.238-07:00</updated><title type='text'>OR Welcomes PR</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
Puerto Rico could send reps to Oregon for a look at Vote by Mail system we have, not perfect, but why not start with one of the best.&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@4DsolutionsPDX) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/4DsolutionsPDX/status/874409350734860288&quot;&gt;June 12, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Some will say it&#39;s a bit preemptive for a former territory, Oregon, to welcome &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/07/the-last-colony-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Puerto Rico&lt;/a&gt; to the Union, as 51st state.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
After some hundred years, I&#39;m glad we have that sorted out.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Welcome. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8495709253346965687'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8495709253346965687'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/06/or-welcomes-pr.html' title='OR Welcomes PR'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2475302903323548918</id><published>2017-06-09T17:15:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-10T07:35:49.521-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Fundraising Dinner</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;375&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;flashvars&quot; value=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157681900124402%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157681900124402%2F&amp;set_id=72157681900124402&amp;jump_to=&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=261948265&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;embed type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; src=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=261948265&quot; allowFullScreen=&quot;true&quot; flashvars=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157681900124402%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157681900124402%2F&amp;set_id=72157681900124402&amp;jump_to=&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Carol (mom) and I are about to drive across the river, against traffic (meaning with a faster trip time), for a dinner with Physicians for Social Responsibility.&amp;nbsp; As &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/02/wilpf-on-road-was-tax-time.html&quot;&gt;a veteran WILPFer&lt;/a&gt;, she&#39;s worked with the Oregon PSR rather closely, most especially on the Hiroshima - Nagasaki commemoration event, a time to pledge never again to indulge in nuclear war.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Since WW2, the planet has endured several nuclear catastrophes, beginning with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/06/golden-rule.html&quot;&gt;so-called &quot;testing&quot;&lt;/a&gt;, which irreparably harmed the ecosystem, followed by nuclear meltdowns. The meltdown in Chernobyl was such that brave and selfless human intervention was possible.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A tunnel was dug in record time to intercept the melting mass before it reached the water table.&amp;nbsp; In the case of Fukushima, human bravery is irrelevant and the Pacific Ocean is becoming increasingly contaminated, and by extension the planet.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The responsible jobs, going forward, have to do with cleanup and disaster mitigation. Humans floating around on military ships, threatening each other, saber rattling, is a lot of toy story nonsense wherein humans refuse to grow out of their kindergarten stage.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;ll have to leave them to play those war games, as they insist, and have the weapons to stop us from stopping them, but we don&#39;t have to treat them as mature adults.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I think a lot of the slowness to respond is about theater (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2017/05/telerama.html&quot;&gt;the T in PATH&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;nbsp; People used to think Kings (a few Queens) had divine powers. Even when that illusion exploded, politicians managed to keep up an illusion of being in control.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That these people actually do any &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/07/what-is-work.html&quot;&gt;real work&lt;/a&gt; is becoming less apparent.&amp;nbsp; But then &quot;work&quot; in its physics meaning simply means &quot;to expend energy&quot; which we all do, of necessity, just to breath.&amp;nbsp; Any meaning beyond that tends to be tinged by moralizing, with Protestants (Christians known for their protesting attitude) among the first to chime in.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I need a haircut.&amp;nbsp; My gray hair is bushy and I&#39;m wearing a maroon turtle neck with not such fancy pants. I&#39;m in the ballpark of &quot;frumpy academic&quot; I suppose, though I&#39;m closer to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/11/identity-politics.html&quot;&gt;a Quaker crime boss&lt;/a&gt; (it&#39;s considered traitorous to laugh at politicians is it not?).&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve been posting &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/06/from-forum-206.html&quot;&gt;to Forum 206&lt;/a&gt; quite a bit. Does that make me a math teacher?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sam Lanahan was by today with a truck load of C6XTY.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll be able to organize workflows for kids, having them construct soccer ball looking things from six curved pieces held together with eight screws. Then come the arms, suitable for interconnecting them in a lattice.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s all this for?&amp;nbsp; Do you know what the isotropic vector matrix (IVM) is?&amp;nbsp; Octet truss?&amp;nbsp; CCP?&amp;nbsp; FCC (no not the government acronym).&amp;nbsp; Maybe we&#39;re just sharing some memes at first, basic STEM.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;ll be awhile longer before humanity grows up.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re a work in progress.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some of us don&#39;t think we need to learn about hard stuff, like science and math, as long as we have our politician parents to take care of us.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;ll protect us from the laws of physics, right?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2475302903323548918'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2475302903323548918'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/06/fundraising-dinner.html' title='Fundraising Dinner'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-959946352538305329</id><published>2017-05-31T00:24:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-01T01:41:52.049-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2017.5.30</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/34637269780/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;A Peter Bechtold Briefing&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;A Peter Bechtold Briefing&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/5/4196/34637269780_68150590ef.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I spent some of the morning listening to the Seymour Hersh telling of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/02/zero-dark-thirty-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Zero Dark Thirty&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; story, based on actual events. Prying apart fiction from non-fiction is not always as easy as some pretend.&amp;nbsp; He provides missing puzzle pieces.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My sense of not needing to pry these apart at every turn, carried me into Peter Bechtold&#39;s talk, giving the history of Syria, the heartland of the Holy Land, as they called it in President Wilson&#39;s day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sure, Wilson sounds racist by today&#39;s standards but that doesn&#39;t make him a complete idiot. Peter sees Wilson relegated to the sidelines as French and British create their own narrative around what happened in the Middle East, subsequent to the end of the Ottoman Era.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The kinds of maps Peter showed of Syria, showing patchworks by micro-climate, language, religion (ethnicity) could be used with North America as well. However as Peter restated several times, these were static snapshots from an earlier time.&amp;nbsp; Much has transpired.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Given we&#39;re in Portland, how the District of Columbia sees the world remains influential.&amp;nbsp; Peter knows a lot of people and has great respect for many of them.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s no fan of the New American Century PR or what the neocons have accomplished, using perhaps dated terminology.&amp;nbsp; Richard Perle and like that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dr. Bechtold volunteered that he had no inside information on events in Idlib, site of the chemical attack in early April, 2017.&amp;nbsp; The relevant international bodies have not confirmed the Assad government still has any chemical weapons, nor was there clear motivation to use them.&amp;nbsp; I share his skepticism.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, Wilson probably had the right idea, about providing peoples in the region with more apparatus for self determination.&amp;nbsp; The arbitrary boundaries and agreements made by English and French social engineers have not withstood the test of time.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/959946352538305329'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/959946352538305329'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/05/wanderers-2017530.html' title='Wanderers 2017.5.30'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7333938469166880702</id><published>2017-05-25T23:19:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2017-05-25T23:19:53.507-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Control Room</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hswm-1wkODw&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dDo45wQd2-o&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/7333938469166880702/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/7333938469166880702' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7333938469166880702'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7333938469166880702'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/05/control-room.html' title='Control Room'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/hswm-1wkODw/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4931531360337124975</id><published>2017-05-25T15:58:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2017-05-25T15:59:32.490-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Coding with Kids</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codepen&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-embed-version=&quot;2&quot; data-height=&quot;455&quot; data-pen-title=&quot;Sine Wave Experiment&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;YVMKaM&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;dark&quot; data-user=&quot;pdx4d&quot;&gt;
See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/pdx4d/pen/YVMKaM/&quot;&gt;Sine Wave Experiment&lt;/a&gt; by Kirby Urner (&lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/pdx4d&quot;&gt;@pdx4d&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4931531360337124975'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4931531360337124975'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/05/coding-with-kids.html' title='Coding with Kids'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6320669117114527749</id><published>2017-05-23T09:44:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2017-05-23T09:59:38.136-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Coroutines</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I see refugees from Chef World (aka &quot;the kitchen&quot;) trying their hand at coding, and thinking they&#39;re making a big leap. Yes, they are, in a way, but in other ways a short order cook is a study in workflows, and an algorithm is a semi-numerical recipe.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The key to cooperative concurrency is the wisely chosen yield keyword in Python, which is two way, and a way of handing back control to the caller, voluntarily we might say, before all business is completed.&amp;nbsp; Queue up a number of such yielding tasks, as promising to deliver in the future, and roll through them, round robin or when the timer dings (ready!) and you&#39;ve got yourself an event loop.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In a seeming change of subject, I had the C6XTY &quot;buckyball&quot; made of six units, screwed together with eight disks, as a &quot;booth magnet&quot; conversation piece.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Even after understanding our proposal, for a smart router that keeps students on task, schools approved by model families, a Pythonista maybe wanted to linger, chat on other topics.&amp;nbsp; Hexapents for everyone (HP4E) meets CP4E (Guido himself sauntered by, but chose neither to engage nor inhibit, per Pycon&#39;s code).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The connection is this concept of &quot;payload&quot; or &quot;something valuable inside&quot;.&amp;nbsp; When a Python generator returns, raising a StopIteration, a payload might go inside at that point.&amp;nbsp; Likewise a Future, or class of Task, this this &quot;cooking&quot; or &quot;baking&quot; internal state, which the event loop keeps checking, not blocking for more than a moment if the task is clearly undone.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Once an egg &quot;hatches&quot; and releases the payload, then other design patterns kick in.&amp;nbsp; Cooked meals get delivered to tables. A waiter / waitress is optimizing in many ways too.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The chef or chefs may be amazing in their seeming ability to multi-task, but lets not forget:&amp;nbsp; the whole restaurant is made from coroutines.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Nor is such an ecosystem incompatible with the pre-emptive multitasking going on at a deeper level.&amp;nbsp; The OS knows the CPU is a resource to share.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s nothing wrong with running &quot;blocking code&quot; or &quot;being a CPU hog&quot; when you&#39;ve been scheduled for useful work, and when the OS retains the channel changer (the &quot;remote&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s how CERN and Hubble both work, with a jobs queue.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s up to the researchers to manage a workflow once their fun in the sun comes around.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6320669117114527749'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6320669117114527749'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/05/coroutines.html' title='Coroutines'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3118536688823840847</id><published>2017-05-18T18:16:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2017-05-18T23:51:14.500-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Haim&#39;s Challenge</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VNqyIm9nn2g&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
In chapters passed, I tried to dispute &lt;i&gt;Haim&#39;s Challenge&lt;/i&gt;, which he &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=10152455&quot;&gt;re-introduced on math-teach&lt;/a&gt; again recently:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
Thank you for the opportunity to re-introduce &quot;Haim&#39;s Challenge&quot;,&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=6300122&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=6300122&amp;amp;tstart=0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;There are no important open questions in math pedagogy.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
(The
 Challenge is to prove the premise wrong by pointing to even one 
long-term, ongoing examination of open questions in math pedagogy, by 
any group of people, anywhere.  The context is K-12 mathematics.)&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I&#39;d bring up A&amp;amp;B modules, T&amp;amp;E modules, clearly referencing &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; for its pedagogical implications.&amp;nbsp; Of course the K-12 curriculum should be adjusted, here and there!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
Of course I do not discuss math pedagogy, for the simple reason that there is nothing to discuss.  Or, so I believe.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I believe:&lt;br /&gt;
(1) We know everything there is to know about school mathematics (i.e., K-12 math), and&lt;br /&gt;
(2) We know everything there is to know about how to teach it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So,
 the only really important question is why don&#39;t the schools do what we 
know they should do to most effectively teach math to the most students?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The
 answer can only be found by exploring the politics of education, not 
the mechanics of long division or anything like that.  We know the 
mechanics of long division.  What is less clear is why the schools don&#39;t
 teach it well, if at all.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
I realize now that actions speak louder than words, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/12/seeking-work.html&quot;&gt;Haim well explains&lt;/a&gt; many phenomena I observe in the ambient culture.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Whether I agree with Haim&#39;s challenge (more like a claim) or not is immaterial.&amp;nbsp; My sphere of influence is definitely limited.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People treat mathematics as a static aspect of their environment.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Hell would freeze over before &quot;tetravolumes&quot; would rise to the level of attracting the attention of grade school math teachers, let alone prove share-worthy, with coming generations. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I get it.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s certainly not a decision I&#39;m comfortable with, which accounts for my somewhat non-mainstream ethnicity.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3118536688823840847'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3118536688823840847'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/05/haims-challenge.html' title='Haim&#39;s Challenge'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/VNqyIm9nn2g/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3750946100851215871</id><published>2017-05-13T20:42:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2017-05-13T20:46:48.610-07:00</updated><title type='text'>On Projection</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
In dime store psychology books for the dummy dumbfuckistanis, you&#39;ll learn that &quot;projection&quot; is something you shouldn&#39;t do, like picking your nose in public.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
With a little training and vigilance, one grows out of this immature practice, and then just sees others doing it, so blind to their own failings.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
More upscale psychology, closer to worth the money, will tell you &quot;projection&quot; is all you&#39;ve got (in the more Plato&#39;s Cave sense) and so the game is one of &quot;fine tuning&quot; (presuming you&#39;re even grossly in the right ballpark).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you make projection be your friend, and then spend the time, do the homework, to learn it as a skill, an intentional art, you might wind up with something more like a crystal ball in your own estimation.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Why we diss projection is it leads us astray. We believe our beliefs and that&#39;s rarely a good idea.&amp;nbsp; Were projection to be trusted, like corrected vision, then that&#39;d be a new chapter.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I do like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gurdjieff.org/hunter1.htm&quot;&gt;Maurice Nicoll&lt;/a&gt;, the intrepid Scotsman, on this topic.&amp;nbsp; He warns us to not identify with every thought or feeling posing as &quot;one&#39;s own&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Many never even get to that first rung of the ladder: of realizing they have a choice, in terms of what inner voices to identify with.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How fast they climb from there, is anyone&#39;s guess.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3750946100851215871'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3750946100851215871'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/05/on-projection.html' title='On Projection'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5325599275640757355</id><published>2017-05-08T22:38:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2017-05-12T23:19:56.699-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Public Policy: Finding Farm Workers</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/drrRn0EuQtY&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Although &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/06/a-flextegrity-story.html&quot;&gt;Glenn&lt;/a&gt; grew up in a union family, amidst other union families, he came to see the downside of unions as well.&amp;nbsp; I learned more of his story this afternoon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
His decision to quit the electricians union in Phoenix is what ultimately led to his joining the Navy and enrolling in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Defense_Language_Institute&quot;&gt;the Defense Language Institute&lt;/a&gt; in Monterey.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The theme of our discussion: the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oregonlive.com/business/index.ssf/2017/04/oregon_farmers_scrambling_as_l.html&quot;&gt;looming agricultural crisis&lt;/a&gt; as states scramble to find farm workers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The clamp down on itinerant field workers is endangering vast resources, from vineyards to asparagus patches.&amp;nbsp; Picture acres and acres of rotting onions, potatoes, you name it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Might states start up their own Guest Worker programs independently of the Feds?&amp;nbsp; What unions might get involved, if any?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Could we use smartphone apps to help workers find opportunities?&amp;nbsp; The same apps might help farm managers find help.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Given we live near Cesar E. Chavez Avenue, the newer name for SE 39th, it makes some sense we&#39;d be wondering about United Farm Workers and so on.&amp;nbsp; What&#39;s the history at least?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Glenn dove into Wikipedia as a start.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Institute for Science, Engineering and Public Policy provided the impetus, and meeting place, for Wanderers in the first place.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That some of us would be focused on the impending farm worker shortage certainly stands to reason.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9feWfihFZfg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5325599275640757355'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5325599275640757355'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/05/public-policy-finding-farm-workers.html' title='Public Policy: Finding Farm Workers'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/drrRn0EuQtY/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6754762796642629386</id><published>2017-05-01T23:29:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2017-05-02T09:04:22.711-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Screen Time</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/33582839565/in/album-72157683231441636/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF4101&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF4101&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/3/2894/33582839565_eb19c14579.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
We spend a lot of time with our screens don&#39;t we?&amp;nbsp; Internet or TV, consuming and/or creating.&amp;nbsp; Our level of media output has been rising exponentially I&#39;d hazard, along with our ability to store it all.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Will the collective nervous system get too nervous?&amp;nbsp; We balance on a tightrope, afraid of falling, with so many clamoring for the more violent alternatives.&amp;nbsp; They want to see it in their lifetimes, whatever it is.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
During our meetup tonight, over the wire, like a closed circuit TV show with chat window, I explained more about my own workflows, rendering out graphics that start out with Python code. A lot of my friends will use C and/or C++.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I wasn&#39;t a software engineer so much as a philosopher by training, and as a consequence I was on the lookout for patterns we could affordably capture with technology of that day, including data from heart procedures, feeding the medical research.&amp;nbsp; Statistics matter.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Shifting gears, I&#39;ve been archiving &quot;Gnome&quot; Chomsky Youtubes to my Facebook profile.&amp;nbsp; Not a lot of them all at once, just a few. [&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/3i9ra-i6Knc&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/ZrEDo9ChSdQ&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/UqFnnoM-ttU&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
Not news: Gnome doesn&#39;t think 43 was in the loop on Nine Eleven. Not 
something I&#39;ve ever claimed either and in fact I don&#39;t think continuing 
to read the Goat Book was a bad reaction. Stay calm, don&#39;t rush around 
like an idiot, which is what they seem good at in DC, lots of 
pin-balling betwixt one office and another in some panic. Caveat: this 
was awhile ago; I have no idea what Gnome&#39;s saying today exactly.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I was working through &lt;i&gt;Pan&#39;s Labyrinth&lt;/i&gt;, on DVD, while taking a break from teacher prep.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s a dark tale that got me catching up on the Spanish Civil War again.&amp;nbsp; One thing led to another and it was the Chechen Wars that got my attention.&amp;nbsp; We didn&#39;t start the fire, but nor have we succeeded in putting it out.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A theme in these blogs is the Bucky stuff could make a difference, but probably in back office philosophy and management at this point, the more outward forms coming from more recent generations, sometimes motivated by the American enlightenment, if we want to call it that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Imperialism long ago alienated Samuel Clemens and William James.&amp;nbsp; These repeated wars against Asians were avoidable it seems, but for that sense of manifest destiny that drives many ethnicities.&amp;nbsp; Everyone seems to consider themselves chosen.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On a micro speck of a planet, ethnic differences seem somewhat trivial, to say the least. But upon zooming in, that tale told by an idiot gets taller and taller, becoming a giant soap opera at the other extreme. People need to be heroes. The vanity of the Captain in &lt;i&gt;Pan&#39;s Labyrinth &lt;/i&gt;only makes him seem more of a monster.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The animations in that movie are pretty good, the faun, the fairies. I&#39;ve not been able to directly produce anything of that quality. I was reminded of &lt;i&gt;eXistenZ&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Synergetics could be an influence in some future animations.&amp;nbsp; I laid some groundwork with the &quot;hypertoons&quot; concept.&amp;nbsp; Check my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vk-cpknOz9E&amp;amp;list=PLeBIlkJm4xglicSifacG4eewD9CQaWvU0&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Synergetics 101&lt;/i&gt; playlist&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;in my Youtube channel maybe?&amp;nbsp; They link to each other, gradually building up a memeplex worth sharing.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/33527630460/in/album-72157683231441636/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF4606&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF4606&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/3/2880/33527630460_871672c3d5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6754762796642629386'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6754762796642629386'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/05/screen-time.html' title='Screen Time'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8434872069386886922</id><published>2017-04-22T14:59:00.006-07:00</published><updated>2023-10-06T12:19:13.243-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Earth Day 2017</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157682832095296&quot; title=&quot;March for Science 2017&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;March for Science 2017&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/2894/33393900683_6b383359a7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The organizers had rented a fairly high powered sound stage and were able to project speeches to the gathering thousands, after which followed a march, permitted, peaceful. One black-block-looking guy seemed out of place, furtively glancing about from behind his mask for at least one other anarchists in his tribe. &amp;nbsp;Police kept a low profile, with no riot cops in gear that we could see.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Glenn and I took the bus downtown and joined in the march but also stood on the sidelines, the better to take pictures and enjoy the exotic assortment of science advocates.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We adjourned to the &lt;i&gt;Yard House&lt;/i&gt; where we were soon joined by Dr. DiNucci, an expert in parallelism and operations research. &amp;nbsp;He&#39;d been marching with the Humanists&#39; banner. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I saw several people I know in the crowd today, including a few Quakers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The perception among many is that politicians, a lower ranking form of social engineer, may have lost their grasp on reality, in an effort to govern through make-believe. &amp;nbsp;Their policies seem increasingly irrational to the point of crazy. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Washington DC, a distant city, run more by lawyers than engineers, seems to have dwindling relevance around the Pacific Rim. &amp;nbsp;All those bellicose threats against our way of life add up to a big turn off.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Those avidly seeking greater political power inadvertently advertise their sense of not having much. &amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The End of Power&lt;/i&gt; comes to mind, a book in the Blue House collection.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/32524917490/in/album-72157617745459466/&quot; title=&quot;Rising Literacy&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Rising Literacy&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/3/2462/32524917490_f390317daf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8434872069386886922'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8434872069386886922'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/04/earth-day-2017.html' title='Earth Day 2017'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>