<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=676'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=651&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=701&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>676</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3651587931831061374</id><published>2015-07-23T12:21:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-07-26T15:18:24.277-07:00</updated><title type='text'>OSCON 2015 Continues!</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Tim O&#39;Reilly held court in the Expo Hall during the break (sponsored by &lt;i&gt;New Relic&lt;/i&gt;), after the UK&#39;s counterpart, the head of a US version of Digital Services, had given a keynote.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oscon.com/open-source-2015/public/schedule/detail/45365&quot;&gt;PayPal with InnerSource&lt;/a&gt; is on the same page as other big enterprises:&amp;nbsp; the open source way of working, with tools that are open source, builds a better enterprise.&amp;nbsp; The shorter tag line:&amp;nbsp; Apache Inside (as in Apache Foundation projects; still a hotbed of open license technologies).&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Walmart Labs&lt;/i&gt; has likewise standardized on the Open Source way inhouse, both using and contributing to the ecosystem, with a stack based on Node, Cassandra and Mongo in large degree, and moving to Trusty for a standard OS (Trusty is in the Ubuntu series).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19385056683/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;apache&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;apache&quot; height=&quot;148&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/338/19385056683_d7fe96fd63.jpg&quot; width=&quot;280&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tim talked a lot about Technology to solve social ills by augmenting people power, not oppressing us. &quot;Where&#39;s the Uber for eldercare?&quot; he wondered, echoing ideas I learned about &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/07/wanderers-meeting-200575.html&quot;&gt;from &lt;i&gt;CareWheels&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a project to let people stay longer in their own homes with light monitoring and community support over the Web, in addition to in-home visits and services.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Uber does seem &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/07/deq.html&quot;&gt;a lot like &lt;i&gt;Transporation Reaching People&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (TRP), originally administered by Clackamas County, software by me, in an age before smartphones.&amp;nbsp; &quot;What about Technology for refugee camps?&quot; asked Tim.&amp;nbsp; Indeed.&amp;nbsp; Any instant city needs ephemeral organs of self government, feedback loops mainly.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s what journalism helps with, in the context of bigger picture framing viewpoints (oft referred to as &quot;bias&quot; but also &quot;leaning&quot; or even &quot;leading&quot; if using esoteric Quaker parlance).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Technology has the ability to create wealth (life support) by augmenting our powers.&amp;nbsp; As Amber Case pointed out in her later talk, with augmentation comes fear, including possible estrangement between those who &quot;have&quot; and those who &quot;have not&quot; whatever new powers we&#39;re talking about.&amp;nbsp; Other technologies are more restorative e.g. eyeglasses, used to bring people up to normative speeds. Her theme was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubiq.com/hypertext/weiser/acmfuture2endnote.htm&quot;&gt;Calm Technology&lt;/a&gt;, meaning feedback loops ranging from non-intrusive to subliminal (highly peripheral).&amp;nbsp; Suggest today&#39;s weather with light hues.&amp;nbsp; Ambient cues.&amp;nbsp; Atmospherics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20011268381/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;ubuntu&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;ubuntu&quot; height=&quot;189&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/490/20011268381_19cee60956_o.jpg&quot; width=&quot;267&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Luciano is running something concurrent to search for 192 country flag URLs, using all 676 letter combinations from AA to ZZ.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s about to talk about Python&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/ramalho/&quot;&gt;new concurrancy features&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s (virtually) hitting against the CIA Factbook, first sequentially (five minutes) than concurrently, at first with five connections (one minute), then with a hundred connections he gets all the flags (thumbnail gifs) in under five seconds.&amp;nbsp; He does this all using Python&#39;s new native &quot;green thread&quot; capabilities.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was just at Damian Conway&#39;s talk about extending Perl 5&#39;s syntax using new packages he&#39;s written, to make it a lot more like Perl 6.&amp;nbsp; One can even add new keywords in that language, by a kind of macro substitution process against the source.&amp;nbsp; Alex and Anna likewise did a language-centric talk on patterns in Python, calling out specific high level features in the standard library.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Advice to Pythonistas regarding asynchronous programming: start with learning generators thoroughly, and then study coroutines.&amp;nbsp; The newest Python (3.5 in 2015) has new keywords:&amp;nbsp; &lt;b&gt;async def&lt;/b&gt; replaces the @asyncio.coroutine decorator and &lt;b&gt;await&lt;/b&gt; replaces &lt;b&gt;yield from&lt;/b&gt;.&amp;nbsp; An asyncio Task wraps a coroutine, giving an API allowing task cancellation and status checks.&amp;nbsp; The style suggested is a way of avoiding &quot;callback hell&quot; according to Luciano.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Luciano would later be wandering over to the &lt;i&gt;Urban Airship&lt;/i&gt; site on the west side to deliver his talk to our Python User Group.&amp;nbsp; I hope I get to ask him how that went.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The grand finale talk for me today was co-worker Patrick Barton&#39;s presentation, about using some fancy &quot;neo-cortical&quot; algorithms (implemented in Python) to predict short term energy demand based on previous learning.&amp;nbsp; Then it was off to Amber&#39;s talk and the &lt;i&gt;WalMart Labs&lt;/i&gt; mixer at &lt;i&gt;Spirit of 77&lt;/i&gt; across the street.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Training a Numenta instance is somewhat like training Dragon speech recognition software.&amp;nbsp; In this case, the &quot;voice&quot; was the collective energy demand of some 116 households in Austin, TX (the site for next year&#39;s OSCON as fate would have it). Paul (co-worker) and I adjourned to &lt;i&gt;Lucky Lab&lt;/i&gt; on Hawthorne in his company car (different company -- he has two jobs) for a nightcap with Ben (former co-worker) and a fellow car nut, then I hopped a bus home.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tomorrow I think I&#39;ll start out walking Mt. Tabor again.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s been quite awhile.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve been working on &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/07/cooling-my-heels.html&quot;&gt;healing the ankle&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Then I&#39;ll watch the opening keynotes &lt;a href=&quot;http://oscon.com/live&quot;&gt;via live streaming&lt;/a&gt; before trekking over there for closing ceremonies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19934859766/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Amber Case&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Amber Case&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/337/19934859766_57ce8103db_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: amber case (esri) ::
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3651587931831061374'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3651587931831061374'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/oscon-2015-continues.html' title='OSCON 2015 Continues!'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2171168487305935473</id><published>2015-07-20T15:06:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-07-25T16:14:41.712-07:00</updated><title type='text'>OSCON 2015 Begins!</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19874079611/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF9079&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF9079&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/324/19874079611_364b430a16.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
This time I had my confirmation code, after the embarrassment of last year where a phone call needed to be placed to confirm my status as a proposal reader.&amp;nbsp; On top of that I&#39;m an employee.&amp;nbsp; Anyway, this year the confirmation code was not required, simply a QR-code on one&#39;s phone, or the email address one had registered with.&amp;nbsp; Super fast, with the name badge printing right there.&amp;nbsp; I was good to go in no time flat.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Holden is in from the UK and we met up with Patrick and Deke at &lt;i&gt;Hop House&lt;/i&gt; last night.&amp;nbsp; Today, he and I were both in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oscon.com/open-source-2015/public/schedule/detail/42203&quot;&gt;the Docker tutorial&lt;/a&gt;, brilliantly presented and organized by Andrew Baker, with Twilio in DC.&amp;nbsp; He had a large number of Ubuntu cloud instances ready to give us each one-on-one access to a docker-ready platform.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So what&#39;s Docker?&amp;nbsp; As Andrew explained, on the spectrum from manually configuring a server from scratch, all the way to configuration scripts and virtual machines, it&#39;s closer to supplying a VM but not in the sense of hosting a guest Operating System.&amp;nbsp; Might one call it a light-weight operating system layer, an OS extension?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Docker containerizes processes (services) and thereby has them join a community of well-behaved players, and in a way that stores to an image one places in a Docker Registry.&amp;nbsp; Run an image to boot up containers, each supervising a processes such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://realpython.com/blog/python/dockerizing-flask-with-compose-and-machine-from-localhost-to-the-cloud/&quot;&gt;a Flask app&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/examples/postgresql_service/&quot;&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.docker.com/2015/04/tips-for-deploying-nginx-official-image-with-docker/&quot;&gt;Nginx&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://neo4j.com/developer/docker/&quot;&gt;Neo4j&lt;/a&gt;, and so on.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I met up with Alex Martelli then rejoined Steve and we shortly adjourned to lunch, in the vast &quot;Holodeck&quot; as some call it, in the Oregon Convention Center, there to be joined by Anna Ravenscroft (also Martelli family).&amp;nbsp; Conversation turned to having enough supplies to last through some unspecified catastrophe, a focus of LDS church members as well as preparedness groups more generally.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I got through the gifify exercise then decided I wanted my XQ-1 back from &lt;i&gt;Camera World&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; I was able to secure the replacement and return before the tutorial had ended, whereupon we splice to the above lunch at the Pythonista table.&amp;nbsp; This is actually a replacement, not a repair (same language used in cardiology) with a new serial number and everything.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m looking forward to blissing out with it.&amp;nbsp; Above is the first shot taken, of Holden on my back deck, after lunch.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19819510228/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;docker2&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;docker2&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/431/19819510228_2af987f888_o.jpg&quot; width=&quot;237&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2171168487305935473'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2171168487305935473'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/oscon-2015-begins.html' title='OSCON 2015 Begins!'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8009114230228531171</id><published>2015-07-17T13:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-07-31T05:51:25.220-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Discipline and Record Keeping</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Although many Friends don&#39;t think of it this way, keeping accurate and complete records falls under the Truth Testimony.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Are these records to be believed?&quot;&amp;nbsp; If the answer is &quot;no&quot; then we may conclude:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
(A) they&#39;re meant as fiction (storytelling) perhaps with embedded teachings&lt;br /&gt;
(B) they&#39;re obsolete (out of date) and in that sense misinforming&lt;br /&gt;
(C) they&#39;re deliberately misinforming&lt;br /&gt;
(D) the records are riddled with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/01/more-geopolitics.html&quot;&gt;outright lies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In moving from A-D, I&#39;m escalating the severity of the untruths.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Many not-truthful records fall into category (B) within NPYM.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We have creaky, obsolete ways of conducting business.&amp;nbsp; Collectively, we lack discipline as a business.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Saying a nonprofit or 501(c)(3) &quot;is not a business&quot; is probably a grave error, one that kills off serious Quakerism by suggesting that our &quot;business&quot; (as in &quot;Meetings for Business&quot; -- a core activity) is not &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; business, and so the idea of applying serious &quot;business logic&quot; or &quot;business rules&quot; need not apply.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The lack of discipline in our record-keeping is thereby justified.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Everyone knows non-profits are dysfunctional&quot; -- a belief I&#39;ve encountered often.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Perhaps it would be constructive to use the term NGO (for non-governmental organization) more assiduously?&amp;nbsp; Personnel in the global development business know that &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/06/visa-commercial.html&quot;&gt;not all NGOs&lt;/a&gt; are slouches,&amp;nbsp; Some NGOs have their act together, including with respect to record-keeping.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What holds us back is the stereotype of a &quot;non-profit charity&quot; as a loose ship run by mostly volunteers, a hobby activity.&amp;nbsp; The outcome:&amp;nbsp; recreational Quakerism, not all that serious and typically middle class Christian, a religion being something people engage in &quot;on Sundays&quot; and on some holidays.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks to the connotations of &quot;non-profit&quot;, our &quot;business&quot; takes a back seat, including record-keeping, as Friends indulge in what they consider &quot;more spiritual&quot; matters.&amp;nbsp; Record keeping is not sexy enough.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
NPYM Friends fall further and further behind, in terms of relevance, as they allow their &quot;business culture&quot; to continue to degrade.&amp;nbsp; Quakers reached their peak in power and credibility sometime &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2014/10/a-quaker-arc.html&quot;&gt;in the late 1700s&lt;/a&gt;, when they actually ran legitimate businesses.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The very idea of a &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;sectarian business&lt;/a&gt;&quot; is fairly unusual by now, at least as a marketing ploy.&amp;nbsp; Everyone knows that Quaker (&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/go-humans-go.html&quot;&gt;the commercial brand&lt;/a&gt;) does not mean Quaker (the religious sect).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When the Rajneeshis tried to start their own company town in central Oregon, they opened some storefronts in Portland, like a bakery, but those all were shut down, leaving a bad taste with many Oregonians (a twisted tale).&amp;nbsp; Churches sometimes have gift shops at least.&amp;nbsp; Christian supply stores abound like at &lt;i&gt;The Grotto&lt;/i&gt; in Portland.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At some point, with the passage of time, the neglect starts to seem more willful and we move from (B) closer to (D) along the Scale of Untruthfulness.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not lifting a finger to become more up to date eventually becomes a way of lying, with lying becoming a way of life.&amp;nbsp; Externalizing &quot;future shock&quot; so that others must endure it, but not oneself, is a way of postponing the day of reckoning.&amp;nbsp; Answering the call of the Zeitgeist to &quot;shape up&quot; means keeping up with best practices around curating and record-keeping.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/10/graphing-relationships.html&quot;&gt;Graph database&lt;/a&gt; anyone?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I don&#39;t believe we need hirelings when it comes to the basics of Quaker record-keeping though.&amp;nbsp; In today&#39;s world, these basics include knowing something about Structured Query Language (SQL) and databases. People in a clerking role should bone up on the relevant technology.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not all ledger books and quill pens anymore.&amp;nbsp; We do not live in Victorian England.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Bottom line:&amp;nbsp; software engineering is not &quot;outside&quot; the spiritual sphere, but is rather at the core of our practice and has to do with the Truth Testimony.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/05/engineering-as-moral-enterprise.html&quot;&gt;Engineering is a spiritual activity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d like to address issues of lax discipline around 
record-keeping in the context of joining said standing Discipline Committee.&amp;nbsp; The 
role of &quot;clerk&quot; involves attention to records.&amp;nbsp; Keeping our information 
up to date is a shared responsibility of clerks, not something to 
outsource or lay at the door of some paid person.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As the Technology Clerk, new position (unpaid of course), I&#39;ve been agitating
 for ex oficio status on the Discipline Committee.&amp;nbsp; I want our practices
 to improve &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?forumID=206&amp;amp;messageID=7344243&quot;&gt;with respect to record-keeping&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Lets see where that goes.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m getting the feeling my proposal is not taken seriously yet.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8009114230228531171'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8009114230228531171'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/discipline-and-record-keeping.html' title='Discipline and Record Keeping'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5860893943920507552</id><published>2015-07-16T07:24:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-07-31T19:59:42.668-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Annual Session (Day One)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19541227340/in/album-72157655634700169/&quot; title=&quot;Lunch Break&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Lunch Break&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/360/19541227340_095f93d54f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Since getting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/v9k8t9&quot;&gt;new air flow meter&lt;/a&gt;, maxi taxi (1997 Nissan, doors dented cosmetically, right side), the ride has been smooth, not lurchy.&amp;nbsp; Carol and I left Blue House (as named within the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/08/business-cards.html&quot;&gt;FNB namespace&lt;/a&gt;) around noon, making it to Spokane by about 18:30, with a stop at Cross Roads truck stop near Umatilla / Irrigon, right where I-82 hops the Columbia.&amp;nbsp; The Caesar salad was enormous.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Barry (Wanderer) drives to Spokane often and talks about the windmills, which he doesn&#39;t like.&amp;nbsp; But then the pylons were there first and he&#39;s OK with those.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Notably, one sees none outside the Gorge margins.&amp;nbsp; The farmlands are still using hydro-power, from the numerous dams.&amp;nbsp; Actually that&#39;s an oversimplification as the windmills feed the same grid.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19680739728/in/album-72157655634700169/&quot; title=&quot;Windmills&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Windmills&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/437/19680739728_90d71a4cb6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d not been out this far by surface vehicle for so long that the windmills were new to me.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m more used to the farmland ones along say I-70 / I-75 in IN, IL, MS or one of those.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Friends (the Religious Society thereof) were born in the 1600s so lets call them Elizabethan.&amp;nbsp; In the times of Shakespeare and the East India Company&#39;s rise to global power, a man named George Fox questioned authority in a big way, and served to focus what a lot of people were thinking at the time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How this sect got branded &quot;Quaker&quot; is a bit of a story, however this was a lucky break as any ad man will tell ya.&amp;nbsp; &quot;The rest is history&quot; as they say.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
After a period of persecution in which Quakers faced &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/PhsvqbCIaAs&quot;&gt;jail time or worse&lt;/a&gt;,
 they become vogue, partially owing to their success in banking and 
business.&amp;nbsp; By the late 1700s, Quakers were making tons of money, and 
doing it &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/12/twelve-years-of-slavery-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;without slavery&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;
 The industrial revolution was in full swing, displacing human labor as a
 source of brute strength.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Brain over brawn, mind over brain&quot; might be
 our mantra.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
George Fox, like William Penn, another big name Friend, has lots of stuff named after him, including a university (at least one).&amp;nbsp; Penn State is a whole state (Pennsylvania i.e. Billy&#39;s Forest -- no one called him Billy AFAIK).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;re sharing eating facilities with a large number of athletic young girls in the middle of summer soccer practice.&amp;nbsp; Women&#39;s soccer was huge this year, a bigger magnet for viewers of that final World Cup game than even the final playoff NFL game or whatever.&amp;nbsp; The US team trounced Japan&#39;s in the final round, wow, what a goal (I caught up later, despite my Facebook-registered intent to catch it live).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lots more soccer players than Quakers so far, have entered the dining area, but then that&#39;s true world wide.&amp;nbsp; I hope they leave me some breakfast.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll add to this account after we hear from the Friend in Residence (traditionally, an invited guest gives the keynote).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Oh wait, duh, basketball, not soccer.&amp;nbsp; Actually seeing the balls was the giveaway.&amp;nbsp; Oh, and the shirts.&amp;nbsp; What was I thinking?&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll leave the above paragraphs to show how I come to false conclusions sometimes (but I am also self-correcting, given enough opportunity).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Good chatting with (in order of appearance): Clint Weimeister, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/07/checking-in.html&quot;&gt;Dave Fabik&lt;/a&gt;, Ethan Berleman, Chris Cradler, Eddy Crouch (we used to work with AFSC together) and assorted University Friends Meeting folks (Seattle), plus one guy from Olympia.&amp;nbsp; Chris&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/08/making-rounds.html&quot;&gt;Larry&lt;/a&gt; will be flying out later.&amp;nbsp; Greg, their eldest is with the grad school in housing close to Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton, which I used to jog through a lot, when a student.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What I&#39;ll call the Zen wing of Quakers is actually very traditional in eschewing theology, preferring to let each Friend fill the void with whatever experimental brain-chatter.&amp;nbsp; The more Zen-like Friends see theology as the bureaucratization of faith by a hireling priest caste.&amp;nbsp; Our Society started out by purging itself of any priestly hierarchy in favor of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/12/management-by-rotation.html&quot;&gt;rotational self-management scheme&lt;/a&gt;, based on clerked committees, both standing and ad hoc.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, women especially love theology and that gender has banded together to form a more theologically-oriented group called the Women&#39;s Theological Conference.&amp;nbsp; They had some PR (book markers) at every table here at Annual Session, advertising their 2016 event.&amp;nbsp; Our &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/03/wqm-mens-group-2015.html&quot;&gt;WQM Mens Group &lt;/a&gt;is hardly &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/07/together-friends.html&quot;&gt;that together&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some brands of Friend actually do hire pastors, going back to the kind of outsourcing familiar to most &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/09/business-trip.html&quot;&gt;steeple house&lt;/a&gt;&quot; Christians (as &quot;spin doctor George&quot; referred to the churches of his day, somewhat disparagingly).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m in favor of the Zen wing breaking off from and/or distinguishing itself from Christianity as away of underlining its freedom from theological concerns, but then right away we &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/06/literary-investigation.html&quot;&gt;get into philosophy&lt;/a&gt;, so what&#39;s the difference?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Philosophy has more room &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2014/02/gnostic-musings.html&quot;&gt;for Gnostic influences&lt;/a&gt; is how I&#39;d put it (Gnosticism in turn inherits a lot from Zoroaster and Hermes T. both).&amp;nbsp; The Jungians would understand I think.&amp;nbsp; Zen is more a psychology and a philosophy than a theology, ditto the Quakerism I practice.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5860893943920507552'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5860893943920507552'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/annual-session-day-one.html' title='Annual Session (Day One)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8845880257403127475</id><published>2015-07-12T07:19:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2016-12-02T13:08:16.313-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Deficiencies in the English Language</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
The BBC interviewed some bloke last night who used to be a BBC journalist and so needed to be unbiased, but was now in a new position, as a pundit, and so could come right out and say that Iran is seeking nuke weapons.&amp;nbsp; He was open about shedding his former journalistic guise and becoming more openly biased.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The pundit was talking about ongoing negotiations in Vienna to establish a &quot;breakout box&quot; inside of which Iran would be boxed, not allowed to break out.&amp;nbsp; This is the Standard Model used within Washington DC circles (e.g. within the Beltway) as well.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s missing from the analysis, as usual, is any calculation as to what&#39;s in it for Iran to paint the Rogue States (the nuclear WMD states) as minions of a Great Satan, the hubristic desire to hold a Sword of Damocles over the rest of humankind, to arrogate the role of a &quot;Do as I Say or Else&quot; supreme bully.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People with nukes tend to threaten, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/07/comments-on-news.html&quot;&gt;gloat&lt;/a&gt;, lord it over, strut, puff etc. (it&#39;s a syndrome) -- we&#39;ve seen it in the White House, and lets talk about &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/09/lampoon-harpoon.html&quot;&gt;Tony Blair&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Saying nuke WMDs are &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/jihad.html&quot;&gt;against Islam&lt;/a&gt;&quot; is a setup to portray Christians, Jews and secularists as morally inferior i.e. susceptible to the military-industrial complex (a meme virus).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/03/why-we-fight-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Eisenhower himself&lt;/a&gt; warned us of this susceptibility.&amp;nbsp; Iran, not just South Africa, stands for hope, sanity, and a better tomorrow in this picture.&amp;nbsp; Islam is about a better future, not Tyranny by the Rogue States, with the same criminal, murderous weapons that Iran should never have (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quakerquaker.org/forum/topics/iran-is-officially-anti-nuke-wmd&quot;&gt;Iran agrees&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Even if Iran &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; secretly building a bomb, or wanting to, it&#39;s poor journalism to not even sketch for the listeners how Iran might actually have a motive to lead the &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/07/july-4-2015.html&quot;&gt;Ban Treaty movement&lt;/a&gt;, and to embrace not only non-proliferation, but criminalization of existing nuclear arsenals, an agreement most UN nations have already signed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Wouldn&#39;t that be good PR, to help leverage a ban on nuke weapons worldwide?&amp;nbsp; Iran would be seen as a moral leader, victorious against the reprobates and backsliders, the less humane.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Politically speaking, it adds to Iran&#39;s gravitas as a principled nation and great civilization, to take a stand against nukes while allowing for atomic power.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Doing so from a position of strength makes it a conscious choice.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The US wants to paint itself as victorious in &quot;forcing&quot; Iran to submit to inspections.&amp;nbsp; But what about the US itself?&amp;nbsp; It has no intention of submitting to anything, and that&#39;s where its hypocrisy is both self evident and self undermining.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The US position well explains its continuing loss of credibility, day by day, which the BBC is striving valiantly to shore up, given &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/07/big-fix-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;that Special Relationship&lt;/a&gt; and perhaps loyalty to another English-speaking culture.&amp;nbsp; But hasn&#39;t all this shoring up become uncomfortably transparent?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In fact, imputing such a motive to Iran, to be a religious leader seizing the moral high ground, which might have an endgame wherein Iran-trained weapons inspectors gain access to syndicate facilities in Colorado someday, once the Ban is imposed, connects a lot of dots already out there, such as the Nuclear Free Zone we know Iran proposed, but which the WMD nations derailed for the region.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Great Satan wants His nuke weapons without restrictions of any kind.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Great Satan has actually used nukes against Japan and &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/11/pacific-islanders-meet.html&quot;&gt;Micronesia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yet through misdirection we&#39;re made to think Iran is the hypocrite.&amp;nbsp; Very clever?&amp;nbsp; Maybe just dumb?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; How long can it last?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The longer &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/06/quakers-2015628.html&quot;&gt;Iran&#39;s rhetoric&lt;/a&gt; and actions match up, the more Great Satan seems engaged in delay tactics around preventing any &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/12/countdown-to-zero-game.html&quot;&gt;Countdown to Zero&lt;/a&gt; clock from ticking.&amp;nbsp; Tick, tick, tick...&amp;nbsp; Austria is already strongly in favor of a Ban Treaty.&amp;nbsp; Is that why they&#39;re meeting in Vienna then?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m not at all surprised that CNN hasn&#39;t the courage to explain the PR situation to the American viewers, easy to fool, none too bright, par for the course. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, I&#39;m a little surprised the BBC won&#39;t let its global listeners even sample this line of reasoning, which is well-known outside the Anglo-speaking sphere.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Maybe tonight?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Will they get anyone more conversant with the actual dynamics of the situation, for balance if nothing else?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One almost thinks the English language, or &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/serving-from-algebra-city.html&quot;&gt;forked tongue&lt;/a&gt;&quot; as some call it, is incapable, almost as a software issue, of revealing its own inconsistencies and hypocrisies.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;d be too undermining.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Perhaps the BBC is really just for superficially intelligent listeners.&amp;nbsp; Certainly real intelligence services would need to keep score at &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/03/nationalism-and-jobs.html&quot;&gt;a deeper level&lt;/a&gt;, if planning to stay relevant on the world stage.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8845880257403127475'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8845880257403127475'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/deficiencies-in-english-language.html' title='Deficiencies in the English Language'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3158520214593302682</id><published>2015-07-10T12:01:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2015-07-10T12:26:59.963-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Term Limits</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
BBC had an engaging episode, in the form of a multi-voice, moderated conversation, last night on the topic of term limits.&amp;nbsp; On &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p02w68yj&quot;&gt;Newshour Extra&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The guy from Singapore posited an East-West dialog with the West trying to be more important than the East in suggesting term limits as a panacea.&amp;nbsp; An ascendant West was an aberration from this gentleman&#39;s point of view, though in some models of our spherical GU (&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/10/toward-history-of-domes.html&quot;&gt;global university&lt;/a&gt;) it&#39;s hard to find these political divides in the first place.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The US President got a lot of focus.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Imagine a Constitution that allowed a president to run for a third term, but under different rules:&amp;nbsp; the electoral college would be bypassed and a simple majority vote would need to be obtained.&amp;nbsp; No fourth term would be possible without interruption i.e. after sitting it out for at least one term, OK to start over.&amp;nbsp; Might we vote for Obama for prez in 2020?&amp;nbsp; Not possible per Amendment XXII.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Grover Cleveland was 22nd and 24th president when a 3rd term would have still been allowed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Or suppose Supreme Court justices had a maximum of eight years?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We make the Judicial Branch a &quot;for life&quot; appointment (yes, I know the theory, similar to that behind academic tenure -- freedom from influence, but if you&#39;re already partisan?) but subject the Executive Branch to stringent term limits.&amp;nbsp; Why not jigger this?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Obviously the inertia behind a system as vast as the United States is there&#39;s no turning on a dime.&amp;nbsp; We could have science fiction movies about this 3rd term alternative campaign.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Imagine &quot;3rd term&quot; were institutionalized as &quot;experimental&quot; i.e. anytime we held a presidential election for a 3rd termer, we&#39;d assume innovation.&amp;nbsp; Then, ideas that worked well, that seemed beneficial, could be worked into the first two terms as reforms.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Nice idea on paper maybe but there&#39;s no turning on a dime as I&#39;ve said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But think of individual high schools full of teenagers eager to interact, to practice self-governance, along with faculty and admin.&amp;nbsp; Why not use our imaginations there?&amp;nbsp; Or in a college?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The appeal, in the college catalog, to prospective students, is not just course offerings, but this intricate manner of self-governance that really gives a resume some cred.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Their Student Senate has real power, wow, I should go there!&quot; thinks the politically-minded prospective.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We think some 200 UN nations might sound like a lot.&amp;nbsp; But think how many corporations we have, some of them supra-national.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Why not have &quot;corporate governance&quot; be more flexible?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Who says it&#39;s not flexible even today?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Quakers have corporations, with no voting, no Robert&#39;s Rules.&amp;nbsp; Doesn&#39;t that prove the corporate structure is already flexible?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s a query not a rhetorical question.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
To be continued.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3158520214593302682'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3158520214593302682'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/term-limits.html' title='Term Limits'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7964168894464858573</id><published>2015-07-07T18:56:00.005-07:00</published><updated>2015-07-10T13:01:21.460-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Big Rock Candy Mountain</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JqowmHgxVJQ?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;420&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;lets hang the jerk who invented work...&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I was listening to KBOO the other day, regarding who owns the Arctic.&amp;nbsp; People living above the Arctic Circle, called &quot;the north&quot; in this namespace, such as in Greenland, have a dialog going with the rest of us in &quot;the south&quot; regarding the use of natural resources. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sometimes there&#39;s a tidy sum to be made from extracting resource X, and it might actually be renewable (eco-tourism depends on an endless supply of tourists).&amp;nbsp; Some level of abstraction, of resources from the environment, if only oxygen and water, is required for biological continuance.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The bootstrapping equation is:&amp;nbsp; knowledge worker jobs such as one might have in some corporate office building, with bandwidth and plumbing, require fancy educations, but before we attain those high levels of education comes maybe decades of more menial work.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s what the more plodding developers think.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Says who?&quot; and &quot;Why not short circuit or leap frog, like skipping landlines for cells?&quot; &amp;nbsp; Lets enroll thousands in general systems theory, prototype curricula, pilot testing.&amp;nbsp; Experiment with XRL (extreme remote livingry), emergency shelters.&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Not&lt;/i&gt; because it&#39;s an emergency necessarily but because when it&#39;s &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; an emergency is a good time to prepare for one.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Conflate study into work / study (chores + scholarship + playful research projects) and actually pay Greenlanders to obtain that schooling starting now.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s a loan against one&#39;s future income, if you want to see it that way.&amp;nbsp; When you&#39;re born, your elderly self is already sending you money from the future!&amp;nbsp; We can &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/07/simtopia.html&quot;&gt;do that with bookkeeping&lt;/a&gt;, no time travel required.&amp;nbsp; Don&#39;t let intermediaries intercept &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/04/wanderers-2013417.html&quot;&gt;your birthright&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets call this the Big Rock Candy Mountain scenario, in contrast with &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/12/iron-mountain-revisted.html&quot;&gt;the Iron Mountain scenario&lt;/a&gt;, which latter feeds and shelters its Army Specialists on the understanding they&#39;ll do work / study under the Generalists (&quot;the generals&quot;).&amp;nbsp; These are very similar Mountains, in terms of the patterns they employ.&amp;nbsp; Livingry and killingry both require innovation and human-powered networks.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7964168894464858573'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7964168894464858573'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/big-rock-candy-mountain.html' title='Big Rock Candy Mountain'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/JqowmHgxVJQ/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7842661237663253305</id><published>2015-07-05T18:13:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2016-01-23T15:29:40.784-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Out of Mind / Sight</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
The usual phrase is &quot;out of sight out of mind&quot; and has numerous applications.&amp;nbsp; In &lt;i&gt;Madness &amp;amp; Civilization&lt;/i&gt;, Foucault traces what he considers to be a series of signal flips in Western Europe&#39;s perceptions of, and ways of coping with madness, which we may also call &quot;extreme deviance&quot; to the point of inconveniencing others and prompting them to seek a radical solution.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the Middle Ages, a town might drive its indigent, especially its beggars, outside the city gates and impose on them fines for returning.&amp;nbsp; Towns alongside rivers or canals might have their madmen hauled away by boat, creating the image of the Mad World as a large place &quot;out there&quot; beyond the boundaries of the Polis (city-state, police).&amp;nbsp; Foucault makes much of this &quot;ship of fools&quot; image.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
With the Renaissance came the view of Madness as a window into a cosmic Other, a demonic realm, making it sacred in some ways, more shamanistic or shamanic.&amp;nbsp; The deranged had their own wisdom which likewise glorified &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2014/02/the-lego-movie-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;the Good Order&lt;/a&gt;, showing how derangement was integral within the wheel of life.&amp;nbsp; Reason and Unreason both derived from the same holy root.&amp;nbsp; This attitude sounds more Oriental to me.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
By the Age of Reason, after the French Revolution, madness was more a pathology associated with &quot;not working&quot; (as in &quot;not making sense&quot;) and the strategy became one of confinement.&amp;nbsp; The mad should be made to work, as under Protestantism, virtue was in one&#39;s discipline and obedience to God&#39;s ordained.&amp;nbsp; What drove the mad mad was not a demonic order but an untamed bestiality, an &quot;animal nature&quot; which normal humans had transcended (risen above) in a moral sense.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A giant hospital system, left over from when leprosy was more of a scourge, was re-purposed to warehouse the scandalous, with the truly insane on display as people to feel superior to.&amp;nbsp; For a fee, one could visit the Asylum and mock the crazies and the freaks, or exude pity according to one&#39;s temperament.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m reading all this against the backdrop of &lt;i&gt;JFK and the Unspeakable&lt;/i&gt; by James Douglass (a well-read theologian) wherein some random guy, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dcdave.com/article5/120418.htm&quot;&gt;Ralph Leon Yates&lt;/a&gt;, picks up a hitchhiker in his pickup.&amp;nbsp; The passenger has a gun-shaped bundle he claims are &quot;curtain rods&quot; and he wants to keep them in the cab.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The driver saw later this man looked just like the Lee Harvey Oswald on TV and the curtain rods were likely the gun he&#39;d smuggled into the Book Repository and killed John Kennedy with.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;d left the Oswaldy guy close to there.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The problem with this story, according to Douglass, was the Warren Commission had already included the one and only &quot;curtain rods&quot; story it wanted, with this extra Oswald story a loose end. Having two variations of the curtain rod story pointed back to a cover-up, as did all the suspicious shenanigans in Mexico City, which had to be rejected also, for much the same reason.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
An overzealous crew of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.peacebuttons.info/E-News/peacehistoryjuly.htm#july51989&quot;&gt;Ollie North types&lt;/a&gt;, imagining themselves clever operatives, had seeded the field a little too zealously with incriminating memories, very likely using an Oswald look-alike -- including in the movie theater where he was later arrested (the &quot;other Oswald&quot; was in the balcony and arrested later per Douglass).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The fate of the driver?&amp;nbsp; He went to the FBI with his story, but since the Establishment understood its job was to support the Warren Commission, they had to commit him to a psychiatric hospital at the end of the day, and subject him to &quot;drug therapy&quot;.&amp;nbsp; His crazy story was too much of an inconvenient truth.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;d passed a polygraph test but that only proved he believed in his delusion, all the more evidence he was insane.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We shouldn&#39;t stop there in associating Yates&#39;s &quot;treatment&quot; with the rigid Rationalism of France.&amp;nbsp; Why not see Langley itself as a mother ship of &quot;hospitals&quot; dedicated to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/spy-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;treatment of the deranged&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets remember though, that deep within the Agency, subterranean, riddled with moles, many an operative was even then delighted to see the cover story was so transparently a cover-up.&amp;nbsp; It would unravel in time, it would have to.&amp;nbsp; Many would participate in the unraveling, even as others would insert new stories designed to misdirect.&amp;nbsp; Right from day one, LBJ refused to blame the Russians, knowing where that could lead, dashing hopes many held for a more serious confrontation.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s what a &quot;cover story&quot; is, when of this magnitude:&amp;nbsp; it buys time, is but a time capsule.&amp;nbsp; One generation hands it off to a next, an obvious puzzle, a mess.&amp;nbsp; One might as well stamp &quot;cover up&quot; on the box.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s radioactive, and has a half life.&amp;nbsp; But in slowly leaking its information, whispering its truths, it&#39;s less explosive, and that&#39;s the intent.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Were FDR-era Americans ready to accept a coup?&amp;nbsp; Had they heard of the Business Plot?&amp;nbsp; Coups were the stuff of Banana Republics.&amp;nbsp; The people of the USA needed a different narrative, the truth could wait.&amp;nbsp; They needed an official madness, a story that couldn&#39;t get them in trouble at work.&amp;nbsp; The job of the Warren Commission was to provide that.&amp;nbsp; People needed something to say that was not crazy, in a crazy world.&amp;nbsp; &quot;A lone gunman, acting alone...&quot; that story would become their security blanket.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Beyond the mother ship is a network of secret prisons, all interconnected by torture taxis.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re familiar with this Gothic infrastructure, as a result of the latest wars.&amp;nbsp; Large chunks of major office buildings, airstrips and old bases, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/10/hotel-oregon.html&quot;&gt;sympathetic contractors&lt;/a&gt;... Capitalism&#39;s Invisible Army.&amp;nbsp; Yet another Gulag.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The madhouses of Reason&#39;s Europe were simply re-purposed, yet again, to confine extremists, inconvenient parties.&amp;nbsp; Madmen were not usually suicide bombers in Medieval times.&amp;nbsp; Even lepers were not that suddenly contagious.&amp;nbsp; Advances in the design of explosives changed the profile of insanity towards that of a Unabomber.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In sketching an appealing profile in courage, of Jack and Robert Kennedy, Douglass somewhat skirts the issue of madness in the Oval Office itself and what that might mean.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/05/murder-mystery.html&quot;&gt;Other books&lt;/a&gt; take up that issue, including in relation to the Kennedy profile e.g. &lt;i&gt;Royal Babylon&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/books/97/11/30/reviews/971130.30powerst.html&quot;&gt;Hersh&#39;s book&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;The Dark Side of Camelot&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In going here, I find much that&#39;s fascinating yet think there&#39;s a danger in over-personalizing what were clearly crazy times.&amp;nbsp; The Oval Office, in its shape, is clearly a metaphor for the skull.&amp;nbsp; Craziness in the Oval Office just means in &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/qcpqHSAzDtU?t=356&quot;&gt;the Executive Branch&lt;/a&gt;, West Wing included.&amp;nbsp; So we&#39;ve come full circle, wherein craziness fights craziness (so who wins? -- it&#39;s the dialectic that matters, so who cares?).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Prohibition (still lingering) had turned the majority of Americans into criminals (aka &quot;sinners&quot;) by that time so I&#39;m never impressed by &quot;organized crime&quot; as anything worse than &quot;organized religion&quot; -- both have done their dirty business.&amp;nbsp; To Douglass, I maybe sound like &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/05/mad-max-fury-road-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Quaker Mafia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Goodies and Baddies&quot; are so much less nuanced than &quot;Cowboys and Indians&quot; (a clash of ethnicities) -- unless you&#39;ve learned to like villains.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A lot of people felt excluded and shoved aside by that Imperial Presidency.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We have a lot more hindsight today, regarding what the Kennedy brothers were up to.&amp;nbsp; At the time, they were likewise considered inconvenient extremists by many factions, as Douglass well documents.&amp;nbsp; Participation in the cover-up was widespread, including by people with no clue about the truth -- they just saw it as &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/01/conspiracy-dynamics.html&quot;&gt;their duty&lt;/a&gt; to support the official line, for &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/02/running-from-crazy-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;sanity&#39;s sake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rBu39kVNG3s?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;420&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: another puzzle piece, take it or leave it :: &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7842661237663253305'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7842661237663253305'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/out-of-mind-sight.html' title='Out of Mind / Sight'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/rBu39kVNG3s/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6273481904911839690</id><published>2015-07-04T01:46:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2015-07-14T10:55:55.849-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Spy (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
My angle into this movie was from too serious a springboard.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve been reading the &quot;new&quot; JFK book (2008), &lt;a href=&quot;http://911blogger.com/news/2013-03-08/vancouver-bound-author-james-douglass-jfk-and-unspeakable-adrian-mack-mar-7-2013&quot;&gt;by Douglass&lt;/a&gt;, who talks about Thomas Merton -- whom I also read as a younger man some, though had no idea about those Cold War letters.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was in second grade or so, when the Cuban Missile Crisis happened.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That new JFK book, recommended to me by Friends, refers to so many other such readings and plunges me back into &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/08/blaming-castro.html&quot;&gt;that whole morass&lt;/a&gt;, wherein the CIA swirls in a more down-the-toilet sense.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve actually not finished reading it yet.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Those were not happy times, and they stayed unhappy.&amp;nbsp; I can relate to &quot;long strange trip&quot; ala the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/10/remembering-dead.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Grateful Dead&lt;/i&gt; reunification&lt;/a&gt; (upcoming in Chicago).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d say the gear shift to this comedy CIA, one &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0082450/&quot;&gt;the movie&#39;s writer-director&lt;/a&gt; unabashedly embraces for a ready meme set of spoof-able cliches, built up by Hollywood, in complicity with the CIA&#39;s own storytellers, over the decades, was somewhat jarring.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At first people seemed to be having some fun here, but no, it was still horrific, and still quite crazy, with rats and bats and stuff in the basement.&amp;nbsp; In making the control room batty, and outfitting it with a Brit, we bridge to British humor, maybe?&amp;nbsp; Did this movie play well in the UK?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I of course appreciate the retro references (e.g. the credits), the semi-knowing satire.&amp;nbsp; But I noticed the audience around me was laughing and I was more just sinking down in my chair, worried I wasn&#39;t getting it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Accents certainly played a role.&amp;nbsp; Spy World has always been about i18n.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s this sense of ordinary people bashing through that wall of illusion (movie screen) behind which the phony world of 007 (one of the previews was for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2379713/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Spectre&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), its Never Land, does not exist.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Said &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/11/good-shepherd.html&quot;&gt;faux world&lt;/a&gt; is here reconstructed as &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/spook-who-sat-by-door-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;more female-friendly&lt;/a&gt; in some way (think &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carmen_Sandiego_%28game_series%29&quot;&gt;Carmen Sandiego&lt;/a&gt;), and a source of edginess and getting lost in fashion.&amp;nbsp; Vanity and jealousy are heavy duty in this space, so what else is new?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Never Land keeps a toe hold in reality e.g. appears to have money, a real building &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/08/drinking-liberally.html&quot;&gt;in Langley&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Buying into horror as part of the genre and making that an object of spoof just reminds me that Spy World is &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/out-of-mind-sight.html&quot;&gt;also Gothic&lt;/a&gt; in the Lovecraftian sense.&amp;nbsp; I keep forgetting that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Kafkaesque too.&amp;nbsp; Lets not forget Byzantine...&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So yeah, maybe not quite in the mood.&amp;nbsp; Why blame others?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So then I ambled down to the Blues Festival, in progress.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I found a patch of grass in the semi-dark and started reading &lt;i&gt;Madness and Civilization&lt;/i&gt; by Michael Foucault.&amp;nbsp; A lot of people have read that already, the Powell&#39;s paperbacks had been around the block a few times.&amp;nbsp; Maybe I&#39;d browsed it before?&amp;nbsp; It seemed fresh to me anyway.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I wanted a copy for Kindle so I could read it on my devices while listening to blues in Portland.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One thing I&#39;ve learned from the new JFK book (also on devices) is how directly the Kennedy brothers took on some of the special interests, steel in particular.&amp;nbsp; Steel speaks up in &lt;i&gt;Grunch of Giants&lt;/i&gt; too.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I like the idea of a president as &quot;one who presides&quot;, which is a long way from what the executive branch had become.&amp;nbsp; But then a lot of people want to participate in government.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As all presidents know, everyone, OK at least a few, want to be, or think they&#39;re a president too.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6273481904911839690'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6273481904911839690'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/spy-movie-review.html' title='Spy (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3797777149141306894</id><published>2015-06-29T16:43:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-06-30T23:04:02.711-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Car Stories</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; msallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; oallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19289731091/in/dateposted-public/player/&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
A well-known plus to renting a car now and then is one gets in a time machine and travels to the far future, the present, 2015 (as of this writing, duh).&amp;nbsp; Normally I drive a 1997 &lt;i&gt;Nissan&lt;/i&gt;, a quality vehicle that I still appreciate.&amp;nbsp; But it needed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/v9k8t9&quot;&gt;new mass airflow sensor&lt;/a&gt; and so I called up &lt;i&gt;Enterprise&lt;/i&gt; and booked a car for a day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The rental was a 2015 bright red &lt;i&gt;Toyota Corolla&lt;/i&gt; with a lot of frills, including radio controls on the steering wheel, rear view camera, great mileage (to Salem and back on a quarter tank).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol and I both caught something probably contracted by Lindsey in her air capsule coming from China &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/06/at-pdx-again.html&quot;&gt;to Bay Area&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Or who knows anymore.&amp;nbsp; In addition, I&#39;m susceptible to seasonal allergies in these hot summer days in the 90s (F-scale) so I&#39;m likely to be a basket case anyway, given the right pollen mix.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I tried &lt;i&gt;Sudafed&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Claritin&lt;/i&gt; both, but stayed pretty miserable and tried not to get too close to people at the Salem Meetinghouse.&amp;nbsp; Carol was likewise in a state, and as a guest speaker, co-appearing with &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/09/wanderers-200892.html&quot;&gt;Dr. Linda Richards&lt;/a&gt;, she actually had a workout, whereas I was just an audience member.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;d started the day &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/06/quakers-2015628.html&quot;&gt;with Paul Barker&lt;/a&gt; at the Stark Street meetinghouse, so two meetinghouses in one day.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d call us dedicated circuit riders.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However mom and Linda were not on strictly Quaker business, more were representing Women&#39;s International League for Peace and Freedom (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2014/08/wilpf-congress-detroit.html&quot;&gt;WILPF&lt;/a&gt;) to Followship for Reconciliation (FOR).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol&#39;s specialty is demilitarization whereas Linda teaches history of science.&amp;nbsp; Both have given excellent Wanderers presentations at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/sets/72157600254540815&quot;&gt;the Linus Pauling House&lt;/a&gt; in Portland (connected with ISEPP).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; msallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; oallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/2865019081/in/album-72157600254540815/player/&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3797777149141306894'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3797777149141306894'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/06/car-stories.html' title='Car Stories'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6497961184668196792</id><published>2015-06-24T11:53:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2017-04-01T10:39:22.491-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Math Avoidance?</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
The accusation of &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=9803473&quot;&gt;math avoidance&lt;/a&gt;&quot; comes from those claiming our K-12 maths curriculum (using the UK plural) is too watered down, too diluted with geegaws and gizmos.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s just &quot;toy math&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Whereas I&#39;m sympathetic to the accusation, I do need to ask if it&#39;s &quot;math avoidance&quot; to simply bury all the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/04/trite-math.html&quot;&gt;late 20th Century innovations&lt;/a&gt; documented in architecture, regarding the relationship of geodesic spheres to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/synergetica/synergetica1.html&quot;&gt;the virus and buckyball both&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Is it wise to be so ignorant of this heritage?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/18934772150&quot; title=&quot;f8812 by Kirby Urner, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;f8812&quot; height=&quot;391&quot; src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/313/18934772150_5d420b3c7c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;432&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Fig. 988.12&lt;/b&gt; Icosahedron Inscribed Within Octahedron:
The four-frequency tetrahedron inscribes an
internal octahedron within which may be inscribed a
skew icosahedron. Of the icosahedron&#39;s 20
equiangular triangle faces, four are congruent with
the plane of the tetra&#39;s faces (and with four external
faces of the inscribed octahedron). Four of the icosahedron&#39;s
other faces are congruent with the
remaining four internal faces of the [ octahedron ]. Two-fifths
of the icosa faces are congruent with the octa
faces. It requires 24 S Quanta Modules to fill in the
void between the octa and the icosa.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Readers of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/synergetics/findex/fx0900.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; already know of the volume 20 VE, which contracts to a volume 18.51 Icosa &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/02/a-tale-of-two-logos.html&quot;&gt;by Jitterbugging&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s our s-Factor at work i.e. (Svol / Evol) to the -1 i.e. Evol / Svol.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
20 * (1&amp;nbsp; / sFactor) = 18.51...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As seen from the excerpt below, from a Python program, these two volumes come with &quot;S + s3&quot; and &quot;E + e3&quot; expressions for volumetric decompositions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In this case-sensitive notation, S:s3 == E:e3 == Phi ** 3 i.e. the linear dimensions of s3 are 1/phi those of the S-module, ditto e3 vis-a-vis the E-module.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The S-module has a tetra-volume of pow(phi, -5)/2.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;print(&quot;VE:         &quot;, 20,                 420 * Svol + 100 * s3)
print(&quot;Icosa:      &quot;, 20 * sFactor ** 1,  420 * Evol + 100 * e3)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
With output:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;VE:          20 19.99999999999996
Icosa:       18.5122958682192 18.512295868219162
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Another Icosa-to-Cubocta relationship involves not Jitterbugging, but keeping the faces flush, eight of them, though only partially overlapping, as shown in the figure below: &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; msallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; oallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19119569932/in/dateposted-public/player/&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;323&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Fig. 988.00&lt;/b&gt; Polyhedral Evolution: S Quanta Module:&lt;br /&gt;
Comparisons of skew polyhedra. 
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We could call this a &quot;skew&quot; relationship and applying 1/sFactor twice to the 18.51 icosahedron takes use to what Koski affectionately calls the &quot;Small Guy&quot; cubocta, of volume ~15.86065.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What is it&#39;s frequency, assuming Icosa edges = 2?  Recalled 20 * F**3 is our formula:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;print(&quot;Small Guy edge:&quot;, 2 * pow(sFactor ** -3, 1/3))
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Output:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Small Guy edge: 1.8512295868219202&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s interesting about that number, a linear dimension, is that it&#39;s 1/10th the volume of the jitterbugged icosahedron&#39;s.&amp;nbsp; The differences in the ending digits above have merely to do with floating point error margins.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So what is the volume of the Icosa within the volume 4 Octa of Figure 988.12?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Clearly it&#39;s 4 - 24 * Svol or 4 - 24 * (pow(phi, -5)/2) = ~2.917961.&lt;/div&gt;
In Python again, and using David&#39;s decomposition formula:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Svol = pow(phi, -5)/2
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; s3 = Svol * pow(phi, -3)
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 60 * Svol + 20 * s3  # S + s3 form
2.9179606750063085
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Applying the reciprocal of the sFactor twice more, to this tiny Octahedron-inscribed icosahedron, nets us the volume of its &quot;skew mate&quot;:  the volume 2.5 cuboctahedron, i.e. 1/8 the volume of the cuboctahedron of volume 20, faces flush with the same Octa of volume 4.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; baby
2.9179606750063085
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; baby * (1/sfactor) * (1/sfactor)
2.5000000000000107
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Wh4hf3dnIIk&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6497961184668196792'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6497961184668196792'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/06/math-avoidance.html' title='Math Avoidance?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/Wh4hf3dnIIk/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5130663217622255997</id><published>2015-06-22T20:45:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2015-06-23T09:15:01.991-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Inside Out (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-kArxASiw3Y?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Yes, I too admired this film for its cleverness and compassion.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As she gets older though, and even while young, I think those five archetypes don&#39;t quite cover it.&amp;nbsp; Maybe we would find some mutant sixth and seventh crew members in different people?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We take only a small sample, with N only &amp;gt; 10 towards the end, if it ever gets that high (cross species, nice touch).&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m talking about how we look in on different control rooms.&amp;nbsp; Always the same five?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This Disney / Pixar movie is the paradigm &quot;control room&quot; movie, taking the meme right to its psychological roots, as a source of core memories feeding complexes (&quot;military industrial&quot; or whatever). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Shades of Woody Allen right?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Long term memories get visited later, by an estranged headquarters pair, seeking to get back to the helm.&amp;nbsp; Not giving too much away.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
She&#39;s a ship in choppy waters, our girl, and through an extended and elaborate set of interlocking metaphors, we get an excursion through a detailed mind map.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Either that (more crew) or each of these five might need to stretch a bit more, to take in new territory?&amp;nbsp; The subconscious covers a lot of ground... I&#39;m maybe just unclear about the plumbing.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I admit the prospect of a sequel somewhat scares me.&amp;nbsp; What if the series catches up and passes me?&amp;nbsp; It gets scarier doesn&#39;t it?&amp;nbsp; San Francisco is just the beginning.&amp;nbsp; Maybe &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2014/10/the-zero-theorem-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Zero Theorem&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; fits here?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
OK, I&#39;m angsting a bit, have some concerns of my own.&amp;nbsp; Maybe I&#39;m a tad envious of little girls and the problems they get to have?&amp;nbsp; Sniff.&amp;nbsp; You&#39;ve gotta admit she has it pretty good, just having so much joy for starters.&amp;nbsp; Her parents have benefited, a stress point right there.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Hey, I&#39;m looking forward to &lt;i&gt;Minions&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Twas fun to see this on a big screen with a friend in an audience.&amp;nbsp; I had my book on &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/06/recent-news-and-readings.html&quot;&gt;cryptography and Poe&lt;/a&gt; along, taking the bus, got a ride back in a new Mercedes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We get more from a spontaneously shared event in a dark movie hall, than watching on a flat screen home alone.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not that I don&#39;t welcome the more kicked-back option; I do that too.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m glad I have the option to choose.&amp;nbsp; Did I mention seeing &lt;i&gt;Jurassic World&lt;/i&gt; with Alexia?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This is one I&#39;d gladly add to my collection. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5130663217622255997'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5130663217622255997'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/06/inside-out-movie-review.html' title='Inside Out (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/-kArxASiw3Y/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2361252858309215432</id><published>2015-06-16T10:50:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-06-16T11:30:30.972-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Villa Touma (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Thanks to a heads up from Dr. Tag, I was able to bus over to 16th &amp;amp; NW Glisan to McMenamins &lt;i&gt;Mission Street Theater &amp;amp; Pub&lt;/i&gt; just in time for this fundraiser for Palestinian Childrens Relief Fund (PCRF).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This showing of &lt;i&gt;Villa Touma&lt;/i&gt;, a film by and about Palestinians, was an event designed to launch a&amp;nbsp; new PCRF local chapter.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
An orphan girl, of an eligible age (almost 19) is taken in by her aunts, who live in the past and want to marry her off to someone judged to be of high social class.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Palestinians I was watching this with found lots to laugh about, but questioned the realism of the premise.&amp;nbsp; &quot;No one is really like that, it&#39;s not true&quot; one of the audience members commented.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But then the film is a spoof, gently mocking those who try to live in the past.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That these sisters take themselves so seriously only adds to the comic element.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We get a window into a dollhouse inhabited by these sad clown ladies, a dog, and a caretaker.&amp;nbsp; The atmosphere is purposely claustrophobic, redolent of the dead ends these lives have become.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Badia does bring some light and joy into this household, slowly lifting spirits, but her oppression is severe and she fails to meet the unrealistic expectations of her silly aunts.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
From my angle, the film was a lot better than the nasty and &lt;a href=&quot;http://variety.com/2014/film/festivals/venice-film-review-villa-touma-1201295632/&quot;&gt;shallow review&lt;/a&gt; by Jay Weissberg in &lt;i&gt;Variety&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As a movie reviewer, Jay has perhaps proved his talent elsewhere, but his panning of this film is flat and unmodulated, deriving from a failure to recognize that he&#39;s dealing with a comedy of manners, not a compelling political analysis of anything.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Faulting a film because one guessed wrong about the genre is more a reflection of viewer immaturity than anything to do with the film itself.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2361252858309215432'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2361252858309215432'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/06/villa-touma-movie-review.html' title='Villa Touma (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4223843641994961136</id><published>2015-06-14T12:45:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2015-06-15T07:43:43.073-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Gender Pride Day</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;375&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;flashvars&quot; value=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157644794825650%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157644794825650%2F&amp;set_id=72157644794825650&amp;jump_to=&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;embed type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; src=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554&quot; allowFullScreen=&quot;true&quot; flashvars=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157644794825650%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157644794825650%2F&amp;set_id=72157644794825650&amp;jump_to=&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: gay pride 2014 (rerun) ::
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I&#39;ll call it that, given today is Gay Pride Parade in Portland, and &lt;i&gt;Prairie Home Companion&lt;/i&gt;, on the radio now, has been appropriately Seattle / Northwest based.&amp;nbsp; Is this a rerun then? &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://prairiehome.org/shows/june-13-2015/&quot;&gt;As of yesterday, sure&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Dang but Garrison is good.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He just advised a guy to go for same-sex marriage next time, funny marriage counselor skit.&amp;nbsp; All morning were poignant &quot;dad&quot; stories on NPR, well made.&amp;nbsp; I found myself admiring radio as a medium again.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s right, unlike last year when I photographed Gay Pride on a somewhat rainy day, capturing Congressman Blumenauer and some others, this year I&#39;m kicked back in an easy chair (&quot;... of computer science&quot;) with my dog and the radio.&amp;nbsp; Having a case of Achilles tendinitis (self diagnosed) is a contributing factor to my relative inactivity. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol wanted to walk home from Stark Street Quakers (SSQs).&amp;nbsp; I drove her there at 9:40, bright sunny day, great for a parade.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Gay&quot; does not even begin to cover the full pantheon of &quot;Queer&quot; or as some say &quot;Pan&quot;, the parent class, most inclusive, from which the subtypes derive.&amp;nbsp; Remember that genders turn off and on and that the asexual dimensions are often the most textured and nuanced.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Turned on&quot; states, even friendly-flirtatious, often feed the exaggerated caricatures more easily, so those working against stereotypes will often do so in a more business class persona, at least around Portland, which has an eclectic Central Business District (CBD) and everything.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Bend gender at work, where it matters, not at the bar, where no one cares (in a liberal town like Portland, it takes a lot more work to get stares, so your mileage may vary).&amp;nbsp; That would be my advice to gender activists.&amp;nbsp; However, work includes business lunches and being out in public, so I&#39;m not drawing a hard line.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
While kicked back, I&#39;m conversing with other math-teachers, or debating in some cases, on &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=9796749&quot;&gt;the issue of multiculturalism&lt;/a&gt; (is that an issue?) and &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=9796748&quot;&gt;technology in the classroom&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, both perennial themes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Last night I was catching up on work-related studies around Cython, the basis of Sage, and I-Python Notebook in synergy therewith.&amp;nbsp; Cython is a hybrid Python + C that &quot;compiles&quot; to C code that in turn compiles using a C compiler.&amp;nbsp; Sage is developed in this language.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In this mode of work-study, I have Safari open on the Samsung tablet (Galaxy 3) and an I-Python Notebook on the laptop.&amp;nbsp; Same chair (&quot;... of computer science&quot;).&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll read for awhile, then tap tap on the computer, read some more and like that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Nor do I have a working camera this year, as of yesterday.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Fujifilm XQ-1, black, which I adore, suddenly no longer powered on, after a bright morning of fun shooting.&amp;nbsp; Taking pictures is such a big habit of mine that I was almost right away on the phone to Camera World, where I bought it under a year ago.&amp;nbsp; An hour later, I was downtown at the store, having it shipped for repairs under warranty.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Good timing for &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/06/ex-machina-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;seeing &lt;i&gt;Ex Machina&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, before driving home.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4223843641994961136'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4223843641994961136'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/06/gender-pride-day.html' title='Gender Pride Day'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6385377063552904838</id><published>2015-06-11T10:56:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-06-11T10:56:24.308-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Opt Out App</title><content type='html'>Patrick is excited to have access to some real electrical meter data from actual households, broken down by appliance (e.g. wine cooler) a level of detail he doesn&#39;t currently need.&amp;nbsp; His goal is to harness input patterns and feed them to a Numenta bot that may prove capable of anticipating what&#39;s next to some degree, better then current technology can.&amp;nbsp; Crystal balls are always in vogue, even if they see ahead only one or two minutes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I just registered for OSCON again, so am looking forward to Patrick&#39;s talk.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of parents with families, an Opt Out app is about opting out of specific kinds of recruiting the Constitution doesn&#39;t say you need to accept.&amp;nbsp; Once opted out, you may also choose to report violations.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve brought this app to the attention of the Portland Peace Program.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Civilian services, such as scouting in its various forms, which involves instruction, investing in infrastructure, winning merit badges, is likewise in need of more people willing to Opt In.&amp;nbsp; Scouting and coding have merged on many levels, as mathematics becomes more of an outdoor sport, thanks to geocaching etc.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6385377063552904838'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6385377063552904838'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/06/opt-out-app.html' title='Opt Out App'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6228230041389183989</id><published>2015-06-06T12:22:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-06-11T11:19:50.074-07:00</updated><title type='text'>High School 2.1</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BbpcfZoQBpY?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I don&#39;t know how directly Nexus architects were influenced by Scott Gray, maybe not at all, directly, however the similarities are striking, between the Nexus and &quot;user active&quot; philosophies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A percentage of the instruction these students receive could be from mentors such as myself, propagating Python skills over the wire, responding individually to students within my caseload.&amp;nbsp; Every mentor, from senior to rookie, is working a beat, which will be defined by track and language of instruction (English or...?).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If students need to take supervised tests i.e. we need to seriously authenticate they&#39;re who the say they are etc., the Node (say a Nexus) provides the venue.&amp;nbsp; If they&#39;re inspired and want to pursue their learning off site, e.g. from home, the same distance learning portals are there.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m upbeat about this new model for high schools and encourage more states besides Michigan to show off their imaginative next versions. </content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6228230041389183989'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6228230041389183989'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/06/high-school-21.html' title='High School 2.1'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/BbpcfZoQBpY/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8428518667284904322</id><published>2015-05-31T13:07:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-05-31T13:10:33.553-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Tomorrowland (movie review)</title><content type='html'>There&#39;s precedent in these blogs for me breaking a review into two or having another review come to me later, more analysis or whatever, and that&#39;s the approach I wanna take here.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Willamette Week, a witty paper, had me all prepared to not like this, for the right reasons, but I ended up admiring it a lot, for all the archetypes and love knots it takes on.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Remember I go by Chief Marketing Officer for some Coffee Shops Network that has Athena very much in its heraldry, and this film has an Athena.&amp;nbsp; The dad-daughter relationship there is encoded in Greek mythology as well:&amp;nbsp; she sprang from his head directly.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s some Gnostic potential there.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So yeah, lots to think about and really well made.&amp;nbsp; Good work.&amp;nbsp; I will follow up at a later date with more thoughts.&amp;nbsp; Hey, I&#39;m still thinking about &lt;i&gt;Mad Max&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; These movies are like time release pills.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re not over when they&#39;re over, if you&#39;re like me.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Alexia, sorry if we&#39;d planned to see this together, I was just pretty sure it was a dud going in and my evening was geared to &lt;i&gt;Starlight Parade&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; You and I would have others to choose from.&amp;nbsp; As it happens, not a dud in my case, and I missed the parade this year, hope to catch it next time. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8428518667284904322'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8428518667284904322'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/05/tomorrowland-movie-review.html' title='Tomorrowland (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-346007696536111387</id><published>2015-05-28T22:11:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2015-05-29T08:19:12.016-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Body Art</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://uabglobal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/pc_50th_lap_brand_sm.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://uabglobal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/pc_50th_lap_brand_sm.jpg&quot; width=&quot;276&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;I have a lot on my plate to write about, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/05/engineering-as-moral-enterprise.html&quot;&gt;the closing ISEPP lecture&lt;/a&gt; for this season, Terry summing up engineering as a moral enterprise (up to some good, one always hopes).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Let me mention the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/05/conference-call.html&quot;&gt;Gift Shop idea&lt;/a&gt; and where that went:&amp;nbsp; Body Art.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;d be quite consistent with &lt;i&gt;Third Eye&lt;/i&gt; across the street and is completely compatible with the decal-based art already in the mix.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So that&#39;s a win.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, I&#39;m talking about Peace Sign (or even Peace Corps sign) tattoos, for many significant, including among the &lt;i&gt;Laughing Horse&lt;/i&gt; reading and viewing circles. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
With most taboos removed and stereotypes crumbling, there&#39;s a niche somewhere on Hawthorne no doubt.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Glenn is repainting.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s-media-cache-ak0.pinimg.com/236x/d0/71/0b/d0710b44b194e6f7514c0438f3570907.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://s-media-cache-ak0.pinimg.com/236x/d0/71/0b/d0710b44b194e6f7514c0438f3570907.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/346007696536111387'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/346007696536111387'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/05/body-art.html' title='Body Art'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4321785990807830336</id><published>2015-05-28T00:02:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-05-28T00:02:28.933-07:00</updated><title type='text'>More NPYM IT</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/17916407158&quot; title=&quot;WQM Mens Group:  Group Settings by Kirby Urner, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;WQM Mens Group:  Group Settings&quot; height=&quot;328&quot; src=&quot;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7728/17916407158_a7cde4fe85.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: working with WQM Men&#39;s Group ::
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4321785990807830336'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4321785990807830336'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/05/more-npym-it.html' title='More NPYM IT'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3873037391189351891</id><published>2015-05-26T19:52:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-05-27T23:34:45.682-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Memorial Day</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/17913211868&quot; title=&quot;DSCF8754 by Kirby Urner, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF8754&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8766/17913211868_56462fc934.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People were out in droves in my neighborhood, enjoying those establishments choosing not to close for the holiday, but stay open.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m reminded of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/04/london-knowledge-lab.html&quot;&gt;my quick visit&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;i&gt;London Knowledge Lab&lt;/i&gt; on a bank holiday when no one sane would be at work. &amp;nbsp;But a kind Lab guy, knowing my itinerary (guest of Shuttleworth Foundation, hot off a jet from Pacific Northwest), realized it was now or never. &amp;nbsp;I gave a presentation. &amp;nbsp;The gig was recorded and for many years made the rounds, plus I got to brag to the Foundation folk I&#39;d already briefed LKL, sounded important.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This year, 2015, I drove Deke, a fine fellow, on an errand to Dr. Bolton&#39;s hood, out Tryon way. &amp;nbsp;We stopped in to visit with Sir Charles, an emeritus sociology department chairman and contemporary of my dad&#39;s. &amp;nbsp;The Boltons started to tune in Urners at University of Chicago, but then went their separate ways. &amp;nbsp;Not until they got together again in Portland did the conviviality really develop, such that when we moved to Rome, we made the trip to Positano, to hang with the Boltons, on sabbatical.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The intersection top of Boones Ferry, where Stephenson T&#39;s in: &amp;nbsp;that&#39;s been a rough corner and a lot of redesign has gone into it recently, I think for the better. &amp;nbsp;This was my landing quad i.e. my starting sector in the World Game of Portland I started playing, off the plane from Bangladesh. &amp;nbsp;Mom &amp;amp; Dad were pulling up stakes there, I&#39;d gone to help them pack up, take another look around Dhaka, and then I stayed with the Boltons rather than resume an East Coast existence. &amp;nbsp;Time to get back to my Portland roots.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2014/08/comic-material.html&quot;&gt;The Nissan&lt;/a&gt; has a fuel system issue that I&#39;ll trace to poor maintenance on my part, casting no aspersions on Nissan for this one. &amp;nbsp;The &lt;i&gt;Altima&lt;/i&gt; I drove to and from, on my recent mid-west tour (St. Louis MO etc.), was a world class motor vehicle. &amp;nbsp;I like how rental car scenarios let us try before we buy, or rent again, or whatever. &amp;nbsp; Anyway, the Maxima bucks like a bronco sometimes, even shutting off. &amp;nbsp;Good thing it&#39;s OK to restart in neutral. &amp;nbsp;But hey, Deke and I both remarked how overall smooth the whole trip was.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Funny part: &amp;nbsp;Charles was just showing us a postcard from Maureen, &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/tiACA9&quot;&gt;in dense handwriting&lt;/a&gt;, and saying he thought she might still be in Europe when, knock knock, there she was at the door, pretty funny. &amp;nbsp;I alerted them to Carol&#39;s immanent arrival and suggested we all get together again soon, Deke included (he liked our energy, think he might join). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Maureen was at the WILPF Centennial like mom was, with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/05/philosophy-talk.html&quot;&gt;her son Erin&lt;/a&gt; in a supportive role. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mom did a lot of her five weeks solo, also tackling NYC YMCA on her own (for visits with UN people) and DC. &amp;nbsp;She routed herself back to LAX via JFK and fortunately made standby on JetBlue, shortening her stay in JFK by a good six hours, way to go Carol! &amp;nbsp;She said she&#39;d gladly take &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/07/jetblues-bizmo.html&quot;&gt;JetBlue again&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The day before, I got together with my friends the Gunnells, new in Portland. &amp;nbsp;I took pictures at the wedding, my former co-worker Eddy&#39;s daughter the bride. &amp;nbsp;Eddy and I were high school teachers at St. Dominic Academy, for girls (young women) in Jersey City, New Jersey. &amp;nbsp;That was back in the 1980s, great gig!</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3873037391189351891'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3873037391189351891'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/05/memorial-day.html' title='Memorial Day'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2693232933942782005</id><published>2015-05-22T17:29:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2015-05-22T17:56:26.439-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Bravo Michigan on Bold Experiments</title><content type='html'>I may have gotten the story a little wrong and will apply corrections in future blog posts, allowing misapprehensions to continue registering here, but my current understanding being that high schoolers in Michigan are guaranteed by law at least one distance education class as a part of their public schooling experience. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #004361; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22.3999996185303px;&quot;&gt;Public Act 205,&amp;nbsp;passed in 2009, allowed the formation of full-time online schools for the first time in fall 2010.&amp;nbsp;In 2006, the Michigan Legislature was the first in the nation to pass a requirement that students have an online learning experience before graduating. [ &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kpk12.com/states/michigan/&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt; ]&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Is that opt in or opt out and what if one wishes more than one?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In any case, the Nexus Academy solution looks promising in that it solves the need to authenticate identity. &amp;nbsp;Those of us in distance learning know a weak spot is what if the student lets her dog do the homework instead. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Most realize they cannot fake it for long on the job, so why fake it now, but adults are more likely to realize this than children maybe? &amp;nbsp;Not that teenagers are children exactly.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In any case, certified testing centers are a need at all levels for all ages. &amp;nbsp;The science wants control and supervision, not some going overboard on some &quot;honor system&quot;. &amp;nbsp;Authentication is required, perhaps with biometrics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One might imagine a combination of experiences, inside one of these centers for some activities, outside for others. &amp;nbsp;You need not imagine yourself cooped up for days on end, as for academic credit you&#39;re required all over the map. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What is distance learning anyway? &amp;nbsp;Thirty feet away can be pretty far, in human terms, in a room of five hundred. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A lecture hall is distance learning? &amp;nbsp;Might as well be.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Actually no, there&#39;s an audience / speaker rapport that makes live talks a bonus, same with music.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, it would be up to Michigan whether an obstacle course in cyber-space such as mine, or some other DL activity, would count for credit per the State of Michigan. &amp;nbsp;That&#39;s not my decision, as an online teacher, and besides who want&#39;s to learn lambda calculus anyway?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But the very idea of a Nexus Academy wherein I might have students, even if I&#39;m in faraway Oregon or St. Louis, does inspire me, whether it&#39;s really practical in the short haul or not. &amp;nbsp;Thank you USDLA for opening my eyes to the possibilities (that&#39;s a conference my school sent me to, and a membership organization).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Raining in Portland, did yard work today.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Decision-making is by many methods, and who has access to all that many boardrooms? &amp;nbsp;We have our finite experiences. &amp;nbsp;Democracy does not just mean once a year elections, or once every three or four. &amp;nbsp;People learn to vote when going out on a group date and picking a restaurant. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But then if you&#39;re Quaker and use consensus, maybe you never choose? &amp;nbsp;&quot;Let someone else program it&quot; might be how the unprogrammed would do it, but presumably &quot;expectant waiting&quot; is more intelligent than that.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2693232933942782005'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2693232933942782005'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/05/bravo-michigan-on-bold-experiments.html' title='Bravo Michigan on Bold Experiments'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1530173925740159324</id><published>2015-05-19T23:18:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-05-20T15:35:50.611-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2015.5.19</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/17882353512&quot; title=&quot;DSCF8673 by Kirby Urner, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF8673&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5331/17882353512_6a187904cc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tonight was my turn to give a Wanderers presentation.&amp;nbsp; I decided to spice it up by saying I was acting a part, not really being my ordinary self.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I wore &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/04/back-at-work.html&quot;&gt;shiny shoes&lt;/a&gt; and my Quaker hat (a Stetson).&amp;nbsp; I was the &quot;Quaker futurist&quot;, like a gig, or act.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Trevor (depicted below), being the Egoist presenter recently, was an inspiration.&amp;nbsp; &quot;If someone says I&#39;m egotistical, I correct them, saying it&#39;s really &lt;i&gt;egoistical&lt;/i&gt; that I&#39;m being&quot; (&lt;i&gt;bada boom&lt;/i&gt; -- one of my jokes).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/11/ieee-presentation.html&quot;&gt;Shades of Portland Center Stage&lt;/a&gt;... &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, I was a bit gruff and abrupt, and people warmed to that as I&#39;d warned &#39;em.&amp;nbsp; I practiced by telling Don to &quot;shut up&quot; a couple times, like I thought I was &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/9J2Ds6zjKtM&quot;&gt;Bill O&#39;Reilly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The idea was my Martian-tinged cult had some future in the pipeline and here was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/satacad/martianmath/toc.html&quot;&gt;a &lt;i&gt;Saturday Academy&lt;/i&gt; class&lt;/a&gt;, already delivered, that had already passed the torch.&amp;nbsp; The future just passed you by, did you even notice?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
1, 12, 42, 92... I kept harping on that, like a mantra.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was touting the standard &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/04/garden-of-eden.html&quot;&gt;Garden of Eden in a Climatron&lt;/a&gt; stuff, a kind of utopianism associated with Whole Earth Catalog if anyone remembers those.&amp;nbsp; The Bucky stuff, I call it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Stewart Brand had a hand in this stuff, and so did J. Baldwin.&amp;nbsp; Stewart pushed to get pictures of the whole Earth, as in &quot;from-space photography&quot; into the public domain.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Shots from space (ET PoVs) were entirely new in those early days of the first orbiting satellites, ala Sputnik et al.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I started my hour-long presentation with two misanthropic cartoons, pulled from my Facebook profile, then flipped through slides from the Martian Math class.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Martian Math stuff was portrayed as 10-20 years ahead of the pack.&amp;nbsp; I was purposely somewhat Cabalistic or cliquish one might say, in implying Silicon Forest was moving ZomeTool, as implied by a picture from our &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/11/onami-tour.html&quot;&gt;field trip to ONAMI&lt;/a&gt;, as a part of some cultic process.&amp;nbsp; We talked about Grunch a lot (Fuller&#39;s coin), and &lt;a href=&quot;http://grunch.net/archives/171&quot;&gt;Ed Applewhite&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cosmic Fishing&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But I digress.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People were quite engaged and full of insights and questions, as I&#39;d hoped.&amp;nbsp; We talked about dedicated freeways with self-driving trucks -- but don&#39;t we have those already?&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re called trains and only one of the cars, called the engine, needs to drive (the trucks would need some kind of supervision too).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Although I was walking them through some slides, the idea was to inspire conversation.&amp;nbsp; We were there to think about Futurism as a discipline, and about how Science Fiction works, as &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/07/interest-group.html&quot;&gt;distopian-to-utopian&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; I mentioned the Paul Allen museum on the subject, in nearby Seattle.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The ratio of science to fiction matters.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s on one of the slides.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
And also:&amp;nbsp; is it about humans expanding elsewhere, or being expanded upon, as in invaded?&amp;nbsp; A little of both maybe?&amp;nbsp; I talked about &quot;angels and devils&quot; as the old days ETs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Regrets poured in from some of the people Don had invited (that&#39;s his role) but who couldn&#39;t make it and maybe wanted to be polite and all, but as you can see from the picture (above), it&#39;s a small room.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks for thinking of me, and lets get together soon!&amp;nbsp; Life is short.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/17160510029&quot; title=&quot;DSCF8333 by Kirby Urner, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF8333&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7760/17160510029_9c2864d793.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Trevor in character at Mother Foucault&#39;s&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1530173925740159324'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1530173925740159324'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/05/wanderers-2015519.html' title='Wanderers 2015.5.19'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7881506565939880484</id><published>2015-05-13T23:22:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-05-17T08:29:02.752-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Voting Machines</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/17005468294&quot; title=&quot;Project Vote by Kirby Urner, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Project Vote&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; src=&quot;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7692/17005468294_0c6ea5d12f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Those of you US people without amnesia (Gore Vidal said this was the United States of Amnesia we live in, if you&#39;ll recall), may remember the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electronic_voting&quot;&gt;voting machine fiasco&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We all lost confidence in the machines because they would not share the algorithms or submit to auditing by students of computer science, who might be high school aged.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One of the nonprofits I work with is &lt;a href=&quot;https://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/elections-wg&quot;&gt;experimenting with state of the art e-voting software&lt;/a&gt; that not even an election administrator can rig.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s a vote-by-email type of system, with one ballot going out to each eligible person.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not saying it&#39;s either fool proof or applicable in its present form to just any election for whatever office.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/06/democraylab.html&quot;&gt;DemocrayLab&lt;/a&gt; is the NGO I&#39;ve written about most in connection with providing &quot;democracy in a box&quot; ideas, i.e. turn-key software that&#39;s democracy-enabling.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However &lt;a href=&quot;https://vote.python.org/init/default/support&quot;&gt;eVote&lt;/a&gt; and Helios are already open source, not saying you need to bother Mark just because you&#39;re interested in either of these two packages.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Every high school needs voting machines as a part of its civics curriculum, with votes counted often, on myriad topics, experimenting with different modes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In some systems, even the voters are secret e.g. you don&#39;t know who in the audience is really &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2014/12/birdman-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;the critic&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/05/quakers-what-do-we-offer.html&quot;&gt;With Quakers&lt;/a&gt;, we tend to move by consensus but that only works in a non-trivial way when the players are communicative.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When people stay strangers, you lose a lot of the inertia that comes from shared access to organizational memes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s why companies do team building and such, even encounter groups in some walks of life, to break down the barriers to speedy / timely / efficient communications.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7881506565939880484'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7881506565939880484'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/05/voting-machines.html' title='Voting Machines'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7636886257847594272</id><published>2015-05-11T19:11:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2015-05-12T11:41:57.634-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Conference Call</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/17564580545&quot; title=&quot;Foreground:  Linus Pauling House by Kirby Urner, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Foreground:  Linus Pauling House&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7708/17564580545_0d6e695370.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In case my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.omsi.edu/science-store&quot;&gt;Gift Shop proposal&lt;/a&gt; flies, I&#39;ve talked to Glenn about a tour. &amp;nbsp;Area Program Committee is considering a proposal to fill in for the missing &lt;i&gt;Laughing Horse Book Store and Video Collective &lt;/i&gt;(&quot;nothing lasts forever but the earth and sky&quot; -- &lt;i&gt;Kansas&lt;/i&gt;). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/back-at-laughing-horse.html&quot;&gt;a hole in this town&lt;/a&gt; that Friends could help fill, both programmed and unprogrammed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
501(c)(3) nonprofit corporations are allowed to sell swag. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But this would be more than a swag shop. &amp;nbsp;We&#39;d have vintage Peace buttons, educational materials. Proceeds fund our non-profit programs. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We get around needing to provide ADA compliance to this rickety old building (the one we&#39;re touring) by having the organizing meetups elsewhere. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We can do sales outside on summer days, so if you&#39;re on crutches you&#39;ll still get access.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/05/axing-staff-in-west-region.html&quot;&gt;The competition&lt;/a&gt; wants a strictly back office low profile in a little trafficked part of town (comparatively). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Their building is for sale and unstable in that sense but the back office people don&#39;t seem to worry as they have few responsibilities and no programs. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our program people are in the field. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Why a small city like Portland should get Philadelphia-type jobs is a bit of a mystery. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Back office&quot; is what Friends Center is for, is what we thought, not West Region where we need to be &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/04/portland-afsc-support-committee.html&quot;&gt;public-facing and engaged&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/16941775754&quot; title=&quot;DSCF8471 by Kirby Urner, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF8471&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5441/16941775754_f49e336e9b_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7636886257847594272'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7636886257847594272'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/05/conference-call.html' title='Conference Call'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8468072302661784940</id><published>2015-05-09T06:54:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2015-05-10T13:25:33.148-07:00</updated><title type='text'>PR for Earlham College</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y2S6n_L-cVI?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: thanks! ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8468072302661784940'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8468072302661784940'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/05/pr-for-earlham-college.html' title='PR for Earlham College'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/Y2S6n_L-cVI/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry></feed>