<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1726'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1701&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1751&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1726</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113718002079380608</id><published>2006-01-13T10:40:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:12.009-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Shake Up</title><content type='html'>I&#39;m demoting KTU2 to &quot;problem child&quot; status.  She never fully recovered from &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Yeti Bubbles&lt;/span&gt; and I haven&#39;t the time to mess with her mind any more (before you human rights people get all bent out of shape:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/12/welcome-to-my-world.html&quot;&gt;she&#39;s a computer&lt;/a&gt;).  The more portable Toshiba here is now my &quot;main machine&quot; with KTU2 as irksome sibling (not really her fault I allowed &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/big-foot-strikes.html&quot;&gt;that troll&lt;/a&gt; to go on a RAMpage --  plus Windows was never that robust to begin with).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I never solved the firewire problem on the camcorder either.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/01/what-shall-i-do.html&quot;&gt;Art&lt;/a&gt; had some good advice about that: get an El Cheapo on eBay just to play the Hi-8s, and move &#39;em all to digital ASAP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also, we need to do something about the commercials. Tara and I were laughing at that stupid doc with med students re-enactment during the news last night, all these white coats mouthing off about side effects. And that other one: let&#39;s count the stethoscopes. Really, the medical profession is looking pretty tawdry these days, with nothing better to do than hawk pills on TV. There used to be some guidelines; deregulation means the freedom to act like jerks in so many cases.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/11/matrix.html&quot;&gt;B2B picture&lt;/a&gt; is likewise pretty dim. Where&#39;re all those high tech computer graphics that advertise some glimmer of awareness? I&#39;m not surprised Iran has lost faith in the west (or North Korea for that matter). I have too, on many fronts (lawyers too slow, get &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.answers.com/ensnarled&amp;r=67&quot;&gt;ensnarled&lt;/a&gt; in unnecessary processing at the drop of a hat) -- so we&#39;re moving some defenses to stronger &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.answers.com/bastion&amp;amp;r=67&quot;&gt;bastions&lt;/a&gt;. Doesn&#39;t PDX also have &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/01/front-page-news.html&quot;&gt;daily flights&lt;/a&gt; to Japan? &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Northwest_Airlines&quot;&gt;Northwest Orient&lt;/a&gt; right?  I&#39;m up for &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/12/sushi-for-xmas.html&quot;&gt;more sushi&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/02/adventures-in-radio-land-part-2.html&quot;&gt;we&lt;/a&gt; could meet downtown -- all you can eat).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Update&lt;/span&gt;:  according to &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Oregonian&lt;/span&gt; (Jan 12, pg. 1), Portland may be getting an optical fiber network soon (I thought we had one already). Nothing has shown up in Google News about Baghdad getting one. I don&#39;t think Portland should have one before Baghdad does, at least in the universities, nor &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; USA city really (although I&#39;m sure in reality many are already pigging out on all that extra bandwidth (&quot;all you can eat&quot; while others starve is the American Way right? (I know, I know, I&#39;m another one of those goddamn bleeding hearts))).  Whatever happened to &quot;you break it you buy it&quot;?  Or is your money not worth the paper it&#39;s printed on?</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113718002079380608'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113718002079380608'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/shake-up.html' title='Shake Up'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113708558640985655</id><published>2006-01-12T09:05:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-11-03T12:41:56.528-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Islamic Art</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/bluesforallah.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/bluesforallah.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;album cover, Blues for Allah&lt;br /&gt;Grateful Dead&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113708558640985655'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113708558640985655'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/islamic-art.html' title='Islamic Art'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113677448755144839</id><published>2006-01-08T19:16:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2024-09-26T11:23:51.958-07:00</updated><title type='text'>The Power of Nightmares (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/kZx1Ovj8tA0?si=Sw1jODS8sIuzEuaD&quot; style=&quot;background-image: url(https://i.ytimg.com/vi/kZx1Ovj8tA0/hqdefault.jpg);&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tagline: idealistic humans, ill-prepared for future shock, look for ideological solutions, but end up being tortured and/or committing atrocities instead.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The narrator&#39;s thesis is that politicians, finding their happy talk wouldn&#39;t fly, switched to scary talk to keep a grip. Their failing futurism was roughly Johnson Era liberalism and the War on Poverty. When that war seemed lost (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/08/visiting-downtown-detroit.html&quot;&gt;witness Detroit&lt;/a&gt;), and Vietnam proved a debacle, the Chicago-based neocons fanned out and dove deep, aiming to rebuild a storyline around battles America could actually &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;win&lt;/span&gt; for a change.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Getting the new script enacted would require educating the CIA about the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;real&lt;/span&gt; Russian mindset, an apparently hopeless task until Casey came along, a blessing in disguise. Plus they had to mobilize an army of traditionally apolitical church people by stoking their hatred of gays who pee on the crucifix (Pat Robertson&#39;s image).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These strategies eventually paid off, as the USSR eventually &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;did&lt;/span&gt; exit the world stage, taking its hated Berlin Wall along with it. Mission accomplished. Finishing off in Afghanistan and Iraq would make the world safe for democracy, once people like Clinton and Bush Sr. (future golf mates) could be shoved to the sidelines.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the meantime, Sayyid Qutb and his disciples, in reaction against this same vacuous liberalism (Jahiliyyah), inspired a long-running jihad, feeding the neocon dream of an evil worth lionizing, then killing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
And the battle continues to this day, with politicians grooving on all the raw fear they get to work with. The media likes it too (war sells). Everyone gets guns, kicks back and enjoys the ride -- except the bad guys and sore losers like Michael Moore.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The narrator, backed by an army of talking heads, counters that the USSR imploded for reasons unrelated to neocon heroism, and that a globally organized Al Qaeda is largely a media myth based on an earlier Mafia example (law enforcement needed a known quantity to go up against).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Soon, the narrator promises, the politicians will run out of gas. However, minus any new futurism to replace the failed one, one wonders if this is really cause for celebration. I guess we&#39;re back to vacuous liberalism again, and future shock part two (bird flu anyone?).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The editing was pretty slick, with lots of funny juxtapositions and embedded messages. Rumsfeld plays his usual &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2014/10/the-unknown-known-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Strangelovian self&lt;/a&gt;, showing us those vast Al Qaeda undergound apartments, computer equipped and well ventilated -- hysterical.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We liberals in the audience (upscale art museum venue, medium sized auditorium, fairly well packed) squirmed a bit at the suggestion Kissinger was really on the right track after all. Plus the CIA&#39;s talking heads (fun to see Bearden again) got to speak on the side of sanity and have the last word -- a curious role reversal since &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/02/neverland-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;those crazy 1960s&lt;/a&gt;. </content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113677448755144839'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113677448755144839'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/power-of-nightmares-movie-review.html' title='The Power of Nightmares (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/kZx1Ovj8tA0/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113648254667432950</id><published>2006-01-05T09:45:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-11-11T09:26:37.801-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Serving from Algebra City</title><content type='html'>Algebra City is of course a nickname for Baghdad.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.insideiraqthemovie.com/&quot;&gt;Mark Shiley&#39;s film&lt;/a&gt; has these poignant scenes of a computer class (both male and female students) trying to learn it all from chalkboards, given Earth, Inc. (stupid to the core) has deprived them of any real computers.  Our cradle of civilization without any decent IT -- it&#39;s just mind-boggling.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The way to counter-recruit against terrorism is through positive futurism.  Hamas shows two faces to the world, a brighter happy face (more like Wal*Mart&#39;s) and a dark ugly face (ski masks, AK-47s).  Al-Qaeda (&quot;the base&quot;) has the same dual nature:  as a comforter and a killer.  USAers sometimes pretend they&#39;re above sponsoring terror in such a two-faced guise, but of course &quot;whiteman&quot; is known the world over for his forked tongue happy talk (thanks to a lot of B-grade --  and a few &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0065988/&quot;&gt;A-grade&lt;/a&gt; -- Hollywood movies).  So yeah, it&#39;s a really familiar pattern:  olive branch or arrows, take your pick.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Baghdadees are crying out for more olive branch, having been shocked and awed way more than any population deserves.  Robust civilian infrastructure would serve the cause.  Even just an &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;announcement&lt;/span&gt; of plans to run more optical fiber (like in Korea) would be helpful.  Why not give key religious leaders an early &lt;a href=&quot;http://viiv.intel.com/eng/&quot;&gt;preview of Viiv&lt;/a&gt;? This is affordable high tech they might use to leap ahead of the competition, by advertising the true merits of Islam, a religion sorely in need of true warrior-protectors these days (and better PR).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bona fide Islam should &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; be confused with these low budget crackpot snuff movies the CIA puts out as misinformation.  Islam should fight back against such terrorist porn, another propaganda tool used by inimical divide-and-conquer strategists (the same ones fomenting so much Sunni-Shiite sectarian violence).  But how is Algebra City to fight back with both hands tied behind its back?  This isn&#39;t a fair fight.  Every time Iraqis get some decent media, the Coalition shuts it down, or the Pentagon throws another bomb.  I dunno about you, but I call that &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/10/commenting-on-news.html&quot;&gt;cowardly&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113648254667432950'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113648254667432950'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/serving-from-algebra-city.html' title='Serving from Algebra City'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113639528349299057</id><published>2006-01-04T09:02:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-06-13T13:05:19.730-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Tragedy in West Virginia</title><content type='html'>According to current versions of events, command center communications were intercepted and misinterpreted, leading families to believe their loved ones were still alive after all these hours in the mine -- only one was.  Friends and families were put on a terrible rollercoaster, going from cautious hope, to elation, to devastation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In retrospect, I see more encryption should have been used, to insulate people from the raw intelligence.  You need a layer of interpretation and analysis in between.  The doctor comes out and explains the situation.  More details will be available later, to the most curious with a need to know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Update:&lt;/span&gt; according to the CBS Evening News tonight, the rescue team did use code.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113639528349299057'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113639528349299057'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/tragedy-in-west-virginia.html' title='Tragedy in West Virginia'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113617853998627595</id><published>2006-01-01T22:01:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:11.618-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Middle School Geography</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/pdxsewer.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/pdxsewer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;browsing Portland&#39;s sewer system&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/winterhaven/&quot;&gt;The web site I&#39;ve been working on&lt;/a&gt; these last couple of days is more for a computer class than a geography class, but computers now do geography in a big way. Really, the way we used to artificially divide the curriculum into separate subject areas doesn&#39;t hold as much water today. Technology is exerting an enormously integrative influence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What with computer maps, hand-held GPS devices (including some cell phones), more publicly available aerial photography, more travel and tourism, we&#39;re becoming increasingly geographically aware as a species. This trend obviously needs to be reflected in our grade school curricula.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I earlier threw together a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/cgi-bin/form1.cgi&quot;&gt;simple quiz program&lt;/a&gt; to test one&#39;s knowledge of the USA state capitals (plus a few territories). Here the focus was the behind-the-scenes SQL engine and server-side scripts. Kids need to know about the ubiquity of databases. That&#39;s where we store all this geographic data, these latitudes and longitudes, street names and so on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Where are the sewers? Your municipality should have that info in electronic form, or be working on getting there. Where are the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inogate.org/html/maps/mapsgas.htm&quot;&gt;gas lines&lt;/a&gt;?  World game players need to know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Likewise our map of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdbwww.gdb.org/&quot;&gt;human genome&lt;/a&gt;, tons of other biological information, all lives in databases. Indeed, the location of species (in time as well as space), their internal layout, in terms or organs, nerves and so on, is just more geography, if you want to look at it that way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.garmin.com/aboutGPS/&quot;&gt;Understanding GPS&lt;/a&gt; also requires an understanding of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satellite_constellation&quot;&gt;satellite constellations&lt;/a&gt;, and that gets us thinking about Earth in its solar system context, and the galactic context beyond that. In this sense, geography encompasses both biology and astronomy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Footnote: &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/12/we-win.html&quot;&gt;Dave Ulmer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://geocaching.gpsgames.org/history/&quot;&gt;invented geocaching&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113617853998627595'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113617853998627595'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/middle-school-geography.html' title='Middle School Geography'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113605717567824411</id><published>2005-12-31T23:08:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:11.537-08:00</updated><title type='text'>MOTD</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/fullerproject.0.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/fullerproject.0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Fuller Projection&lt;br /&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.metamute.com/twiki/pub/Home/WebHome/metamap2001.pdf&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; for PDF version)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;tt&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt; Re domestic spying: so how *is* the NSA supposed to interpret &quot;domestic&quot;, when the Fuller Projection shows This Land is Our Land (merry little tune). -- &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;K. Urner, Synergeo #25562&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113605717567824411'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113605717567824411'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/12/motd.html' title='MOTD'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113596156680972815</id><published>2005-12-30T09:02:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2008-12-30T18:13:24.809-08:00</updated><title type='text'>New Years Fireworks</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/timessquareball.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/timessquareball.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recombined a lot of my Math Forum themes into some &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=1317644&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;year end polemics&lt;/a&gt;, hoping to spark some interest in our open source agenda for the new millenium. Having &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nysun.com/article/25159?page_no=1&quot;&gt;the ball in Times Square&lt;/a&gt; be a 3-frequency geodesic certainly helps (10ff+2; V+F=E+2; N:2N:3N and like that).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But newspaper editors don&#39;t seem to have much time for a high tech math-science spin (fullerenes, viral shells, octet truss...), especially one that could snowball. Can&#39;t have that. Better to recycle the usual stories we always get around this time of year (&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/12/loose-ends.html&quot;&gt;booze etc.&lt;/a&gt;).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113596156680972815'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113596156680972815'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/12/new-years-fireworks.html' title='New Years Fireworks'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113555927899915145</id><published>2005-12-25T17:04:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2008-03-09T13:07:12.178-07:00</updated><title type='text'>We Win?</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/ulmervictory.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/ulmervictory.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Dave Ulmer signaling from his &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/daves-bizmo.html&quot;&gt;desert bizmo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;(self portrait)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113555927899915145'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113555927899915145'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/12/we-win.html' title='We Win?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113501117708664136</id><published>2005-12-19T09:14:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2008-06-10T21:16:47.040-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Presents for Iraq</title><content type='html'>If I could wave a magic wand and give gifts to Baghdad (to share with environs of course), I&#39;d probably put the following under the tree: Office and Home Depot outlets (substantial ownership in both chains, including stateside), a SeaWorld (Iraqis choose the site), lots of steady, cheap electricity (they can certainly afford it), membership in Costco, a new science museum (like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.omsi.org/&quot;&gt;OMSI&lt;/a&gt;), Netflix.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These gifts would be delivered &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.answers.com/irregardless&amp;amp;r=67&quot;&gt;irregardless&lt;/a&gt; of religious affiliation or sexual orientation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the USA, Xmas is a commercial/secular holiday, on which religions piggy-back. Jesus was not likely born on December 25 and in any case the gift-bearing Magicians showed up later (ritually on &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/01/christmas-folk-lore.html&quot;&gt;Epiphany, January 6&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The USA traces its origins to many Roman institutions (evident to anyone visiting Washington, DC), including &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saturnalia&quot;&gt;Saturnalia&lt;/a&gt;.  None of which is to say there&#39;s anything &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;wrong&lt;/span&gt; with Christians piggy- backing on our secular holiday, as long as they don&#39;t mind sharing it with the rest of us.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113501117708664136'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113501117708664136'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/12/presents-for-iraq.html' title='Presents for Iraq'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113466075967861324</id><published>2005-12-15T08:25:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2012-01-19T22:04:13.021-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Thinking Globally</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/img/254/1836/640/fullerproject.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/img/254/1836/320/fullerproject.jpg&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom: rgb(0,0,0) 1px solid; border-left: rgb(0,0,0) 1px solid; border-right: rgb(0,0,0) 1px solid; border-top: rgb(0,0,0) 1px solid; margin: 2px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;Fuller Projection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This recent call from some president in Iran for Israel to vanish from the world map might be construed as a proposal to make more use of the Fuller Projection, whereon &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; nations have disappeared.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The idea here is it&#39;s &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; Israel, while the frequently-heard accusation that Jewish networks seek &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/04/cywar-in-cyberia.html&quot;&gt;global domination&lt;/a&gt; is less a source of paranoia than of hope. Mature schools of thought, many found within Judaism, are indeed committed to the long term viability and sustainability of Spaceship Earth, our promised land, for millenia to come.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our USA operating system is up to the same thing: providing robust, secure infrastructure for our global dominion. Certainly many pro Russians think intelligently about their ship, and act accordingly wherever they may be. Space-minded Chinese call it &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/12/our-land.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Our Land&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Fuller School &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;encourages&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/02/on-edge-of-chaos.html&quot;&gt;thinking globally&lt;/a&gt;. We &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;want&lt;/span&gt; whole systems thinking, global management philosophies, people who think in big picture terms. Letting your mind get boxed in by some arbitrary political boundaries just dumbs you down, artificially constrains your horizons.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So, how will the new Persian power plants fit in to the regional grid and how will the IAEA be assured that no weaponization is happening? These are supranational concerns. Let&#39;s use a Fuller Projection to brainstorm some answers. Let&#39;s make our Iran a safe and secure world.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mid-level managers who still need to cling to some jigsaw-puzzle nation state approach to global thinking are welcome to do so, have plenty of other maps to choose from to sustain their patterns of thought.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113466075967861324'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113466075967861324'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/12/thinking-globally.html' title='Thinking Globally'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113451320565471194</id><published>2005-12-13T15:16:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-12-24T12:45:26.735-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Design Science</title><content type='html'>Terry Bristol and I had a high level meeting of the minds in my living room this afternoon. He said I needed more Christmas tree lights, and I agreed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bigger still, however, was my realization that his &quot;intelligent design science&quot; (a kind of science that&#39;s comfortable with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buckminster.info/Index/T/Teleologic.htm&quot;&gt;teleological&lt;/a&gt; / purposeful language) and my &quot;design science&quot; (absorbed through years of immersion in the Fuller School), come close enough to form a closable cosmic gap.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lots of big names in philosophy, many of them Greek, got tossed about. Terry&#39;s account of a certain Native American training (and rite of passage) reminded me a heck of a lot of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;est&lt;/span&gt;, in terms of sharing the same &quot;getting it&quot; experience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Using the language of synergetics: Terry sees that an eternal war of incommensurability (987.061) might give rise to two competing orders, such that awareness of otherness becomes critical to the integrity of any science or core set of beliefs. There&#39;s always that complementary / missing 720 degrees (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everything2.com/index.pl?node_id=874600&quot;&gt;omnidirectional halo concept&lt;/a&gt;), a seed for negative Universe (the antithesis of Universe), both arising from the same cosmic integrity, what Ervin Laszlo calls Metaverse. Awareness of cosmic otherness begets a dialectic and synergy (symbolized for Bucky by a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buckminster.info/Index/B/Bow.htm&quot;&gt;bow-tie&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyway, good meeting, good outcome, and worth saving as an operational part of my control room.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Related reading:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Invisible Landscape Series&lt;/span&gt; (by me): [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/synergetica/invisible1.html&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/synergetica/invisible2.html&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/synergetica/invisible3.html&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/synergetica/invisible4.html&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/synergetica/veil.gif&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=4146272&amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Questions for ID Propenents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; @ Math Forum&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=1311085&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;More re ID&lt;/a&gt; @ Math Forum</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113451320565471194'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113451320565471194'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/12/design-science.html' title='Design Science'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113383877142310476</id><published>2005-12-05T20:17:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:10.960-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Another Meeting @ Wired</title><content type='html'>Trevor and I had dinner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityguide.aol.com/portland/entertainment/venue.adp?sbid=111290343&quot;&gt;Fujin&lt;/a&gt; this evening, compared notes with the owner and son about petty thievery in China (its current shape, ever shifting). I googled with my cell (466452), looking for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0379786/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Serenity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in PDX (Trevor is enthused about it, I&#39;ve yet to catch it). Met Derek on the corner of 39th, enroute to Chinese. Bid Trevor adieu at a 75 bus stop across from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fixmydeadpc.com/&quot;&gt;FixMyDeadPC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ve been active around cyberspace per usual today, but also doing a lot of hospital work, coding in FoxPro, working on Excel spreadsheets.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Earlier this morning, I read up on music making using contemporary components and software. Some of the best GUI interfaces come from musicians. I&#39;m consulting for a locally based pro, ready to move into the new era.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tomorrow I&#39;ll be teaching Python some more. We started with &quot;hello world&quot;, moved to data structures (lists and dictionaries), types (primitive and collections).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Last night, I wrote some notes about an ACM paper on pedagogy around computer programming (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2005-December/005607.html&quot;&gt;teaching coding to kids&lt;/a&gt;).</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/113383877142310476/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/113383877142310476' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113383877142310476'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113383877142310476'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/12/another-meeting-wired.html' title='Another Meeting @ Wired'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113321579239558382</id><published>2005-11-28T15:03:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:10.896-08:00</updated><title type='text'>PDX:  Open Source Capital</title><content type='html'>So I&#39;m in a small coffee shop. Terry is at the house, with another business associate and my wife the bookkeepper for ISEPP, as a consultant.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Terry wishes the plan to rennovate the property next to Pauling Campus, the renting office repair store, into a &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Cafe Philosophicus&lt;/span&gt; or like that, might materialize.  Just needs the $100K.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Don&#39;s asking &quot;how&quot; (his name will appear this time).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So PDX was in some write-up in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Christian Science Monitor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csmonitor.com/2005/1128/p03s02-ussc.html&quot;&gt;today&lt;/a&gt;, as an up-and-coming hub of the global open source network, thanks to the hard work of so many geeks (aka software and hardware engineers), trying to write some benign-enough science / fiction.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Terry just walked in.  Our meeting resumes...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Derek appears.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113321579239558382'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113321579239558382'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/11/pdx-open-source-capital.html' title='PDX:  Open Source Capital'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113313125015384343</id><published>2005-11-27T14:40:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:10.830-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Quaker Gun</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/hello/254/1836/640/P63000341.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;border: 1px solid rgb(0, 0, 0); margin: 2px;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/hello/254/1836/320/P63000341.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&quot;insanely difficult to use effectively&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;(photo by K. Urner @ Europython 2005)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113313125015384343'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113313125015384343'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/11/quaker-gun.html' title='Quaker Gun'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113313099164792346</id><published>2005-11-27T14:34:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:10.750-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Songs of Non-Violence?</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/PB270063.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/PB270063.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&quot;now playing...&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;(K. Urner, Olympus Stylus 500)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113313099164792346'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113313099164792346'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/11/songs-of-non-violence.html' title='Songs of Non-Violence?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113250430573621589</id><published>2005-11-20T08:31:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:10.662-08:00</updated><title type='text'>More Map Talk</title><content type='html'>Just because the Fuller Projection is by definition nationless, at least in its most pristine, least dumbed down form, doesn&#39;t mean we don&#39;t see the barbed wire, concrete barriers, armed guard kiosks and so on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;World Game players may very well carry passports (complete with &lt;a href=&quot;http://slashdot.org/articles/05/11/19/149242.shtml?tid=133&amp;tid=117&quot;&gt;RFID&lt;/a&gt;) or find workarounds (like staying home). Plus as any pilot knows, the no fly zones don&#39;t just follow national boundaries. Our targets of interest may have no visible presence &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;except&lt;/span&gt; on our maps.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Whenever people pour into the streets to register their views, in Beirut, Tehran, New York or wherever, that&#39;s of course visible to satellites as well. One way we play the game is by massing ourselves in open areas, such as at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Woodstock&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Burning Man&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So it&#39;s not like we&#39;re waiting for any political events to occur, before we start displaying global data in the Fuller format. We&#39;ve been doing it for years.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Once you have your global data sets in compatible electronic format, its fun to mix and match them, including across time. What dinosaurs lived in your local area code? How might we assign zip codes to off shore floating cities? The permutations are endless.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113250430573621589'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113250430573621589'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/11/more-map-talk.html' title='More Map Talk'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113200516646593141</id><published>2005-11-14T13:23:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:10.563-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Memo re The Map</title><content type='html'>In my view, Snyder is a damned good cartographer and I have no problem using his algorithm to populate global data displays making use of Fuller&#39;s preferred layout, with uninterrupted landmasses (one layout among many).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m aware of cheap imitations of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.google.com/images?q=fuller+projection&amp;hl=en&amp;amp;btnG=Search+Images&quot;&gt;Dymaxion or Fuller Projection&lt;/a&gt;, which slice into Japan or wherever, and I know would-be World Game players would be dismayed by such a dumbing down. Competent players want access to the real deal, I understand that.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m also aware that Fuller&#39;s algorithm, as computerized by Bob Gray starting with Fuller&#39;s simulations, expressed with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/synergetics/s11/figs/f0102.html&quot;&gt;Polynesian-style artifacts&lt;/a&gt;, might be used to replace Snyder&#39;s in some contexts, giving different gaussians (i.e. the triangles are still distorted, but in a different way).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mostly, I&#39;m interested in just cutting through the BS, such that open source global data displays, of relevance to NGOs especially, don&#39;t involve diverting precious resources from field offices and control rooms already fully engaged in serious-minded service on the front lines.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We don&#39;t have the time/energy to spare to ensure compliance with a lot of complicated EULAs. That&#39;s why we use Ubuntu/Gnome and like that: we&#39;re short of money on paper, and yet we&#39;re performing vital high tech services on behalf of omnihumanity nevertheless.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Fuller Projection should be immediately accessible to such remotely deployed individuals, as well as to school kids in their safe &#39;n secure classrooms, complete with relevant data overlays.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our school&#39;s objective is to foster competent planning and collaboration skills, such as we&#39;ve been learning and benefitting from in the open source community more generally. Let&#39;s keep up the good work while making GIS/GPS more integral to our thinking.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113200516646593141'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113200516646593141'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/11/memo-re-map.html' title='Memo re The Map'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113143082018690843</id><published>2005-11-07T22:13:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-10-12T15:32:04.821-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Headline: GENI Out of the Bottle</title><content type='html'>I found a Plone site about the Iraqi economy, including news and views regarding regional hookups, stretching as far away as Europe (e.g. through Turkey). That&#39;s encouraging. The global grid gets mentioned in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/02/ayatollah-of-tetrahedron.html&quot;&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt;, and in neighboring blogs. The buzz around GENI is not new.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0312174918/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Critical Path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; project (high priority): network the high voltage long distance distribution grids, to facilitate buying and selling of power. ENRON failed to elucidate the vision, got side tracked into attacking California, getting caught in off shore language games around tropical fish &#39;n stuff. Maybe not really the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0413845/&quot;&gt;smartest guys in the room&lt;/a&gt;.  More of those at Google.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113143082018690843'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113143082018690843'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/11/headline-geni-out-of-bottle.html' title='Headline: GENI Out of the Bottle'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113033821741596509</id><published>2005-10-26T07:23:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:10.377-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Control Rooms?</title><content type='html'>Notably absent from coverage of a FEMA response, or lack thereof, to recent hurricanes, has been any view of a control room. Apparently FEMA has no central nervous system it feels proud enough to show off, no Hollywood-style NORAD or Mission Control ala Houston.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Relief engineers don&#39;t huddle over monitors, tracking the progress of this or that mobile relief convoy, with a big screen up front sharing overview. Nor do we see such centers on TV when disaster strikes around the world, e.g. in Pakistan or Guatemala.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;TV news rooms come closer, give a sense of a high tech hub receiving reports from journalists around the world. The evening news is a tip of the iceberg sampling of top stories, but there&#39;s a sense of thousands more hours going to some archive for later retrieval and review.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But news rooms field spectators, watchers. The ethic of journalism is not to participate, but to report. In nervous system terms, news rooms receive pleasure and pain signals, but have no direct way to trigger a motor response. We hope other control rooms get the message.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course a lot of control and situation rooms don&#39;t get much TV exposure. Demolition engineers punch up real time satellite imagery, video feed from drones and so on and battleships have their bridges. When it comes to command and control, Pentagon style, wreaking havoc is the name of the game. Our script writers and scenario planners tend to be apocalyptic and/or vengeful in their thinking, anxious to fight human enemies, not weather, earthquakes, fire, famine, drought or poverty.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;World Game still takes a back seat to war games, in the fantasy lives of so many children, when they imagine what a safer, more secure world might be like. Control rooms focused on disaster relief and monitoring civilian infrastructure don&#39;t really enter their consciousness. Instead they dream of overwhelming fire power, missile defense, ray guns on orbiting space platforms, zapping Earth-bound terrorists on the run.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have the technology to play World Game for real, but our thinking remains immature, stuck in yesteryear&#39;s science fiction. Not enough grown ups. Not a new problem.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113033821741596509'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113033821741596509'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/10/control-rooms.html' title='Control Rooms?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-112803484942754914</id><published>2005-09-29T15:40:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:10.293-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Baghdad, City of</title><content type='html'>We may legitimately expect great advances in civilization from Baghdad, once the dust settles.  &lt;span class=&quot;querybold&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;artcopy&quot;&gt;Muhammad ibn Musa al-Khwarizmi&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; lived in Baghdad, according to an online Britannica.  I was just &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=3986056&amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;checking into that&lt;/a&gt; a few minutes ago.  I hear Greenspan favors still teaching the long division algorithm in K-12.  I&#39;m certainly not averse.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Did I ever mention my job at Georgetown University, refiling Arabic language texts to their rightful shelf positions? The job required at least knowing the regional alphabet. At the time, I kind of did, thanks to a course I almost failed at Princeton. I also used the time to read more about James Joyce (the Hugh Kenner connection), and naval history (this is closer to the time when Fuller&#39;s whimsical/poetical &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Critical Path&lt;/span&gt; was still new).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let&#39;s keep working on getting Imperial Rome out of the picture. Old Glory, in symbolizing a fight against British Imperialism in the 1700s, knows something about beating back illegitimate tyranny. Democracy and self-determination at the local level go hand in hand.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We understand that a stable world system doesn&#39;t require power to apex in any one apex. Tower of Babel was for a reason: to keep Man where he belongs, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;out&lt;/span&gt; of the control room (within those limitations, we do as much as we responsibly can, and then some).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/112803484942754914'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/112803484942754914'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/09/baghdad-city-of.html' title='Baghdad, City of'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-112697598693013953</id><published>2005-09-17T11:04:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:10.161-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Return to the Moon?</title><content type='html'>Mom pointed out an interesting juxtaposition of stories on the front page of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Oregonian&lt;/span&gt; today:  the rural southeast feels bypassed by federal aid agencies; NASA wants to return to the moon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have Google set to sweep newsmedia for any mention of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/09/omr.html&quot;&gt;OMR&lt;/a&gt; stadium-shaped city idea.  Turning stadiums &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;into&lt;/span&gt; cities seems to be a favored solution to date, but that doesn&#39;t seem very practical in the long run.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If NASA could build us a spanking new moon base (a dot-mil operation), maybe it could help us brainstorm about new high tech ecovillages right here on Spaceship Earth. We civilians (remember us?) could use some help from the aerospace sector.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But NASA may not have the imagination for it, may not have the &quot;right stuff.&quot; OK, so how &#39;bout The Mouse in Orlando? EPCOT used to mean Experimental Prototype Community of Tomorrow, before the language lawyers changed it to Epcot (deliberately meaningless) and disgused the &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.google.com/images?svnum=10&amp;hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;q=epcot+spaceship+earth&amp;amp;btnG=Search&quot;&gt;BuckyBall&lt;/a&gt; with the wave of a magic wand (camouflage?).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/112697598693013953'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/112697598693013953'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/09/return-to-moon.html' title='Return to the Moon?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-112658668528162370</id><published>2005-09-12T22:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:10.081-08:00</updated><title type='text'>More on Mathematics</title><content type='html'>I&#39;ve gone back to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=1218351&amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;Internet brainstorming&lt;/a&gt; with other math heads, trying to find a way to engage the media more successfully in high def, high bandwidth, prime time &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.answers.com/pedagogy&quot;&gt;pedagogy&lt;/a&gt;, i.e. how do we live up to the promise of TV as a medium for education? Obviously it needs to be entertaining as well. The two go together, positive synergies are inherent.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Inventors always dreamed it might be used for good, even as they cringed, bracing for worse. Well, we know what worse looks like, but there&#39;s still plenty of bandwidth for better. And we&#39;ve had a lot of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;excellent&lt;/span&gt; television. I&#39;ve often been awed by the talent, the writing, the whole shebang.[1] Not on every channel nor every program mind you. But sometimes TV just blows me away, the way some books and movies do, or some dreams.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A lot of thinkers have focused on &quot;symbol dances&quot; as a genre to focus on, by which I mean multimedia language games that have, as their content, some of the alpha/numeric, iconic, ideogrammatic, and variously stylized glyphs of our or other cultures. Like, flash the ancient &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.omniglot.com/writing/greek.htm&quot;&gt;greek letters&lt;/a&gt; and say them.  Sigma, phi, pi, theta.  Ro ro ro your boat.  But with Flash as in Macromedia, as in Shockwave, as in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Sesame Street&lt;/span&gt; with Big Bird -- and Evil Bert (not really evil -- that was a joke from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://politicalhumor.about.com/library/images/blosamabert2.htm&quot;&gt;political sphere&lt;/a&gt;, some kids won&#39;t remember).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ve &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/flash/sumtotients.html&quot;&gt;played with&lt;/a&gt; Flash myself, and come up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/flash/group.html&quot;&gt;primitive&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/flash/reciprocal.html&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt; of what I&#39;m talking about. But I&#39;m no super incredible artist when it comes to some sophisticated art-making technologies. I write pretty well. But I&#39;m no great prodigy when it comes to animation (I like to think I add to the team, but I&#39;m not as good in all positions, obviously).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[1] &quot;shebang.&quot; &lt;u&gt;WordNet 1.7.1&lt;/u&gt;. Princeton University, 2001. &lt;i&gt;Answers.com&lt;/i&gt; GuruNet Corp. 13 Sep. 2005. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.answers.com/topic/shebang&quot;&gt;http://www.answers.com/topic/shebang&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/112658668528162370'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/112658668528162370'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/09/more-on-mathematics.html' title='More on Mathematics'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-112611032347000144</id><published>2005-09-07T09:18:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:10.001-08:00</updated><title type='text'>More Global Data</title><content type='html'>Of course another stargate that&#39;s opened (metaphor) is between New Orleans and Amsterdam, Louisiana and the Netherlands. I was pleased to see so much set in the Netherlands in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Quicksilver&lt;/span&gt;, however twisted that telling.  Such wonderful canvases.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;People elsewhere on the globe are starting to get more of a picture of what the heartland of America is like. The logistics are poor here. Like, look at our dikes. Kids in Holland stare at the TV agog: so America is like this stone age place, like in &lt;a href=&quot;http://imdb.com/title/tt0053502/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Flintstones&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;?</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/112611032347000144'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/112611032347000144'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/09/more-global-data.html' title='More Global Data'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-112586449465086718</id><published>2005-09-04T12:40:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-02T23:01:57.646-07:00</updated><title type='text'>OMR?</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Is now the time to dust off shelved megaproject proposals, e.g. Old Man River City (OMR)? Trevor brought this up at our meeting yesterday -- seemed apropos.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This stadium-shaped A-frame features terraced living, with apartments taking the place of bleachers (obviously its scale dwarfs ordinary football stadia), plus a cover.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I updated &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/domes/domeproto.html&quot;&gt;a web page&lt;/a&gt; on my site with a pictured scale mockup (see Bucky Fuller&#39;s &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Critical Path&lt;/span&gt;, 1981 for more details).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;synergeo&lt;/span&gt; (Yahoo eGroup) some guy thought I was talking about replacing New Orleans with this leviathan, but I&#39;m more thinking how to bring something on-line that&#39;d be faster to start using (it could go up in sections), while employing companies starting now, thereby giving folks some options (shades of New Deal thinking).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The eventual fate of New Orleans needn&#39;t hinge on what we do or don&#39;t do in the East St. Louis area.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
And we might have learned something in Baghdad about building in transparency (sorely lacking in that context).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The tsunami story isn&#39;t over yet either, by a long shot. Disaster relief could and should be one of the world&#39;s principal industries (like the body&#39;s immune system), fading into construction, communications, health care and education at the civilian end of the spectrum.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Emergency response becomes part of the military way, what with its chain of command and experience with heavy equipment. Restoring order means reverting to a natural state of nonviolent civilian living. Putting out fires is the name of the game -- not starting them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I don&#39;t know if OMR is just a solution looking for a problem here, but bouncing back from Katrina with megaproject proposals, one of which would be rebuilding New Orleans itself (a daunting task), is a healthy response. However, going to the moon wouldn&#39;t be that relevant (thinking back to Hurricane Camille, which came &lt;a href=&quot;http://vlib.iue.it/history/USA/ERAS/20TH/1960s.html&quot;&gt;shortly after&lt;/a&gt; Apollo 11).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Floating city ideas should also be revisited while we&#39;re at it, with realistic attention to natural disaster possibilities. Not every technology is suitable to every ecosystem -- presumably we know &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; much by now.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/112586449465086718'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/112586449465086718'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/09/omr.html' title='OMR?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>