<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=651'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=626&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=676&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>651</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7228675734527698269</id><published>2015-09-21T19:28:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-04T17:17:06.270-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Triangulation Puzzles</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/21381449720/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;ToonTown&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;ToonTown&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/605/21381449720_889b093986.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I invited &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/09/zardoz-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Alan Potkin&lt;/a&gt; to address Wanderers at Pauling House tomorrow, about his work in the field of environmental impact.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ve had lots of &quot;eco talks&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As Alan points out:&amp;nbsp; so often the institution charged with undertaking an environmental impact study has a vested interest in the outcome in that it not mess with already drafted plans, many jobs on the line.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The dam building company is supposed to do PR about what could be lost?&amp;nbsp; The builder is supposed to pay for an objective review?&amp;nbsp; They&#39;d hire Alan and get what they&#39;d paid for; and more than they wanted to know.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Why isn&#39;t this design in itself seen as a problem?&amp;nbsp; We let the accused plead the Fifth.&amp;nbsp; If someone is going to be working against you and your perceived interests, then really have that be someone else.&amp;nbsp; One can only be one&#39;s own sparring partner up to a point.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How do we solve conflicts of interest?&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/10/terminal-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Triangulation puzzles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not solving them &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/09/investigating-how-things-work.html&quot;&gt;begets corruption&lt;/a&gt;, we know that much.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Alan may have left town however; no reply to my voicemail.&amp;nbsp; Maybe next time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Other loose ends, for the Home Management committee:&amp;nbsp; the 1000 megabit service is to be throttled back to just 40, and they&#39;ll throw in TV.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m also getting the local digital broadcasts in the public frequencies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The main thing is to stay on fiber with its faster up as well as down speeds, for an affordable monrhly fee.&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;CenturyLink&lt;/i&gt; would actually charge me more to not get TV, same bandwidth!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;No&quot; said their office, I must pay the installation I thought was thrown in, but she agreed to shave off the bill for the few months.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lumping &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/09/car-karma.html&quot;&gt;Car and House karma&lt;/a&gt; into one:&amp;nbsp; K&amp;amp;M had it fixed by this afternoon; indeed a new starter was needed.&amp;nbsp; Thanks to AAA for prompt towing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
City life can be pretty smooth, if you&#39;re able to pay for it.&amp;nbsp; Aye, there&#39;s the rub.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A cornucopia of animations from &lt;i&gt;ToonTown&lt;/i&gt;:&amp;nbsp; that&#39;s what &lt;i&gt;Portland Knowledge Lab&lt;/i&gt; was forecasting, in an earlier chapter.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d rented an office near &lt;i&gt;Lucky Lab&lt;/i&gt;, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/12/new-beginning.html&quot;&gt;moved out&lt;/a&gt; when Internet proved too slow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d been expecting Synergetics-infused blends &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/01/curriculum-notes.html&quot;&gt;any day now&lt;/a&gt;&quot; but that assumes art schools were priming the pump with lectures of the type I&#39;ve not been slated to give (&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/art-history.html&quot;&gt;yet&lt;/a&gt;), nor much of anyone apparently.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So that economy stalls.&amp;nbsp; Malesh.&amp;nbsp; Think where we could have been by now.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Other parts of our economy keep barreling ahead.&amp;nbsp; Even the bare &lt;i&gt;ToonTown&lt;/i&gt; image seems to stick.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s because Portland does have relevant heritage.&amp;nbsp; I was building on an existing image.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We could be making more manga, not to mention anime.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But I&#39;m thinking most especially of cartoons of a techie type i.e. in &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/09/opting-out.html&quot;&gt;this age of nano-tech&lt;/a&gt; / ONAMI it&#39;s the area of STEM visualization (or STEAM) were we need most focus.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Just talking heads are not enough.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The genre of biology videos, showing the happenings with DNA...&amp;nbsp; the problem being the bottleneck &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/02/munching-on-medical-data.html&quot;&gt;identified by &lt;i&gt;Pfizer&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&amp;nbsp; everyone is silo-ing IP (intellectual property) when it&#39;s the Open Way that&#39;s known to work (the liberal arts model, not penalizing sharing information but on the contrary making it easier).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Roadblocks aside, we could be practicing with curriculum treating of topics that already are Open Source, such as file systems and how they work.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets see what I can find...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vSMriAHpzQM?list=PLZ7F41JMKc07BvdS1bhCwflStQ7ul1FXF&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yeah, I do like those &quot;sped up&quot; drawing whiteboards, with fun drawings.  I&#39;ve watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/zDZFcDGpL4U&quot;&gt;lots of those&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Too many talking heads, teacher&#39;s back turned, writing... Not how we want it on TV.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d also like &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/boosting-bandwidth.html&quot;&gt;more density&lt;/a&gt;, with cutaways to talk about hardware, the history of storage (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Selectron_tube&quot;&gt;per Von Neumann&lt;/a&gt;)... a much wider selection of topics, inter-connected.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How &#39;bout it? Better STEM TV anyone?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets build up the library, the videogrammatron, of short clips anyone might use.&amp;nbsp; High production values are maybe self defeating if locked entirely behind some IMAX screen.&amp;nbsp; Lets share the IP.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Plus I&#39;m talking about quirky art in addition, affordable and within range of solo artists.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The mix would be reminiscent of &lt;i&gt;Sesame Street&lt;/i&gt; in some collections.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7228675734527698269'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7228675734527698269'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/09/triangulation-puzzles.html' title='Triangulation Puzzles'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/vSMriAHpzQM/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-586062871443766549</id><published>2015-09-17T23:35:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2015-09-19T13:29:52.639-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Zardoz (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/21371670445/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF0266&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF0266&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/591/21371670445_675f6fc8a0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
This is an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0070948/&quot;&gt;oldie but goldie&lt;/a&gt; I&#39;d probably never have seen were it not for Alan Potkin of Brooklyn NY (by birth) becoming a lightning bolt in my reality, joining me at &lt;i&gt;Horse Brass&lt;/i&gt; out of the blue (we set it up by cell) along my Belmont Street descent from Mt. Tabor (local hill), getting back in shape from a bout of ankle-itus.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Alan and I always have lots to talk about.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s been in these blogs &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/07/july-4-2015.html&quot;&gt;before&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Alan&#39;s wife, from France originally, is a distinguished scholar of that region of the world we think of as &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/01/beyond-rangoon-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;mostly Burma&lt;/a&gt; (Myanmar) these days, a region where ethnic strife continues, with world religions in the blender, mixing it up to make puree.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Alan shares her deep love for this region and goes there to pursue projects.&amp;nbsp; They married in our living room in Thimphu in the 1980s.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The fact that humans adapt to their world differently and then get flung together by fate, as is happening now in &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/09/pedestrian-thinking.html&quot;&gt;the EU&lt;/a&gt;, how the US was formed, has never been smooth, to say the least, though in isolated cases (e.g. specific marriages) it can work out well and serve as an inspiration to others.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Somehow the conversation turned to &lt;i&gt;Zardoz&lt;/i&gt;, a film, and since we were but a block away from &lt;i&gt;Movie Madness&lt;/i&gt;, I was eager to prove its &quot;we have everything&quot; reputation, and indeed it did, filed by Hollywood Director, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000958/&quot;&gt;John Boorman&lt;/a&gt;, who wrote, produced and directed it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Boorman is of British heritage Alan wanted me to know (i.e. he didn&#39;t only work through Hollywood&#39;s institutions), continuing our conversation later, with Carol, at &lt;i&gt;Maru&lt;/i&gt;, the Japanese restaurant (Alan was ecstatic about the squid).&amp;nbsp; We&#39;d watched the DVD, sans Carol, in my living room.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets see if I can get this right after only one viewing (I&#39;m tempted to watch it again but hey, I&#39;m not making a living as a movie critic and have to keep moving).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Zed (Sean Connery), a badass outlander, gets angry and disillusioned when his preferred lifestyle, with the Pentagon (by analogy, not mentioned), is disrupted by the stupid Sky Head, which now wants them to try agriculture.&amp;nbsp; The Sky Head used to barf guns, telling them to go crazy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Instead of shooting the Brutals and raping their women (maybe the best part), Zed now has to teach them to farm, which is tedious and without shooting.&amp;nbsp; However by this time he&#39;s literate himself and knows the stupid Sky Head is really like some Wizard of Oz instrument of control, and the civilization behind it is just using him.&amp;nbsp; So he resolves to stowaway and get revenge against higher management.&amp;nbsp; This he does.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Higher management, in the meantime, has existential worries of its own, having tricked itself into immortality without sex.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re bored, plagued with a serious death wish.&amp;nbsp; Apathy and senility are claiming their people, or they become renegades, which is also not fun.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Real death without coming back simply as another copy of the same worn-out persona, the same goon, would be a blessing and Zed, and those like him, may be the answer to their prayers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The film ends on an up note, as needs dovetail and sex is back in the picture.&amp;nbsp; Everyone seems to get what they wanted.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Alan has been checking up on the hydrological projects, i.e. the hydroelectric dams, in South / Southeast Asia that have occupied his attention for the past few decades.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
His technique is to boost the efficacy of environmental impact statements by pushing the PDF format to its limit, including movies of the waterfalls and waterwheels, the cultures, that might be lost if engineering fails to optimize for tourism and local welfare.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fortunately, in many cases, by using pipe-fed turbines, as in Bhutan, engineers may take advantage of drops in the topography, i.e. of gravity, without a massive dam.&amp;nbsp; The pipe fills to capacity, but is not sucking down or backing up the whole river and thereby develops sufficient pressure for at least a micro-hydel-style turbine.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Of course this solution is not always relevant.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m just glad people have been thinking outside the box a little.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Feng-shui of optimal power generating, that takes everything into account, is something we would hope the Chinese would be good at, but engineering needs to advance in its understanding of itself too?&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/05/engineering-as-moral-enterprise.html&quot;&gt;We shall see&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; From my viewpoint, Alan has been encouraging the engineering to improve.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/586062871443766549'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/586062871443766549'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/09/zardoz-movie-review.html' title='Zardoz (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7139810937748918946</id><published>2015-09-15T20:20:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-09-19T13:34:52.370-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Autobiographical Interlude</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20834533734/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;libya&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;libya&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5727/20834533734_7056d35d2b_o.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldatlas.com/webimage/countrys/africa/ly.htm&quot;&gt;worldatlas&lt;/a&gt; ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
How did I get to be &quot;kicked back&quot; in the Steve Holden Chair of Computer Science (large recliner), here in the Blue House, Asylum District -- and what does that mean for humanity?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That sounds like a good B-movie opening; that&#39;s right we&#39;re low budget.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not going to tell a story of how I amassed a great pile of drachmas (pesos, lira).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Jack, my dad, wanted to practice his profession with a blanker slate than a busy metro area like Portland could offer -- which makes sense given his PhD work was in regional planning for less developed nations (we could say &quot;Third World&quot;).&amp;nbsp; By the end of the 1960s, after some good years in Portland, we ended up in Rome as a family, so he could easily commute to the &quot;project site&quot; otherwise known as Libya.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
From Rome we moved to Florida, with a few weeks in Ramallah, Palestine that summer, working with AFSC (a Quaker NGO, founded by a philosophy professor and Friends).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d attended both Junior English School of Rome, and American Overseas School of Rome, which we called OSR (ASOR today).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then after Bradenton, we moved to the Philippines, arriving near the start of martial law under Marcos and cronies. I attend the International School (IS) in Makati.&amp;nbsp; Dad worked for the UN, USAID, University of the Philippines.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At that point, having finished high school, I branched off on my own trajectory, but continued visiting &quot;home base&quot; as it moved around, after that, to Egypt (Cairo), Bangladesh (Dhaka), Bhutan (Thimphu) and Lesotho (Maseru) in that order.&amp;nbsp; My younger sister pursued higher education in Ohio and New Jersey, ending up in Greater LA.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My dad was killed in a car crash in South Africa (RSA) in October 2000, and my mom, who sustained injuries, and was not expected to live, divides her year between myself and my sister.&amp;nbsp; She&#39;s in good health at 86 and continues her peace activism.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol his a history degree from Ateneo de Manila, a Jesuit college.&amp;nbsp; She knows a lot about St. Francis and also his friend Jacopa, an admirer from a powerful family in Rome at that time (a period she intensely studied).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Now I&#39;m back in Portland, Oregon, have been since 1985, having left for Rome after 2nd grade.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was joined by Dawn Wicca, as a business partner and later as my wife, from the 1990s to 2007, when she died of breast cancer.&amp;nbsp; Dawn was survived by two daughters, one from her previous marriage.&amp;nbsp; She was from Ohio, then Florida, an activist in the women&#39;s self help movement, and a bookkeeper, specializing in non-profit accounting. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
From the Philippines I moved to Princeton for four years of university then kicked around the east coast, living in Jersey City, DC, Brooklyn, Queens, Apple Valley NC, before returning to Portland, by way of Bangladesh.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dad&#39;s PhD work in planning had been at the University of Chicago.&amp;nbsp; He was completing that work when I was born, in 1958.&amp;nbsp; Both parents were Quakers by then, pacifists by leaning and training.&amp;nbsp; That accounts for the AFSC work, which I continued in my own way.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol (mom) was active in Women&#39;s Strike for Peace, and later WILPF (Women&#39;s International League for Peace and Freedom).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Post Princeton, I continued my interest in &quot;futurism&quot;, encouraged by the example of my dad (his big picture plans for Libya and other countries were about anticipating needs for the next fifty years or so). By high school I&#39;d become an avid reader of science fiction, and movie goer.&amp;nbsp; These traits are reflected in my blogs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My foci at Princeton were myriad, though with philosophy paramount.&amp;nbsp; The combination of futurism, philosophy and international affairs (which I studied through Woodrow Wilson school courses) remains an evident source of thematic content in my writing and life&#39;s work.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My Quaker background led me to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quakerquaker.org/forum/topics/friends-ideas-about-poverty?commentId=2360685%3AComment%3A136699&amp;amp;xg_source=activity&quot;&gt;such writers as Kenneth Boulding&lt;/a&gt;, and later Dawn and I joined a group called Quaker Economics led by Joe Havens.&amp;nbsp; Joe&#39;s wife Teresina was an avid student of Buddhism and we were also members of her group.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dawn and her first daughter joined me on a trip to Bhutan during which we visited the temple to Tara at Tongsa, for which figure our second daughter was named.&amp;nbsp; She is now college aged.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If I start talking about my career I&#39;ll start sounding like I&#39;m giving my resume.&amp;nbsp; I might as well just &lt;a href=&quot;http://grunch.net/kirby-urner&quot;&gt;link to it&lt;/a&gt; instead. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7139810937748918946'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7139810937748918946'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/09/autobiographical-interlude.html' title='Autobiographical Interlude'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7897359387183173619</id><published>2015-09-12T09:21:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-09-15T09:58:36.199-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Reality TV</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Time to review some old themes and writings, with lotsa links to the &quot;business mobile&quot; (smartvan) concept.&amp;nbsp; The idea is we fan out in smartvans, not willy-nilly but as part of concerted World Game maneuvers and missions to assist refugees, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quakerquaker.org/forum/topics/friends-ideas-about-poverty?commentId=2360685%3AComment%3A137026&quot;&gt;other victims&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re &quot;dispatched&quot; in other words, which implies a &quot;control room&quot; (any number) and &quot;planning&quot; in some scenes.&amp;nbsp; If you&#39;ve watched a lot of movies, you have the innate ability to extrapolate and imagine a few episodes, at least in rough outline.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The TV angles are many, but lets talk about fundraising.&amp;nbsp; Our fans patch in to our web portal or we may even have a DVD show, like with seasons.&amp;nbsp; Broadcasters pick us up maybe.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re like this weekly adventure series of brave / attractive people in a smartvan, part of a larger fleet, out there being helpful to our fellow humans in various dramatic ways that home viewers want a piece of.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not only do the fans donate and get credit for so doing, they apply and train to jump in, to join us in the &quot;MercyCorps style&quot; swimming pool, this &quot;model UN&quot;, this &quot;scouting trip&quot; or whatever.&amp;nbsp; A &quot;terraforming corps&quot;?&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s Planet Earth that I&#39;m talking about.&amp;nbsp; We terraform more or less consciously, as a species, but either way, we make a big difference to the biosphere, that&#39;s obvious.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So yes, I&#39;m turning Peace Corps / Americorps type work, jazzed up with smartvans and more high tech, into Reality TV that&#39;s self funding, with product placement another big part of it.&amp;nbsp; Who made the smartvans and just how smart are they?&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m bringing it down to earth while projecting role models.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Crowning me a king of this genre (a producer) and paying me royally (not that much really -- I&#39;m middle to business class) just adds momentum (inertia) to all this happening (helps make it real).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So what are the critics saying, and why haven&#39;t we done this already if it&#39;s such a good idea?&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve certainly been vocal enough about the possibilities.&amp;nbsp; Is it that &quot;do gooder&quot; programming is too &quot;bleeding heart&quot;?&amp;nbsp; Maybe only Catholics will watch our shows?&amp;nbsp; &quot;If it bleeds it leads&quot;.&amp;nbsp; But then we&#39;re going to trouble spots and disasters in some shows, so if it&#39;s blood they&#39;re looking for...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d say we&#39;ve been evolving the infrastructure.&amp;nbsp; The problem of dealing with micro-amount donations, nevertheless tracked (giving credit to donors who gave -- with anonymous mode options), is still not fully solved.&amp;nbsp; More banks may need to lend their expertise.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People aren&#39;t used to viewing a screen while contributing a few cents here, a few cents there (or call &#39;em bitcoins), optionally building their own record or profile, not to prove that they&#39;re rich so much as to show off their values and ability to &quot;pick &#39;em&quot; over time.&amp;nbsp; You&#39;re leaving a record of your intelligence, but in a way that&#39;s not yet habitual given insufficient infrastructure.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s what a lot of philanthropy is a lot about (leaving a record of one&#39;s intelligence).&amp;nbsp; These Foundations have their own version of horse races.&amp;nbsp; But if you&#39;re a working stiff, you&#39;ve not had time or leisure to invest in that &quot;rich tycoon with zeal&quot; mentality.&amp;nbsp; You don&#39;t get to look out over the world thinking &quot;what shall I fund&quot;?&amp;nbsp; Junk mail isn&#39;t working so well either, lets say.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s where Coffee Shops Network comes in.&amp;nbsp; You buy your scone from Green Mountain and already get a sliver of GM&#39;s profit to toss in some bucket, like a chit or chad, say ten cents just to trivialize (in charitable casinos the amounts may be much higher).&amp;nbsp; Sipping your latte, you pop in your ten cents and flip up a game, say a Sudoku.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Given how fast and deft you are, you&#39;ve won a whole dollar before it&#39;s over, and GM empowers you to be a &quot;for the moment&quot; shareholder / stakeholder (you bought their scone didn&#39;t you?) and to commit that dollar, your heroic skill having amplified value ten fold, to some worthy cause that these game machines know how to connect with.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some favorite charity in Nepal just got another dollar.&amp;nbsp; Both you and GM have netted some good karma.&amp;nbsp; You feel accomplished.&amp;nbsp; You get a kick (energy boost) out of the experience.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s a somewhat &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2014/09/more-marketing.html&quot;&gt;simplified and idealized&lt;/a&gt; rendering of the standard CSN transaction:&amp;nbsp; profit slice towards good will shared by company and procuring customer.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Accounting for &quot;good will&quot; on the books, as a way of building company reputation, is not at all a new idea.&amp;nbsp; What&#39;s new is the micro-management of donated amounts and the cutting in of customers as momentary shareholders, almost board members (in committing micro amounts of profit).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some supermarkets do this at checkout, with coin jars for charities, but usually with no pledge to match, and with no way to give name credit to the donor.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But what if company X is ideologically opposed to funding Y or Z as &quot;bad for the company&#39;s image&quot;?&amp;nbsp; No problemo.&amp;nbsp; The range of options, the charities that might benefit, is known in advance and if the customer is truly hell bent on supporting Y or Z, just procure from a different outfit, free country.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some of our shops host games that support some controversial causes, what can I say?&amp;nbsp; You may disapprove of your children&#39;s choices.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not here to dictate who gets what.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m talking about wiring, an infrastructure, and a pleasant environment in which to help steer planetary affairs, with &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2010/04/smart-bar-lcds.html&quot;&gt;interesting reveries on the LCDs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The CSN business model helps pave the way for doing the same things at home i.e in PWSs (personal workspaces), procuring investment credits, playing games, adding value.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People in their smartvans, getting support from others, in turn give support.&amp;nbsp; Channeling funds to the right places is a game we should all be in on, starting young.&amp;nbsp; We develop that ethic of paying attention to world problems.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our cultivating a philanthropic mentality is not just for altruistic churchy &quot;get me to heaven&quot; reasons.&amp;nbsp; One simply acts more logically as a part of some solution when thinking globally.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re less awkward, less wasteful, more attractive (including to ourselves) in proportion to our ability to solve problems as an intelligent life form, both individually and collectively (as team players).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Doing good for real&quot; makes for better television in other words, and better sex (I had to say that).&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Hollywood stars learned these lessons long ago.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7897359387183173619'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7897359387183173619'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/09/reality-tv.html' title='Reality TV'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1582397899672952984</id><published>2015-09-08T19:25:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2015-09-09T15:43:51.565-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2015.9.8</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/21074360659/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Carol Addresses Wanderers&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Carol Addresses Wanderers&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5747/21074360659_d1615431d7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I got to the Pauling House early, given Carol (mom) is the presenter again.&amp;nbsp; I fumbled for keys, realizing I didn&#39;t have them, when Dick Pugh tried the door.&amp;nbsp; It was open.&amp;nbsp; Duh.&amp;nbsp; We made ourselves at home around the table.&amp;nbsp; Glenn, the official opener, arrived on time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dick was on the cell about the fire ball over Thailand last night.&amp;nbsp; Meteorite.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s on it.&amp;nbsp; Don usually opens but he&#39;s got a meeting that will delay him until start time.&amp;nbsp; Hey, here he is!&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m blogging in real time (I do that quite a bit, then polish up later).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol is talking about developments in the &lt;i&gt;Countdown to Zero&lt;/i&gt; campaign, i.e. the abolitionist movement vis-a-vis WMSs (weapons of mass suicide).&amp;nbsp; She&#39;s been working in this area, mostly with Women&#39;s International League for Peace and Freedom, for quite a number of years, certainly since 2000, when she moved back to the US from Lesotho, after the accident.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
She opened by talking about the Iran Deal, inviting discussion.&amp;nbsp; She passed around some PR, a poster, on Keeping Space for Peace.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This year the campaign is delving into Cyberspace more, which one might suggest is only metaphorically space, or virtual space, but that&#39;s taking too narrow a view.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Cyberspace is supported physically by satellites, which are used not just to carry communications, but to support GPS, which means ballistics / guidance.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol suggested that Geeks have the most insight into cyber warfare, which triggered a discussion of the difference between Geeks and Nerds.&amp;nbsp; I gave my standard &quot;a nerd is the larval form of geek&quot; spiel (short), while Glenn reminded us of the etymology of &quot;geek&quot; (carnival origins).&amp;nbsp; I think of nerds as socially awkward, more the ugly duckling phase of the more socially adept swan.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Jon sees the parallels to &lt;i&gt;Lysistrata&lt;/i&gt;, what the women are doing, in trying to drag the guys away from wartime fixations.&amp;nbsp; WILPF does include men however.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not one single nuclear weapon has been destroyed, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fukushima-is-still-news.com/2015/08/ban-ki-moon-calls-for-nuclear-free-world.html&quot;&gt;Ban Ki-Moon&lt;/a&gt;, according to Carol.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;ve been stowed, or are being cannibalized to make new / improved weapons.&amp;nbsp; Dave DiNucci came up with an actual quote.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dick Pugh insists that many physical warheads have indeed been destroyed, but the active materials stay active.&amp;nbsp; Dick thinks a lot of warhead material has been diluted in some cases, to be useful for reactors only.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our little group is not uber-informed about all this, it seems to me, but that just goes to show why we need a &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/12/from-day-to-day.html&quot;&gt;college major of Weapons Inspector&lt;/a&gt; or something similar.&amp;nbsp; Decommissioning is going to require a lot of watch dogs and engineeers.&amp;nbsp; Such dogs do not just appear without grooming.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol went over the Marshall Islands lawsuit, against all powers who are supposed to be working on disarmament, according to existing treaties.&amp;nbsp; The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hankaku-j.org/data/jalana/npt_008_en.html&quot;&gt;Okinawa Nuclear Free Zone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;How much does Japan contribute to the &lt;i&gt;Countdown to Zero&lt;/i&gt; campaign?&quot; a Wanderer asked.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I said I was looking forward to a simple ethical code wherein anyone harboring or nurturing the creation of nuke weapons was obviously a &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/05/aqua-teen-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Dr. Evil type&lt;/a&gt; psychopath Baddie worthy of some 007 or 003 type take down by a Goodie state and/or agency.&amp;nbsp; Persian Intelligence is already looking forward to fighting Dr. Evils on a world scale.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1582397899672952984'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1582397899672952984'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/09/wanderers-201598.html' title='Wanderers 2015.9.8'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3003961752767734760</id><published>2015-09-07T11:21:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2015-09-08T07:22:58.839-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Pedestrian Thinking</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
WDC could very easily charter a bunch of ships, or use its own Navy, to help alleviate the refugee situation, the result of a nation-state breakup and breakdown in zones opened to aerial bombing versus &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/07/wanderers-2015728.html&quot;&gt;some Islamic State&lt;/a&gt; (hypothetical, not a UN nation at this moment in time). &amp;nbsp;Civilians, caught in this theater, are understandably scrambling to get out of the way.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/11/city-as-campus.html&quot;&gt;WDC&lt;/a&gt; and its Media Army (WMA = Washington&#39;s Media Army) are spinning it like this is all about the EU standing up for its principles. &amp;nbsp;The EU is now a proxy for Statue of Liberty rhetoric, as so far you don&#39;t see much evidence of open arms in North America. &amp;nbsp;However, I expect this will soon change, as the hypocrisy of thinking the Atlantic Ocean is a meaningful barrier, where refugees are concerned, was exposed long ago. &amp;nbsp;In the 21st Century, you can ferry them by jet. &amp;nbsp;Lets talk troop numbers and how many ferried so far.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The perception that the US exports its refugees from the civilian economy, as people not needing visas, to military bases around the world, such as in &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/11/pacific-islanders-meet.html&quot;&gt;the Marshall Islands&lt;/a&gt;, is somewhat based in fact. The US itself is a nation of refugees, is closer to the bigger picture, including those hosting &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/09/best-of-enemies-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Fourth Reich meme viruses&lt;/a&gt; (&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/02/philosophy-101.html&quot;&gt;USA uber alles&lt;/a&gt;&quot; nut cases abound in DC, where they might be properly looked after). &amp;nbsp;In founding this Federation, there was no way to close the doors to descendants of ancient Romans with imperialist reflexes, as filtered through Normans and Anglos -- long story.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The pedestrian thinking on display is that Syrian refugees can walk to Austria because these are connected landmasses, whereas we don&#39;t need to talk about Ohio or Michigan or Oregon each taking 20K, because there&#39;s an Atlantic Ocean in between, and whatever happens in the Holy Land stays in the Holy Land. &amp;nbsp;Obviously such thinking is not in touch with reality, which is why I&#39;m expecting that bubble to pop soon.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3003961752767734760'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3003961752767734760'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/09/pedestrian-thinking.html' title='Pedestrian Thinking'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6713332344155125309</id><published>2015-09-06T11:23:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-09-22T16:44:00.138-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Visiting M3</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
M3 or &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2014/10/hash-tag-m3.html&quot;&gt;#M3 as a hashtag&lt;/a&gt; (one of many) is a less-used abbreviation for MMM.&amp;nbsp; Putting the 3 as a superscript, designating exponentiation, or atomic number, is more esoteric yet.&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Multnomah Monthly Meeting of the Religious Society of Friends&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;is a part of &lt;i&gt;Willamette Quarterly Meeting&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;which in turn is within the sphere of &lt;i&gt;North Pacific Yearly Meeting&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s as &quot;high&quot; as it gets for us. &amp;nbsp;NPYM has not yet joined any larger group, such as FGC (&lt;i&gt;Friends General Conference&lt;/i&gt;). &amp;nbsp;I&#39;d call &lt;i&gt;Pendle Hill&lt;/i&gt; a Quaker &quot;think tank&quot;. &amp;nbsp;QUNO and FWCC are more like satellites, though with the latter having a complicated structure of its own e.g. a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fwccamericas.org/&quot;&gt;Section of the Americas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, we jokingly refer to our Quaker Vatican in Philadelphia, but that&#39;s more for historical reasons than because of any currently operative administrative lines of control.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;i&gt;American Friends Service Committee&lt;/i&gt; (AFSC) is its own non-profit, intricately interwoven with the Yearly Meetings through interlocking executive roles and Corporation representatives (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/03/corporation-meeting.html&quot;&gt;my role&lt;/a&gt; in many blog posts), but is not directly &quot;bossing&quot; Quakers anywhere unless they&#39;re on staff.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s a social action arm, a corporate face for PR and wholesome programming.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At North Pacific Yearly Meeting we nominate our delegates to these various Quaker organizations, such as Yearly Meeting Appointees (YMAs) to AFSC.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s what I mean by &quot;Corporation representative&quot; in that I&#39;d represent AFSC to the world, as one of its Corporation members, but also I&#39;d represent&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/08/alphabet-soup.html&quot;&gt;NPYM to AFSC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
An example of an issue for us, during my tenure: &amp;nbsp;NPYM is less concerned with &quot;member&quot; as a title than some Yearly Meetings, and more concerned with participation.&amp;nbsp; Some of our most active participants, especially in AFSC work, are not officially members of our Religious Society, yet affiliate closely therewith.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So the AFSC&#39;s directive to send &quot;its most experienced members&quot; as Corporation members, to Philadelphia for annual meetings, was somewhat problematic in light of Yearly Meeting goals, as sometimes the most enthusiastic participant, most in need of relevant experience (and likely aware of that fact), would be an obvious nominee from our point of view, in addition to perhaps an old timer.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That was me in earlier chapters, new to AFSC Corporation meetings, though not to Philadelphia.&amp;nbsp; The old chicken:egg conundrum applies:&amp;nbsp; how to get experience when they only want those with experience already. &amp;nbsp;By now, as an old timer, I&#39;ve had enough experience that asking for more seems greedy. &amp;nbsp;We have many more up and coming. &amp;nbsp;However, there&#39;s still plenty of room to participate, without re-upping for past roles.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br class=&quot;Apple-interchange-newline&quot; /&gt;
How many delegates and who sets the number was another bone of contention. &amp;nbsp;AFSC has its own corporate bylaws, but how do these reconcile with Yearly Meetings at the&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Faith &amp;amp; Practice&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;level? That&#39;s an ongoing discussion. &amp;nbsp;During my tenure, NPYM&#39;s policy was to pick up the tab on air travel and hotel, or leave it to the delegate to make those costs an in-kind donation. &amp;nbsp;Either way, in not making our delegates an expense to AFSC, we were hoping to keep the question of &quot;how many&quot; more in our court.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then there&#39;s FCNL:&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Friends Committee on National Legislation&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; That entity is based in Washington DC and is all about communicating with legislative bodies i.e. the House and Senate.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s right, it&#39;s a lobby.&amp;nbsp; AFSC is more like a government in exile, still in Philadelphia, a city that used to be the nation&#39;s capital and remains an important hub in the Quaker State.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Where the State Department might not see a way clear to hold talks with so-and-so, AFSC might, nevertheless.&amp;nbsp; Quakers make up their own minds in some dimensions, more like Christian Scientists in that way.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The practice of Quakerism does not dictate uniformity when it comes to viewpoint and some are temperamentally more prone to work &quot;within the system&quot; (FCNL&#39;s role) whereas others are more interested in challenging the status quo with even more &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/09/quaker-curriculum.html&quot;&gt;efficient systems&lt;/a&gt;, doing more with less (the term &quot;dymaxion&quot; might apply).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets name the canonical representatives of these extremes of temperament. &amp;nbsp;How about &quot;the law-abiding good doobies&quot; versus &quot;the rebels&quot;? &amp;nbsp;Or maybe &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/05/cry-baby-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&quot;squares&quot; versus &quot;drapes&quot;&lt;/a&gt; (is slang OK)?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Quakerism caters to the full spectrum, from boat rocker to quietist, as do most religious lineages of longstanding. &amp;nbsp;They started out as rebels, subversives in the 1600s, but within a century had come out on top as law-abiding lawmakers, or at least bankers and builders, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2014/10/a-quaker-arc.html&quot;&gt;pivotal in England&#39;s industrialization&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Quakerism has been nurtured both by revolutionaries and pillars of the status quo, begetting new synergies in self-organization.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
AFSC was established by a Quaker mystic and college professor, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2014/01/rufus-jones-luminious-life-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Rufus Jones&lt;/a&gt;, among others, and is about doing the work George Fox called &quot;removing the occasion for wars&quot; i.e. once those selling the prospect of war have captured the imagination, it&#39;s almost too late. &amp;nbsp;One needs to stay ahead of the curve.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Quakerism is anticipatory in seeing any attempt to oppress or starve (conquer) a people will lead to blow back and perhaps unforeseen consequences.&amp;nbsp; The opposite of freedom is feeling conquered and under the boot of some cast of authority figures. &amp;nbsp;Aren&#39;t there better ways to spread knowledge of the tools for good living (tractors and so on)?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Working &quot;with the grain&quot; of the human animal, for its well being, is the way to go if at all possible, as the long haul religions will often attest, corporations too.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Food not Bombs&quot; is the basic message.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So when many Anglos were hell bent on starving the German people, AFSC did its best to &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2014/04/wanderers-201448-ww1.html&quot;&gt;end that blockade&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Getting medical supplies to the people of Vietnam suffering aerial bombardment and other atrocities, was a priority in a later chapter.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Friends have filled the ground floor social hall since I started writing this, many of whom I don&#39;t recognize, others of whom I do of course.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s Leslie Hickcox, Multnomah Meeting&#39;s FCNL representative.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re meeting at &lt;i&gt;Horse Brass&lt;/i&gt; later today, across the street from the local AFSC office.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve been coming to this meetinghouse, off and on since the 1960s, before our family moved to Rome.&amp;nbsp; I also sometimes attend &lt;i&gt;Bridge City Friends Meeting&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;(also NPYM), or roam around, not wanting to get too &quot;stuck in a rut&quot; as my dad would say.&amp;nbsp; West Hills Friends Church?&amp;nbsp; Why not? Reedwood? &amp;nbsp;Sure thing. &amp;nbsp;And that&#39;s still just within Oregon in under thirty minutes by car, plus I skipped mentioning some worship groups and at least one more Quaker church.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In terms of role playing, I&#39;m on the NPYM IT Committee these days, as one of its clerks, the one into Technology.&amp;nbsp; They call me the Technology Clerk. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Until recently one could say with confidence that NPYM was made up of Meetings, Preparative Meetings and Worship Groups, not Churches, Temples, Synagogues or &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2014/08/pilgrimmage.html&quot;&gt;Mosques&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;The latter two seem pretty well branded, as Jewish and Islamic respectively, but then who&#39;s to say Quakerism can&#39;t spring up within other religions besides &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/x6V4vS&quot;&gt;Buddhism&lt;/a&gt; and Christianity? &amp;nbsp;We might &lt;a href=&quot;http://dogs.thefuntimesguide.com/2010/11/hybrid_dog.php&quot;&gt;co-design such sects&lt;/a&gt;, not just wait for them to happen. &amp;nbsp;Hybrids beget exciting new breeds sometimes (i.e. lineages).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You&#39;ll see me wearing that Technology Clerk hat in some of these blog posts as well.&amp;nbsp; My term as NPYM YMA to AFSC ended October of last year (2014). I&#39;ve been doing Quaker IT for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quakerquaker.org/profile/KirbyUrner&quot;&gt;almost a year now&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, it&#39;s a rotating position. &amp;nbsp;Our brand of Quakers likes to keep &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/07/npym-annual-session-2013.html&quot;&gt;mixing it up&lt;/a&gt;, a way to fight off the rigor mortis that may attack the more frozenly hierarchical religions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/21209305201/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Across from AFSC&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Across from AFSC&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/638/21209305201_f9438bc1d8_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6713332344155125309'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6713332344155125309'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/09/visiting-m3.html' title='Visiting M3'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3726082512064676974</id><published>2015-09-02T20:02:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2015-09-08T07:52:33.809-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Done Deal</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
OK, so done deal already, the news media are saying the same.&amp;nbsp; Given the vote in the Senate is to say nay to this not-a-treaty, the President may gainsay with a veto, with thirty-four needed to sustain that veto.&amp;nbsp; The Iran Deal goes through, checkmate.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
NPR spelled that out in some detail in the last couple days, and by this morning a thirty-fourth supporter had been announced.&amp;nbsp; That meant Game Over in some dimension, but then politicians know how to keep a ball rolling.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We may shift our sense of suspense to some newer arena and stop &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/pretending-to-care.html&quot;&gt;pretending to care&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Also encouraging:&amp;nbsp; the words &quot;air strike&quot; were used with regard to a Syrian family, one of millions, fleeing a veritable Katrina of air strikes over Syria.&amp;nbsp; Their home was leveled, no doubt &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2015/jul/02/the-guardian-view-on-bombing-isis-in-syria-just-say-no&quot;&gt;collateral damage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Who has &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/09/pedestrian-thinking.html&quot;&gt;so much ordnance&lt;/a&gt; again?&amp;nbsp; Was that some Islamic State dropping bombs?&amp;nbsp; Pretty terrifying, those hits, with collateral damage lowering land values and quality of life for everyone on the receiving end.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Will the computers have each crater by serial number, to help with reparations?&amp;nbsp; No.&amp;nbsp; Remember the ordnance drop over Laos.&amp;nbsp; Napalm and all that.&amp;nbsp; Check the recent &lt;i&gt;National Geographic&lt;/i&gt; issue about those craters.&amp;nbsp; The perps tend to stay anonymous, or try to, just &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/08/city-of-morons.html&quot;&gt;following orders&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[ Note:&amp;nbsp; the news reports are not saying that product, Napalm, was used in Syria, just that aerial strikes tend to come from those controlling the air.&amp;nbsp; That would be physical airspace.&amp;nbsp; Controlling the media is another matter and requires &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/10/busy-day.html&quot;&gt;spin and finesse&lt;/a&gt;. ]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cbsnews.com/news/syrian-refugees-stuck-in-limbo-at-budapest-train-station/&quot;&gt;subways of Budapest&lt;/a&gt; are the new stadium in an unfolding New Orleans scale disaster, though more spread out.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Congrats to CBS on 53 years of half hour news broadcasting.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Humanitarian aid is not something governments are necessarily any good at.&amp;nbsp; NGOs will need to step in here shortly.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Chinese Peace Corps&quot; and all that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Don&#39;t expect espresso-sipping cube farmers, corporate peasants, to come to the rescue of the latest &quot;hurricane&quot; victims.&amp;nbsp; Remember the Coalition has been waging a holy war in the region.&amp;nbsp; Old ethnic tensions flare up when push comes to shove.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Many Asians had a hard time adjusting to North America in the aftermath of the war in Indochina.&amp;nbsp; My NGO (the one I worked for), Center for Urban Education, had government contracts to work in refugee resettlement in the 1980s, which is when I moved back to Portland from the Atlantic coast (by way of Bangladesh) where I&#39;d gone for higher education at Princeton.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/06/summer-solstice-2015.html&quot;&gt;Refugee resettlement&lt;/a&gt; is a source of social work with many ripple effects through small business and banking, as families do their best to recreate some semblance of what they have lost.&amp;nbsp; The Empire State, for example, has seen a lot of this kind of activity over the years.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Humans are on the move, suffering denial of service attacks where they live.&amp;nbsp; Nation-states act as prison guards.&amp;nbsp; The prison-state system is about denying humans their birthright:&amp;nbsp; access to a whole planet.&amp;nbsp; Refugees the world over are those falling through the cracks as &quot;undocumented&quot;, as if it&#39;s their fault no one cares enough to create some documents for them.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3726082512064676974'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3726082512064676974'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/09/done-deal.html' title='Done Deal'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5759183407381136479</id><published>2015-09-01T09:09:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-09-02T15:04:21.974-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Ugly Philosophy</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
In the &lt;i&gt;Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus&lt;/i&gt; (TLP) &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/nuVdoZ&quot;&gt;Ludwig Wittgenstein&lt;/a&gt; draws a strong link between aesthetics and ethics.&amp;nbsp; You&#39;ll find a similar association among engineers, with Ludwig on the edge of being one of those, perhaps in a software engineering sense.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Build something completely apropos for its task and beautiful it will be, because functionality screams purpose and meaning.&amp;nbsp; But then the purpose itself might be ugly, such as an instrument of torture, or a guillotine say -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/09/caltrops.html&quot;&gt;very functional&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/02/ayatollah-of-tetrahedron.html&quot;&gt;Applewhite&lt;/a&gt; used to talk about science journalists getting away &quot;with impunity&quot; with their uglifications of philosophy, such as in that book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wiley.com/WileyCDA/WileyTitle/productCd-047119333X.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;A Most Beautiful Molecule&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, about &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/08/commercial-product.html&quot;&gt;BuckyBalls&lt;/a&gt;, by an author mostly ignorant of &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; (Bucky&#39;s magnum opus).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A similar ugliness pervades the art world, wherein &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/09/focal-points.html&quot;&gt;the Concentric Hierarchy&lt;/a&gt; is scarcely mentioned, despite its being a set of paradigm relationships, a grammar for spatial thinking.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Imagine a computer science curriculum that only taught FORTRAN and never LISP.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dividedspheres.com/&quot;&gt;Popko&#39;s &lt;i&gt;Divided Spheres&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; helps compensate for what&#39;s missing in many a curriculum.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What we&#39;re seeing in this chapter is less a weakness in STEM than in STEAM, where the A adds Anthropology, more encompassing than Art.&amp;nbsp; Anthropology embraces psychology, the study of the human mind.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Advertisers have learned to play on insecurities and adapted their technology to politics, with PR firms now running campaigns and managing inter-governmental relations.&amp;nbsp; But has Anthropology been taken seriously in other dimensions?&amp;nbsp; Yes and no.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The notion that Anthropology is always about studying &quot;those other people&quot; reeks of ugly philosophy, yet is a somewhat omnipresent attitude.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Solution:&amp;nbsp; art schools have historically helped to provide an avant-garde, but mainly as networking tools among the truly creative.&amp;nbsp; Here in Portland, I&#39;ve had ample &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/08/sa-pedagogy.html&quot;&gt;access to classrooms&lt;/a&gt; when it comes to sharing with people under twenty (yes, I&#39;m fingerprinted and everything), reserving my andragogy (teaching of adults) to more on-line settings.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That mix may be about to change, as I access more workspaces (&quot;maker spaces&quot;) and classrooms designed for adult topics and geared for adult DIY learning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Given &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/04/bumper-sticker.html&quot;&gt;my karma&lt;/a&gt; (dharma), I&#39;m already a resource for the Greater Portland area, as are my partners in &quot;integral design&quot; (Glenn&#39;s term for it).&amp;nbsp; A lot of it&#39;s just storytelling, with history as a backdrop, technical content mixed in.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But then storytelling is an art, about leaving stuff out as irrelevant, as much as tuning stuff in as of vital importance.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In proving a successful role model for how to up the level of play in one city, with help from my friends and their group affiliations, I pioneer a path for others to not clone exactly, but at least learn from.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20058662559/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Hat in the Ring&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Hat in the Ring&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3708/20058662559_4d1d7773c9_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: hat in the ring ::
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5759183407381136479'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5759183407381136479'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/09/ugly-philosophy.html' title='Ugly Philosophy'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1913963498644464259</id><published>2015-08-30T08:52:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2015-09-01T08:04:17.870-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Pretending to Care</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Some elements in the business community argue that the &quot;sane politicians&quot; have already shown they still have enough of the old chutzpah to negotiate a multi-way deal &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/iranian-festival.html&quot;&gt;with Iran&lt;/a&gt;, which the US legislative branch is now supposed to ratify, with a counterpart ratifier embedded in the Iranian apparatus. &amp;nbsp;The &quot;insane politicians&quot; whom President Obama &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/story/2015/08/obama-calls-opponents-of-iran-deal-the-crazies-121701&quot;&gt;characterizes as &quot;crazies&quot;&lt;/a&gt; have their inevitable &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fear,_uncertainty_and_doubt&quot;&gt;FUD campaign&lt;/a&gt;, which goes to the masses who become stressed and concerned and maybe die early as a result.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The question is how much to care about legislative branches and their crazies, now that engineering has taken the wheel in terms of working out the business logic of world trade. &amp;nbsp;Legalese is too slow in the Software Age. &amp;nbsp;Do we care what they think? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On paper, yes, but in practice many board rooms have already positioned to open new channels with Iran, especially in the entertainment industry. &amp;nbsp;Nuclear medicine will never be huge. The construction costs for the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/08/pycon-tehran.html&quot;&gt;freeway network&lt;/a&gt;, from Kabul to Istanbul, translates to good jobs for Iranian construction companies. &amp;nbsp;What about &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/04/speculations.html&quot;&gt;the new SeaWorld&lt;/a&gt;, will that happen soon?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Washington DC has this persona of a &quot;superpower&quot; that it wants to project, wherein everyone waits to see what Big Brother decides. &amp;nbsp;The decision has to be consequential, by definition, and the crazies seem committed to plunging the world into war, just to prove how their side would be victorious in any battle with WMDs. &amp;nbsp;That&#39;s what being a superpower &lt;i&gt;means&lt;/i&gt; -- to them. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So when it looked like the deal would go through in Vienna, we were immediately put on notice that we could look forward to not just one, but &lt;i&gt;two&lt;/i&gt; months of lame whining by the crazies. &amp;nbsp;They have delivered on that promise.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The truth behind the facade, I would suggest, is that no one really cares what the crazies think, really about anything (almost by definition). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, they have the right to make noise and &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/03/occupy-silicon-valley.html&quot;&gt;Occupy Congress&lt;/a&gt;, as they&#39;ve been doing for some time now. &amp;nbsp;The police let them stay there and pose for the cameras, but big business cannot afford to care that much what the Kindergarten Krazies (cute name) want or don&#39;t want regarding the Iran Deal. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So if you&#39;re in business, a best strategy is to &quot;pretend to care&quot; if you want continued contracts from the Beltway Bandits (rebranded as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/?gws_rd=ssl#safe=off&amp;amp;q=%22Beltway+Goons%22&quot;&gt;Beltway Goons&lt;/a&gt; by some), but then get on board with the rest and help with the rewiring. &amp;nbsp;Waiting two months is waiting too long. &amp;nbsp;The sane politicians have demonstrated their sanity and that&#39;s about as much as we have a right to expect from that corner. &amp;nbsp;The crazies will bring up the rear, as usual, but lets not confuse the parade with the elephant poop.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1913963498644464259'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1913963498644464259'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/pretending-to-care.html' title='Pretending to Care'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6875777807830068816</id><published>2015-08-28T18:43:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-08-31T19:06:11.438-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Revisiting Landmark</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20777325778/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Newly Purchased Cigar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Newly Purchased Cigar&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/577/20777325778_4a824bc94b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I went a step deeper with my re-engaging with &lt;i&gt;est&lt;/i&gt; as we called it, creating a corporate subculture around &quot;what is&quot; somehow.&amp;nbsp; That subculture had momentum and is &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/at-landmark-event.html&quot;&gt;branded as &lt;i&gt;Landmark&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; today, with &lt;a href=&quot;http://landmarkworldwide.com/&quot;&gt;landmarkworldwide.com&lt;/a&gt; for a website.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
During my conversation with Adam before our event, we talked about &lt;i&gt;Landmark Forum&lt;/i&gt; being offered for free in Detroit for a period.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll dig into that a little.&amp;nbsp; I mentioned &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/08/visiting-downtown-detroit.html&quot;&gt;being in Detroit&lt;/a&gt; not so long ago, and got into my rap about skyscrapers having a natural lifespan.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyone building a skyscraper today needs to consider its life cycle and plan ahead for its eventual demise.&amp;nbsp; Those who simply &quot;build for the ages&quot; and leave it entirely &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/03/insurgent-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;to future generations&lt;/a&gt; the problem of retiring and recycling the monster, are not conceptualizing their responsibility as architects.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The office is just off Barbur and in miss-dialing the address, let maps.google.com take me to the parking lot of St. Clair, where my friend Matt went to elementary school.&amp;nbsp; This had been my neighborhood.&amp;nbsp; Even with heavy traffic, and that misinformation, I managed to reach the venue on time, which had been a core concern.&amp;nbsp; As it was, I beat the party from Eugene by about 15 minutes, but then Eugene has no Landmark office.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was treated like an equal by these democratic and egalitarian Americans, though it helped I was an &lt;i&gt;est&lt;/i&gt; vet, which means I was already somewhat on the same wavelength, at least in their minds.&amp;nbsp; Sara gave me a tour of the suite.&amp;nbsp; The 3 PM event she came for was cancelled so we filled the time rehearsing an Introduction to the Landmark Forum session, Sara leading it, with the room captain insisting Sara repeat a few segments, taking advantage of our time to practice together.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I had my exercise routine in the not working section of the workbook, then created for myself the possibility of already being quite wealthy, in terms of access to copious learning materials with which to stock &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/04/olpc-oppa.html&quot;&gt;my &lt;i&gt;Coolpad&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; before hitting the gym.&amp;nbsp; In no way should &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/08/hsf-2015.html&quot;&gt;the Elliptical&lt;/a&gt; be a doldrums or boring in any way.&amp;nbsp; I realized my being wealthy could be a satisfying solution to several not-working areas before the evening was done, so yes, I got some value, just how much remains to be seen&lt;i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Although I stayed through Part 2 (after the mock break), I had already chatted with Nathan and the others about maybe reviewing the Forum in Japan or some other faraway place.&amp;nbsp; The anthropologist in me wants to study inter-cultural events more.&amp;nbsp; Like are there Forums not in English, with English only in translation?&amp;nbsp; I see that there are.&amp;nbsp; Given &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2014/07/i18n.html&quot;&gt;my focus on i18n&lt;/a&gt;, such questions come up for me a lot.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Upon leaving the Landmark office, I went straight to &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://portlandhamburgers.blogspot.com/2007/09/humdinger.html&quot;&gt;Humdinger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, a milkshake place from my youth.&amp;nbsp; He had butterscotch this time!&amp;nbsp; Also, since I&#39;d parked in the lot of an adjacent store, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://tobaccotown.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tobacco Town&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I felt duty bound, plus curious, to check it out and ended up with the above depicted cigar.&amp;nbsp; The cigar meme goes with the wealth meme, as a part of the stereotype / memeplex. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20925759002/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Kirby in Middle School&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Kirby in Middle School&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/570/20925759002_8a73b83bb4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6875777807830068816'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6875777807830068816'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/revisiting-landmark.html' title='Revisiting Landmark'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8951546936689284151</id><published>2015-08-27T15:42:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-09-02T16:54:59.813-07:00</updated><title type='text'>PPUG 2015.8.27</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;375&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;flashvars&quot; value=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157655578412223%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157655578412223%2F&amp;set_id=72157655578412223&amp;jump_to=&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=237555616&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;embed type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; src=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=237555616&quot; allowFullScreen=&quot;true&quot; flashvars=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157655578412223%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157655578412223%2F&amp;set_id=72157655578412223&amp;jump_to=&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Almost September of 2015.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve not attended a Portland Python User&#39;s Group in awhile.&amp;nbsp; True, I show up on Meetup as a co-organizer, and I am on that listserv, but others have been far more active than I, who am more just a figurehead presence.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I do have a lot of memories, of where we&#39;ve met, where Urban Airship used to be.&amp;nbsp; The Fox Tower chapter, &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/03/serving-buzz.html&quot;&gt;Cubespace&lt;/a&gt;...&amp;nbsp; Portland has been friendly to Python for a long time.&amp;nbsp; We used to be &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.onlamp.com/pub/a/python/2001/11/15/pythonnews.html&quot;&gt;Poor Piggies&lt;/a&gt;&quot; as in &quot;Portland Python Interest Group&quot; but then rebranded to &quot;P-PUG&quot; which is more dog-like.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If a sponsor buys us pizza, they get to make a pitch or something like that.&amp;nbsp; We give companies a way to show their support in a public manner and to recruit and/or offer services at the same time, right when people are feeling good about how you&#39;re feeding the Python ecosystem.&amp;nbsp; Thanks to Rentrak in this case.&amp;nbsp; Great &lt;i&gt;Hot Lips&lt;/i&gt; pizza, hard to beat.&amp;nbsp; I stopped at two slices [sic], knowing my proclivity to eat an infinite amount, especially when it&#39;s gratis.&amp;nbsp; I hoard calories, as if that made any sense.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of hoarding, I was enjoying my faster fiber optic connection today, downloading a large number of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/oscon-followup.html&quot;&gt;OSCON 2015 videos&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Once on OB (OpenBastion) I can archive the media to one of the USB drives I have floating around.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Of course coming here on a Thursday means I&#39;m missing Thirsters.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s a conversation I&#39;ve been enjoying but I need to offset political chatter with software engineering, as a matter of diet.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Paul is here with me, a co-worker.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ll probably grab a couple brews after.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re not serving any alcohol at the meetup, which is fine with me.&amp;nbsp; Those enjoying such beverages have plenty of options after it&#39;s over.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Walking here from Stark and SW Sixth, about a half a mile, was a joy, as it took me through interesting intersections.&amp;nbsp; I found myself snapping those pictures.&amp;nbsp; At Pioneer Courthouse Square:&amp;nbsp; an Italian Cultural Festival.&amp;nbsp; Wow, to take over the downtown square:&amp;nbsp; that proves Italy has mega-clout in our CBD.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Hey, Patrick just showed up.&amp;nbsp; Party!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Rentrak is shifting from Perl to other dynamic languages.&amp;nbsp; They aggregate data from TV remotes through cable companies, giving more insights than the old way of doing it.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re looking for engineers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Robert Dordier has been working on a computer algebra system named Maxima for Jupyter, the language-independent part of I-Python.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s browser-embedded.&amp;nbsp; Maxima was started in 1968 as a LISP project.&amp;nbsp; The standard UI is ASCII-art console.&amp;nbsp; How might Jupyter make this better?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
ZeroMQ provides the sockets from front and back ends in Dordier&#39;s solution.&amp;nbsp; The I-Python Kernel on the server talks to several front ends at once.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re talking about a REPL based on LaTeX and SVG for output.&amp;nbsp; Pretty typeset math.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Main takeaway:&amp;nbsp; Jupyter may be customized.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Amy Boyle presented a talk entitled &lt;i&gt;Data Transformation Super Powers with Digital Signal Processing&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; OSCON wanted the &quot;super powers&quot; to fit with this year&#39;s theme, where she originally gave this talk.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
She took us through what it looks like to use NumPy to do Fast Fourier Analysis on audio through time, and then how to doctor images with PIL.&amp;nbsp; The Mathematica demos cover a lot of this same territory.&amp;nbsp; Both of these talks echo patterns in the Mathematica ecosystem.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As a grand finale she dove into JPEG, an algorithm not a format, created by the Joint Photographic Experts Group. I didn&#39;t know RGB was converted to YCbCr.&amp;nbsp; Amy&#39;s &#39;splainings were enlightening.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I think we&#39;ll jump into Paul&#39;s rig and hit &lt;i&gt;Lucky Lab&lt;/i&gt; on Hawthorne.&amp;nbsp; Perl Mongers meet there.&amp;nbsp; Paul, like Rentrak, is rooted in Perl, newer to Python.&amp;nbsp; These two subcultures like to cross-fertilize.&amp;nbsp; I often joke the Republic of Perl is so close to Pythonia that you can see &quot;Guido&#39;s house&quot; in the background (a windmill; he&#39;s Dutch; get it?).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20753636219/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;perl_mug&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;perl_mug&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/700/20753636219_0b4a6ea23c_o.jpg&quot; width=&quot;252&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8951546936689284151'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8951546936689284151'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/ppug-2015827.html' title='PPUG 2015.8.27'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7661335360112179106</id><published>2015-08-25T20:09:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-18T11:46:03.700-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2015.8.25</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20699615578/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Improving, still slow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Improving, still slow&quot; height=&quot;307&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/573/20699615578_16a55f2f10.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: still slow but getting faster ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I got here late. Ecology talk.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How does all that decaying salmon nitrogen feed the forest floor?&amp;nbsp; Mycelium, mushrooms, provide nutrition-moving infrastructure, like capillaries.&amp;nbsp; The Pacific Northwest forests owe a lot to dead salmon, or lets just say the salmon cycle in general.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The salmon used to pile up high in the spawning grounds, given how many got through.&amp;nbsp; That was before all the logging and dams.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;CenturyLink&lt;/i&gt; sent an engineer to affix a fiber box to my house and run a wire into the basement, up into the Buddha Room.&amp;nbsp; I had to move Lindsey&#39;s altar.&amp;nbsp; Then I dug into the garage to fish out an old fairly tiny desk for the Mac workstation, an &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/02/open-secrets.html&quot;&gt;Open Bastion asset&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
With a direct Ethernet cable, I&#39;m seeing around 450 MBps to an OS X workstation, which is awesome.&amp;nbsp; My Wifi is still 802.11n (not 802.11ac) and I&#39;m apparently not exploiting the 5 Ghz bands this mid-2011 Mac Air supposedly capable of using, netting up to 300 MBps.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;i&gt;CenturyLink&lt;/i&gt; modem comes with WiFi but not at rated to such high speeds.&amp;nbsp; Having a large number of devices, as in a classroom, would be the model.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m still well under 100 MBps both up and down over Wifi, still way faster than with DSL.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This talk reminds me of Jim Buxton&#39;s talk on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/12/nehalem-watershed-wanderers-meeting.html&quot;&gt;Nehalem River watershed&lt;/a&gt;, some years back.&amp;nbsp; That talk was all about salmon too.&amp;nbsp; N8v casinos have been paying for culvert upgrades that will help with the salmon cycle.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m no expert.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
With an accessory purchased at Apple Store today, the Thunderbolt plug (also used for external monitor) becomes an Ethernet port.&amp;nbsp; I expect higher bursts to / from the Mac Air by that means as well.&amp;nbsp; This is a trial, a free month demo, a way for &lt;i&gt;CenturyLink&lt;/i&gt; to get the box to the customer before fixing a final rate.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My thought is to drop to a slower but still fiber optic speed, keeping the modem in service, with the ability to crank back up again should devices warrant it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/12/countdown-to-zero-game.html&quot;&gt;The &lt;i&gt;Countdown to Zero&lt;/i&gt; campaign&lt;/a&gt; (as I call it) is in high gear these days.&amp;nbsp; Citizen diplomats are concerned that legislators in DC no longer have our best interests at heart (did they ever?).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The UN nations do not want to subject themselves to the continued oppression of a few Dr. Strangelove disciples who cling to their balance of terror dynamics and puppet their politicians accordingly.&amp;nbsp; Of course harboring nuke weapons with an intent to use them is a serious crime against humanity, who doesn&#39;t see that?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Apparently the hypocrisy of having nuke WMDs for oneself, while dictating that all others should kneel in obedience, is just common sense to those intending to engage in nuclear blackmail.&amp;nbsp; Those who would use nukes to threaten others cannot be considered other than terrorists.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yet you&#39;ll hear such threats as a subtext in many a speech and / or off-the-cuff remark.&amp;nbsp; People have their ways of divulging their own psychopathologies, resulting in demotion more often than promotion (statistics work in our favor).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our networking around the playground bullies proceeds at a furious apace.&amp;nbsp; We outnumber them and have agility on our side.&amp;nbsp; The nuke-heads tend to think more slowly, given they&#39;re weighed down by cognitive dissonance and psychological repression, not to mention a lack of self reflection. Getting an edge in the business world is not that difficult, when the competition is so lacking in integrity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Obviously my train of thought has strayed from the coal trains now under discussion.&amp;nbsp; I should do some shopping maybe?&amp;nbsp; Here&#39;s a call coming in, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/10/starbucks-asylum-district.html&quot;&gt;Deke the Geek&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20704120789/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;faster_net&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;faster_net&quot; height=&quot;355&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/719/20704120789_4eb67fe04c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: speeding up ::
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7661335360112179106'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7661335360112179106'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/wanderers-2015825.html' title='Wanderers 2015.8.25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5631532548315313530</id><published>2015-08-22T20:04:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2017-11-19T23:38:14.588-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Climate Change</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20809371891/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;very_unhealthy&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;very_unhealthy&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/633/20809371891_ca62dcf068.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
When climate change started to be an issue I&#39;d read about, the theory I first encountered was called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_D._Hamaker&quot;&gt;Hamaker-Weaver Hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Critics say their theory was just to justify selling rock dust as fertilizer, and the outcome predicted, a next ice age, seems off the mark when the talk on everyone&#39;s lips is greenhouse gases, CO2 and methane in particular and how these are contributing to warming, not cooling.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The ozone hole was a different issue, though also gas-related.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, lets remember that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/An_Inconvenient_Truth&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;An Inconvenient Truth&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; did not skirt the Ice Age question, and in fact Al Gore&#39;s chart showed us plunging into one, after we peak.&amp;nbsp; The roller coaster will be higher than ever, is what I recall.&amp;nbsp; Am I wrong?&amp;nbsp; Am I misreading?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Coincidentally, our city of Portland is awash in particulate carbon today, as fires burn in the east and smoke gets carried along the Columbia Gorge like up a chimney.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re all chimney sweeps today, and the high albedo or fog or whatever it is, reminds me of the nuclear winter projected should we choose to turn &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/08/disarm-day-2015.html&quot;&gt;our own cities&lt;/a&gt; to fine powder, using Weapons of Mass Suicide (WMSs).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When the blanket of powder descends, one gets colder not hotter, as more of the sunlight bounces back into space, unable to penetrate.&amp;nbsp; Once the glaciers advance, the sheets of ice do their own reflecting, starting a self-reinforcing cycle.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That was Hamaker-Weaver in a nutshell:&amp;nbsp; a lot of carbon would belch into the atmosphere, thanks to wild fires and pretty soon that would contribute to falling temperatures and the glaciers would advance, grinding rock to fine powder and in some sense plowing the Earth, performing a kind of top soil restoration in geological time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The wild fires would in turn be a result of depleted soil, a natural cycle which humans, also natural, were maybe making more exaggerated than ever?&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ve had lots of Ice Ages.&amp;nbsp; Antarctica may have been an important continent for human civilization according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.messagetoeagle.com/lostcivantarctica.php#.Vdk7Ys6Ky2w&quot;&gt;a new Atlantis Hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;, one coupled with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.skrause.org/writing/papers/hapgood_and_ecd.shtml&quot;&gt;Hapgood Hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;, that the lithosphere slid quickly at one point:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
Hapgood claimed that towards the end of the last ice age, around 12,000 
years ago, the extensive mass of glacial ice covering the northern 
continents caused the lithosphere to slip over the asthenosphere, 
moving Antarctica, during a period of at most several centuries, from a 
position in the middle latitudes to its current location, and at the 
same time rotating the other continents.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I forget if the sun cycles played a role or any different axis tilt or magnetic flip or any of that, in Hamaker&#39;s thesis.&amp;nbsp; I don&#39;t think so.&amp;nbsp; Albedo was important.&amp;nbsp; From &lt;i&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/i&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&quot;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; has its primary importance as the initiator of 
glaciation. Once an extensive ice field is established, its cooling 
effect maintains the temperature differential which keeps glaciation 
going. Variations in the amount of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; simply cause 
variations in the world albedo, but they do not stop or start 
glaciation. The world is committed to glaciation when the ice fields 
alone reflect enough sunlight to ensure cooling.&quot;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/05/twenty-one-guns.html&quot;&gt;Nick Consoletti&lt;/a&gt; got me into climate change literature through that door.&amp;nbsp; Nowadays we say &quot;terraforming&quot; sometimes, a way of acknowledging that humanity has already transformed &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/10/biosphere-is-better.html&quot;&gt;the biosphere&lt;/a&gt;, not applying a judgement right away, just showcasing the obvious, like in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/07/movie-sunday.html&quot;&gt;Qatsi movies&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Whether the global temperature goes up or down, humans are responsible, but then so is life in general, for the current gas mix.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s called the Gaia Hypothesis and is not that controversial.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Life has a lot at stake, for the sake of argument, and homeostasis should be its business, as adaptation can be expensive and unpredictable.&amp;nbsp; That sounds like a conservative arguing for the status quo, but it&#39;s more just Newtonian mechanics:&amp;nbsp; it takes external forces to disturb an equilibrium and a tendency of life is to regulate and resist haphazard change, as a form of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/08/core-stem-topic-cardio.html&quot;&gt;self-preservation&lt;/a&gt;, and yes, I&#39;m verging on tautologies here.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Let me hasten to append that in reviving Hamaker-Weaver as a blog post topic and mentioning a hypothetical Ice Age to come, I am not thereby denying climate change nor global warming theories.&amp;nbsp; Even under the Hamaker-Weaver Hypothesis this would still be the &quot;going-up side&quot; of the roller coaster, with the descent into Colder Times coming after &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/10/oil-water-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;we peak&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5631532548315313530'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5631532548315313530'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/climate-change.html' title='Climate Change'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3540016113339895889</id><published>2015-08-20T11:25:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-08-30T11:56:12.624-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Fantastic Four (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I will advance the rather plain thesis that this portal to another dimension the kids are experimenting with is code for the drug experience, i.e. in reading this Marvel text, a youngster is enabled to mediate on the problems and issues around psychotropic use and abuse.&amp;nbsp; What else could the portal be and why would it hold such interest to everyday teenagers if it didn&#39;t relate to everyday possibilities?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The questions are several:&amp;nbsp; is there anything over there in that other dimension that I might bring back that could be useful to my world?; might I bring back something damaging?; might I not come back at all?&amp;nbsp; On top of mere substance, the metals involved, one might be transformed or transmuted oneself, psychologically, and of course this possibility is where the film spends most of its time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Here I&#39;d make the &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/05/mad-max-fury-road-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;connection to &lt;i&gt;Mad Max&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the psychological landscape it provides, a denuded Earth laid waste, presumably by humans&#39; doing.&amp;nbsp; The other world in &lt;i&gt;Fantastic Four&lt;/i&gt; is not presumed to be Earth, nor its features attributable to humans.&amp;nbsp; Rather it&#39;s a crucible in which one has near death or rebirth experiences as a result of which one&#39;s persona is affected, perhaps with new and different powers manifested.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The comics, or manga tradition, has long embraced the archetypal story line of humans undergoing some stressful test only to emerge with at least quasi superpowers, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/08/the-dark-knight-rises-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Batman&lt;/a&gt; a prime example, but with so many other examples.&amp;nbsp; Just as likely, a villain is born of such a test, or a worthy ally.&amp;nbsp; The cast of characters, and therefore plot possibilities, multiplies as a function of unpredictability that stress and risk occasion.&amp;nbsp; Growing up is stressful and doesn&#39;t stop with the attainment of adulthood.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Back to the details:&amp;nbsp; we need role models and examples of what to do and how to be, in the face of this portal.&amp;nbsp; One guy is just too into it and is more jealous and proud in ordinary meat space (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/08/meat-therapy.html&quot;&gt;meetup space&lt;/a&gt;) as well.&amp;nbsp; These character flaws turn out to matter and this older character has the most trouble keeping his superpowers under control.&amp;nbsp; We find a similar arc in &lt;i&gt;Buffy&lt;/i&gt;, wherein the bewitching Willow goes over the line and comes back more a demon.&amp;nbsp; Something along those lines.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We should remember that &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/08/monster-university-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;monster&lt;/a&gt;&quot; &quot;mentor&quot; and &quot;Minotaur&quot; have important overlapping connotations, connecting likewise to &quot;masks&quot;.&amp;nbsp; In a Biblical setting, the vision-seeker comes back from the desert singing a more prophetic tune.&amp;nbsp; We need not interpolate any drug taking rituals, and in a different interpretation of &lt;i&gt;Fantastic Four&lt;/i&gt; we might take The Portal to be simply the experience of reading (maybe the Torah, maybe something else), learning to read being, at one time, more revolutionary than taking any little red pill (both &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thefreedictionary.com/phylogenically&quot;&gt;phylogenically&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thefreedictionary.com/ontogenically&quot;&gt;ontogenically&lt;/a&gt; speaking).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In light of the above interpretation, though, the one I&#39;ve adopted, what are the lessons learned?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Maybe the main one is some changes are permanent, last a life time or longer, one could say &quot;leave scars&quot; if wanting to scare more.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s no going back and undoing.&amp;nbsp; Again, true in many dimensions besides this one, so a useful teaching.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Just growing older means saying good bye to a succession of former selves and close neighbors.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The film has to work pretty hard to spread responsibility for the whole portal thing in the first place, if our heroes are to end up with moral high ground status.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One could say the whole experiment was an unmitigated disaster, does nothing but damage, a new hellmouth having been opened (thanks a lot guys) and now its just more good money after bad, trying to repair the damage (but also more family wage jobs, which I suppose is a silver lining).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The military plays the role of grounding this ultimate irresponsibility just as it does in the real world i.e. the BP disaster in the Gulf, or the seepage at Hanford, has everything to do with the military&#39;s being ravenous for what oil rigs and uranium mines come up with.&amp;nbsp; Destroying the planet to save it, is the name of the game.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My movie review here is likely colored with my summer reading in late August, an autobiography by Dennis McKenna regarding his life and adventures with his older brother Terance.&amp;nbsp; Their primary area of exploration was psychotropics and the dissemination of &quot;Magic School Bus&quot; knowledge (not to be confused with Ken Kesey&#39;s, a more literal bus).&amp;nbsp; Or knowledge of some &quot;Screaming Abyss&quot; as the case may be (an allusion to the book&#39;s title).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I got to listen to Dennis live at one of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/10/attending-esozone.html&quot;&gt;the &lt;i&gt;Esozones&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I attended, some years back.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve yet to sample much of Terry&#39;s stuff but expect I&#39;ll be getting around to it in &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/05/philosophy-talk.html&quot;&gt;my wanderings&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20676449752/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Americana&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Americana&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5832/20676449752_5e057bbc89.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3540016113339895889'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3540016113339895889'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/fantastic-four-movie-review.html' title='Fantastic Four (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6659478428742003642</id><published>2015-08-15T14:35:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-08-30T12:24:24.909-07:00</updated><title type='text'>OSCON Followup</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/21019659901/&quot; title=&quot;oscon_vids_2015&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;oscon_vids_2015&quot; height=&quot;313&quot; src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5716/21019659901_21bd73a7c6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I feel fortunate to have had a high access path through OSCON this year, as one of the proposal readers.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m able to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/07/oscon-2015-wrap-up.html&quot;&gt;watch the videos&lt;/a&gt; of all the talks, the majority of which I missed, obviously.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2014/07/r0mls-talk-why-schools-dont-teach-open.html&quot;&gt;Seeing R0ml&lt;/a&gt; teaching Haskell brought me joy and I started downloading Part 1 immediately, having had some trouble with the online player.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s a segue to my next piece of good news:&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;CenturyLink&lt;/i&gt; has finally brought optical fiber speeds to my neighborhood.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ve seen the trucks.&amp;nbsp; Yes, I&#39;m &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/08/health-talk.html&quot;&gt;ready to starve a little&lt;/a&gt; bit to get more of the world online.&amp;nbsp; I hunger for bandwidth, both up and down.&amp;nbsp; These OSCON videos are a case in point.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I want to download copies for my phone, other devices, for train and plane viewing (cars not self driving yet but &lt;i&gt;Bolt Bus&lt;/i&gt;... to Seattle maybe?).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I hope to get the try-out setup before the month is out.&amp;nbsp; Today I&#39;m still Mr. DSL with my slow uplink.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Glenn and I did &lt;i&gt;Atlas Pizza&lt;/i&gt; today and talked about floating &quot;flextegrity cities&quot;.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ve both had experience with &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/crzsp1&quot;&gt;Sam&#39;s material&lt;/a&gt; and the way it might deal with waves, damping them, seemed worth its weight in science fiction at least.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Why not speculate?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was saying in general I think more experience with oceans, before tackling Mars, might be smart.&amp;nbsp; The rigors of ocean living would help the landlubbers clean up their act, which would pay for itself right there.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I told Glenn Stockton about Dan Suttin, who&#39;s birthday it is today.&amp;nbsp; He was so taken with what we call &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/octet.html&quot;&gt;the Octet Truss&lt;/a&gt;, or IVM, that he made a museum about it, now &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mysanantonio.com/news/local/communities/southside/article/Eccentric-Octa-Tetra-museum-finds-safe-haven-5757526.php&quot;&gt;getting more recognition&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s 71 today. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20605039975/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Happy Birthday to Dan&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Happy Birthday to Dan&quot; height=&quot;462&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/722/20605039975_4d894d8ae1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6659478428742003642'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6659478428742003642'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/oscon-followup.html' title='OSCON Followup'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1651653310010451238</id><published>2015-08-13T22:38:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T14:16:52.480-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Pi (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20363359540/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;From the Movie&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;From the Movie&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5657/20363359540_03daf6df07.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
The title the movie uses is actually the Greek letter.&amp;nbsp; This is an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0138704/&quot;&gt;oldie but goodie&lt;/a&gt;, a recent present from Glenn (he got two copies, each for a buck).&amp;nbsp; Best viewed as a comedy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I watched it 1.5 times actually, not counting the first time, years ago, as it&#39;s fun to see it from the beginning having seen the end -- circularity is a theme after all.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The hero seems overly paranoid in the beginning but that&#39;s because we&#39;re flies on the wall and don&#39;t know anything.&amp;nbsp; We join the story as it spirals out of control.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Cohen is on the brink of unlocking some mystery of the universe that will have far reaching consequences and two cabals, one from Wall Street and one of Orthodox Jews (into Kabbalah), want to get the secret from him.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That secret is apparently well protected by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceandnonduality.com/akashic-field-and-consciousness/&quot;&gt;Akashic Fields&lt;/a&gt; and the would-be knower is driven close to crazy in its pursuit.&amp;nbsp; Given it&#39;s a 216 digit number, it&#39;s also hard to memorize, shades of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/mission-impossible-rogue-nation-movie.html&quot;&gt;Tom Cruise in &lt;i&gt;Rogue Nation&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Fortunately, we have a pause button.&amp;nbsp; But wait, aren&#39;t the numbers different in the two shots?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Shades of a lot of movies actually.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The repetitive nature of the shots and actions give an Eternal Return flavor to Everyman&#39;s conundrum, a sense of being trapped or embedded in a puzzle palace of cosmic origins.&amp;nbsp; His cross to bear is this sense of an unsolved puzzle, tantalizingly close to resolution.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But the secret seems well protected.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A film I&#39;d compare this one to rather directly:&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2014/10/the-zero-theorem-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Zero Theorem&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I went to &lt;i&gt;Thirster&lt;/i&gt;s immediately after watching the first half a second time, and appreciated the contrast, of a group looking for a more rational explanations of world events, even while acknowledging the irrational.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That everything from the stock market to the cyclic nature of diseases should be &quot;ruled by the numbers&quot; is Pythagoreanism at its radical root, and Cohen is definitely an adherent of the faith -- even though his computer is named Euclid.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As Cohen converges on the secret, with the best chips available (provided by the Wall Street cabal), his computer needs more and more power.&amp;nbsp; Something like ectoplasm drips from the circuit boards.&amp;nbsp; His mind likewise becomes more tortured.&amp;nbsp; The two, brain and rack, seem one and the same.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
His Go-playing buddy, an elder and mentor who in his youth went down a similar path, offers sage advice which we may paraphrase as the Steve Holden 3-2-1 rule:&amp;nbsp; if you&#39;re at a conference and having a great time, still make sure you get at least three hours sleep every twenty-four, and two meals, and at least one shower.&amp;nbsp; If things get really hectic and you need to skimp on any of these, make sure it&#39;s &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; the shower (treat that as mandatory).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Likewise his friend keeps telling him to take a bath, especially after expressively recounting the well-known story of Archimedes, in which bathing occurs.&amp;nbsp; Open up to others.&amp;nbsp; Listen.&amp;nbsp; Learn.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Cohen&#39;s dogged pursuit of some solution to his puzzle is actually setting him back.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s such a thing as &quot;too dogged&quot; maybe?&amp;nbsp; He needs to learn to relax.&amp;nbsp; He needs the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/at-landmark-event.html&quot;&gt;Landmark Forum&lt;/a&gt; maybe.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The fun cliche though, which this movie captures, is how when converging to some zero point, some Faustian holy grail, one finds Wall Street and Jewish mystics both breathing down one&#39;s neck, and fighting with each other to get there first.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s powerful is to know or anticipate the future, and awareness of hidden patterns in events is just the ticket for doing that.&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Beautiful Mind&lt;/i&gt; fits here too.&amp;nbsp; Reality is overwhelmingly full of patterns, but as the Go buddy reminds Cohen:&amp;nbsp; chaos and infinite complexity is what the simple Go grid anchors (no two games are the same).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway we already know these archetypes, these stereotypes regarding the close proximity of insanity and genius.&amp;nbsp; What&#39;s satisfying about this movie is how it distills them down to a black and white set of touchstones, a necklace of scenes, looped through over and over.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s as if there&#39;s already a code...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Great scene:&amp;nbsp; he explains &quot;theta&quot; [sic] then it&#39;s spirals everywhere and he quits the scene, on to the next. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1651653310010451238'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1651653310010451238'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/pi-movie-review.html' title='Pi (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3713458118767673425</id><published>2015-08-11T23:48:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-02T10:52:21.257-07:00</updated><title type='text'>At a Landmark Event</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19885971243/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF9753&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF9753&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/270/19885971243_390fc515d8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Close readers of my blogs know they&#39;re like a Russian novel in terms of the number of characters weaving through them, but that&#39;s life for a lot of us, not saying I&#39;m special in attending to many threads or narratives, besides my own.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Along those lines, one Sara whom I&#39;ve known since what we called &quot;the Gathering&quot; for short, 1980s, appears in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/07/wrap-up.html&quot;&gt;my account of a Quaker Annual Session&lt;/a&gt; in Spokane, Washington this year.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
By the way, while I&#39;m on the topic of chronicling events, Melody (a Food Not Bombs co-conspirator) very kindly found me a working Nikon Coolpix to tide me over while the XQ-1 was in the shop.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I switched back to an XQ-1 right about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/oscon-2015-begins.html&quot;&gt;start of OSCON&lt;/a&gt;, but neglected to set the clock properly.&amp;nbsp; My archive may have some discrepancies, up to where &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/08/concurrency-again.html&quot;&gt;Dr. DiNucci alerted me&lt;/a&gt; to the issue a few days ago and I finally set it right in the camera.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I asked about the photography policy:&amp;nbsp; none during the event.&amp;nbsp; I adjudged said event to be bracketed by more informal milling about time, during which Sara did some registrations.&amp;nbsp; I took my few pictures before and after.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was pleased to rediscover I could review The Forum for the reviewer price, and that records from &lt;i&gt;est&lt;/i&gt; days were pretty &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=integrious&quot;&gt;integrious&lt;/a&gt; i.e. they&#39;d be able to verify my &quot;&lt;i&gt;est&lt;/i&gt; vet&quot; status.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d been to a Landmark event with Sara before, her graduation, some years back.&amp;nbsp; I understand her excitement about the programs, even if she had some issues staying awake through this latest, led by Forum Leader Naveed, our host for tonight as well.&amp;nbsp; She took intelligent action to counter any falling asleep.&amp;nbsp; Been there.&amp;nbsp; Getting sleepy is not a sign the training isn&#39;t working.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Naveed Bhatti correctly pointed out this wasn&#39;t television (he could see us after all), however I marveled at how well Americans spontaneously do first take quality TV on the fly, once coached to be stars by their compatriots.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s not intended to sound cynical, more admiring.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I don&#39;t mean to single out Americans alone as having this talent and indeed I hear from mom that the Philippines has surpassed all of us in hip hop these days -- our disciplines travel around, more so in the jet age than ever.&amp;nbsp; However this was Ambridge Event Center on MLK in Portland, Oregon, so allow me the local coloring.&amp;nbsp; These folks were adorable, trust me on this one.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Which is why I was tempted to jump into the next available swimming pool (i.e. forum), but hey, lets look at the options.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m in the mood to mull.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Naveed, of Pakistani heritage, was deeply into IT.&amp;nbsp; As the night progressed, he continued to provide vignettes from his personal life, as Forum Leaders have lives too and deserve to work on whatever.&amp;nbsp; Even if one repeats the &quot;same&quot; stories, it&#39;s always a new crop of listeners willing to keep an open mind.&amp;nbsp; Tuesday nights especially are an opportunity for Forum Leaders to get more autobiographical.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Naveed knows people will speculate about the accent, or about whether he even has one, given he looks like he does. His English is pure Floridian (that&#39;s his homeland).&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s from Orlando, to pin it down.&amp;nbsp; His field, prior to joining the Landmark faculty, was fiber optics and related technologies, so he&#39;s a bit of a geek, he was quick to confess.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I hope I didn&#39;t offend anyone (well OK, a few) in saying &quot;adorable&quot; just now, about those completing their Forum and sharing things they&#39;d realized from the Friday through Sunday experience.&amp;nbsp; Tuesday, included in the program as a course completing experience, is also an opportunity to bring friends and family, fellow co-workers, whomever, to this guests-welcome event.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Landmark enterprise has been successful in remaining secular yet friendly to religions.&amp;nbsp; One video we saw sampled from Clergy, Scientists, Artists, and other walks of life.&amp;nbsp; The talking heads delivered strongly positive testimony obviously, not that Naveed avoided the topic of skepticism in any way.&amp;nbsp; Suspicion is natural and part of human nature for a reason.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Clearly the Tuesday event is designed to mitigate any psychological obstacles to signing up, the tuition cost itself obviously a consideration.&amp;nbsp; That sacrifice fuels the event in that practically no one intends to be ripped off after signing up to commit to something about improving the quality of one&#39;s own life for a pretty penny.&amp;nbsp; The logic is tight and well known in the education community:&amp;nbsp; people are more open to accepting rewards they sense they&#39;ve earned, through hard work and risk taking.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Having those just completing said course offer personal testimonials, and having invited guests join them, is a working recipe, not unlike how some restaurants build their business.&amp;nbsp; Since the early days, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/12/some-storytelling.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;est&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was accused of using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.motherjones.com/media/2009/07/landmark-42-hours-500-65-breakdowns&quot;&gt;&quot;hard sell&quot; tactics&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Advertising in a billboard or TV sense is not among those tactics however.&amp;nbsp; Word of mouth is the way to go.&amp;nbsp; Slick advertising would actually undermine the practice grads get in applying their own spin, not that the videos they showed us don&#39;t constitute PR.&amp;nbsp; I went away with a colorful brochure.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I don&#39;t want to say that Landmark has &quot;cornered the market&quot; on what it does, just that it does what it does quite well, which had been my experience with Centers Network in an earlier chapter.&amp;nbsp; I served as logistics supervisor and so on, as recounted elsewhere in more detail -- this was back in New York City, and in New Jersey before that, rewinding the tape to Princeton days and Walter Kaufmann etc. then fast forwarding, showing me getting into the Bucky stuff pretty quickly.&amp;nbsp; I was then living in Jersey City, teaching high school, and tracking Werner Erhard&#39;s career.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Rather than focus on competitive aspects of the human potential programs, both religious and secular, and including AA, I prefer to see Landmark as somewhat in &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/revisiting-landmark.html&quot;&gt;the Open Source ballpark&lt;/a&gt;, as community supported.&amp;nbsp; Sure, much is confidential, in terms of individuals&#39; records, but 2.2 million people is not negligible and the whole point is to take the methodology back to work.&amp;nbsp; Oaths of secrecy are not a big part of it, just don&#39;t blab if you see Britney (or whomever) in your room.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At events like this, where people wore name tags prominently identifying their Landmark affiliation, it&#39;d be silly to say total anonymity was a goal.&amp;nbsp; On the contrary, testimonials are worth a lot more when personally signed, i.e. when traceable to real people.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Saying the Landmark Forum is &quot;secret&quot; is therefore way too melodramatic.&amp;nbsp; Listening with an ear for the possibilities a communication and/or relationship presents is worth more as a willingness and a skill, than as good avuncular advice, and intensive training goes beyond mere advising in these dense format sessions, or call them &quot;boot camp&quot; experiences.&amp;nbsp; &quot;You had to be there&quot; is a cliche for a reason.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The software industry likewise intensifies and concentrates in some places.&amp;nbsp; The Landmark Forum has elements in common with the &quot;sprint&quot; in software development circles, especially when conducted as in-person events.&amp;nbsp; Participants are there to add value, and to learn, not as passive spectators but as active contributors, even though in software that may mean little more than wiggling one&#39;s fingers over a keyboard.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Panda Express company, among others, is happy to endorse the quality of the Landmark experience.&amp;nbsp; Quite a few companies are not especially shy about advertising their connection, with some offering tuition as an employee benefit.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Again, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/07/oscon-xv.html&quot;&gt;Open Source culture&lt;/a&gt; is similar in having reached a truce or understanding in a kind of charitable activity that earns good will, yet advantages the participants in more specific and technological ways.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Lets agree on these public utilities and add value within&quot; -- that attitude becomes a source of a network&#39;s cohesion as a shared resource.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If we agree on &lt;a href=&quot;https://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2015-July/011289.html&quot;&gt;co-creating the playing field&lt;/a&gt;, then we can have our secrets within it.&amp;nbsp; We agree on the rules of poker but then -- and so then -- don&#39;t need to show all our cards (according to the rules of poker, MIT license or whatever).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Although I did not wear my anthropology hat, not literally (I have a black Stetson we might call my Anthropology hat -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/08/all-math-is-ethnomath.html&quot;&gt;reminds me to stay ethnic&lt;/a&gt;), part of my motivation in being there was to update myself on this side of my culture.&amp;nbsp; What was the lineage like these days coming up on a half century?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Of course to know the answers in more detail I&#39;d have to review the course.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s a real possibility. I&#39;m examining my options as to where in the world would be a good place.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s one in Seattle where they&#39;re translating into Farsi.&amp;nbsp; That looked pretty interesting.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19886077493/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF9758&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF9758&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/534/19886077493_aef2b5f8d7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3713458118767673425'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3713458118767673425'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/at-landmark-event.html' title='At a Landmark Event'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1528545839356509724</id><published>2015-08-10T01:26:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2015-08-10T08:57:03.839-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Mission Impossible:  Rogue Nation (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iq-YeD4L-bg?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;420&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
After watching Bernie Sanders, preceded by some great keynotes, on my Samsung tablet with mom, I decided to check out the new &lt;i&gt;Mission Impossible&lt;/i&gt; film at Regal Cinemas Lloyd Center 10.&amp;nbsp; I took &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/08/from-gothamite.html&quot;&gt;Maxi Taxi&lt;/a&gt; (the Nissan) for the 9:45 PM show.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Around here, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/02/thirsters-2015226.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Rogue Nation&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a brewery, nor is &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/07/more-buckaneer-talk.html&quot;&gt;Syndicate&lt;/a&gt;&quot; necessarily a bad word, but of course I was rooting for the Goodies throughout, made to seem like underdogs so we&#39;d root for &#39;em even more.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Like so many boomers, I was brought up on &lt;i&gt;Mission Impossible &lt;/i&gt;on TV, with Peter Graves et al.&amp;nbsp; I liked the cleverness and gadgetry, instead of just gun play, which latter always seemed kinda dumb.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As with the &lt;i&gt;007&lt;/i&gt; franchise, and the &lt;i&gt;Bourne&lt;/i&gt; movies, these agents have what amounts to either superpowers and/or super good luck.&amp;nbsp; The puzzles they need to solve are as unbelievable as those in &lt;i&gt;Uru&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re in a video game with levels.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Their plans are incredibly far fetched, yet seem to work out.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People go to the circus for the same reason, and in those you don&#39;t get to shoot retakes or employ cine-magic in quite the same way.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Indeed, Tom&#39;s trick for escaping a certain Houdini-like binding reminded me a lot of something I saw at &lt;i&gt;Cirque du Soliel&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Naturally we saw lots of control rooms, standard fare in such movies, along with ticking time bombs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Where would this world of secret agents be without Hollywood?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Theater has created this backdrop and appropriately we spend a fair amount of time in a theater, an opera no less, watching these phantoms of our own imaginations.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Catching a film in August is a good time to preview the Fall / Winter lineup.&amp;nbsp; The last &lt;i&gt;Hunger Games &lt;/i&gt;is coming in November.&amp;nbsp; The &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/12/casino-royale-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;next 007 film&lt;/a&gt; is in the can, ready to share.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20437728272/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Carol&#39;s Office:  Watching Bernie Sanders in PDX&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Carol&#39;s Office:  Watching Bernie Sanders in PDX&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/279/20437728272_87686b6c94_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: watching Bernie Sanders rally on tablet, Carol&#39;s office ::&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div div=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1528545839356509724'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1528545839356509724'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/mission-impossible-rogue-nation-movie.html' title='Mission Impossible:  Rogue Nation (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/iq-YeD4L-bg/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1284117686903533528</id><published>2015-08-08T17:04:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-08-08T17:05:17.342-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Summer 2015</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20174816800/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF9609&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF9609&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/324/20174816800_0a00d9d35c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19741977163/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF9610&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF9610&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/303/19741977163_9a553f1342.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20354284632/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Skidmore Fountain&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Skidmore Fountain&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3686/20354284632_dbc0401578.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1284117686903533528'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1284117686903533528'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/summer-2015.html' title='Summer 2015'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1633006545300723214</id><published>2015-08-05T11:40:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-08-09T13:06:07.968-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2016.8.5</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20134480940/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Lindsey and Kirby, Alpha Helix, Linus Pauling House&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Lindsey and Kirby, Alpha Helix, Linus Pauling House&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5618/20134480940_cbbb12645b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Today was an opportunity to saw good bye to Linz (Lindsey Walker) for a spell, as she makes last minute arrangements to return to her field studies, with OSU&#39;s blessings.&amp;nbsp; She came to my upstairs office this morning wondering if Wanderers was a go.&amp;nbsp; Why not?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Everyone there knew her already, but I re-introduced her as &quot;the Queen of 97214&quot; though she demurred on &quot;queen&quot; and later I said &quot;child of&quot;.&amp;nbsp; That was to be the theme of our later photo shoot.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The point being:&amp;nbsp; she met her new community of friends, me one of them, via the Pauling House, thanks to her meeting Patrick Barton (currently with O&#39;Reilly School), who &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/10/market-research.html&quot;&gt;at one time&lt;/a&gt; rented office space therein (when working for a Chicago-based psycho-metrics firm).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then by osmosis and synchronicity she become enamored of Buddhism (they call this the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2014/02/winter-wonderland-weather.html&quot;&gt;Buddhist ghetto&lt;/a&gt;&quot; after all) and in Newar Buddhism in particular.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The only Newar temple in North America, or maybe anywhere outside Kathmandu Valley, is in the same block as the Pauling House, just around the corner.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s why she&#39;s a daughter of our block and zip code (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/02/surgery-on-blue-house.html&quot;&gt;Blue House&lt;/a&gt; is right nearby). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Plus OSU was Linus Pauling&#39;s domain (there&#39;s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://untappd.com/b/sky-high-brewing-linus-pauling-ale/385246&quot;&gt;Linus Pauling Ale&lt;/a&gt; now, in Corvallis) and that&#39;s where Lindsey is now enrolled, as a combined religious studies and anthropology major.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
She&#39;s already lived through that major earthquake in April (her guest room was on a fifth floor) on her second trip over, yet she&#39;s eager to return, and to commute between Corvallis and Patan.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was in St. Louis around the time of that quake, and in Champaign-Urbana, on assignment for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/wXa2jC&quot;&gt;same school&lt;/a&gt; Patrick works with.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/04/usdla-keynote.html&quot;&gt;USDLA&lt;/a&gt; (US Distance Learning Association) holds an annual conference there and we were checking out (and learning from) &quot;the competition&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Steve Mastin, Dick Pugh, Don Wardwell, Jon Bunce and myself were present (Glenn showed up in time for the photo shoot).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Between the lot of us, we have lots of experience in and around academia and there was no shortage of well-meaning advice for this promising forty year old degree candidate from Florida State, where Lindsey&#39;s undergrad work began, before she left for a career &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/crisis-line.html&quot;&gt;in IT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20296118686/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Newar Temple&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Newar Temple&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/558/20296118686_1fa16e4648.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1633006545300723214'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1633006545300723214'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/wanderers-201685.html' title='Wanderers 2016.8.5'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6541091069398204595</id><published>2015-08-02T10:46:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-08-22T10:55:03.322-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Asynchronous Learning Engine (ALE)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/17304692495/in/album-72157654417641521/&quot; title=&quot;Flights of Fancy&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Flights of Fancy&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7688/17304692495_b1b8e0203e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I created a stub outline of an Asynchronous Learning Engine on GitHub today (link below).&amp;nbsp; That may sound impressive however all the classes are abstract stubs, with an underlying metaphor.&amp;nbsp; The implementation is left as an exercise.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The metaphor (living at the base class level) centers on picturing airplane flights as courses of study, with a beginning, middle and end.&amp;nbsp; One could do ships and cruises -- hey, they&#39;re just metaphors, feel free to mix &#39;em.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Geek cruises&quot;are a reality already, including of the non-metaphoric kind.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Names like Student, Course, Mentor make up the foreground, but without leaving our extended metaphors behind.&amp;nbsp; The course fills to a minimum, gets start and stop dates, but in many models students manage their own time (talking months) and finish anytime before deadline.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some are in a hurry, some not.&amp;nbsp; Some have time to study hard, others have only tiny windows in their day, to inch ahead.&amp;nbsp; Few if any synchronized events are required therefore.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not about all moving in lockstep, even if in the same course.&amp;nbsp; That doesn&#39;t preclude some exercises involving a stop watch or timer.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Flight Recorder (built in to the Course or Airplane class) saves the transactions, meaning submitted and handed back work, communications to and from a mentor. Quality Assurance (QA) is about going over these records and learning from them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20014016398/in/album-72157654417641521/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF9346&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF9346&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/292/20014016398_16ce55bd31.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Feedback loops are the name of the game.&amp;nbsp; Mentors improve by learning from each turn in the cockpit, perhaps we have co-pilots (like co-clerks, of committees).&amp;nbsp; One might be the apprentice of the other in one course, the senior pilot in another.&amp;nbsp; Mentors are students themselves as there&#39;s never a shortage of new stuff to learn, new skills to pick up.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some designs encourage chatter amongst the passengers however more typical is the private one-on-one experience, with the mentor interacting individually with everyone and anyone in the course (or courses -- in this world a mentor may fly several airplanes simultaneously, called &quot;multi-tasking&quot;, just as a student may take more than one course at a time, just like in college).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What I envision as a typical use case are EC2 / AWS (Amazon) type implementations of the Personal Studio or Personal Workspace (PWS) model, such that learners remote in to their personal Ubuntu or whatever, the instance pre-configured per whatever course design.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Are we doing &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/08/stem-carbon-as-theme.html&quot;&gt;2D &amp;amp; 3D graphics&lt;/a&gt;?&amp;nbsp; Is &lt;a href=&quot;http://vpython.org/&quot;&gt;VPython&lt;/a&gt; installed?&amp;nbsp; That all depends on the course, although presumably there are many parts of the Ux (user experience) that are common to all courses, giving a branded and perhaps eventually familiar, look and feel.&amp;nbsp; A student might work on more than one course within a given PWS instance.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Containerized services at the other end of a student dashboard given &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/02/learning-on-line.html&quot;&gt;the &quot;traveler&quot;&lt;/a&gt; (wanderer, browser, tourist, visitor, guest... scout) a way to &quot;book flights&quot; including with &quot;connecting flights&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The mentor dashboard shows the task queues (see source outline below).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Student and mentor are connected asynchronously through the ALE.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s it&#39;s primary job, to glue together all the components required to run an airline (or railroad, if you prefer).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For example:&amp;nbsp; { Ruby
                        &lt;span class=&quot;html-code&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Rails 
                        &lt;span class=&quot;html-code&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; JavaScript in the Browser (including JQuery) 
                        &lt;span class=&quot;html-code&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; JS on the Server } would earn a merit badge or certificate in our &quot;learning by doing&quot; space (hiking trail metaphors apply also -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=9748346&quot;&gt;as in scouting&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve been looking at { Python &lt;span class=&quot;html-code&quot;&gt; Java &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;html-code&quot;&gt; Clojure }&amp;nbsp; as a set of connecting flights, perhaps spanning &lt;a href=&quot;https://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2015-August/011290.html&quot;&gt;grades 10 to 16&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The ALE does not nail down curriculum content per se.&amp;nbsp; Its job is to organize students into courses, assign them mentors, and keep things moving forward towards completion.&amp;nbsp; Course designers have a known framework to work with -- whatever version of ALE the client / school uses.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;html-code&quot;&gt;Mentors, like students, have different availability, different schedules, as well as areas of expertise.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s where Air Traffic Controlling (Dispatching) comes in.&amp;nbsp; We need admin to help us with load balancing such that no one mentor burns out under the caseload.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;html-code&quot;&gt;&quot;Adding to the fleet&quot; where demand is high is easy with ALE (our in-house system, not Open Source, isn&#39;t called that).&amp;nbsp; Smaller more esoteric courses may have higher marginal costs, but add to a school&#39;s luster in other ways (guest mentors may be celebs in their fields).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;html-code&quot;&gt;Colleges and universities may be set in their ways and may as yet have no internal 
&quot;dog food&quot; they might eat and/or modify, nothing Open Source to share and partake in.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;html-code&quot;&gt;Sometimes upstart companies, 
including not-for-profits, NGOs, are better positioned to try new 
things.&amp;nbsp; ALE is not just another Moodle or Banner.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;html-code&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;i&gt;For further reading&lt;/i&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/07/pws-personal-workspace.html&quot;&gt;ALE Use Case&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/4dsolutions/async_learning_engine&quot;&gt;GitHub Repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://clojars.org/clojure-python&quot;&gt;clojure-python&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6541091069398204595'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6541091069398204595'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/08/asynchronous-learning-engine-ale.html' title='Asynchronous Learning Engine (ALE)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-9102772387704869087</id><published>2015-07-31T19:25:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2015-07-31T22:59:38.743-07:00</updated><title type='text'>About a Factory</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/20146827752/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF9325&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF9325&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3771/20146827752_f417425715.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Glenn and I enjoyed &lt;i&gt;The Bagdad&lt;/i&gt; today, another hot one.&amp;nbsp; Lots of street theater, though none of the buskers from the other day (above).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A long happy chapter in Glenn&#39;s life was re-purposing an old abandoned high school, twelve foot ceilings, tall windows, maple floors, a huge walk-in air conditioning solution... to make it a healthy place to work, producing sensitive measuring devices.&amp;nbsp; The town had already dwindled to not quite a ghost town, when a new generation of young people showed up, Glenn among them, a Vietnam vet (exNSA).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Glenn did a lot of the wiring and our discussion turned to conduit, how it&#39;s bent without crimping.&amp;nbsp; Ingenious spring sleeves do the trick, though he also described a more conventional solution.&amp;nbsp; Having tried to bend copper tubing by hand, and quickly crimping it (a kindergarten experience, saved for kitchen sink owning adulthood), I could appreciate the need for tools.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fishing the wire through (this is conduit for wiring) is another art.&amp;nbsp; He talked about an air pressure powered &quot;mouse&quot; that may be used to fire the pull-cord right through the length, after which a tightly bound bundle of wires is pulled behind it, perhaps with the help of lubricant.&amp;nbsp; Why tighter is better I wasn&#39;t sure, having a memory of &quot;cable trays&quot;, suspended from the ceiling, open to the air, but then there&#39;s a difference between high voltage cables and data cables.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The plant was in Jerome, Arizona, and the instrument was a very fine almost-pure gold mesh.&amp;nbsp; One could detect toxins at parts per billion not million, including the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/2013/06/20/sour-gas-hydrogen-sulphide-hs2_n_3473666.html&quot;&gt;sour gas&lt;/a&gt;&quot; that kills oil rig workers, if they hit a pocket of the stuff.&amp;nbsp; And mercury.&amp;nbsp; These were canary in a mineshaft devices, and used by environmentalists to document &quot;externalized costs&quot; in the form of deteriorating health (lower living standards) for surrounding populations (some factories are more polluting than others).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At its peak, this &quot;mostly hippie&quot; factory, meaning egalitarian, no cubicles, parties every Friday afternoon (well earned), turned a pretty penny and outperformed the competition, making a lot of less competent companies look bad.&amp;nbsp; I guess the factory was publicly listed or something, or in any case it got bought out and ruined by lesser minds from Phoenix or one of those.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s from Glenn&#39;s angle of course, given the takeover involved everyone being fired (and adding cubicles &quot;so people couldn&#39;t see you not working&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The unions, when influential on a construction site, have their respective turf when it comes to tubes and ducts.&amp;nbsp; Pipe fitters have their specialty.&amp;nbsp; However once the building is complete and in service, a next cast of ongoing maintainers get to practice a more inter-disciplinary blend of skills.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Glenn really benefited from all the talents he got to develop, extending what he&#39;d learned from growing up around a construction site:&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.canyon-country.com/lakepowell/gcdam.htm&quot;&gt;Glen Canyon Dam&lt;/a&gt; near Page, Arizona.&amp;nbsp; His dad was a senior engineer on that one, the family having moved there from St. Helen&#39;s, Oregon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19989647608/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF9342&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF9342&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/365/19989647608_240bedc21b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9102772387704869087'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9102772387704869087'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/about-factory.html' title='About a Factory'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4846383424055178063</id><published>2015-07-30T09:49:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-08-10T06:52:12.275-07:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="clojure"/><title type='text'>Ramping Up</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19534330974/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Synergetics Modules&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Synergetics Modules&quot; height=&quot;406&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/263/19534330974_280ce9c65a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Fig 1: Clojure IDE:&amp;nbsp; IntelliJ&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
In &lt;a href=&quot;https://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2015-July/011285.html&quot;&gt;this classroom&lt;/a&gt;, we foreground &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; while &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/4dsolutions/synmods/tree/master&quot;&gt;ramping up&lt;/a&gt; at a slower rate in the background with &lt;a href=&quot;http://clojure.org/&quot;&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt;.  That lets us dabble in Functional Programming while absorbing the Object Oriented mindset, providing a strong basis for future exploration and new skills acquisition.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The segue computation, twixt Python and Clojure, is this &quot;volume of a tetrahedron based only on six edge lengths for input&quot; algorithm handed down to me &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.berkeley.edu/~wkahan/VtetLang.pdf&quot;&gt;from the ancestors&lt;/a&gt;, and in my subculture fine tuned by one Gerald de Jong (of &lt;a href=&quot;http://springie.com/&quot;&gt;Elastic Interval Geometry&lt;/a&gt; fame) to natively output in what we call tetravolumes, i.e. when all edges are one, the thing is calibrated to return one (unit volume in this system). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Gerald shared his results on &lt;i&gt;Synergetics-L&lt;/i&gt; which used to run in the Teleport domain.&amp;nbsp; I brought the result to sci.math, coming under attack (by some guy named Chapman) for not getting my priorities straight.&amp;nbsp; I have not gone back to sci.math with anything important (too frenetic!).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
David Chako, Gerald, myself, and later Tom Ace, were all working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quadray_coordinates&quot;&gt;Quadrays&lt;/a&gt; at the time, which we also called Chakovian coordinates. I became aware of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/pyqvectors.html&quot;&gt;Darrel Jarmusch&#39;s parallel efforts &lt;/a&gt;somewhere in the course of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/quadvols.html&quot;&gt;this R&amp;amp;D&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Imagine a regular tetrahedron centered at O with four radial arms to its four vertexes.&amp;nbsp; These are the unit vectors, at most three of which are needed, in linear combination, to span each quadrant. All IVM (= CCP) ball centers have positive integer or zero coordinates with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/quadintro.html&quot;&gt;origin O at (0, 0, 0, 0)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Quadrays may be used in combination with tetravolume measures to show all &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waterman_polyhedron&quot;&gt;Waterman polyhedrons&lt;/a&gt; have whole number volume, as do all tetrahedrons with all four corners at IVM points (proof by Robert Gray, the original transcriber of &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; onto the Web).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
To use the Volume function (below), one gives the three edges from a common apex, call it O, meaning we input OA, OB, OC.&amp;nbsp; The next three edges are the AB, BC, CA respectively, i.e. going around the base.&amp;nbsp; The algorithm works with 2nd powers of these lengths, forming products of &quot;open&quot;, &quot;closed&quot; and &quot;opposite&quot; sets of edges.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19969071198/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;new_improved&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;new_improved&quot; height=&quot;332&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/552/19969071198_9748a8e2e6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Fig 2:&amp;nbsp; Call-out:&amp;nbsp; the Volume function&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the above figure, the summary Volume computation is matched with a special case example, that of the A module, for output of:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;All edges D=1, Volume: 1.0
Amod volume: 0.04166666666666668
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The labeling in that case corresponds to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/synergetics/s09/figs/f86421.html&quot;&gt;some plane net&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt;.  The unit volume tetrahedron fragments into 24 such modules, 12 left and 12 right (inside-outs of each other), and therefore each with a volume of 1/24 (same as B and T modules).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/d/msg/clojure/RvHQPfBKJuM/k0_2AWcmas8J&quot;&gt;The Clojure program&lt;/a&gt;, just like &lt;a href=&quot;https://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2013-August/010872.html&quot;&gt;the Python version&lt;/a&gt;, then goes on to compute other module volumes, including the E and S module volumes, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/synergetics/s09/figs/f8813a.html&quot;&gt;published plane nets&lt;/a&gt;, with the S / E volume ratio named &quot;sFactor&quot; in other computations relating to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/02/a-tale-of-two-logos.html&quot;&gt;the Jitterbug Transformation&lt;/a&gt; (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2015/07/mind-gap.html&quot;&gt;CSN blog&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I recommend Wittgenstein&#39;s philosophical investigations, into mathematics especially, for those balking at the very notion of a unit volume tetrahedron, which may at first seem counter-intuitive, just as Clojure&#39;s LISP-like syntax may feel too alien (remote) at first. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Showing how the tetravolumes language game extents to the planar case, along with the payoff in terms of whole number volumes, may lower the student&#39;s skepticism level enough to where engaging in hands-on exercises with these concepts, using computer languages, does not seem a waste of time on some purely &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/09/a-haunting-planting.html&quot;&gt;nonsensical activity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19523370654/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF9317&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF9317&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/444/19523370654_640e0c640e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4846383424055178063'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4846383424055178063'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/ramping-up.html' title='Ramping Up'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6358953216468416005</id><published>2015-07-25T10:34:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-07-31T10:19:56.241-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Of Kepler and Aristotle</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19378784383/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;World Game Continues&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;World Game Continues&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/443/19378784383_24a188a2de.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve grown in both my respect and understanding for several historical figures in recent years, Descartes and Mercator in particular.  Both had to navigate in the treacherous waters of fear, based in strife &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/04/another-wittgenstein-essay.html&quot;&gt;among namespaces&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Religious wars were rampant in other words.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mercator ended up in jail for a spell, whereas &lt;a href=&quot;http://reasonsociety.blogspot.com/2011/08/descartes-secret-notebook-1.html&quot;&gt;Descartes&lt;/a&gt; was always dodging the equivalent of paparazzi and may have been poisoned in the end, as chief adviser to a Scandinavian Queen.&amp;nbsp; Copernicus was also cool.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Johannes Kepler, however, I&#39;d come to appreciate much earlier, through Arthur Koestler&#39;s works.&amp;nbsp; Here was a guy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keplersdiscovery.com/SixCornered.html&quot;&gt;really into&lt;/a&gt; the classic rhombic dodecahedron, a space-filling shape.&amp;nbsp; He understood its connection to what we today call the CCP or FCC matrix, both with the word &quot;cubic&quot; in them, yet 60-degree and 120-degree angles are what stand out given balls closest-pack in triangular relationships as much as square.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The growing cuboctahedron of dense-packed spheres that defines the CCP is actually &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2015/07/mind-gap.html&quot;&gt;the dual shape &lt;/a&gt;to the rhombic dodecahedron, the shape which naturally encases each of those spheres such that they become inter-tangent at the centers of its twelve diamond faces.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/graphics/cubanim.gif&quot; onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/graphics/cubanim.gif&quot; style=&quot;cursor: pointer; display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; width: 225px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%; font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;1, 12, 42, 92, 162...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;:: Growth of the IVM (= fcc, = ccp) ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/11/isepp-kick-off-2013-2014.html&quot;&gt;graphene&lt;/a&gt; and the emergence of the Age of Carbon as some call it, &lt;a href=&quot;http://hexagonalawarenessproject.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;hexagonal awareness&lt;/a&gt; has surged to the foreground, with checker-board patterns (except Chinese) receding, though also present in the CCP in cross-section.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The discovery of buckminsterfullerene as an allotrope of carbon in the 1980s marked the beginning of a cascade of events, leading to nano-tubes and then graphene.&amp;nbsp; The computer industry has converged to this space of hexagons, and, by extension, the rhombic dodecahedra so fascinating to Kepler.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On to Aristotle, who fits in for his controversial claim that tetrahedrons are space-filling.&amp;nbsp; Regular ones are clearly not, so is that what he meant?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Rather than put words in Aristotle&#39;s mouth, or take them out, we should simply remember the MITE or Minimum Tetrahedron, as a component of Kepler&#39;s rhombic dodecahedron.&amp;nbsp; Crisscross each diamond face and pull out the four right angle tetrahedrons.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These Mites also form cubes in assemblies of 24, and the space-filling Coupler (= 8 Mites), an oblate octahedron.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That &quot;Coupler&quot; rhymes with &quot;Kepler&quot;, at least a little, helps hold this memeplex together.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The MITE is space-filling, in other words, as are some of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/03/forbidden-knowledge.html&quot;&gt;the Sytes&lt;/a&gt; built from them.&amp;nbsp; The quarter Rite (also space-filling) is yet another.&amp;nbsp; None of these have &quot;handedness&quot; and so qualify as Sommerville Tetrahedrons, named for the geometer who studied them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What Glenn Stockton calls &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/03/global-matrix-wanderers-meeting.html&quot;&gt;the Global Matrix&lt;/a&gt; includes concentric hexapents, like carbon cages of arbitrary frequency, as a data store and display structure.&amp;nbsp; Such layering for mapping purposes is consistent with other geometry learned from dividing spheres.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/04/gis-2009.html&quot;&gt;Shifting education channels&lt;/a&gt; to help bring these patterns forward into more common everyday awareness could mean putting more emphasis on both Kepler and Aristotle for the reasons mentioned.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When it comes to memes and memetics, the core metaphor is: &quot;connecting the dots&quot; -- the stuff of graph theory and graph databases.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6358953216468416005'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6358953216468416005'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/of-kepler-and-aristotle.html' title='Of Kepler and Aristotle'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>