<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1701'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1676&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1726&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1701</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114124637219198700</id><published>2006-03-01T12:33:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:16.369-08:00</updated><title type='text'>FEMA Villages?</title><content type='html'>I caught some Congress dude pointing to an aerial photo of manufactured homes (huge numbers of them) some 450 miles from ground zero (New Orleans etc.), on C-SPAN (flip flip flip).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He was making a lot of good points e.g. why is FEMA just sitting on these homes, while in the meantime stopping payment on hotel rooms?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;OK cool, so Congress is waking up.  I&#39;m all for it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The reason of course (for sitting on these homes) is there&#39;s this pervasive assumption among bureaucrats that people are undeserving of the valuable services they might provide.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You find this in India a lot:  the greatest satisfaction is in denying others what they most sorely could use.  It&#39;s a back-handed way of meting out justice (however sick and twisted that &quot;justice&quot; may be).  At last, a way to punish, a way to be in control of others, to have some power.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Or on a stereotypical English estate:  the biggest snob is the butler.  If you buy there&#39;s this totem pole or ranking system, and you&#39;re three rungs up the ladder, then &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;no way&lt;/span&gt; are people on rungs one and two going to get above you, come hell or high water.  They&#39;re just scum of the earth after all.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In a democracy, we&#39;re less enamoured of any totem poles in the social stratification sense.  Old timers get respect by default, because their &quot;been there done that&quot; quotient is likely higher.  We acknowledge experience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But in the lifestyle department, we take a more theatrical approach:  people live on different stages, act out in different soaps.  They&#39;re not atop one another.  More like Universal Studios:  the sound stages are laterally dispersed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Does this make any sense at all?  I think so.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the social stratification sense, I consider myself as high as I need to be.  I&#39;ve got a middle income lifestyle and that&#39;s sufficient.  I like being average in that dimension.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ram_Dass&quot;&gt;Ram Dass&lt;/a&gt; was a teacher in this regard:  &quot;keep to the eight fold bath of the upper middle way&quot; he said (like, I wouldn&#39;t mind having a jacuzzi -- might have to up the amps to my fuse boxes though).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And I use my disposable income to man a battle station.  That&#39;s a luxury, privilege, freedom, and right that I have:  to engage in battle, to make alliances, to practice the art of war ala Sun Tzu and Machiavelli.  Bucky was my teacher, but not my only one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our democracy affords me this opportunity.  Thank you Uncle Sam.</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/114124637219198700/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/114124637219198700' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114124637219198700'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114124637219198700'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/03/fema-villages.html' title='FEMA Villages?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114111999290434205</id><published>2006-02-28T10:02:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:16.291-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Levee Town</title><content type='html'>I watched lots of stats marshalling on my CBS TV last night, mostly about approval/dis of that Oval Office guy (oval like a cowboy hat they tell me -- so like how many gallons?).  In this skit I imagine, some pollster&#39;s on the phone:  &quot;so whaddya think of the job our prez is doin&#39;?&quot;  Ten minutes later, phone rings again:  &quot;so how &#39;bout &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;now&lt;/span&gt;?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&#39;s those levees that&#39;ve got &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; attention.  Like, I wouldn&#39;t move back or invest if I thought &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/09/more-global-data.html&quot;&gt;The Flintstones&lt;/a&gt; were still in charge.  Ol&#39; Hurricane Harry of 2010 might obliterate my casino &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;again&lt;/span&gt;.  And what &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;about&lt;/span&gt; those pumps?  They tell me one of the last to croak was this 1929 jobber.  True?  Makes a good story anyway.  And some giant &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mcs.drexel.edu/%7Ecrorres/Archimedes/Screw/SourcesScrew.html&quot;&gt;screw of Archimedes&lt;/a&gt; by Leonardo himself, was still turning at 10 feet under (!) -- not that this helped much.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recall some dinner conversation in Portland, many months before Katrina, where I soaked up some talk about those levees.  New Orleans was a disaster waiting to happen, was the gist of it.  I listened, wide eyed, incredulous, as if to some episode of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Believe It or Not&lt;/span&gt;.  Little did I realize how soon would come my chance to &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;believe&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And at that St. Helen&#39;s viewing center north of here, they show this movie about Mt. Rainier having a bad hair day, shuffing off a glacier or two (no big eruption or anything, just a hiccup, or a sigh), and what &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; might be like.  Picture a sudden river/tsunami smashing through used car lots, playgrounds, Burger Kings.   Did the people evacuate in time?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And that &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/12/forces-of-nature-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;IMAX movie&lt;/a&gt;:  there&#39;s this pattern of earthquakes, marching rather predictably it seems, with Istanbul (or some suburb thereof) in the cross-hairs.  The older mosques have already weathered a few and are still standing.  It&#39;s the speculators who throw up the cheap apartments, cut corners against code, play dice with the lives of Allah&#39;s children.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bottom line:  many disasters have been queued by Mother Nature, a &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;few&lt;/span&gt; of which we&#39;re even half expecting.  God to humans:  &quot;you&#39;ll need to stay alert.&quot;  Humans: (lost in some soap) &quot;upgrading those levees will just have to wait Mr. Almighty Sir, we&#39;ve gotta keep winning against those godless communists!&quot; Satan snickers.  Remember the story: angels were deeply &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;jealous&lt;/span&gt; God had found this new love, these wingless &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;humans&lt;/span&gt;, and the meaner ones (Satan the meanest) just &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;love it&lt;/span&gt; when we goof up big time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another skit:  journalists break into the Pentagon, inner sanctum, expecting to find all these maps of the Middle East, but it turns out everyone&#39;s focused on levees, earthworks, evacuation plans, other civil engineering.  &quot;We haven&#39;t been into war planning for &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;years&lt;/span&gt;,&quot; some general confides sheepishly,  &quot;that&#39;s more a big business thing.&quot; Cutaway to Raytheon or other beltway bandit hide-out: now &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;here&#39;s&lt;/span&gt; a real war room (very reassuring) and yep, a war with Iran might mean selling a few &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;hundred&lt;/span&gt; cruise missiles through Congress (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=kaching&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;kaching!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And hey, speaking of cruise missiles, did anyone even &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;ask&lt;/span&gt; if the word &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fas.org/man/dod-101/sys/smart/bgm-109.htm&quot;&gt;tomahawk&lt;/a&gt;&quot; might be copyrighted?   I bet they owe billions and won&#39;t pay.  Them forked tongue lawyers &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;never&lt;/span&gt; pay -- the Injuns learned that early -- far cheaper to just change the law.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Rrrring&lt;/span&gt;.  &quot;So how &#39;bout &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;now&lt;/span&gt;?&quot;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114111999290434205'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114111999290434205'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/levee-town.html' title='Levee Town'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114090026465927097</id><published>2006-02-26T13:30:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-04-25T20:03:29.162-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Boosting Bandwidth</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/mathworld.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/400/mathworld.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;font-size:85%;&quot; &gt;A Math World&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(click for larger view)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So if a picture is worth 1K words, then 30 frames/sec = 30K words/sec. That&#39;s a lot of info.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course the real differences between frames may be small (static background).  MPEG capitalizes on that.  Gregory Bateson:  information = differences that make a difference.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;An MTV generation has grown up on fast cuts, slick editing, making music &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/02/conundrum.html&quot;&gt;on a multitrack&lt;/a&gt; (if privileged), but then comes formal schooling and a sudden slow-down.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One can hear the gears shearing, the cultures clashing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Like in math class: the... teacher... talks... really... slowly... as she squeaks out some chalkboard algebra, back to the room (spit ball, paper airplane -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=337915401775060679&amp;amp;q=mathematics+nashville&quot;&gt;anything to add bandwidth&lt;/a&gt; (starvation is painful)).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nothing dances, nothing moves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Typical adult response:  kids have been spoiled by TV, can&#39;t concentrate, short attention spans, need drugs (the legal ones).  Oh and Johnny, I&#39;ll be late coming home from work:  watch TV or something.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How about we try meeting them at least half way?  I&#39;m thinking of math movies, DVD clips, flashy shorts with high production values.  Abacus, subtract in base 10, then in base 8.  Play Tom Lehrer&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sing365.com/music/lyric.nsf/SongUnid/EE27EF26A4F581BE48256A7D002575E1&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;New Math&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in the background.  Lots of video collage (mix in some history:  sputnik, Eisenhower, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.toontracker.com/funnyco/funnyco.htm&quot;&gt;Weisenheimer&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then let kids dream up their own, editing/recombining from a growing stash of stock footage.  Mix &#39;n match.  Hip hop TV, and with some real academic content.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Slow down for talking heads, sure (caution:  heads talking).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; saying &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;only&lt;/span&gt; teach this way.  But at least let&#39;s give it a try.  I&#39;ve seen so few good examples to date (&lt;a style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot; href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/power-of-nightmares-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Power of Nightmares&lt;/a&gt; was pretty good, showed off lots of media literacy, but not much in the way of math).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I know this culture is capable of more, much more.  We take pride in our media savvy, yet so often refuse to use it except to push an easy credit, consumer-based lifestyle, combined with &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;fantasies&lt;/span&gt; of being one of those smart people on TV (some doctor, cop, or lawyer -- rarely a priest anymore, unless it&#39;s Robert de Niro on late night cable, or maybe &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tbn.org/&quot;&gt;TBN&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The rest of the world watches our endlessly dumbing it down and rightly wonders:  how low will they go?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://walkingthesea.blogspot.com/2009/04/sesame-street-old-school.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Sesame Street&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was something of a breakthrough, but Big Bird doesn&#39;t know anything about icosahedra, vectors, or complex numbers (or if he does, he isn&#39;t sharing).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Related posts:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=1339786&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;Math on video.google.com&lt;/a&gt; (the early days) @ the Math Forum&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/alien.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Another Alien Curriculum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2006-March/005865.html&quot;&gt;Follow-up thinking on edu-sig&lt;/a&gt; @ &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.python.org/&quot;&gt;python.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=5112846&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;Follow-up thinking on math-teach&lt;/a&gt; @ Math Forum</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114090026465927097'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114090026465927097'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/boosting-bandwidth.html' title='Boosting Bandwidth'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114066618205485316</id><published>2006-02-22T19:10:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-09-10T02:00:33.906-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Back from Catalina</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/catalina.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/catalina.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;font-size:85%;&quot; &gt;Avalon in February&lt;br /&gt;(photo by K. Urner, Olympus Stylus 500)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After a couple blissful days watching breaking waves on Catalina, a movie makers&#39; haven, I&#39;m back in the world of &quot;breaking news&quot; on airport monitors.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;CNN&#39;s &quot;Situation Room&quot; aesthetic seems especially shrill, more like a panic room. Whatever happened to simply monitoring events vs. squeezing them for cheap thrills?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Last night CNN was all about fungus in our pillows, close ups of dust mites. I suggest buying a Kirby if that&#39;s your concern; they suck pillows big time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today we&#39;re all up in arms about globalization, as if there&#39;s no discernable difference between UAE and OBL (they&#39;re both &quot;Arab&quot; right?).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some idiots blow up a mosque and now it&#39;s civil war -- seems there&#39;s a real appetite for it, an eagerness for the next disaster, the next spectacle. Will TV be used to fan the flames or cool them? The medium works wonders either way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;OK I&#39;m venting a bit.  I&#39;ve come down with a mild case of misanthropy.  I&#39;ll shake it soon I hope.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114066618205485316'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114066618205485316'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/back-from-catalina.html' title='Back from Catalina'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114029035166011793</id><published>2006-02-18T11:20:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-06-22T21:25:53.046-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Welcome to Reality</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/cooper.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/cooper.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Writer / Director Stephanie Cooper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;(photo by K. Urner)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Stephanie Cooper’s &lt;i style=&quot;&quot;&gt;Welcome to Reality&lt;/i&gt;, a play in nine scenes, is set in Lone Oak, a small New England town wherein all the adults have committed to a rationalist / literalist mode of thinking, with two exceptions:&lt;span style=&quot;&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;a science fiction writer who speaks of his characters as if they were real, and a civil war buff who believes he was once a rebel captain (sometime before the car accident).&lt;span style=&quot;&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;     &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt; &lt;/o:p&gt;These latter two have no problem relating to Hannah, an eight year old with an imaginary friend, Mr. Teddy the giraffe. &lt;/p&gt;     &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt; &lt;/o:p&gt;But Hannah’s mother and grandmother take the majority view that an imaginary friend is but a stepping stone to madness.&lt;span style=&quot;&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;Hannah should be focusing on learning to count past 29 (she has trouble with 30).&lt;span style=&quot;&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;They and other townspeople conspire to drum the two quirky eccentrics out of town, because of their supposedly subversive influence on the children.&lt;/p&gt;     &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt; &lt;/o:p&gt;Ironically, many of these hyper-rationalist adults later prove defenseless against meme epidemics spreading through popular culture:&lt;span style=&quot;&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;Hannah’s father gets sucked in by the &lt;i style=&quot;&quot;&gt;Left Behind&lt;/i&gt; series, and dissolves his family in order to preach about the coming Rapture in Washington, DC, while Hannah’s grandmother spends her life’s savings on a “Da Vinci tour” in France, organized around Dan Brown’s popular novel, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/08/da-vinci-code-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i style=&quot;&quot;&gt;The Da Vinci Code&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;     &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt; &lt;/o:p&gt;I took Stephanie’s theme to be the danger in not recognizing and nurturing the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/aphiloview2.html&quot;&gt;double-barrel nature of the human psyche&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;span style=&quot;&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;We’re designed to think both logically and mythically. &lt;span style=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Those who fail to responsibly mythologize as free-standing individuals tend to fall prey to mob mythologies created and propagated by others.&lt;span style=&quot;&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;     &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;To stifle one’s powers of imagination, so evident in childhood, is to risk lowering ones immunity against oft times predatory and/or opportunistic belief systems in later life.&lt;/p&gt;     &lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;The actors, a cast of sixteen, put a lot of time and talent into this one-time performance of Stephanie’s senior project. Our venue: Ms. Brunel’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/02/california-state-standards.html&quot;&gt;drama classroom&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wuhsd.k12.ca.us/whittierhs/site/default.asp&quot;&gt;&lt;st1:place st=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;st1:placename st=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Whittier&lt;/st1:placename&gt;  &lt;st1:placetype st=&quot;on&quot;&gt;High School&lt;/st1:placetype&gt;&lt;/st1:place&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, on the evening of February 17, 2006.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114029035166011793'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114029035166011793'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/welcome-to-reality.html' title='Welcome to Reality'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114003031438262410</id><published>2006-02-15T10:54:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2011-10-04T12:42:03.297-07:00</updated><title type='text'>American Islam</title><content type='html'>There&#39;s nothing to stop Islam from being a politically constructive player on the USA domestic scene. &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=7579008&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;Malcolm X&lt;/a&gt; was a trail blazer in this regard.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These emerging schools needn&#39;t take direction from overseas. As a Quaker, I look forward to working with a pacifist branch that understands the Lamb&#39;s War, i.e. we&#39;re in a battle for hearts and minds, fighting against fear, corruption and tyranny. Outward weapons are for losers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Pentagon is shifting gears to focus less on nukes and more on psychological warfare, a positive development (long overdue), and not inconsistent with a warrior class value system, per many Asian examples.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The idea of a war for freedom and liberty isn&#39;t specifically Christian (indeed, many Christians hate our freedoms as surely as some Muslims do).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As a secular state, we&#39;re free to learn from Islamic schools about how to resist terrorism and parasitism in all their ugly forms.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114003031438262410'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114003031438262410'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/american-islam.html' title='American Islam'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113997768783697970</id><published>2006-02-14T20:22:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:15.847-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Jihad</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/zamora.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/zamora.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;mosque in Alabama, by Temcor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nuclear weapons = sin (pride, hubris, Satan -- see &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Paradise Lost&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Allah to humans:  be loyal, disarm.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113997768783697970'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113997768783697970'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/jihad.html' title='Jihad'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113986692995295644</id><published>2006-02-13T14:00:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:15.771-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Mishima: A Life in Four Chapters (movie review)</title><content type='html'>A real joy on this DVD is director Paul Schrader&#39;s commentary, which frames what&#39;s already a multi-level puzzle box of art about art.  The film weaves grayscale memories with color-themed theatrical excerpts from Mishima&#39;s works, within the outer frame of the artist&#39;s final performance, a kind of paramilitary maneuver and homage to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bushido&quot;&gt;bushido culture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mishima was a great post-WWII Japanese writer who, with the rise of film and television, morphed into a media celebrity and cult figure.  He used his prominence to make a statement, signed with the blood of his own surreal and spectacular suicide, along with that of his adjutant, on November 25, 1972.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Scharder&#39;s postmortem commentary in November 2000, at the Lucas Skywalker Ranch, provides insights into the intricate dynamics behind the making of this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0089603/&quot;&gt;1985 film&lt;/a&gt;, which resulted in its being temporarily suppressed in Japan, where Mishima, survived by his widow, remained a controversial figure.  Just making this film took guts, especially if one were Japanese (the foreigners were expected to be insensitive and reckless).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My thanks to Trevor Blake for putting me on to this film, and to Netflix for making it easy to come by.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113986692995295644'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113986692995295644'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/mishima-life-in-four-chapters-movie.html' title='Mishima: A Life in Four Chapters (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113977330831676042</id><published>2006-02-12T11:42:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2017-03-22T22:52:22.724-07:00</updated><title type='text'>More Adventures in Quakerdom</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/P2110058.jpg&quot; onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/P2110058.jpg&quot; style=&quot;cursor: pointer; display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;informative brochure from an outward weaponry museum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;(from the chronofile of Annis and George Bleeke)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tara and I drove out Hwy 26 towards Mt. Hood, to Road 39 past Rhododendron, a small town with a cool relic: a junked &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/02/articulated-bus.html&quot;&gt;articulated bus&lt;/a&gt;, extravagantly tagged, likely one of those Hungarian jobbers we used in Portland for some years (they proved a maintenance nightmare). MMM clerk Peter Ford and I snapped pix when going back to the Rhododendron food market in search of garlic and mustard (we found both).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dawn stayed home to work on the books for MMM (which she converted from Peachtree to Quickbooks) and NPYM among others. I complained to Annis Bleeke that Quakers want too much for their dime, the way my wife gets chained to her computer like that. But of course this was not her doing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I tried to help with her sudoku puzzle but it had a five-star difficulty rating and Annis, of sound logical mind, obviously didn&#39;t much need my help.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I studied her three ring binders, a chronofile of the Bleekes&#39; FWCC adventures for those years when Annis was General Secretary. She had a lot of Africa pix. Annis and George helped me immensely with logistics in Lesotho in 2000, in the wake of the October 13 car accident; the estate sale went very smoothly thanks to them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, while we were standing in line, waiting for food, Janet asked if I&#39;d reconsider being the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/web-wrangling.html&quot;&gt;webkeeper&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npym.org/&quot;&gt;NPYM&lt;/a&gt;, now that Steering Committee had implemented some of my suggestions around boosting network security and smoothing turnover around the webkeeper position. I said OK. So my name goes back to nomcomm, and I&#39;ll likely be assuming my new duties soon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Addendum&lt;/span&gt;:  nope, nomcomm decided to go with someone else, which is good, as it looks like I&#39;ll be heading to Switzerland around the time of NPYM&#39;s Annual Session this year (combined with FGC).&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113977330831676042'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113977330831676042'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/more-adventures-in-quakerdom.html' title='More Adventures in Quakerdom'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113960093519393996</id><published>2006-02-10T11:51:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:15.621-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Yes!</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/outsideinbizmo.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/outsideinbizmo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;photo by K. Urner, Feb 10, 2006&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I usually collect my bizmo pix over in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Bizmo Diaries&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but I&#39;d just been posting on funding services for children, so I thought here might be &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.answers.com/apropos&amp;amp;r=67&quot;&gt;apropos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outsidein.org/&quot;&gt;Outside In&lt;/a&gt; is one of our social service agencies working with youth.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113960093519393996'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113960093519393996'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/yes.html' title='Yes!'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113942760744648993</id><published>2006-02-08T15:08:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:15.547-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Fund the Children?</title><content type='html'>I just got a solicitation call from a nonprofit tasked with publishing a directory of missing children, a kid finder, a locator of some kind.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It sounded extremely important, and apparently this directory is often used by Multnomah County social services, to assist in its job of providing assistance to juveniles and their families.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I did not offer to send any money.  Why?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Because I think County services should get the taxes it needs to generate these directories minus any need to go begging.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That&#39;s a problem in this country: anyone with a worthy cause has to beg, while anyone with a sure-fire way to make dough, all ethics aside, is assured of a friend in Congress.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There&#39;s gotta be some happier medium, even without crossing that dreaded line into 20th century socialism. 20th century capitalism: it&#39;s your &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;company&lt;/span&gt; that owns that computer, so use it to do &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;company&lt;/span&gt; work, not &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;personal&lt;/span&gt; work.  Works great if you&#39;re a company prez like me, of some nebulous &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/01/faq-so-whats-global-data.html&quot;&gt;Global Data&lt;/a&gt; dot net.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course I don&#39;t want the guy who phoned me just now to lose his job. I want him to work full time helping with that missing children situation, not begging for hand-outs. Same with Congress, they deserve more freedom from special interests. Like, we &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;make&lt;/span&gt; them need gobs of money, just to stay in the game, but then say &quot;oh, but bribery is illegal.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the original USA theory, elections could be run cheaply, and some worthy individual with drive, but shallow pockets, could get a crack at holding office. Holding office wasn&#39;t supposed to be an exclusively rich man&#39;s game, not even high office (we differed from Britain in that way). Not even exclusively men (still tends to be though, at least as long as it&#39;s war time).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That&#39;s all gotten stretched out of kilter by now.  Elections were made super expensive (not to mention untrustworthy), and you &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;had&lt;/span&gt; to be on the take somehow, just to get inside the beltway.  Going back to the old ways won&#39;t be easy on any national level.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That&#39;s why I&#39;m suggesting we start local and small.  Like, let the County do its job, don&#39;t make it &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;beg&lt;/span&gt; to save the children. Let&#39;s just save the children already. That&#39;s just our job, as older adults, s&#39;been that way since prehistory (and &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; just if we&#39;re &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/08/march-of-penguins-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;penguins&lt;/a&gt;).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113942760744648993'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113942760744648993'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/fund-children.html' title='Fund the Children?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113942490138271733</id><published>2006-02-08T10:48:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:15.472-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Icosa Globes</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/icosaglobes.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/icosaglobes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;student projects suspended from the classroom ceiling&lt;br /&gt;(photo by K. Urner)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sixth graders in Portland study plate tectonics (Pangea, subduction plates, geological stratification, volcanoes and earthquakes) using these paper fold-up globes.</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/113942490138271733/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/113942490138271733' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113942490138271733'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113942490138271733'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/icosa-globes.html' title='Icosa Globes'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113933750056710122</id><published>2006-02-07T10:40:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:15.384-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Congress at War</title><content type='html'>Congress keeps suckering for this &quot;nation at war&quot; hypothesis, and so eagerly swallows a lot of other bunk, in its mad scramble to please big ticket defense lobbyists.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Like, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;of course&lt;/span&gt; we&#39;re at war, the most profitable damn war the weaponry pros have ever seen:  open ended, an inexhaustable supply of dispensible bad guys, enough religious righteousness to fuel a simmering armageddon to kingdom come.  And so let&#39;s keep recruiting those extras, those fanatics we love to see killed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But doesn&#39;t Congress have the power to say, &quot;hey wait a minute, we&#39;re done with this war&quot;?  That&#39;s happened before.  Wars get called off.  People go back to being civilians.  Soldiers come home from the front.  Why isn&#39;t that happening?  Doesn&#39;t anyone ever win eventually?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No, that&#39;s the whole point:  Congress needs to keep certain people happy, come hell or high water (we&#39;ve had a lot of both).  So war it shall be, grimly, gravely, with much pageantry and show.  A circus for the masses.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Welcome to Rome.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113933750056710122'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113933750056710122'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/congress-at-war.html' title='Congress at War'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113918285687733805</id><published>2006-02-05T15:36:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2012-03-28T11:12:08.409-07:00</updated><title type='text'>History is Surreal</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/nixoninchina.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/nixoninchina.jpg&quot; style=&quot;cursor: pointer; display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Nixon in China&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Or there&#39;s this thread in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergetics Dictionary&lt;/span&gt; (Applewhite):  only the impossible happens.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This picture has the look of one of those posed propaganda posters, but for what episode of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/01/wild-blue-yonder-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Alien World&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Another day in the twilight zone&quot; might be a good caption.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113918285687733805'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113918285687733805'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/history-is-surreal.html' title='History is Surreal'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113907839888266135</id><published>2006-02-04T10:41:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:15.233-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Meeting @ Wired with Sam Lanahan</title><content type='html'>Sam and I had a jovial and convivial meeting regarding his latest explorations in the geometry of Flexblox. We had coffee, plus he had a scone, me a Guinness (&quot;the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;better&lt;/span&gt; breakfast beer&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then, using the Toshiba (my main machine, although KTU2 &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; behaving better lately) we oggled pavilions going up in Beijing for the 2008 Olympics. That &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.beijing2008.com/62/74/article211987462.shtml&quot;&gt;bird&#39;s nest&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.beijing2008.com/81/74/article211987481.shtml&quot;&gt;bubble prism&lt;/a&gt; are breath-takingly bold.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also used the opportunity to share &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=1330849&amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;some of my own strategy maps&lt;/a&gt;, which center around an old theme in this blog: OSCON versus NCTM. I use these two conferences to typify two directions in math/engineering: towards a bright future of open source and tech savvy kids; towards a dreary and pedantic world of more of the same (and lots of clueless adults grousing about how dumb the kids seem to be these days).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m sure NCTM doesn&#39;t appreciate being the symbol of all that is dreary, but just use your own powers of research and track down how many references to Medal of Freedom winner R. Buckminster Fuller you find in the last 20 years of &quot;OK with NCTM&quot; text books. How much synergetics-friendly mathematics?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The NCTM even changed &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/19981212031257/http://www.nctm.org/&quot;&gt;its own logo&lt;/a&gt; to make it &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;less &lt;/span&gt;likely to remind us of an octet truss.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Don&#39;t tell me these Stalinesque cover-ups of huge swatches of history only take place in totalitarian countries. Take any large enough bureaucracy of gutless enough wonders, and watch your edgy little design science curriculum turn into some &quot;safe enough for everyone&quot; pablum.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fortunately, our nation is still free enough to &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; get all marching orders from pedantic and narrow-minded bureaucrats. We have many ways to bypass curricula which don&#39;t treat our students with the dignity and respect they deserve e.g. by short changing them regarding their heritage as Americans. We have the Internet. We have television. We have music. The future looks bright.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113907839888266135'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113907839888266135'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/meeting-wired-with-sam-lanahan.html' title='Meeting @ Wired with Sam Lanahan'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113892451402297552</id><published>2006-02-02T16:58:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:15.159-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Voting Machines</title><content type='html'>I caught Lynn Landes on &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Ed Schultz Show&lt;/span&gt;, KPOJ AM, PDX, somewhere around 2:45 PM today.  She&#39;s a journalist suing the civilian authorities to recover transparency in voting, and now has a docket number with the US Supreme Court.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;From the sound of it, she&#39;s against using machines entirely, at least in their present form, which makes sense, as their transparency is near zero.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So could we ever ensure a computerized voting system was honest?  I imagine ballot type objects, each with a unique ID, and able to reconstitute as printed objects any time we like.  Plus the ID numbers collate under each candidate, forming a cross-check.  Historians get to download the bulk data in some standard format and analyze the hell out of it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We keep it anonymous by not linking ballot ID numbers to people -- which doesn&#39;t mean we lose control on how many or which people get to vote (it&#39;s just &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;how&lt;/span&gt; they vote that we don&#39;t track, not how many times).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With this infrastructure in place, one could randomly create fictitious ballots with known content and shunt then through the system, having them originate with the real votes, indistinguishably therefrom, at the precinct level.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the final count, we would see if our fictitious ballots had been credited properly, as we&#39;d have their ID numbers, which would then become public as not-counted audit checks.  Since the ballot stuffers would come from a black box (stored in more than one location, including with election watch dogs), no vote counter would have a way to tell them apart from bona fide votes.  Any significant miscounting would show up in the postmortem, perhaps voiding the results.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;American Express uses a similar technique to spike proprietary mailing lists; if your store sends junk mail to the list more times than it paid for, various bogus addresses get pinged too many times, and your store gets called on the mat.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;An interesting design question:  should we give individuals privileged access to their own ballot ID number?  Then it&#39;s their secret to keep or reveal.  I could go to the data base via web form, ballot ID in hand, and call up my own voting record.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Any changes to any of my votes would be immediately obvious to me, although without the printed receipt (not counterfeited) no one would have to believe me if it said I&#39;d wanted Chicken Little for president.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some people might keep their ballot receipts just long enough to verify their choices were recorded properly (the ID number links to candidates&#39; names in the relational data base), then destroy them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here&#39;s an idea:  since the NSA is getting more involved on the domestic front, thanks to Al Qaeda, why not have the NSA come up with some new voting machine infrastructure, or at least the specifications?  A consortium of universities could assist with this project.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Network security is a key specialty at the NSA.  If our ability to accurately count the votes is  being impaired by some kind of behind-the-scenes &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.websters-online-dictionary.org/definition/Skullduggery&quot;&gt;skulldudgery&lt;/a&gt;, our USG security establishment should be all about uprooting that.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The integrity of our USA codes is undermined to the extent we&#39;re unable to establish an unbroken link to the actual will of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;we the people&lt;/span&gt;.  The legitimacy of the courts themselves depends on protecting the integrity of this social contract.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Congress has seemed remarkably reluctant to take this bull by the horns and address the widespread concerns of ordinary Americans that our system is broken.  Maybe the executive and/or judicial branches will show more backbone?</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113892451402297552'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113892451402297552'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/voting-machines.html' title='Voting Machines'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113868632623318905</id><published>2006-01-30T21:46:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:15.084-08:00</updated><title type='text'>One: The Movie</title><content type='html'>Dawn and I caught &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0493155/&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; at the Bagdad free of charge. Given the offgassing of fumes from the floor varnish in the soon-to-be pool table room (behind the big screen), management decided to forego the $3 admission and just sell refreshments.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The staff never dimmed the house lights, although I made a special trip to the counter with this request. The dimmer guy was on the phone. Oh well.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyway, as the liner notes and movie script spell out: some middle aged, middle Americans take it into their heads to get a DV cam and make a movie on the meaning of life. As might be expected, given no training or background, they come up with a hodge-podge.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The saving grace of this film is they manage to record some trully talented people sharing honestly and sincerely, including but not limited to several &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/11/acting-locally.html&quot;&gt;VBNs&lt;/a&gt; on the spirituality circuit (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/kiyoshi.html&quot;&gt;some of whom I&#39;d read&lt;/a&gt;, but never seen, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0862201/&quot;&gt;Robert Thurman&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But the interviewers, being somewhat clueless and inane, tend to squander the opportunity by asking &quot;big&quot; questions instead of probing or insightful ones. Now if only we&#39;d had Bill Moyers... There&#39;s also some storyboard about some guy on a &quot;journey&quot; (he rides buses and stuff).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In sum, this isn&#39;t very good reality theater, much as I admire the players.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My sense is there&#39;s tremendous talent out there, especially in the religious sector, ready and willing to rise to the occasion, but a lot of this talent goes untapped. We just don&#39;t have the needed directors yet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The solution may be for more religious groups to see the making of film and television as a divine calling, and not leave it to others to get it right. A role model here might be &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0634897/&quot;&gt;Khyentse Norbu&lt;/a&gt; of Bhutan.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And let&#39;s script in more technology working to alleviate suffering in tangible ways. I&#39;m tired of this ridiculous stereotype that spiritual people can&#39;t do engineering or use computers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Add to all this dumbing down all those supposedly God-directed clowns brandishing firearms and making terrorist TV, and you can see why so many good people tend to marginalize religion as irrelevant at best.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113868632623318905'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113868632623318905'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/one-movie.html' title='One: The Movie'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113840816603631224</id><published>2006-01-27T16:24:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:14.985-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Memo Re Google in China</title><content type='html'>&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Here&#39;s text I just posted to a private Forum I frequent.  The Forum question was about recent news reports, of Google collaborating with aliens to dumb down its search engine service.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;I think Google should play by American rules, meaning Bill of Rights and First Amendment. I didn&#39;t like it when Microsoft pulled that Chinese blog either, because it offended certain readers in China. Many other readers in China, including a small following of journalists, loved that blog, and were deeply hurt that Microsoft would get involved in Chinese politics, and side with some ruling faction against them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If Chinese authorities want to dumb down the Google service, they shouldn&#39;t expect Google to do this work for them. They should build a new franchise, with pass-through to Google, and censoring of what comes back. This franchise should not use Google trademarks, except maybe to confess to clients that they&#39;re piggy-backing on a back end by some other company (truth in advertising).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Or you could just appoint some government minder to stand behind every Chinese student who wants to Google up Tiananmen Square, and use a cudgel.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;See Wikipedia: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tiananmen_Square_protests_of_1989&quot;&gt;Tiananmen_Square_protest_of_1989&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But it&#39;s the Chinese themselves who need to pay for all that extra manpower. Google has enough to do without worrying about local censorship rules. Push that off onto the clients, leave Google free to not dumb down its own service.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kirby&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Addendum:&lt;/span&gt;  please feel free to send an email to Google if you&#39;re in China and can&#39;t google up this Blogspot post, Blogger being a Google service.  Cc me if you like.  Use my Gmail address.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113840816603631224'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113840816603631224'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/memo-re-google-in-china.html' title='Memo Re Google in China'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113823158574282180</id><published>2006-01-25T15:19:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:14.915-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Update from Winterhaven</title><content type='html'>I&#39;m sitting at one of the Win2000 workstations in McCarty&#39;s computer lab, the place where I teach 8th graders on Tuesdays. I&#39;m waiting for Tara to finish some project.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Earlier, I was painting a &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=4252208&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;thumbnail of my vista&lt;/a&gt; here in PDX, sharing it with some community college math teachers, who could use some fresh thinking. Students have become increasingly bored and commensurately rebellious about the traditional math department fare. My sense is we&#39;ve done way too little to rethink our pedagogy in light of what new technology is up to providing. My work here in Portland aims to make up for lost time. If you&#39;ve been reading my blogs, you already pretty much know all about it. Geek TV, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/10/saturday-academy.html&quot;&gt;Saturday Academy&lt;/a&gt; and like that.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m looking at chartering various &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=1327350&quot;&gt;new schooling options&lt;/a&gt;, including for the home based, that will bring new opportunities into focus. The strategy is not to drum up funding so much as give clear definition to the curriculum, and have it fly on its merits. That might not be the best strategy in every context, but here in Portland, we&#39;ve already been given funds, by Google (for open source development), by Bill and Melinda Gates (for redesigning high schools), and by Meyer Memorial Trust (a principal local player).</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/113823158574282180/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/113823158574282180' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113823158574282180'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113823158574282180'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/update-from-winterhaven.html' title='Update from Winterhaven'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113797344931592552</id><published>2006-01-23T10:09:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:14.846-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Another Quaker Story</title><content type='html'>Bruce Kaad was over today, another &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kenwilber.com/&quot;&gt;Ken Wilber&lt;/a&gt; fan, to pick up a ream of thank you letters going out to Friends and affiliated donors who&#39;d been kind enough to kick in.  I used Microsoft Word and Excel to do the job, plus this Brother MFC-8820D, a truly excellent piece of equipment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bruce is Treasurer of MMM, an uncompensated, rotating position, filled by nom comm through a clearness process in Business Meeting (technically another form of worship).  My wife is their hired gun, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bookkeepingcollaborative.org/&quot;&gt;TBC&lt;/a&gt; priestess of nonprofit books (the web site currently sports an Hawai&#39;ian theme, an ironic lament given our rain forest weather (I&#39;m not really complaining, much as I love Maui)).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We&#39;re expecting visitors from the Bend area, other side of the Cascades.  Portland, as you know, is where the Willamette meets the Columbia, in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.answers.com/butte&amp;r=67&quot;&gt;buttes&lt;/a&gt; to the south (Mount Tabor, for example, but a short walk from here).  We serve as a major sea port, though nowhere near as major as Seattle / Tacoma. We&#39;re not a very large city, are the biggest in a chain of cities and towns stretching further south along the Willamette:  Salem, Albany, Corvallis, Madras, Philomath, Eugene.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our principle exports are technological in nature, which is why the moniker &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Silicon Forest&lt;/span&gt; (as distinct from &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Silicon Valley&lt;/span&gt;).  Our Hawthorne district saw the birth of such giants as Tektronix and ESI.  The latter company inherited a &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/planting-seeds-in-silicon-forest.html&quot;&gt;first facility&lt;/a&gt; from Jantzen (swim suit company) and then passed it on to Quakers when required to move.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/08/wanderers-2005830.html&quot;&gt;Doug Strain&lt;/a&gt; was a big part of all that.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another regional headquarters for high tech would be Spokane and its Gonzaga University.  That&#39;s the home of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyan.com/company.php&quot;&gt;Cyan&lt;/a&gt;, makers of the classic &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Myst&lt;/span&gt; series, and &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Uru&lt;/span&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113797344931592552'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113797344931592552'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/another-quaker-story.html' title='Another Quaker Story'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113786419817848536</id><published>2006-01-21T11:43:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:14.777-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Web Wrangling</title><content type='html'>NPYM&#39;s nominating committee (nomcomm) approached me about webmastering for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npym.org/&quot;&gt;NPYM&lt;/a&gt; and I originally said OK.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then it turned out the leadership had no keys to the website -- I&#39;d have to go to whomever is being relieved of duty and beg for the keys (not that this is the actual soap -- the current webmaster and I are friends -- but it &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;could&lt;/span&gt; be, procedurally speaking).  Bad process.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;NPYM needs to be able to change the locks at will. The outgoing webkeeper simply finds the web site subaccount has been rekeyed, while the new webkeeper gets the new keys by some channel. Keys to the master account, with control over the subaccounts, stays with a trusted inner circle (say the NPYM secretary and clerk).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Otherwise, what if we were infiltrated by a bogus webkeeper who then spray painted &quot;work of the devil&quot; all over our pretty NPYM website? More realistically, the webmaster might just start making all kinds of design decisions that don&#39;t jibe with our sense of who we are, and refuse to change course even in the face of negative feedback.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Is NPYM going to say &quot;please kind sir, we&#39;d like you to stop&quot;? That&#39;s silly. That&#39;s the tail wagging the dog. Just decide it&#39;s not working out, change keys, restore from the backup. Should take about 30 seconds, once the decision is made.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The only way to really challenge NPYM at that point, once the web site is truly secure, is to define a schism, i.e. some breakaway rebel team says &quot;we&#39;re the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;real&lt;/span&gt; NPYM.&quot; Happens all the time in religion. In politics too i.e. governments in exile. Or the rebels might just create their own namespace (which is how NPYM itself came into being, having &quot;branched off&quot; from PYM).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After finding out how ramshackle and unprepared the NPYM leadership was to do the job correctly, I started to reconsider. Do I really want to work this hard, starting from scratch with a bunch of amateurs?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My prior commitment is to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/08/web-wrangler.html&quot;&gt;Nirel&lt;/a&gt;, web wrangler for &lt;a href=&quot;http://wwwanderers.org/&quot;&gt;Wanderers&lt;/a&gt;. We&#39;ve never paid her anything, and Wanderers itself is a full time job for Don, her dad (likewise uncompensated). This volunteer family does a dynamite job in my estimation. NPYM is back burner compared to Wardwells and Wanderers in my book, when it comes to advancing my design science agenda (Fuller School business).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So I changed my mind and said no to NPYM nomcomm.  Some other time maybe.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113786419817848536'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113786419817848536'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/web-wrangling.html' title='Web Wrangling'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113775705962578422</id><published>2006-01-20T03:38:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:14.705-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Local Issues</title><content type='html'>So if you live in oil rich &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cia.gov/cia/publications/factbook/geos/qa.html&quot;&gt;Qatar&lt;/a&gt;, far from PDX, you might not know much about our local energy grid. We plug in to Bonneville, started during the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bluebook.state.or.us/cultural/history/history25.htm&quot;&gt;FDR administration&lt;/a&gt;, which was very heavily into public works. Our hydropower network extends back up the Columbia, which is frustrating to &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.google.com/images?svnum=10&amp;q=stealhead&amp;amp;btnG=Search&quot;&gt;salmon&lt;/a&gt; (it was plenty hard even &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;before&lt;/span&gt; all those turbines got in the way).  We export a lot of this hydropower, including on ultra high voltage DC (don&#39;t touch).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So you might wonder, given all this, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wweek.com/story.php?story=7006&amp;page=1&quot;&gt;why we had Enron&lt;/a&gt; trying to run things up here, using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.portlandgeneral.com/Default.asp?bhcp=1&quot;&gt;PGE&lt;/a&gt; as a front company. Enron was a Texas thing after all. What&#39;s that got to do with Oregon? Texas was messing with California too. They tell me Texas has its own power grid, somewhat separate from the surrounding ones, so I&#39;m not sure how they broker everything from Houston or Dallas or whatever. I think they wear big hats and chew stuff. Oregonians have a lot of lame ideas about Texans I think (I drove through there once, on Route 66 or one of those).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here&#39;s something I heard about oil rich princes in Qatar -- this is hearsay and maybe isn&#39;t true. Anxious to try alcohol, but not old enough (because in Islam, you&#39;re &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;never&lt;/span&gt; old enough), these guys with money to burn escape the scrutiny of their elders by boarding commerical jets and flying first class to Europe and places, home by evening (&quot;yeah mom, I learned a lot in school&quot;). The moral depravity begins even before they break out the wine and cheese. I mean, just &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;look&lt;/span&gt; at those stewardesses, not properly covered. For shame!</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113775705962578422'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113775705962578422'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/local-issues.html' title='Local Issues'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113761453974154582</id><published>2006-01-18T12:33:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:12.247-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Quality Time with Wanderers</title><content type='html'>Allen Taylor addressed Wanderers today, on the topic of large scale networks, the Internet in particular, about which he is writing a dissertation.  His offer to write another edition of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;SQL for Dummies&lt;/span&gt; was recently accepted, other deals are in the offing.  The guy stays busy, as does the rest of his talented family.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One upshot of this meeting:  academics writing about the Internet and its networks should be clear about the distinction between the hyperlink topology and the physical topology.  These are somewhat unrelated.  Having a popular web page that a lot of people go to, seemingly more every day, is a more fluid kind of happening than swapping in a new switch, or having to set out in some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lr.org/news/press_releases/2001/pr0801_at_guardian.htm&quot;&gt;fancy satellite-monitored ship&lt;/a&gt;, to fix a break in some cable (which sharks have been known to chew through). Allen is of course completely clear about this difference.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was happy &lt;a href=&quot;http://mitpress2.mit.edu/e-journals/Leonardo/rolodex/voss-andreae.julian.html&quot;&gt;Julian&lt;/a&gt; could come by.  We decided to take the Xmas lights off his statue outside, which prompted a couple &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.celilo.net/&quot;&gt;Celilo Group&lt;/a&gt; staffers to come out and inquire about our doings:  they own the lights, the sculpture is in their patch.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We reassured them we were just trying to make things easier for Terry, reducing the tackiness factor (Xmas lights are long out of season by now, and all that wiring spoils a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.julianvossandreae.com/Work/SlideShowGallery/Seiten/01-pauling.htm&quot;&gt;handsome red molecule&lt;/a&gt; in daylight) -- I said this while leaning on a railing, which started to give way (&quot;please accept my apologies for destroying your building -- I love the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Chinook Book&lt;/span&gt;&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then Julian came by my place to look at geometry puzzles and my &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Barrel Tower&lt;/span&gt; again (a gift from the sculptor).  Julian was privileged to meet with &lt;a href=&quot;http://kennethsnelson.net/&quot;&gt;Ken&lt;/a&gt; in his SoHo studio in 2005.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/01/national-treasure-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Dave Fabik&lt;/a&gt; also joined us this morning, our token Quaker with helicopter gunship experience.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113761453974154582'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113761453974154582'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/quality-time-with-wanderers.html' title='Quality Time with Wanderers'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113743794076789677</id><published>2006-01-16T11:02:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:12.172-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Crime Scene:  Pakistan</title><content type='html'>Fragment of breakfast conversation, over waffles (abbreviating from memory)...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kirby: there&#39;re these giant engines out there that do nothing but look up domain names all day, called DNS servers.  You give &#39;em a domain (like google.com) and they hand you back a number (like 192.168...).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dawn:  sounds more intelligent than missile guidance systems.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tara:  yeah, missiles don&#39;t have to &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; as much.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kirby:  Yep.  Although it&#39;s a missile making the headlines today [see &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Oregonian&lt;/span&gt;].  It&#39;s out and out murder of course, and whoever did it should go to jail for life, but they hide behind the CIA, saying &quot;the CIA did it&quot; (sarcastic voice, impersonating a dumb-ass).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dawn and Tara:  [laughter]</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113743794076789677'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113743794076789677'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/crime-scene-pakistan.html' title='Crime Scene:  Pakistan'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-113726092655109093</id><published>2006-01-14T10:01:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2014-12-20T19:09:42.776-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Quotable Quotes</title><content type='html'>&lt;blockquote&gt;
The computer revolution is about acceleration -- which is necessary to keep global humanity from all the train wrecks that could happen if we kept thinking in such a plodding, low bandwidth, parochial kind of way (not very presidential).&lt;/blockquote&gt;
... if I &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; say so myself.  From this morning, in one of the two threads I&#39;ve sequenced off my &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/12/design-science.html&quot;&gt;summit with Terry&lt;/a&gt;&quot; post.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The TV revolution is/was about the same thing by the way (accommodating globalization by boosting bandwidth). Now that these two technologies are converging, the speed-up is even &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;more&lt;/span&gt; noticable (Alvin Toffler:  accelerating acceleration (wow, a non-zero third derivative)).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
And it&#39;s not like our brains can&#39;t handle it. There&#39;s nothing low bandwidth about life in the jungle, what with those lions &#39;n tigers &#39;n bears, oh my!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The printed word was a bottleneck in many ways. Some learned to suck meaning from text through a fat pipe (mostly strong reader &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/08/elitism.html&quot;&gt;elites&lt;/a&gt; in the humanities), but many folks never developed these skills.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The newer media help level the playing field -- especially if we keep widening the circle of those empowered to roll their own.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Here&#39;s another quotable quote (Bucky this time):&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Marshall McLuhan told me the first day he met me -- on one of the early Doxiadis cruises -- &#39;I am your disciple.&#39; He held up copies of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;No More Secondhand God&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Nine Chains to the Moon&lt;/span&gt; and said &#39;I&#39;ve joined your conspiracy!&#39;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
McLuhan has never made any bones about his indebtedness to me as the original source of most of his ideas.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
E.J. Applewhite, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/SynergeticsDictionary/status.html&quot;&gt;Synergetics Dictionary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Vol 2, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/SynergeticsDictionary/SDCards.php?cn=10229&amp;amp;tp=1&quot;&gt;pg. 592, card 4&lt;/a&gt;. ISBN 0-8240-8729-1 (one typo fixed) -- my copy a gift from the author.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Followup note to media students&lt;/span&gt;: grab the CBS Evening News broadcast on the Monday after this post.  Like some episode out of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Alien World&lt;/span&gt; compared to what viewers were used to. These TV editors were very good at their jobs, even back then, and knew how to whip up these promising new looks; oft times the shape of things to come. [remark added Jan 20]
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;283&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; msallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; oallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/15881789109/player/&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;align center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/align&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: click for larger view ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113726092655109093'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/113726092655109093'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/quotable-quotes.html' title='Quotable Quotes'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>