<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1151'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1126&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1176&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1151</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2006719438688337311</id><published>2009-10-17T00:03:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-10-17T08:11:15.536-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Equipment Drop</title><content type='html'>I&#39;m doing an equipment drop at Circadia, patching in to the wifi for a few. Tomorrow is &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Burn Out&lt;/span&gt;, a festival relating to &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Burning Man&lt;/span&gt;.  Lots of weird buses in the parking lot, a stage crammed with instruments.  Lindsey is volunteering with setup, as well as taking part in the show tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lindsey pulled off a superb performance this evening, shades of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/05/over-hedge-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Over the Hedge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (we met the president of the homeowner&#39;s association).  Another upright piano conquered in any case.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of suburbanite neo-liberals, some of these diversity groups turn out to be little more than the middle class brats seeking to extend both their comfort zone and entitlements.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Python&#39;s is different I&#39;m hoping.  As I posted earlier, to the diversity list:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;The first guideline for diversity trainers might be something like: you have no human right to not be offended, as life is offensive and (here&#39;s the kicker) there&#39;s no one to blame.  It&#39;s like when &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt; Buddha&lt;/span&gt; first left the palace compound, where he&#39;d been spoiled rotten: &quot;who are all these sick and dying around here, is this some inferior species?&quot;  From there to enlightenment was a long and strange journey.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My talk in Vilnius (Jacob was there) featured snake defecation (snake poop), a way I teach about queues and FIFO in early Pythonic math classes, using eat() and poop() methods.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I preface this by saying kids love Grossology (some do) and have these books of Madlibs (fill in the blank stories) that are gross by design. You can code that way too.  Some find this offensive, yet also find they learn Python a lot faster.  No one walked out of my talk, as my slides and presentation were both tasteful, as was my three hour workshop in Chicago which mentioned Hitler&#39;s holocaust and included a scantily clad Britney Spears on one slide (first 57 minutes are &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/03/urner-workshop.html&quot;&gt;on Blip TV&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All that being said, intelligent managers do tend to provide ways for humans to sort themselves, exercising their own freedoms of choice, into niches where they&#39;ll be happy and productive, with co-workers they&#39;re OK teaming with.  Or call them schools (as in schools of fish, schools of thought).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;d be pleased if Pycons were models of well attended, well managed events, and from what I&#39;ve seen so far, I have no reason to expect disappointment.  These are stellar and talented geeks, with every potential to accelerate into multiple Pycons happening with quite high frequency around the world.  But the faster you grow, the more tourists you&#39;ll get checking you out and muddying the waters, hence my plans for more exclusive venues, where BOFs are more likely to find one another.&lt;/blockquote&gt;BOF stands for Birds of a Feather.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of Python, Scott David-Daniels was at the venue this evening.  He struck up a conversation with Lindsey about arms profiteering and how to escape its grip.  They found some points to agree on, given a shared background in IT.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Scott has some papers he&#39;s working on, one about a new data structure (currently undergoing testing), and maybe another about his super fast search algorithm.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Good Bye Party&lt;/span&gt; played the opening gig, will be here tomorrow as well.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2006719438688337311'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2006719438688337311'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/10/equipment-drop.html' title='Equipment Drop'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5011527881874396132</id><published>2009-10-13T12:37:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-10-13T12:42:02.860-07:00</updated><title type='text'>To Wanderers...</title><content type='html'>[replying to internal message traffic on &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;wwwanderers at Yahoo&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yes, pessimism requires scientific justification these days as cognoscenti needn&#39;t be &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/05/wmbs-satire.html&quot;&gt;knee-jerk Malthusians&lt;/a&gt; to gain entre to the best parties.  Of course if you&#39;re &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; knee-jerk... Malthus was a pretty cool guy right?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Regarding power generation, there&#39;re also those slow turning high torque thingys buried under rivers i.e. you have no unsightly or obstructive dams to contend with.  The spin is slow enough to not kill the fish.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2008/09/19/AR2008091903729.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.washingtonpost.com/&lt;wbr&gt;wp-dyn/content/article/2008/&lt;wbr&gt;09/19/AR2008091903729.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Keep in mind that some of the best most fuel efficient cars, e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mpgomatic.com/2008/05/19/mini-cooper-d-65-mpg-diesel-dream/&quot;&gt;a 65 mpg diesel Mini Cooper&lt;/a&gt;, are simply unavailable in the USA because the so-called &quot;capitalists&quot; in this country are for the most part wimps who can&#39;t stomach real competition and puppet Congress to protect them from those with an unfair advantage, such as better engineers.&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(136, 136, 136);&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5011527881874396132'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5011527881874396132'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/10/to-wanderers.html' title='To Wanderers...'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-9111238342020648926</id><published>2009-10-11T11:06:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-28T15:39:30.563-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Subgenius Devival</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157622440758735&quot; title=&quot;Subgenius Devival 2009&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/2611/4000192889_116a780462_w.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Subgenius Devival 2009&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: subgenius devival, pdx 2009 ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our company forked into parallel tracks last night, though in retrospect I wish I&#39;d been positioned to welcome another subgenius into the fold, as this was quite a good show. Reverend Stang was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4002751768/&quot;&gt;in good form&lt;/a&gt;, as were these others from the inner circle.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was checking out this &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Ash Street Saloon&lt;/span&gt; as a possible venue for the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Lindsey Walker Show&lt;/span&gt; and it met my criteria: room for dancing, a distinguishable stage area (preferably raised), and no problems with the neighborhood i.e. compliant with local zoning ordinances. This place definitely qualifies, as do &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Red Cap&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Angelo&#39;s&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Ladd&#39;s Inn&lt;/span&gt;. That&#39;s not to say she won&#39;t book elsewhere, just this is the groove or &quot;ground state&quot; as it were, to get more quantum mechanical about it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Subgenius Church&lt;/span&gt; imitates televangelical fire and brimestoney speech, encourages ranting. The clientèle tend to range to the geeky side, to the point of embracing weird as a badge of honor, like Portland does, or Austin. Bob Dobbs is the titular deity with uber-femme Connie a manifestation of his luckiness (more than smarts). Bob is modeled on the pipe-smoking 1950s salesman figure well-known to Americana lovers. You&#39;ll &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/05/decoding-usa-culture.html&quot;&gt;find him everywhere&lt;/a&gt; in the glossy commercial literature of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/05/american-look-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;that era&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This morning I was more on the serious side, with other earnest Friends engaged in an overhaul of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Faith and Practice&lt;/span&gt;, the privilege of any generation worth its salt (we&#39;re even somewhat inter-generational, though tend to be aging boomer-seniors for the most part -- &quot;geezers&quot; as Jane calls us). That was at Bridge City (hi Larry). Then it was back in the maxi taxi to blog and munch on some factory bread products. Now it&#39;s on to Multnomah Meeting wearing my Oversight hat (metaphorical -- the real deal is around the house someplace), going on foot, testing my iPod.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The reason my iPod needs testing is I went into the red for a &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Toblerone&lt;/span&gt;, to celebrate this first Portland Devival in like a decade. I consumed a lot of it, but stuffed the balance in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3441042342/in/set-72157622440758735/&quot;&gt;my Python fleece&lt;/a&gt; pocket when boarding the 14 bus, not bothering to wrap it in plastic or foil. This proved to have consequences: melted chocolate all over, meaning I spent much of the service licking my iPod, trying to cleanse it of the brown stuff. This was an appropriately kinky and bizarre activity to be engaged in, &lt;a href=&quot;http://pdxdevival.com/&quot;&gt;given the venue&lt;/a&gt;. I was also &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/03/returning-to-pdx.html&quot;&gt;drinking &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Jack Daniels&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, grateful for a little R&amp;amp;R in a war crazy world.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9111238342020648926'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9111238342020648926'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/10/subgenius-devival.html' title='Subgenius Devival'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4255336846413197842</id><published>2009-10-06T22:16:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-10-10T11:50:00.563-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Triangulating</title><content type='html'>I was just posting over on &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergeo&lt;/span&gt; how I&#39;m looking at a conceptual triangle as governing my projects:  Wittgenstein, Synergetics, Python.  Yes, esoteric (&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/10/scholarly-meetup.html&quot;&gt;Esozone conference&lt;/a&gt; coming right up, but nothing scheduled yet on my end).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wittgenstein was a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Jew_of_Linz&quot;&gt;contemporary of Hitler&#39;s&lt;/a&gt;, an Austrian, who ended up in a POW camp in WWI, where he started hammering together a world famous philosophy that made him the darling of Cambridge.  After publishing his magnum opus, he hung up his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3048559779/in/set-72157609640895901/&quot;&gt;academic regalia&lt;/a&gt; and took off into the wilds again, only to return with a slap of the forehead, realizing he&#39;d made some mistakes, or at least now he had a better way of saying what he&#39;d been trying to say.  I did my Princeton thesis on his so-called second philosophy (&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Philosophical Investigations&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;On Certainty&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Remarks on the Foundations of Mathematics&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Philosophical Grammar&lt;/span&gt; etc.).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergetics&lt;/span&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/&quot;&gt;a philosophical language&lt;/a&gt; invented by the famous American born inventor &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/bio.html&quot;&gt;R. Buckminster Fuller&lt;/a&gt;, one of the first jet setters and one of the most intrepid, never traveling as a tourist.  He used this &lt;a href=&quot;http://4dsolutions.net/synergetica/synergetica1.html&quot;&gt;invented language&lt;/a&gt; as a way to anchor all kinds of incoming communications from all over the globe.  He was friends &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/quotable-quotes.html&quot;&gt;with Marshall McLuhan&lt;/a&gt; and the two of them formed the nucleus of a subversive network which also included &quot;Sonny&quot;, my mentor &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/02/ayatollah-of-tetrahedron.html&quot;&gt;E.J. Applewhite&lt;/a&gt;.  The magnum opus is on the web and, like Wittgenstein&#39;s stuff, is very much a topic in these blogs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Python is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.python.org/&quot;&gt;a computer programming language&lt;/a&gt;.  The first language I really respected a lot was APL by Kenneth Iversion, first encountered at Princeton.  Then I followed the xBase trajectory for many years, starting with Ashton-Tate&#39;s dBase II and ending with Microsoft Visual Foxpro (VFP9).  Whereas xBase was retrofitted to become object oriented, I think successfully (it&#39;s a better language than VB), Python was &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=1993475&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;object oriented&lt;/a&gt; from the ground up and is even more intelligently designed.  It reminds me of APL in some ways, although these two are not in the same language family.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How I relate these three vertices of my triangle is as follows:  the later Wittgenstein introduces the notion of &quot;language games&quot; which relates easily to the computer science concept of &quot;namespaces&quot;, which Python well implements.  The idea of namespaces helps thinkers make room in their thinking for remote vocabularies, alien shop talks, extraordinary grammars (philosophies), such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/synergetics/synergetics.html&quot;&gt;Bucky Fuller&#39;s &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergetics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  Given the latter has a lot of geometric content for its core logic, implementing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/cp4e.html&quot;&gt;Python modules&lt;/a&gt; to express this geometry has been yet another edge on this triangle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The mutually reinforcing nature of this design helps guide my curriculum writing, which includes journaling in my blogs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjZfs5T-RTwGUEYR3D0XsPYMxPq-C9yIr-GXvOuNP2eo9_5Pq6_dCJtb2B5-TgYeuOmz1vH4sJEVJfnm0iflruSDMkpJ1sissuygY-nBDGCFKjenKbD-wtWGtckQDcNGxn4zEHb/s1600-h/google_barcode.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 276px; height: 110px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjZfs5T-RTwGUEYR3D0XsPYMxPq-C9yIr-GXvOuNP2eo9_5Pq6_dCJtb2B5-TgYeuOmz1vH4sJEVJfnm0iflruSDMkpJ1sissuygY-nBDGCFKjenKbD-wtWGtckQDcNGxn4zEHb/s320/google_barcode.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5390027062366236578&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: google today ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4255336846413197842'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4255336846413197842'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/10/triangulating.html' title='Triangulating'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjZfs5T-RTwGUEYR3D0XsPYMxPq-C9yIr-GXvOuNP2eo9_5Pq6_dCJtb2B5-TgYeuOmz1vH4sJEVJfnm0iflruSDMkpJ1sissuygY-nBDGCFKjenKbD-wtWGtckQDcNGxn4zEHb/s72-c/google_barcode.gif" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5128456109945374708</id><published>2009-10-05T11:15:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-10-06T00:39:14.537-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Eyes Wide Shut (movie review)</title><content type='html'>I&#39;ve long been curious about this movie, given I&#39;m a Stanley Kubrick fan.  This was my first time seeing it, and I wasn&#39;t sure what to expect.  I was pleasantly surprised, as I&#39;d been bracing for some kind of horror movie, not upper crust New York, more like Woody Allen world, lots of doormen and taxi cabs, around people who have everything and then some.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tom and Nicole (the celeb stars in their characters) manage to get into a fight over the price of holy matrimony.  It seems to work for the daddy-I-want-a-pony minded, and indeed daddy is used to spending money, but it&#39;s rough on the couple.  Daddy is off at work, looking at naked women all day (he&#39;s a doctor) while mommy is highly appreciated by members of the opposite sex (as well as her own) yet does all that semi-boring staying home stuff (nice pad!), while wondering what her husband is really up to out there.  Little does she know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As a result of the fight, Tom at least gets that he&#39;s taking too much for granted.  He&#39;s now haunted by the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112579/&quot;&gt;Bridges of Madison County&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112579/&quot;&gt; story&lt;/a&gt;, with someone besides him as Clint Eastwood.  That&#39;s disturbing of his equilibrium and he goes off the deep end into film noir country, in this case a kinky patriarchy full of voyeurs, ala Elizabethan Era Globe Theater (the origins of stagecraft in English, inheriting &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/05/squanderers.html&quot;&gt;from Greeks&lt;/a&gt; via Romans).  As private cave DVD watchers, we join the rest of the masked (and Tom) for some brief peep show.  No, we don&#39;t have limos either, aren&#39;t that politically powerful, but at least we have VCRs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What&#39;s amusing about this film is that Tom &amp;amp; Nicole ride so high in their social network that the &quot;dark underworld&quot; of pulp fiction seems just as out of reach in the sense of economically advantaged.  The two temptress roommates are pretty much like my girlfriends &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/05/princeton-25th-reunion.html&quot;&gt;at Princeton&lt;/a&gt;, well off enough to afford a slumdog apartment in The Village (we weren&#39;t actually that well off by a long shot, lived &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/10/our-big-new-york-adventure.html&quot;&gt;in Jersey City&lt;/a&gt; until finding that place in the Big Apple (where my girlfriends moved, me staying behind to teach in a Catholic girls&#39; school, but I digress)).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tom Cruise, being in over his head, out of his element, is what adds levity to this interesting film.  He keeps flashing that doctor badge like it&#39;s supposed to justify his playing private detective or undercover cop, like &quot;hello, I&#39;m Kojak, just let me wake you up in the middle of the night so I can dress up and go to a kinky party in the steens&quot; (or wherever that was).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Obviously I&#39;m coming from some kind of economic jealousy angle, which I think the film consciously encourages.  We have a hard time feeling sorry for these well off people and their exciting lives, identify more with the working class who keep getting to take Tom&#39;s coat.  I&#39;m coming from being the limo chauffeur probably, stuck outside with the taxi driver, not even blindfolded because I can&#39;t play some fool musical instrument, plus I suck at sleazy dancing like that guy at the party was doing, sucking up to Nicole (whom I&#39;d gladly suck up to if I could figure an angle, but then &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/12/hollywood-usa.html&quot;&gt;glitzy LA aka Hollywood&lt;/a&gt; is hardly my stomping grounds;  I&#39;m a fish out of water in that neighborhood (that&#39;s more Governator turf)).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of Hollywood, earlier last night I saw &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/08/which-hollywood-star-for-president.html&quot;&gt;Whoopi Goldberg&lt;/a&gt; apparently likin&lt;i&gt;g Google Android&lt;/i&gt; on the LCD flats (at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Claudia&#39;s&lt;/span&gt; sports bar on SE 30th &amp;amp; Hawthorne).  We also saw boomers in a &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Windows 7&lt;/span&gt; commercial; I advised Annis to try extending the life of the old Toshiba to take advantage of Xmas discounts on new laptops with that Microsoft OS, more suitable for &quot;normal people&quot; than GNU/Linux maybe (a geek favorite), and less Cadillacy than MacOSX.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Open source (e.g. Python) runs on all of the above so I&#39;m not required to be dogmatically against all proprietary layers above and below my level (talking &quot;chip-to-cloud stack&quot;), even though copylefting more assets remains a worthy undertaking and goal.  I&#39;d like freedom to gain and/or hold on to some stack pieces at all levels, making purists happy while continuing to leverage economies of scale.  To this end, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2009-October/009596.html&quot;&gt;I encourage free products to advertise&lt;/a&gt;, given boosting sale price has never been the only motivation for flaunting what you&#39;ve got.  There&#39;s also simply recruiting a user base (cite the Java campaign, or the PR for ostensibly not-for-profit religious brands, Quakers included).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5128456109945374708'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5128456109945374708'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/10/eyes-wide-shut-movie-review.html' title='Eyes Wide Shut (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8055662669024073154</id><published>2009-10-02T10:22:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2022-06-28T09:00:06.548-07:00</updated><title type='text'>High School Geometry</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157612330643992&quot; title=&quot;Synergetics&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Synergetics&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/3108/3179826263_17682c5d68.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: math cast by 4D Studios ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;My proposal to teach &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/09/random-posting.html&quot;&gt;a non-Euclidean geometry&lt;/a&gt; as a part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/&quot;&gt;4D spun&lt;/a&gt; DM track (digital math track) is met with ridicule in some circles, as isn&#39;t the priority to gain some grounding in Euclid first, before delving into college level topics?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

These ridiculers may not appreciate the meaning of dialog and/or dialectic that much, not having studied philosophy maybe.  The Platonists, taking a page from the Sophists, continued the tradition of recording conversations, debates.  One needed interlocutors, like what we see on listservs today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

In other words, to really &quot;get Euclid&quot; you&#39;ll need to contrast his metaphysics with some other&#39;s, say that of Democritus (our &quot;patron saint of discrete math&quot; -- as in: &quot;it gets down to atoms&quot; (quanta) vs. continua).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

The pragmatists don&#39;t so lazily resort to ridicule in the opening frames, but do worry we&#39;re muddying the waters.  These might be neo-liberals or neo-cons, secretly and somewhat desperately hard at work to shore up some central authority (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/07/wanderers-2009729.html&quot;&gt;an imagined monarchy&lt;/a&gt;). The idea of young children questioning the existence of &quot;infinite planes&quot; and/or &quot;perfect solids&quot; just sounds like chaos to them.  What will they doubt next?  The existence of &quot;real numbers&quot;?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

One solution in this case is fairly easy to implement:  keep these worry wart types teaching along the creaky old analog math track (aka the status quo in 2009), a sequence of connected curriculum segments already well memorialized in any number of textbooks, some better than others (Dolciani gets some respect, also Saxon, whereas some brands of corporate pabulum cut way too many corners, leaving many in the Lower48 with mush for brains, &quot;pseudo-educated&quot; as Dom Rosa would say).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

In other words, don&#39;t &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; them muddy these waters they&#39;re so worried about muddying -- leave this non-Euclidean stuff to the certified gnu math teachers, properly trained to not botch it.  They have a computer at their elbow (know two or more coding languages), have enough linear algebra to teach the neo-Euclideans&#39; XYZ orthodoxies, even as they express skepticism in the face of its more dogmatic apologists (you&#39;ll find these zealots in all walks of life).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Just zooming back from an ancient greek geometer, sketching a proof in the sand with a stick, showing it&#39;s on a beach, on a ball (ala Google Earth), not something infinitely flat, would be too subversive for some teachers to handle.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/01/some-space-program-history.html&quot;&gt;The space program&lt;/a&gt; sort of went over their heads maybe.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

But in a school truly committed to diversity (do they have &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/09/equinox-retreat.html&quot;&gt;a statement&lt;/a&gt;?), students will have some leverage, as will the parents.  If you don&#39;t have a spanking new DM track, hotly relevant with lots of bright screens, maybe contact your state and/or local representatives.  Ask about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/09/responding-to-critics.html&quot;&gt;new standards&lt;/a&gt;, the new K-12 pipeline.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh2soOMMqi4WH5gRQVhbKejBAQM6t9y-EXpdTyylkLqDz2QDkZRnws4pcrP3zEhNLD-ekTycfoN52ON8i8QKJDAqjCMiHkc_ZtRWZ7swiast22msnrR78c6i7rL8jVU0LeHCUY9/s1600-h/gandhi09.gif&quot; onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5388066326992917554&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh2soOMMqi4WH5gRQVhbKejBAQM6t9y-EXpdTyylkLqDz2QDkZRnws4pcrP3zEhNLD-ekTycfoN52ON8i8QKJDAqjCMiHkc_ZtRWZ7swiast22msnrR78c6i7rL8jVU0LeHCUY9/s320/gandhi09.gif&quot; style=&quot;cursor: pointer; display: block; height: 125px; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; width: 320px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/11/linus-pauling-in-news.html&quot;&gt;question authority&lt;/a&gt; ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8055662669024073154'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8055662669024073154'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/10/high-school-geometry.html' title='High School Geometry'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh2soOMMqi4WH5gRQVhbKejBAQM6t9y-EXpdTyylkLqDz2QDkZRnws4pcrP3zEhNLD-ekTycfoN52ON8i8QKJDAqjCMiHkc_ZtRWZ7swiast22msnrR78c6i7rL8jVU0LeHCUY9/s72-c/gandhi09.gif" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1068170940250755218</id><published>2009-09-29T12:10:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-09-29T17:10:54.466-07:00</updated><title type='text'>More Gardening</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3926676055/&quot; title=&quot;HPIM0672 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3424/3926676055_a119c9d299_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HPIM0672&quot; width=&quot;180&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=6855004&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;we also teach gardening&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The philosophical underpinnings of the garden remain important.  Better the seeds be harvested directly from the local scene than obtained through the cash economy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The game is to develop using biological methods having root access in ways money does not, unless converted from bracelets back to cows (a few bulls) per &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/01/wheres-beef.html&quot;&gt;the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Critical Path&lt;/span&gt; codec&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The dirt pile was developed with assistance from a borrowed pickup truck.  Various flavors of compost will be mixed for raised beds.  This is a process any family with a lawn might engage in, if &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/urban-edibles.html&quot;&gt;seeking urban edibles&lt;/a&gt;.  Which reminds me, we met at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Back Space&lt;/span&gt; again.  I got it all working on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3951019433/&quot;&gt;the Starling&lt;/a&gt;, with Mark giving me some invaluable pointers on how to operate it more successfully.  He&#39;s a pretty &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/09/september-ppug.html&quot;&gt;brilliant guy&lt;/a&gt; I think.  And yes, there&#39;s a plan to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/09/geodjango.html&quot;&gt;go with GeoDjango&lt;/a&gt;.  I&#39;m recruiting talent from PSU and such places.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We elected not to view &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Constant Gardener&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/12/limiting-ball.html&quot;&gt;the Boltons&#39;&lt;/a&gt; last night, though I am eager to learn of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/10/fine-friday.html&quot;&gt;Maureen&#39;s adventures&lt;/a&gt; in Kenya.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/05/constant-gardener-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;I&#39;d seen the movie&lt;/a&gt;, even read the book, had all this pending business to attend to, including around Quarterly Meeting.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of which, Glenn and I just met Lisa at the corner of 37th &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/2943807898/&quot;&gt;at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Bagdad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to discuss options.  She was on a bicycle, whereas my party was walking Weird Sarah to Laurelhurst Park (a designated off-leash area in the neighborhood).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/09/coffee-shop-show.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Private Party&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/09/private-party.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Duke&#39;s Landing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was recorded live (about 3.5 hours) and sliced up into 109 separately entitled tracks for archiving and blogging.  At least half of them are dialog.  Some of the song takes are headed straight to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.myspace.com/lindseywalkermusic&quot;&gt;the Myspace site&lt;/a&gt; whereas some of the more private stuff will go exclusively to event participants, at least at first (the most recent plan, as of this writing).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We&#39;re happy to have a mobile sound studio solution so that rough cut recordings get some air time.  I&#39;d like to add video at some point and find some R-rated TV slot on community access, or just burn straight to DVD.  The various video products will then draw from this raw footage.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/02/outreach-to-japan.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Coffee Shops Network&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is already a client.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lindsey is not playing covers so there are no issues around who controls the music at this point.  Most cities have a Wild West of this kind, frequented by talent scouts, intrepid tourists.  I&#39;ve not spent much time &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/03/temple-to-athena.html&quot;&gt;in Nashville&lt;/a&gt;, yet imagine &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/08/gibson-bizmo.html&quot;&gt;something similar&lt;/a&gt;.  Savannah must not be that different either, given Lindsey&#39;s duck to water transition to the PDX music scene.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Glenn suggested I nudge Trevor to get Lindsey a slot at the upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.esozone.com/&quot;&gt;Esozone conference&lt;/a&gt;.  That&#39;s smart thinking, whether it happens or not.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgHZbY-mdjIJdzP9jETpFhYy-LaLerMFCyEa4GSbetGXRO4gnLv7kTSrfQTodph-Kq2FiotsDnARKVwwDFVAmbjNhQsZry9CQsw-UhUq9V8WUw5OA3yHgSouhvZSvkck0yoSQWn/s1600-h/kgb_party_cia_invited.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 207px; height: 320px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgHZbY-mdjIJdzP9jETpFhYy-LaLerMFCyEa4GSbetGXRO4gnLv7kTSrfQTodph-Kq2FiotsDnARKVwwDFVAmbjNhQsZry9CQsw-UhUq9V8WUw5OA3yHgSouhvZSvkck0yoSQWn/s320/kgb_party_cia_invited.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5386997636766312770&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1068170940250755218'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1068170940250755218'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/09/more-gardening.html' title='More Gardening'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3424/3926676055_a119c9d299_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3836695355323736900</id><published>2009-09-27T18:54:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-09-29T13:36:50.441-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Architects of Control (movie review)</title><content type='html'>This comes from the equivalent of the horror shelf at the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Laughing Horse&lt;/span&gt; co-op.  Michael Tsarion does a stream of consciousness rant, eloquent yet annoyed at peoples&#39; evident gullibility.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He pushes the conspiracy theorist envelope by bringing in a lot of interesting history and fringe characters, providing a kind of 101 introduction to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freelists.org/post/wittrs/Reforming-Wittrs-Volume-of-Mail-Etc,9&quot;&gt;Esozone type threads&lt;/a&gt;, ala &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Da Vinci Code&lt;/span&gt; and like that.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One gets the impression the mind controllers hold all the high cards (&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/10/we-are-borg.html&quot;&gt;resistance is futile...&lt;/a&gt;&quot;), plus the production values are good, so this becomes one more mesmerizing piece of media in the hard to find category.  The irony in controlling (checking the power of) other mind controllers is not lost on this audience.  Spin doctors R us eh?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scene where Clark Kent and Superman get into a knock down drag out fight in a junk yard... where was that from again?  What are these movies we keep excerpting?  I admit to being out of the loop on a lot of pop culture.  &quot;What&#39;s the difference between sorcery and magic?&quot; is one of the questions, fair warning to the science-minded that we&#39;re talking to your irrational side in this film -- but about building up your rational powers as a counter, heightening your skepticism quotient.  That&#39;s a positive community service in my book, so I&#39;m hardly panning this film.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Michael reminds me of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/05/wanderers-2008513.html&quot;&gt;our own Alex Ansary&lt;/a&gt;, a kind of on-steroids version given all the help he&#39;s been getting from props and production.  I recommend this film if only for the archival footage and the obscure historical allusions.  This was only Program One in the series, after which I fell back into a passive state, the effect of the trigger words having worn off already.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Followup: when Maureen showed up next day, I offered to screen this to &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/02/methodist-morning.html&quot;&gt;her United Methodists&lt;/a&gt;, maybe answer questions.  But then it&#39;s not mine to show in public, could get in trouble &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/09/wanderers-2009923.html&quot;&gt;with ASCAP&lt;/a&gt; or one of those.  Also:  the excerpts from other movies are clearly labeled i.e. I don&#39;t want to leave the misapprehension this isn&#39;t a scholarly work with the equivalent of video footnotes.  Plenty of thinking went in to this rendition.  I haven&#39;t seen Program Two yet (it&#39;s a four DVD set right?).  &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Laughing Horse&lt;/span&gt; only has Program One.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3836695355323736900'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3836695355323736900'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/09/architects-of-control-movie-review.html' title='Architects of Control (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6444481809858794998</id><published>2009-09-19T16:42:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-17T15:08:13.356-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Equinox Retreat</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157622422453330&quot; title=&quot;Equinox 2009&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/2639/3939194372_32971f7e5d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Equinox 2009&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
  
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: fall equinox 2009 ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Shomar is here, a favorite Wanderer. Dr. Nick is sauntering through. Dr. Tag is at the beach maybe?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I attended a neighborhood meeting of the Palestinian rights group recently, focused on Palestine&#39;s right to exist. There&#39;s an initiative at local schools to have students notice whenever Palestine is bleeped over as a &quot;forbidden state&quot; (one of a long list of banned and/or esoteric institutions).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We also discussed the two and no state solutions, the former being a neoliberal preference, the latter having to do with demoting nations more generally, treating them as tourist attractions ala EPCOT i.e. less as a part of Tomorrowland (the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/02/flash-forward.html&quot;&gt;Spaceship Earth projection&lt;/a&gt; cite BuckyBall).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Linus Pauling House is nearby, so some of this thinking spills over (97214 is close knit).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The PSF has the following Diversity Statement, still in beta, thanks to a bunch of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/09/barcamp-alpha.html&quot;&gt;alpha geeks&lt;/a&gt; hacking:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
The Python community is a global community. The Python Software Foundation and the broader community of which it is a part welcome and encourage participation by all. Our community is based on mutual respect, tolerance and encouragement, and we strive to help each other live up to these ideals. We would like our community to be more diverse, so we extend an especially warm welcome to everyone who will broaden it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I was out until 3 AM last night with the Lindsey Walker Show, enjoying the scene at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Local Lounge&lt;/span&gt; on MLK. We used the company car. I&#39;m still a little retarded regarding set up and tear down, especially w/r to the Bose Tower. Her skills surpass mine w/r to SQL probably, too, though with the Django product &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/urban-edibles.html&quot;&gt;Urban Edibles&lt;/a&gt;, we&#39;re one step removed from raw SQL, thanks to the data model. If she comes by the Pauling House, I&#39;ll steer her towards Steve&#39;s eggplant dish, pretty tasty.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6444481809858794998'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6444481809858794998'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/09/equinox-retreat.html' title='Equinox Retreat'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3472254352201642229</id><published>2009-09-12T22:58:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2023-08-23T10:28:39.725-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Beautiful Pizza</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157622228719807&quot; title=&quot;J. Shea&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/3495/3913248545_64aa1d13ab_w.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;J. Shea&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: art by J. Shea ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;I went by &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Fine Grind&lt;/span&gt; today to show Joe the pictures I&#39;d snapped of his artworks &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lizardloungepdx.com/&quot;&gt;at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Lizard Lounge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  Tag and I checked it out a few days ago.  This is mostly a retail outlet for clothing and accessories, but offers coffee and a couple workstations.  Blending in some art gallery motifs works well in this ambiance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My other work at FG was to set up a developer&#39;s workbench vis-a-vis VPython and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2009-September/009530.html&quot;&gt;document some of the steps on edu-sig&lt;/a&gt;.  Those of you following my curriculum writing know that I put a lot of stress on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vpython.org/&quot;&gt;the VPython add-on&lt;/a&gt;, which bridges Python to OpenGL in a manner friendly to ordinary mortals who just want a simple API for real time spatial renditions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Over on &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergeo&lt;/span&gt;, I&#39;ve been consolidating some of the gains we&#39;ve made around the T, E and K modules and their respective rhombic triacontahedra of volumes 5, 5+ and 7.5 respectively.  Of course these values are in tetravolumes, a feature of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/07/practicing-multiculturalism.html&quot;&gt;this Portland ethnomathematics I share &lt;/a&gt;through &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Coffee Shops Network&lt;/a&gt;, Esozone, Saturday Academy and &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/08/education-planning.html&quot;&gt;other places&lt;/a&gt;.  We&#39;re training a next generation of advertiser... designer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The title of this post refers to the venue from which I&#39;m posting.  After a long day in service of my country, it&#39;s great to get some R&amp;amp;R listening to a favorite vocalist and friend who also happens to be a talented rock star.  Life is good sometimes.  The set is over now.  Lindsey is having some well deserved beer and pizza with the newest fans -- all guys here tonight, with a mix of passers by checking us out through the window.  She&#39;s talking &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/01/repatriation.html&quot;&gt;solidarity with the soldiers&lt;/a&gt;, other policies (yes, I&#39;m eavesdropping).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ve been working on this Starling / System76 since 8 PM, still have up to an hour of battery life.  I&#39;m so far pleased with this netbook, although it doesn&#39;t let me get away with being as ham handed as I&#39;m used to.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3472254352201642229'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3472254352201642229'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/09/beautiful-pizza.html' title='Beautiful Pizza'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-477542169519879078</id><published>2009-09-10T09:46:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-09-12T12:38:07.428-07:00</updated><title type='text'>DjangoCon (Day 3)</title><content type='html'>Our keynote speaker this morning is Ted Leung from Sun Microsystems.  He&#39;s giving us the 10,000 foot view wherein DjangoLand is but one domain among many, albeit a robust one (he likes our Pony, currently at the front of the room, enwrapped by you know who).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We&#39;re looking at some of the Erlang competitors, though not in much detail, such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://nitrogenproject.com/&quot;&gt;Nitrogen&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/webmachine/wiki/WebmachineSetup&quot;&gt;Webmachine&lt;/a&gt;.  Then of course there&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://liftweb.net/&quot;&gt;Lift&lt;/a&gt;, written in Scala, a JVM language, with brilliant support for Comet.  Not everyone is using Python for everything, so true.  Some are using Jython.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kirby&#39;s aside:  So WTF is Comet?  Checking...  OK, basically AJAX on steroids, doesn&#39;t stand for anything, means the server might be aggressive about updating its clients, doesn&#39;t lazily wait for http requests.  More of a udp datagrams model.  Think of a multi-user game environment (business lingo:  multi-user collaboration tool) wherein every player needs frequent updates, even if only passively.  Think of Twisted, already a basis for such global game playing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Chris McAvoy, on cold meds, is talking about Django on Jython.  Most attenders have flooded the &quot;scaling your django applications&quot; in the room next door, now that the ballroom has divided in half (I say ballroom somewhat sloppily, as there&#39;s no ball in here, let alone a hexapent version).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He&#39;s suggesting JRuby and JPython define an Enterprise-y web framework that&#39;s more agile than the usual Oracle, &quot;portal&quot;, Websphere kind of stuff.  &quot;We&#39;re all ops people now&quot; in the sense that writing the app is now the easy part.  It&#39;s the Apache / mod_wsgi crap that&#39;s killing us.  So how is Django on Jython an answer?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pip django-jython to build WAR files, get the zxJDBC package for chatting with Postgres, SQLlite (MySQL still in the works -- ironic given Sun&#39;s position here).  Sequence:  use virtualenv, install pip, pip install Django 1.1, install patch django-jython.  http://bit.ly/django-jython-fix for Django 1.1, delete settings$py.class if you&#39;re using 1.0 for some silly reason.  Forget about models.ImageField -- you won&#39;t have PIL.  If PIL moves to ctypes...  doj.backends.zxjdbc.postgresql will be your database_engine in settings.py (for example).  jython manage.py war is going to roll up your stuff for throwing over the wall to admins (for deployment).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Andy McKay is giving &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.agmweb.ca/blog/andy/2224/&quot;&gt;a fascinating talk&lt;/a&gt; about his trip to Kenya in support of health care workers, originally &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rapidsms.org/about/projects/rapidresponse/&quot;&gt;using Rapidsms&lt;/a&gt;, similar to Twitter on cell phones.  Kenya has great cell phone coverage.  He&#39;s learned a lot about malnourishment.  &quot;Robbed of vital nutrients as children they grow up stunted and sickly, weaklings in a land that still runs on manual labor.&quot; (NYT).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Andy helped wire Django in as the switchboard for sms messages in the field, forwarding to the clinic.  An Eee PC running Ubuntu is the server.  One of the bugs was in spomskyd, a Ruby daemon.  pygsm has since replaced spomskyd (&quot;Ruby rubbish&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Malaria was added to malnutrition, as another set of sms messages.  He also branched out to Malawi.  from rapidsms.message import Message gives you the sms messages.  urls.py makes routing sms commands easy -- so what these aren&#39;t urls.  A non-standard use case, woo hoo.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/simon/classbased-views-with-django&quot;&gt;Class based views&lt;/a&gt; to the rescue when Malawi wanted a different command set -- just subclass.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/andymckay/django-rapidsms-malnutrition/tree/master&quot;&gt;Here&#39;s some code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Erich Ocean:  HTML5 is a technical spec, but culturally its more a Flash killer.  The beefy JavaScript engines are making a big difference.  Dynamic languages win again (sorry Java).  &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SproutCore&quot;&gt;SproutCore&lt;/a&gt; is the HTML5 application framework adopted by and now developed at Apple.  It&#39;s open source, like WebKit and LLVM.  Erich thinks &lt;a href=&quot;http://webkit.org/&quot;&gt;WebKit&lt;/a&gt; is the future for the browser, thinks Django is well positioned on the server side. Webkit will run on Windows.  HTML5 is moving faster than many think.  You&#39;ll be able to sneak WebKit in the back door into IE6 even.  This talk relates to the anticipated future of low latency push apps that keep updating the browser without waiting for client-side requests i.e. like Comet (see above).  HTML5 web sockets...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dr. Russell Keith-Magee:  &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;No! Bad Pony!&lt;/span&gt;  A &quot;pony&quot; is shorthand for &quot;desirable feature&quot; in some ways.  &quot;Daddy, I want a pony&quot; might be a typical developer&#39;s feature request to the Django core developers.  The core  developers, being protective of the project&#39;s aesthetics, as well as being busy, often have to say &quot;No!&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lightning talks:  lots of good stuff,  James K. Tauber made use of Steve Holden&#39;s input to welcome us to the wider Python community, giving some sense of what Python Software Foundation is doing in the world.  He gave a second lightning talk about how to pronounce &quot;Django&quot; -- very technical, plus 30 seconds over, meaning the Pony was thrown (raised an exception).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/477542169519879078'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/477542169519879078'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/09/djangocon-day-3.html' title='DjangoCon (Day 3)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-435875621710679783</id><published>2009-09-09T11:19:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-09-12T12:42:50.421-07:00</updated><title type='text'>GeoDjango</title><content type='html'>This talk helps me integrate many themes from these blogs.  Our speaker, Adam Fast, is from Lawrence, Kansas, the Django HQS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He&#39;s showing some really cool geodjango apps that he&#39;s worked on, including one with all the bird strike data coming from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wxgk.net/&quot;&gt;the nation&#39;s airports&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He uses PostGIS with Postgres.  MySQL is really quite deficient in this area.  django.contrib.gis and a custom test runner are needed.  Set some POSTGIS stuff in settings.py.  You&#39;ll have these different field types in models.  You need objects = models.GeoManager().  You can start getting points on maps right in the custom Admin.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;GeoPy is a great dependency for talking to the different map service back ends, e.g. Google&#39;s and Yahoo&#39;s.  It&#39;s really easy to do polygon stuff, like with zip codes.  His example &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/09/forced-march.html&quot;&gt;uses 97214&lt;/a&gt;.  Distance lookups are also easy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So shouldn&#39;t &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/urban-edibles.html&quot;&gt;Urban Edibles&lt;/a&gt; be a GeoDjango application?  Maybe it is at this point.  I&#39;ve been out of that loop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is the kind of free stuff we need in Portland Public Schools.  Yes, we&#39;ll need lots of scaffolding to get set up.  A lot of that is already available in the form of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2009-September/009528.html&quot;&gt;tutorial code&lt;/a&gt; on the web.  These geographic coordinate systems aren&#39;t going away and the resources are plentiful.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Advice re some of the gotchas:  geometries are big, maybe use .defer().  You don&#39;t want huge data sets going over the wire with every page request.  Xapian and SOLR might help with search down the road but for now searching isn&#39;t as straightfoward as it might be.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This stuff is really cool.  Is anyone at PSU a GeoDjango expert?  I went up after the talk to ask some questions about ramping up from inside IDLE at first, then moving to a dev server for maps &#39;n stuff.  Adam thought that&#39;d be highly doable.  PyGeo by itself, without Django at all, would be a good place to start, for like the stuff we were doing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/winterhaven/&quot;&gt;at Winterhaven in 2006&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Clever tweet:  &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/jtauber&quot; class=&quot;screen-name&quot; title=&quot;James Tauber&quot;&gt;jtauber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; RT @&lt;a class=&quot;tweet-url username&quot; href=&quot;http://twitter.com/dartdog&quot;&gt;dartdog&lt;/a&gt;: it is about to be 09-09-09-09 must be a continuation of @&lt;a class=&quot;tweet-url username&quot; href=&quot;http://twitter.com/jtauber&quot;&gt;jtauber&lt;/a&gt; &#39;s plot at &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/search?q=%23Djangocon&quot; title=&quot;#Djangocon&quot; class=&quot;tweet-url hashtag&quot;&gt;#Djangocon&lt;/a&gt; ....</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/435875621710679783'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/435875621710679783'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/09/geodjango.html' title='GeoDjango'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1130660003340950466</id><published>2009-09-08T13:09:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2010-09-08T13:30:53.013-07:00</updated><title type='text'>More from DjangoCon</title><content type='html'>I joined &lt;a href=&quot;http://lincolnloop.com/&quot;&gt;Lincoln Loop&lt;/a&gt; guys for lunch.  This is a well known Django shop based in Colorado, although the developers are spread out, including this one guy from Portugal (we discussed Portland&#39;s planned aspect, strong zoning, with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://geography.about.com/od/urbaneconomicgeography/a/cbd.htm&quot;&gt;tightly focused CBD&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every subculture has its &quot;buzz word city&quot; which I work to tune in (anthropologist hat).  Here it&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.fabfile.org/0.9/&quot;&gt;Fabric&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://pinaxproject.com/&quot;&gt;Pinax&lt;/a&gt;, also &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.ianbicking.org/2008/10/28/pyinstall-is-dead-long-live-pip/&quot;&gt;pip&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.ianbicking.org/2007/10/10/workingenv-is-dead-long-live-virtualenv/&quot;&gt;virtualEnv&lt;/a&gt; (both Ian Bicking projects) -- gotta know about &#39;em.  Also &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.satchmoproject.com/&quot;&gt;Satchmo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getlfs.com/&quot;&gt;Lightning Fast Shop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These latter two on-line shopping frameworks are the kinds of free tools Stu Quimby was experimenting with, when coding &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/01/tale-of-two-toymen.html&quot;&gt;Design Science Toys&lt;/a&gt; to do more business over the web.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My side of the conversation drifted into medical uses of SQL and ~SQL (not-SQL).  I reiterated my view that legal medical records (LMRs) would go document-oriented non-SQL, because you want to stay schemeless in such an amorphous environment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No one wants a table structure expected to handle every medical eventuality and/or course of treatment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;However, for outcomes research purposes, when comparing apples with apples, oranges with oranges, you&#39;ll want to harvest clinical research records (&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/05/weekend-haps.html&quot;&gt;CRRs&lt;/a&gt;) from raw data, scrub it clean by  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/02/wanderers-2008213.html&quot;&gt;masking true identities&lt;/a&gt;, to build these valuable clinical datasets of a more traditional schema-based nature, suitable for sharing among doctors and statisticians.  Heads nodded around the table.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jtauber.com/pinax/&quot;&gt;James Tauber&#39;s talk&lt;/a&gt; on Pinax replays the &quot;gateway drug&quot; meme.  He&#39;s also &lt;a href=&quot;http://jtauber.com/mathematics/&quot;&gt;a math geek&lt;/a&gt; I see (@&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/jtauber&quot; class=&quot;screen-name&quot; title=&quot;James Tauber&quot;&gt;jtauber&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pinax core-dev how: there&#39;s a task tracker, wiki, pastebin, &#39;new&#39; vs. &#39;accepted&#39; workflow, &#39;fix needs review&#39; tag, &#39;resolved&#39; vs. closed&#39; status.  This infrastructure dovetails with discussions on Diversity@python.org re the Postgres core-dev process, versus Python&#39;s (Selena contributing).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/pinax/pinax/tree/master&quot;&gt;repository for Pinax&lt;/a&gt;.  #pinax-dev the IRC channel, #pinax the Twitter channel.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Andy McKay (@&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/clearwind&quot; class=&quot;screen-name&quot; title=&quot;Andy McKay&quot;&gt;clearwind&lt;/a&gt;) is next up.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.agmweb.ca/blog/andy/2223/&quot;&gt;&quot;What the heck went wrong?&quot;&lt;/a&gt; is his topic.  Andy has been a strong player in the Plone community over the years, good seeing him again (we talked later in the lobby, mostly about conference organization issues).  He&#39;s talking about debugging Django apps (how to).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;First:  use the dev server, set DEBUG = True.  Use assert False and print statements as primitive debugging stubs.  Remember to print the type as everything prints as a string. mod_wsgi will halt if you print.  Fix: &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.dscpl.com.au/2009/04/wsgi-and-printing-to-standard-output.html&quot;&gt;WSGIRestrictStdout Off&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Next level:  logging.  The logging module in the Standard Library is notoriously complex, e.g. (log.debug(&quot;blah blah&quot;)).  Then comes pdb (import pdb; pdb.set_trace()).  pdb is essential.  The &lt;a href=&quot;http://werkzeug.pocoo.org/&quot;&gt;werkzeug debugger&lt;/a&gt; is also really cool.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Next:  unit tests and Django debug toolbar.  Continuous integration products are good for keeping costs down:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jetbrains.com/teamcity/&quot;&gt;TeamCity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mozilla.org/projects/tinderbox/&quot;&gt;Tinderbox&lt;/a&gt;...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Arecibo is a good example of a live error monitoring service.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot; href=&quot;http://immike.net/files/restful_ponies.pdf&quot;&gt;RESTful Ponies&lt;/a&gt; by Mike Malone (@&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/jtauber&quot; class=&quot;screen-name&quot; title=&quot;Mike Malone&quot;&gt;mjmalone&lt;/a&gt;), currently &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sixapart.com/&quot;&gt;with Six Apart&lt;/a&gt;:  Roy T. Fielding came up with REST in 1999, per his doctoral dissertation.  It&#39;s an architecture, like Bauhaus, Baroque, or Functionalist.  WWW, based on HTTP, conforms to REST.  Representational State Transfer is also like a programming paradigm, like OO.  RESTocity:  uniform interface, statelessness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A resource is something that can be named, like an object in Python.  On the web, these are typically URIs.  Terminology:  a representation is a sequence of bytes on the wire, describing a resource. Hypermedia contain hyperlinks.  Application state affects how a request is processed.  This isn&#39;t the same as resource state.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;RESTful web services should use HTTP 1.1 as defined in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/Protocols/rfc2616/rfc2616.html&quot;&gt;RFC 2616&lt;/a&gt;.  This is your API.  Give resources URIs.  GET, POST, PUT and DELETE are your four essential methods.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-dusseault-http-patch-13&quot;&gt;PATCH is in the wings&lt;/a&gt; (has momentum, not here yet).  He&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://linux.about.com/od/commands/l/blcmdl1_curl.htm&quot;&gt;using curl&lt;/a&gt; for demos.  Status codes define how to handle requests and responses.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Media types are part of the content-type in HTTP.  Examples:  JSON, RDF: FOAF; XML (e.g. Atom) etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You also need to specify cacheability using the Cache-Control HTTP header.  Django has conditional GET middleware, but you still need to manage Etags and Last-Modified yourself (e.g. use Python hashlib, md5). These same techniques are used to establish preconditions.  Statelessness means don&#39;t use sessions or cookies.  All state information the server might need goes via the hypermedia.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://bitbucket.org/jespern/django-piston/wiki/Home&quot;&gt;django-piston&lt;/a&gt; by Jesper Noeher is worth studying for RESTful Django.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Simon Willison: Renting old castles and forts is a fun way to host a sprint.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://wildlifenearyou.com/&quot;&gt;WildLifeNearYou.com&lt;/a&gt; was co-developed over 10 days using &quot;cowboy development&quot; techniques.  Consensus processes are important. Pair programming helps a new team achieve common coding standards.  Shared blogs, Twitter-like programs also help coordinate projects.  The fort team &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/simonw/bugle_project/tree/master&quot;&gt;hacked Bugle&lt;/a&gt;, had no Internet connection, just an intranet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Simon, who works for &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/span&gt; is giving us his British-style spin on that topic (rapid application development).  The scandal around MP expenses provided raw material.  The result:  a Django application for investigating these revelations.  The plan was to break scanned A4 pages into individual images using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyberciti.biz/faq/howto-convert-a-pdf-file-to-an-image/&quot;&gt;convert&lt;/a&gt; and send them to a MySQL database.  In the end, other tools were required given the non-standard nature of the PDF materials.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This process was educational but also proved &quot;cowboy development&quot; has some real downsides.  The better way:  use pair programming, unit tests, mocks, Team City, deployment scripts.  He&#39;s mentioning redis (link below), with its atomic data structures.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our day is concluding with the technical panel.  I need to bus home to grab the PSF snake and head down to the Portland Python User Group meeting.  @psf_snake has tweeted invites to the conferees, with a link to the Meetup site.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1130660003340950466'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1130660003340950466'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/09/more-from-djangocon.html' title='More from DjangoCon'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2724876260848488945</id><published>2009-09-08T11:24:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-09-12T12:47:10.767-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Django Conference (Day 1)</title><content type='html'>I&#39;m in the great hall, registered with T-shirt.  @psf_snake is still in her FedEx container, to join us later.  At least she&#39;s able to tweet.  They&#39;ve done a good job providing power strips here.  So many hotels aren&#39;t set up for one laptop per adult (OLPA).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of which, I&#39;d hoped to be lugging my new 2.6 lbs Ubuntu Starling, a replacement for &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/06/jackalope-down.html&quot;&gt;the Dell that died&lt;/a&gt;, but after first picking mode of delivery (paid extra for 3-day), I then got notification it takes up to seven business days to run orders through manufacturing (nothing &quot;just in time&quot;).  So I don&#39;t have the sexiest &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/10/accessorized-quaker.html&quot;&gt;of accessories&lt;/a&gt;.  At least I&#39;ve got my high heels (and Olympus Stylus).  Need coffee...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is a friendly mostly-guy world.  I was offered a free pastry, met Travis in line for coffee.  He&#39;s fresh from Kansas, the Django capital.  The Django pony is here, more like a unicorn, all pink and adorable.  Are our totems both shes then?  More gender studies ahead.  Most of us are from out of town, camped out here at DoubleTree.  I introduce myself as the local guy, say &quot;Welcome to Portland&quot; quite a bit.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fake JKM (a quick keynote):  James Konrad Tauber (JKT) is &quot;impersonating&quot; JKM (Jacob Kaplan-Moss).  &lt;a href=&quot;http://djangopeople.net/freakboy3742/&quot;&gt;Russell Keith-Magee&lt;/a&gt;... RKM JKM JKT... it&#39;s &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The DaJango Code&lt;/span&gt;, flash to book cover (JK... MT... so many riddles).  MT = Malcom Tredinnick (Cornwall, UK).  Simon Wilison is allegedly the original inspiration for JKR&#39;s Harry Potter, the K taken to comply with the code.  TMR is Tom M. Riddle (Voldemort).  Obviously a conspiracy and yeah that KKK down the middle is disturbing, probably just means &quot;Kansas on steroids&quot; (note to diversity@python.org: maybe check poet Gene Fowler&#39;s &quot;e pronoun&quot;? -- I&#39;m having trouble googling anything on it (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=3894490&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;math-teach&lt;/a&gt; is down again)).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Avi (@avibryant) is now taking the podium.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Avi is from Smalltalk (.st) and Dabble DB worlds.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.seaside.st/&quot;&gt;Seaside web framework&lt;/a&gt;?  Never heard of it. &lt;a href=&quot;http://trendly.com/&quot;&gt;Trendly&lt;/a&gt;: another product he&#39;s plugging.  The theme here is obsolete systems, a theme for me too (I was poking fun at MUMPS while in line with Travis (he&#39;d never heard of it)).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Primo Levi story:  we didn&#39;t need the onions anymore (as a metrological tool for testing varnish, a kind of thermometer).  Lots of &quot;onions&quot; left over from CGI days.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yes, we&#39;re aware of ~SQL e.g. Cassandra (Facebook), these &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/redis/source/browse/trunk/client-libraries/python/redis.py&quot;&gt;key:value&lt;/a&gt; and map:reduce machines.  Yes, web frameworks &quot;of the future&quot; will back end into these too.  This jibes with my idea of the legal medical record as more like a Facebook scroll, medical instruments leaving signed results, applications harvesting what they know to look for.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If your entire dataset fits into 600 Meg, just put it in RAM (duh). Affordable RAM changes the dynamics.  It&#39;s the &quot;database wars&quot; (finding the right tool for any given job).  Persistence doesn&#39;t have to mean SQL, we&#39;ve all learned that by now.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Concurrency is the other thing to keep thinking about (yay, dimming the lights, about time).  The GIL is not a big deal.  He&#39;s going with what I call &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/chicago/2009-April/005830.html&quot;&gt;the &quot;snakes on a plane&quot; model&lt;/a&gt;, i.e. many separate Pythons doing their thing, ala the plain vanilla buzzbot design (thinking of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2009-September/009517.html&quot;&gt;Patrick&#39;s architecture&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gmail is prototypical of tomorrows applications in providing all the HTML and Javascript up front, then just sending JSON snippets back and forth.  This isn&#39;t about being swoopy (glitzy) so much as making the browser the puppet theater, pulling strings with jQuery etc.  The JavaScript VMs have gotten so much better, e.g. V8 in Chrome.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Incremental updates means more behind-the-scenes gnarly URLs, a kind of lower level conversation between a client back door and the server.  Django URL routing might become less pretty? Google&#39;s GWT is probably the only framework taking this challenge head-on.  However Avi sees going to smelly Java (from JavaScript) as something of a step backward, even if strategically justifiable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recall Alan Kay&#39;s being excited about JavaScript at &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/04/shuttleworth-summit-day-one.html&quot;&gt;our London summit&lt;/a&gt;, thinking it has a bright future (he&#39;d done a turtle graphics demo to amuse himself while recovering from a back injury).  His prognostications have borne out.  Portland&#39;s &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Admirers of JavaScript&lt;/span&gt; would appreciate this talk.  Avi has developed a Smalltalk development environment internal to the browser that translates to JavaScript under the hood.  Could Python do something similar?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Ur Doin It Wrong&lt;/span&gt; by James Bennett:  RTFM.  &quot;Help! I don&#39;t know Python&quot; is the other big problem.  How do I do X in Django is often really a Python question.  Do the tutorial, get a couple books, read &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/pymotw&quot;&gt;Python module of the week&lt;/a&gt;.  You need to know about PYTHONPATH, super(), closures, decorators... know how to read error messages.  Read &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/reusable-django-apps/&quot;&gt;bit.ly/reusable-django-apps/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Django really is just Python, not some language on top of Python.  Main beef:  Django does not make you use the default components.  Learn how to swap in the components you need.  It&#39;s just Python.  Wanna point Django &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/twisted-second-coming/&quot;&gt;at Twisted&lt;/a&gt; ala &lt;a href=&quot;http://ozmm.org/posts/leafychat.html&quot;&gt;LeafyChat&lt;/a&gt;?  Go for it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you&#39;re distributing Django applications, follow packaging guidelines.  Advice:  steer clear of setuptools for now, stick with distutils (need a README, /docs, license.txt etc.).  &lt;a href=&quot;http://sphinx.pocoo.org/&quot;&gt;Use Sphinx&lt;/a&gt; for docs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;James likes MIT, BSD licenses over GPL, which &quot;might as well be proprietary&quot; the way he looks at it.  Have unit tests.  Use django-lint, pep8.py and pylint.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://pypants.org/&quot;&gt;pypants&lt;/a&gt; is a fun implementation of some of this.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a Perl guy now, Frank Wiles.  This is a good complement to our Smalltalker keynote -- proves the Python community is not just a buncha KKK-style language bigots.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Frank is addicted to Django and not ashamed to admit it.  Django is his &quot;gateway drug&quot; (this is a pep talk).  Frank is from Revsys, part of the Kansas-based Django cartel, has been with the project almost since its inception.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The difference between good code and bad is &quot;WTFs per minute&quot; upon code review.  zc.buildout, django-admin.py -- nothing as clean and nice in Perl world.  Testing setup much easier -- saves so much time, nicer hangover, the high is better... (check out the slides).  &quot;My hands don&#39;t hurt anymore...&quot; (less shift key, than in Perl).  You&#39;ve gotta love your tools, is the basic message.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2724876260848488945'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2724876260848488945'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/09/django-conference-day-1.html' title='Django Conference (Day 1)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7292551164917456558</id><published>2009-09-07T11:04:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2009-09-07T11:29:32.546-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Up (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3895110783/&quot; title=&quot;Up at 5:15 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3430/3895110783_17d6cd254f_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Up at 5:15&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Up&lt;/span&gt; is about the puer-senex combo, to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/05/with-friends-of-jung.html&quot;&gt;Jungian parlance&lt;/a&gt;.  The pair embarks on a classic quest, in a spirit of adventure shared by an off camera mother figure.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The villain is just trying to prove his authenticity (at the expense of harming an endangered species -- so unacceptable) and has surrounded himself with talking dogs in that effort (it&#39;s a cartoon, and Disney knows how to animate dogs).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I saw this as a double feature with &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/span&gt; (later, back at my place) so that may color my thinking (deja vu is a theme).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The &quot;little mail man&quot; (pun) &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/12/some-youtube-r.html&quot;&gt;looks like Humpty Dumpty&lt;/a&gt; and brightens the picture right from the start, turning a potentially bitter old man story into an heroic epic instead.  Uplifting.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7292551164917456558'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7292551164917456558'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/09/up-movie-review.html' title='Up (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3430/3895110783_17d6cd254f_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2493959257285498570</id><published>2009-09-04T07:25:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-09-05T09:10:20.950-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Poster Art</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi2mG_3WJPX6AtiC8Pal_TLee1P4-YLE_WqCPUw2Sz4ILlrw1Z1eTFC1f3f0Cdn3Td2_M_Ab56amscV6G50-HepLWgwyaaUKFc3MDO4f-4dOaAj_iOlXvRqMMnEthe3AHr3jWeQ/s1600-h/three_friends.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 207px; height: 320px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi2mG_3WJPX6AtiC8Pal_TLee1P4-YLE_WqCPUw2Sz4ILlrw1Z1eTFC1f3f0Cdn3Td2_M_Ab56amscV6G50-HepLWgwyaaUKFc3MDO4f-4dOaAj_iOlXvRqMMnEthe3AHr3jWeQ/s320/three_friends.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5377617930853269714&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: poster art by claire ::&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjoOwVHhL9lLuKvmBzrLO3NO5hi-uI1lLgc9k92dR40eMRwZOtnaljsDjgl6IsM6A3a4Btdq-sLA-e4j2hyphenhyphenBCShCfKkQD7P6wTVTgMz1VThGho4Cjb7CDnJVVNBvwaxvAqUzDv5/s1600-h/P7170082.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 240px; height: 320px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjoOwVHhL9lLuKvmBzrLO3NO5hi-uI1lLgc9k92dR40eMRwZOtnaljsDjgl6IsM6A3a4Btdq-sLA-e4j2hyphenhyphenBCShCfKkQD7P6wTVTgMz1VThGho4Cjb7CDnJVVNBvwaxvAqUzDv5/s320/P7170082.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5377236972861014034&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: lw @ duke&#39;s ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjRtNR_sDsmG58EhyphenhyphenjuwF1nSqJSe9VYobdLa9S80266q9PT3Oe-qu9w1rnvUoD_29a4m433FZV8ws9YPYDRQgC3XtjsLCop9TJeh4ITJHWKYsYApaV0QeEWGd8xb88XK-G57Kqu/s1600-h/dukeslanding.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 207px; height: 320px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjRtNR_sDsmG58EhyphenhyphenjuwF1nSqJSe9VYobdLa9S80266q9PT3Oe-qu9w1rnvUoD_29a4m433FZV8ws9YPYDRQgC3XtjsLCop9TJeh4ITJHWKYsYApaV0QeEWGd8xb88XK-G57Kqu/s320/dukeslanding.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5378012625849481330&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: private party byob ::&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhvWcmkznVlTSpGTTf5ycdmnYo2AYaEefOpYeiL87hFuR-EAqklrBZctbZMLOy9jVWrZfozKEzeXgVtInzVzvoasyOfOQT7Bl2wZYU6Pwc3educTKI68YtgFZ_7skj6PNQohkj9/s1600-h/LincolnPoster.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 207px; height: 320px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhvWcmkznVlTSpGTTf5ycdmnYo2AYaEefOpYeiL87hFuR-EAqklrBZctbZMLOy9jVWrZfozKEzeXgVtInzVzvoasyOfOQT7Bl2wZYU6Pwc3educTKI68YtgFZ_7skj6PNQohkj9/s320/LincolnPoster.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5378011536225826626&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: public event @ Angelo&#39;s ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjM3smdzfQ__rBfdzvRRZn-LLGDktUmgi50zYc_rjP_NGLr_nBZ3MTcNljLGgj-Dv8Ukjf0UYToeFi2yifrIs9nRf-f65klO4Uf__jslCFYf89ezBubEtdNAqY6IGKbcs4X7-88/s1600-h/lindsey_schedule.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 320px; height: 202px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjM3smdzfQ__rBfdzvRRZn-LLGDktUmgi50zYc_rjP_NGLr_nBZ3MTcNljLGgj-Dv8Ukjf0UYToeFi2yifrIs9nRf-f65klO4Uf__jslCFYf89ezBubEtdNAqY6IGKbcs4X7-88/s320/lindsey_schedule.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5377293980598275778&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.myspace.com/lindseywalkermusic&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;from myspace&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3885244501/&quot; title=&quot;Good Bye Party by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3487/3885244501_d09670b693_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Good Bye Party&quot; width=&quot;180&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: click thru to photostream ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgYy71tNH9_viRtCZ_yeTtiQu-Egwwy2vWUXSUIS3WvnRmsUQM3NJ25FsFmafbWrjCBskWAYGGpbKzbXgXtUqcxBAjYGAIVYA0lkuZ09gAuZMt0VybY0VHT5NsdWXCOPvf-oKsB/s1600-h/It&#39;s+a+Beautiful+Pizza+Poster+Version+1.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 207px; height: 320px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgYy71tNH9_viRtCZ_yeTtiQu-Egwwy2vWUXSUIS3WvnRmsUQM3NJ25FsFmafbWrjCBskWAYGGpbKzbXgXtUqcxBAjYGAIVYA0lkuZ09gAuZMt0VybY0VHT5NsdWXCOPvf-oKsB/s320/It&#39;s+a+Beautiful+Pizza+Poster+Version+1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5378016016042420130&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: on upright piano ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2493959257285498570'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2493959257285498570'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/09/poster-art.html' title='Poster Art'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi2mG_3WJPX6AtiC8Pal_TLee1P4-YLE_WqCPUw2Sz4ILlrw1Z1eTFC1f3f0Cdn3Td2_M_Ab56amscV6G50-HepLWgwyaaUKFc3MDO4f-4dOaAj_iOlXvRqMMnEthe3AHr3jWeQ/s72-c/three_friends.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4156796991713060241</id><published>2009-08-29T18:36:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-08-31T19:15:34.231-07:00</updated><title type='text'>On Break</title><content type='html'>Per my power lunch &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.synchronofile.com/&quot;&gt;with Trevor&lt;/a&gt;, we&#39;re probably going to need to decorate Bucky a @creationist, a kind of war paint, given &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/02/wanderers-2009217.html&quot;&gt;limited debating positions&lt;/a&gt; in Lower48, with &quot;anti-reductionism&quot; maybe too highfalutin for post Scopes Trial killer bees.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Any top-down synergism is creationist in that sense.  Certainly there&#39;s an entry on &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;teleology&lt;/span&gt; in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergetics Dictionary&lt;/span&gt;, as like &quot;voltage pressure&quot;.  Likewise, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/08/holding-pattern.html&quot;&gt;Teilhard de Chardin&lt;/a&gt;, though friendly to fossils, happy to embrace Darwin, was not above a more Masonic &quot;intelligent designer&quot; world view, with an Omega in place of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/11/fixing-g.html&quot;&gt;a G&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhoMpPUnY5unLoC98ZF1POUUNPgZP7JJGo2fekRqKmEX6bUw67E_nUDiyDds-VYZhFKgtAuxUjUHUVGlj3uOz6SIoXn2LghrBcDoyDkphW9-GSI6IJqrAuHbbUtB3f9lRExvBj4/s1600-h/babel_masonic.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 145px; height: 320px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhoMpPUnY5unLoC98ZF1POUUNPgZP7JJGo2fekRqKmEX6bUw67E_nUDiyDds-VYZhFKgtAuxUjUHUVGlj3uOz6SIoXn2LghrBcDoyDkphW9-GSI6IJqrAuHbbUtB3f9lRExvBj4/s320/babel_masonic.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5376315897560784594&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shopmcmenamins.com/categories/112-Posters/products/1479-The-Tower&quot;&gt;the tower&lt;/a&gt; ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;I&#39;m on break from chauffeur duties for the Lindsey Walker Show, a private party at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Duke&#39;s Landing&lt;/span&gt;, though we&#39;re not encouraging alcohol (BYOB is a right since &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/12/repeal-day.html&quot;&gt;the end of Prohibition&lt;/a&gt;) on the off chance there&#39;s still a way to repair the relationship with the neighbors.  Zoning permits a street of dreams in SE Portland, but youth culture is traditionally repressed in post-Victorian societies.  Portland is scarcely out of its Wild West years, has a long way to go in some dimensions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3865452725/&quot; title=&quot;30th and Belmont by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2453/3865452725_2991546027_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30th and Belmont&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Anyway that private party with 80 people staged by &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Babies with Rabies&lt;/span&gt; might&#39;ve helped tip it in favor of the killjoys. OLCC looks for people stepping on the sidewalk with anything boozaholic.  That&#39;s the name of the game, when they want to crack down. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt; Duke&#39;s&lt;/span&gt; had its alcohol monitor, sure, but that wasn&#39;t enough to satisfy the referees in this case.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m learning a lot about the Wild West these days, am looking forward to Lindsey&#39;s playing.  I&#39;ve invited a bunch of people.  Glenn, another Wanderer, is on his way over.  She&#39;s a top talent though her loud edgy sound is not for everyone.  Here&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/08/lindseys-flyer.html&quot;&gt;her latest circular&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Bizmo Diaries&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEj-boRJ32uY_C7_3jviQF-098_6k4so0M8Z2HX1MGe7oARMBzxkEk0WHToMk-f6QhgxB1mqnqDAu0XKlgWRf2XE3y7_xeM9vQ7xhCq9dJi7COK6tigFVqsH3Apd7mfV3f1NwFSF/s1600-h/lindsey_tweet.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 320px; height: 64px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEj-boRJ32uY_C7_3jviQF-098_6k4so0M8Z2HX1MGe7oARMBzxkEk0WHToMk-f6QhgxB1mqnqDAu0XKlgWRf2XE3y7_xeM9vQ7xhCq9dJi7COK6tigFVqsH3Apd7mfV3f1NwFSF/s320/lindsey_tweet.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5375657672543175330&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I had a fine time with Tag recently although &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Annex&lt;/span&gt; turned into a hoot and holler fest (some sports team, full of gusto).  We wound up at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Ringler&#39;s&lt;/span&gt; instead, much quieter.  Our main order of business:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.python.org/moin/Languages&quot;&gt;help Python.org&lt;/a&gt; tune in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.wxpython.org/index.cgi/ValidI18nCodes&quot;&gt;Arabic speaking&lt;/a&gt; blogosphere and, more important, look for NGOs wanting to make a difference in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2009-August/009506.html&quot;&gt;helping small businesses&lt;/a&gt; get going, jump start new careers in the arts, in design, in banking, in food services, health and education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m steering her towards the next PPUG meeting, even if I&#39;m to be at the Django conference.  We have a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.idealist.org/&quot;&gt;Idealist.org people&lt;/a&gt; at most of those meetings, perhaps from other world domination shops I&#39;m still clueless about (I&#39;m far from omniscient, even regarding geekdom here in Portland).  What would it look like, to code &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Palestine on Rails&lt;/span&gt;?  I should put her in touch with &lt;a href=&quot;http://democracylab.org/&quot;&gt;DemocracyLab.org&lt;/a&gt; as well, to yak about Google App Engine solutions (Dr. Chuck a new Plaxo friend).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3869359449/&quot; title=&quot;Quaker Dude by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3513/3869359449_841afdc0f4_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Quaker Dude&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4156796991713060241'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4156796991713060241'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/on-break.html' title='On Break'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhoMpPUnY5unLoC98ZF1POUUNPgZP7JJGo2fekRqKmEX6bUw67E_nUDiyDds-VYZhFKgtAuxUjUHUVGlj3uOz6SIoXn2LghrBcDoyDkphW9-GSI6IJqrAuHbbUtB3f9lRExvBj4/s72-c/babel_masonic.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-9092353231259301877</id><published>2009-08-27T00:24:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-08-27T23:22:54.728-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2009.8.27</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhisbzLgWiTw3_fMEnzq5cbob_pLjozfS7sHI5M5pwb5m9LdeH-u7YT9T8ZRaNqIOGAmAY6gF7ziyNvDC55mNQzGNB8d9XDFVxMWnNIs26EZ4KJhyphenhyphenowBEfw92EaJm3jkSD6r1OP/s1600-h/BALAS+AG+27+DE+09+%281%29.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 200px; height: 195px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhisbzLgWiTw3_fMEnzq5cbob_pLjozfS7sHI5M5pwb5m9LdeH-u7YT9T8ZRaNqIOGAmAY6gF7ziyNvDC55mNQzGNB8d9XDFVxMWnNIs26EZ4KJhyphenhyphenowBEfw92EaJm3jkSD6r1OP/s200/BALAS+AG+27+DE+09+%281%29.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5374873034145469890&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot; href=&quot;http://www.mariomarin-poliedros.com/&quot;&gt;by Mario Marín&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;d gotten some of the inside scoop from two of the returning crew at the potluck, however Jeff&#39;s projected pictures this morning added a whole new dimension.  Sam&#39;s boat is quite commodious, although five pretty much packed it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jon Bunce joined us, in good form, and later Buzz.  A lot of the talk was about music, early cartoons (including Disney&#39;s), and about Wikipedia.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One could invent a back story about this small co-op of good-hearted people, either selling out to, or having control seized by, some conglomerate that now censors the content out of rapaciousness and/or cowardice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I offered an alternative back story:  entrepreneurs suck down open source Wiki software but are competing with the likes of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Britannica&lt;/span&gt; and can&#39;t afford to let the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/span&gt; brand &quot;go bad&quot; because (for example) fringe ideologues capitalize on its &quot;free and open source&quot; nature to troll, spread FUD, trash talk and be obnoxious i.e. you&#39;ve gotta set standards and enforce them to be taken seriously as an encyclopedia with backbone, and not just a hodgepodge of misleading misinformation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We talked about the new &quot;geezer teaser&quot;: talking heads of the Woodstock era, retrospecting.   I&#39;m looking forward to seeing it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We also yakked about needing an appropriate buyer for Pauling Campus, an ally.  I recycled some of my somewhat stale (or at least no longer novel) ideas, then came up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/10/hotel-oregon.html&quot;&gt;a fresh one&lt;/a&gt;, relating to aerospace.  The Fuller School has all these plans for adapting technology in that sector for civilian shelter solutions, going back to Wichita house and before (the genesis of that 4D moniker, which I perpetuate with my 4D Solutions).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Whether or not this particular idea pans out isn&#39;t the real point I suppose.  It&#39;s more just a sign of the times that we&#39;d even consider reaching across ideological lines in this way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Teddy Kennedy is being remembered on all networks today for his ferocity and commitment to worthy causes.  His ability to bridge across chasms in our political landscape is what many think we&#39;re missing today and I see much reason for concern, although I think the White House is still pretty good at it.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9092353231259301877'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9092353231259301877'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/wanderers-2009827.html' title='Wanderers 2009.8.27'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhisbzLgWiTw3_fMEnzq5cbob_pLjozfS7sHI5M5pwb5m9LdeH-u7YT9T8ZRaNqIOGAmAY6gF7ziyNvDC55mNQzGNB8d9XDFVxMWnNIs26EZ4KJhyphenhyphenowBEfw92EaJm3jkSD6r1OP/s72-c/BALAS+AG+27+DE+09+%281%29.JPG" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6728805897657320637</id><published>2009-08-23T22:25:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-08-24T11:28:29.584-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Some Analysis</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhcbOB0i8n5w4qFOr1tZcJ1VB3ylG-fbD24vdj8aL80W9vUgPsjZDfdx4E8PH9ncF6zPoKPukVcRP5YkxV2rYSw-lF-6QNR-iarb2Ca_tpj7_O_mod-h9X4_fq6YYMREhN61Aq3/s1600-h/richierich.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 140px; height: 200px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhcbOB0i8n5w4qFOr1tZcJ1VB3ylG-fbD24vdj8aL80W9vUgPsjZDfdx4E8PH9ncF6zPoKPukVcRP5YkxV2rYSw-lF-6QNR-iarb2Ca_tpj7_O_mod-h9X4_fq6YYMREhN61Aq3/s200/richierich.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5373413985756471634&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[from some email to an AFSC-friendly Quaker, hyperlinks added ]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Republicans are projected as big daddy richie rich figures to which rebellious teenager Democrats say &quot;end the war&quot; well knowing they will fail i.e. Republicans in power means keeping &quot;the war&quot; going.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But then when daddy Republican is in the back seat, Democrat teenagers stop thinking about the war and selfishly focus on domestic concerns like health care and &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/06/recessionology.html&quot;&gt;recession&lt;/a&gt;, because they too need &quot;the war&quot; to keep going (for economic reasons).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In other words, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/pelosis-war-editorial.html&quot;&gt;neither the left nor the right&lt;/a&gt; applies any real brakes in this picture, because of that shared &quot;we are a superpower&quot; ideology (aka the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/03/why-we-fight-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Eisenhower-diagnosed&lt;/a&gt; &quot;military-industrial complex&quot;, akin to mad cow).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This superpower complex (a &quot;meme virus&quot;) is then acted out per &quot;the sorrows of empire&quot; as &lt;a href=&quot;http://hnn.us/articles/3015.html&quot;&gt;Chalmers Johnson&lt;/a&gt; puts it (mom organized a guest speaking event for him).  The left and right appear to oppose one another, but really they&#39;re enablers of a common dysfunctional world model, a psychological disorder (&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/05/wmbs-satire.html&quot;&gt;WMBS&lt;/a&gt;?).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Again, welcome home to Portland,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kirby&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiDe5iwIRiWNW-V4ta8N8qmS7ENJoLNnpu1-DGKI6QmV5KAIC9zQrrGNpmNizdE6OXDkLR2cFDnyET7ha6SeL04jROkfue-OgAKVKDE_SOINBv0-uLgprs_6lPdyMJpO1gleMpz/s1600-h/teen_with_float.jpg.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 200px; height: 150px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiDe5iwIRiWNW-V4ta8N8qmS7ENJoLNnpu1-DGKI6QmV5KAIC9zQrrGNpmNizdE6OXDkLR2cFDnyET7ha6SeL04jROkfue-OgAKVKDE_SOINBv0-uLgprs_6lPdyMJpO1gleMpz/s200/teen_with_float.jpg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5373415645869327330&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;cc:attributionURL&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/heyskinny/&quot;&gt;http://www.flickr.com/photos/heyskinny/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;license&quot; href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6728805897657320637'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6728805897657320637'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/some-analysis.html' title='Some Analysis'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhcbOB0i8n5w4qFOr1tZcJ1VB3ylG-fbD24vdj8aL80W9vUgPsjZDfdx4E8PH9ncF6zPoKPukVcRP5YkxV2rYSw-lF-6QNR-iarb2Ca_tpj7_O_mod-h9X4_fq6YYMREhN61Aq3/s72-c/richierich.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8736273240043436701</id><published>2009-08-21T14:21:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2011-11-07T13:11:53.054-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Designing Engineers</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://blip.tv/play/gvhDgZeaKAI%2Em4v&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;258&quot; width=&quot;360&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8736273240043436701'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8736273240043436701'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/designing-engineers.html' title='Designing Engineers'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4761913463292425227</id><published>2009-08-18T22:02:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-08-18T22:59:41.332-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2009.8.18</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3836222230/&quot; title=&quot;Spiral with Hat by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3472/3836222230_ed9e314325_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Spiral with Hat&quot; width=&quot;180&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Portland is having hot weather again.  Tara gets to house sit in a place with some air conditioning, lucky devil, me invited, but I&#39;m kicked back in the living room, home from Pauling House.  Sarah the dog was earlier treating me like a salt lick in the desert, but is currently dreaming up a storm...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Great seeing &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/08/friends-gather.html&quot;&gt;Jon Bunce&lt;/a&gt; at Wanderers again, still recovering from some illness.  Lynne Taylor swept through, changing our XY:XX ratio to like 10:1.  Glenn, two Steves, Barry, Jeff, Don, Jon, me, Sam... most of them planning a boat trip starting Thursday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I told a couple stories, had &#39;em rolling in the aisles (an idiom, don&#39;t really have aisles), drank some wine, left early, trying to get some work done.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also shared the secret knowledge that Double Dog Dare for $2.88 is maybe better than so-called Two Buck Chuck ($2.99) from Trader Joe&#39;s.  Sam commented he couldn&#39;t see himself buying wine at a Seven Eleven.  He probably hasn&#39;t been to Gothenburg (Sweden), where that company has one the more upscale outlets.  But then &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/07/more-on-gothenberg_25.html&quot;&gt;Gothenberg&lt;/a&gt; is kinda surreal in that way (Portlandia has a boyfriend there).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I did some writing about Python, posted about some new user groups I&#39;d like to see, including in Baghdad (Iran has one already, as does Israel).  The meeting &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/11/smiley-guy.html&quot;&gt;at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Fine Grind&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; seemed productive.  The idea is to prototype &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/08/new-kind-of-charter.html&quot;&gt;the international schools&lt;/a&gt; nearby, work the kinks out, then spread some of the lessons learned -- not a new model, although much of the technology is new.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m liking the School of Technology approach, need to reinstall Eclipse.  The Jackalope is still down.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4761913463292425227'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4761913463292425227'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/wanderers-2009818.html' title='Wanderers 2009.8.18'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3472/3836222230_ed9e314325_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2186138170300929699</id><published>2009-08-17T21:54:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-08-18T00:20:44.272-07:00</updated><title type='text'>From the Album (summer 2009)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi_NiKH-9boRHLUtNDWWyjSsGy1DG05fTv79DEFXcxaUUzsVtzTrzNF0g69blBXoxqTTx3RMdYdgrELs84JV6Ue751ylx_x6U_ycgVfRcf0vlXU6XXOVxD1whm44ydfQRgyV-Gq/s1600-h/orcas.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 320px; height: 239px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi_NiKH-9boRHLUtNDWWyjSsGy1DG05fTv79DEFXcxaUUzsVtzTrzNF0g69blBXoxqTTx3RMdYdgrELs84JV6Ue751ylx_x6U_ycgVfRcf0vlXU6XXOVxD1whm44ydfQRgyV-Gq/s320/orcas.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5371200228001721202&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: tara&#39;s vista (photo by elise) ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhYanyw9OsJSr6ECzfEgTHWuz73vYmf7uuzeSTqdyoaGwbnosFZAwaTiUQJ-pxeDckuvvOZDdD-o2CE1F8djn-1pI60MrDA4T0ykofxjqpPNuP-aqEP01xZrzoBajBSAbp10zh4/s1600-h/P8160068.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 240px; height: 320px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhYanyw9OsJSr6ECzfEgTHWuz73vYmf7uuzeSTqdyoaGwbnosFZAwaTiUQJ-pxeDckuvvOZDdD-o2CE1F8djn-1pI60MrDA4T0ykofxjqpPNuP-aqEP01xZrzoBajBSAbp10zh4/s320/P8160068.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5371163778477288210&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: jimmy lott ::&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEif_jBqyofIoc7zxFts5zJNV02yqMevNH6c3zjsq7qSBB8k0uc9prWyBTQBoQYljzwstcarNs5Ox56CsQ74gKHR-kU-fvOCREApfzRuJAj0l3Q_nqLzN0X2O8OoWMnDei54Q7d6/s1600-h/P8160072.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 320px; height: 240px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEif_jBqyofIoc7zxFts5zJNV02yqMevNH6c3zjsq7qSBB8k0uc9prWyBTQBoQYljzwstcarNs5Ox56CsQ74gKHR-kU-fvOCREApfzRuJAj0l3Q_nqLzN0X2O8OoWMnDei54Q7d6/s320/P8160072.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5371163448846494850&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: lindsey &amp;amp; tag ::&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgBDyY1rdTXe8FvsIs1_QAicbdLUTK-tIc1y77gTRHGFPmsEmK3LzJ8PWPgcUiLtNQ_k5qxFTSsWSOglK_kWdRjYYVJtb1WOUqOTHY86fMqSeydKUQGYh06tzKWe0Om6cH2thYl/s1600-h/P8160053.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 240px; height: 320px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgBDyY1rdTXe8FvsIs1_QAicbdLUTK-tIc1y77gTRHGFPmsEmK3LzJ8PWPgcUiLtNQ_k5qxFTSsWSOglK_kWdRjYYVJtb1WOUqOTHY86fMqSeydKUQGYh06tzKWe0Om6cH2thYl/s320/P8160053.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5371163197986527922&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: wilfp / pauling connection ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2186138170300929699'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2186138170300929699'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/from-album-summer-2009.html' title='From the Album (summer 2009)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi_NiKH-9boRHLUtNDWWyjSsGy1DG05fTv79DEFXcxaUUzsVtzTrzNF0g69blBXoxqTTx3RMdYdgrELs84JV6Ue751ylx_x6U_ycgVfRcf0vlXU6XXOVxD1whm44ydfQRgyV-Gq/s72-c/orcas.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6218789965937965330</id><published>2009-08-14T20:39:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2012-10-06T16:42:32.828-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Slogging On</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/pentagonmath.jpg&quot; onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/pentagonmath.jpg&quot; style=&quot;cursor: pointer; display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Pentagon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Google Earth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Hey, my rant below is talk of the town in some circles, got a report from Thirsters that my name was in the wind, easy to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/12/thirsters.html&quot;&gt;imagine Fred&lt;/a&gt; bellowing it, but I was not an eyewitness.  I tend to steer clear of that group these days, for reasons I was explaining to Dr. Tag.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Up close and personal, I&#39;m worried about Razz (8 year old Subaru Legacy AWD station wagon, stick shift), her &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3816210934/&quot;&gt;fender bender&lt;/a&gt;&quot; pushing into &quot;totaled&quot; range according to the body shop doing the estimates, though I have a hard time accepting a car I bought used for over $13K &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/05/key-fob.html&quot;&gt;from Dick Hannah&lt;/a&gt; would be worth only 4/3 of $5.7K already (i.e. $7.6K).  &lt;a href=&quot;http://autos.msn.com/research/vip/pricing.aspx?year=2001&amp;amp;make=Subaru&amp;amp;model=Legacy%20Wagon&amp;amp;trimid=-1&quot;&gt;Bluebook&lt;/a&gt; is $8-8.5K. I know if Farmer&#39;s cuts me a check for $7.6K (5.7 = 75% of 7.6) I&#39;d not get a car nearly as cool.  No frame damage [update:&amp;nbsp; there &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; some frame damage, from boulders underneath on driver side], just fenders and shit, bet like $85 at the factory for some of those pieces, but capitalism is nothing if not about markup (but then show me a system without markup -- lets talk turkey somewhere (not here)).  Don&#39;t sharia-practicing camel dealers know the difference between retail and wholesale?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m liking that some US Army guy (Colonel Timothy R. Reese) came out in NYT calling for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tomdispatch.com/post/175106&quot;&gt;100% withdrawal from Iraq by 2010&lt;/a&gt;.  Takes guts, thanks dude.  Neoliberals wanna push it back to 2011 so they can &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/08/yakking-with-old-timers.html&quot;&gt;force a new verdict&lt;/a&gt; and maybe keep those &quot;mega-bases&quot; -- like maybe under John Kerry?  Sure, they&#39;ll &quot;feel guilty&quot; about that post-911 spazz attack, but it&#39;s worth feeling guilty if the price is right.  So I&#39;m betting the so-called &quot;wimpy left&quot; (vs. the &quot;hard left&quot;) will push to stay, by spinning our Army guy as &quot;out of touch with the mainstream at the Pentagon&quot; (neoliberals, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/03/cubespace-anon.html&quot;&gt;like truckers&lt;/a&gt;, think they know all about what the Pentagon thinks, even if they don&#39;t know shit &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/08/mathcasting-about-phi.html&quot;&gt;about phi&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I watched the spatter on MSNBC around health care on &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/08/wanderers-2009812.html&quot;&gt;Olbermann again&lt;/a&gt;, followed by that smart chyk show, maybe catch her name next time (reminds me of Rowley) -- Rachel Maddow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Hey, great that Dick Cheney is refocusing on &quot;nuke tech as weaponry&quot; in the hands of terrorists (by definition!) as a topic.  That&#39;ll put some spine back into the debate maybe, though focusing on end of life care &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a mature audiences topic (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/10/wanderers-2008108.html&quot;&gt;R rated&lt;/a&gt;).  The shows I&#39;m watching give it (mortality) a slightly comical spin, feels like a pain med of some kind.  Thanks TV!  Sometimes a prefrontal lobotomy is more healthful than a bottle in front of me -- especially if it&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8AyVh1_vWYQ&quot;&gt;a Sony&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tara is heading out of town again, though not to the high desert this time.  We&#39;re fortunate to have so many ecosystems within easy driving range.  Most kids in day care just get to sit in a boring classroom and read about the world in textbooks.  Real schools take &#39;em to the field, out to various &quot;mega-bases&quot; to appreciate life &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; in the big city.  Hang out with some overseas types, already self schooling with rancher families, learning to ride horses, far from a polluted homeland.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I get a kick outta these knee-jerk something-or-others (I lose track of which mirror image) decrying the Americorps brainwashing camps, saying the government shouldn&#39;t be mind- controlling our children (leave that to big pharma).  A lot of these same families are all flag wavy around military bases, not seeing the connection.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s why we need professionals sometimes:  because the average civilian is getting by on two cylinders and we sometimes need all six (like in some military or paramilitary capacity ala LL or P-W (or even me, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/12/action-figure.html&quot;&gt;in Santa Fe&lt;/a&gt;)).  Without &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/01/war-college-philosophy.html&quot;&gt;my Princeton brainwashing&lt;/a&gt;, I wouldn&#39;t be pure of heart enough to do &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freelists.org/post/wittrs/On-the-Mechanism-of-Understanding,10&quot;&gt;the Lord&#39;s work&lt;/a&gt;&quot; as &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/02/moral-relativism.html&quot;&gt;Mirsky&lt;/a&gt; put it, perpetuating my guru&#39;s lineage (talking about Ludwig Wittgenstein again, one of my heros, also a war vet).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On the brighter side, I&#39;m looking forward to eyeballing some great Python today, new curriculum materials, not by me this time.  Even I get tired of just talking to myself, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h1T_eDE84W0&quot;&gt;arguing with Frank Zubek&lt;/a&gt; about whether 24 Mites make a 1F or 2F cube.  Working with other professionals is what keeps me going.  Inspirational!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgnVg4xfZCM0bV7hIZc2Vco-y0XbQBLBgtfdVTgKAnqjJZnjimbHk898OTnLADFp9tJXddwClzeEA19QcWkWh_xZT1Lay_tbQttprQifdxfb0g4YOVqGbxbS4AjEjyxkcFqPYGa/s1600-h/stella.gif&quot; onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5370034011594302290&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgnVg4xfZCM0bV7hIZc2Vco-y0XbQBLBgtfdVTgKAnqjJZnjimbHk898OTnLADFp9tJXddwClzeEA19QcWkWh_xZT1Lay_tbQttprQifdxfb0g4YOVqGbxbS4AjEjyxkcFqPYGa/s320/stella.gif&quot; style=&quot;cursor: pointer; display: block; height: 143px; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; width: 146px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6218789965937965330'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6218789965937965330'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/slogging-on.html' title='Slogging On'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgnVg4xfZCM0bV7hIZc2Vco-y0XbQBLBgtfdVTgKAnqjJZnjimbHk898OTnLADFp9tJXddwClzeEA19QcWkWh_xZT1Lay_tbQttprQifdxfb0g4YOVqGbxbS4AjEjyxkcFqPYGa/s72-c/stella.gif" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-59895527802019212</id><published>2009-08-11T09:57:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-08-12T22:17:42.912-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Pelosi&#39;s War (Editorial)</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgE2dF0wZ-wjwgRag9TUrbq1H1DuX4SNOvC4NT0g_zWrnLEBYp3wKX0az-pYoUZgDnAOY4k-tSVZb6T9mbhQQqfkilRlyW_qJQ0OllGIouGpg269v-BbdDwrQmwYT_xHE1KA6k_/s1600-h/mommy.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 270px; height: 184px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgE2dF0wZ-wjwgRag9TUrbq1H1DuX4SNOvC4NT0g_zWrnLEBYp3wKX0az-pYoUZgDnAOY4k-tSVZb6T9mbhQQqfkilRlyW_qJQ0OllGIouGpg269v-BbdDwrQmwYT_xHE1KA6k_/s320/mommy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5368779661241335730&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Clearly the liberal Democrats have every intention of escalating in Afghanistan, per campaign promises to feed the war machine in that area.  Of course the Republicans would have done the same, as both parties are rooted in congressional districts &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/12/iron-mountain-revisted.html&quot;&gt;with mouths to feed&lt;/a&gt; and weaning oneself off the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/03/why-we-fight-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;military-industrial tit&lt;/a&gt; is something neither party is prepared to engage in, at least not yet and not now (&quot;there&#39;s always tomorrow&quot; -- the big lie in politics, as sometimes it&#39;s too late (journalists know these as deadlines)).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Liberal Protestants are uncomfortable being in power, have a hard time seeing themselves that way, as &quot;to protest&quot; is to feel like a &quot;power out&quot; who &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/07/ban-liposuction.html&quot;&gt;sucks up&lt;/a&gt;&quot; to power.  The neocons were more comfortable stridently asserting &quot;we&#39;re it&quot; (i.e. the best and the brightest, and in power to boot) whereas clearly they weren&#39;t, were just another &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/power-of-nightmares-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;nightmarish species&lt;/a&gt; of incompetent goon, another ideological experiment gone sadly awry.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So what does one do with a &quot;superpower&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/12/techietown.html&quot;&gt;out of control&lt;/a&gt;, with neither side into peace, justice or anything close?  There&#39;s always the funding angle.  Incentives to build schools, pave roads, civilian infrastructure, including right here in North America, could tempt some patriotic districts to participate in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/01/repatriation.html&quot;&gt;Operation Rebuild the USA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; versus the current &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/07/toga-party.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Democracy at Gun Point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (a first person shooter). Military personnel include many competent engineers, skilled teachers.  We could use those skills and services, know-how around logistics, in a less self-destructive capacity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/07/wanderers-2009729.html&quot;&gt;Liberals&lt;/a&gt; have the weakest discourse because they profess to be &quot;for peace&quot; but mostly indulge in hypocrisy.  We have no one in the streets.  The huge &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/06/recruiting-commercial.html&quot;&gt;troop levels in Iraq&lt;/a&gt; are &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/08/yakking-with-old-timers.html&quot;&gt;not coming down&lt;/a&gt;.  These are the same Bush Era policies but now the Party of Protest has majorities everywhere, so it&#39;s back to a more Clinton-like period, where poverty is allowed to fester at home, while the treasury is opened to corporate marauders intent upon cultivating a vast army of enemies overseas.  Never mind neither Iraqis &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/05/bait-and-switch.html&quot;&gt;nor the Taliban&lt;/a&gt; had much if anything to do with 911.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/02/more-rocket-science.html&quot;&gt;Explaining one&#39;s actions&lt;/a&gt; is not the goal here, simply business as usual, under whatever convenient pretense or cover.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/59895527802019212'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/59895527802019212'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/pelosis-war-editorial.html' title='Pelosi&#39;s War (Editorial)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgE2dF0wZ-wjwgRag9TUrbq1H1DuX4SNOvC4NT0g_zWrnLEBYp3wKX0az-pYoUZgDnAOY4k-tSVZb6T9mbhQQqfkilRlyW_qJQ0OllGIouGpg269v-BbdDwrQmwYT_xHE1KA6k_/s72-c/mommy.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-9094252627870404797</id><published>2009-08-09T18:10:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-08-10T12:02:03.654-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Urban Edibles</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3807729509/&quot; title=&quot;Irony by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2569/3807729509_60ec269af1_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Irony&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m here at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Backspace&lt;/span&gt; with Michael, Mark, Laura, Rick and Lindsey, these latter three forming &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Good Bye Party&lt;/span&gt; when operating as a band (I&#39;m hoping to catch a rehearsal later).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rick and Laura bicycle everywhere (I saw them zipping by &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/08/remembering.html&quot;&gt;on August 6&lt;/a&gt;), so weren&#39;t able to answer the two touristy questions we got between here and where we parked:  one about the Max, one about the bus.  Rick is from Chicago, has only been in Portland for about six months.  He visited Seattle for the first time just recently.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I used the morning to polish my blog post &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/08/education-planning.html&quot;&gt;on Education Planning&lt;/a&gt;, make some followup contacts.  I&#39;m also still quite active on the new Wittgenstein list, published a seven point &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Wittgenstein for Dummies (not!)&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freelists.org/post/wittrs/some-helpful-guidelines-for-reading-Wittgensteins-philo,6&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freelists.org/post/wittrs/some-helpful-guidelines-for-reading-Wittgensteins-philo,8&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the car on the way over (I&#39;m the designated driver today), Lindsey yakked about her food coop syndicate, brokering subscribers, providers and distributors.  She&#39;s obviously given the matter some thought.  I found myself thinking about Andy Cross and Barb Frank, their small urban farm.  We used to be subscribers, but fell out of the habit.  We occasionally buy fresh produce during social hour at the Quaker meetinghouse, from whomever brings it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the PSF list, Guido is reminding us that Pycon, though not designed to rake it in necessarily, can&#39;t keep running at a loss either, unless subsidized to do so (not the current model).  I&#39;ve been pushing a &quot;more bang for the buck&quot; model for corporate sponsoring members, who might up the ante in exchange for real results.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/08/psf-posting.html&quot;&gt;Here&#39;s a link&lt;/a&gt; to some of my verbiage to that list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So Lindsey and I are just getting up to speed on Mark&#39;s data model (models.py).  Getting to the Django admin interface &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/07/tech-talk.html&quot;&gt;in Cygwin on Windows&lt;/a&gt; required:  using my already-installed Mercurial to clone &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/urbanedibles/wiki/GettingStartedWithMercurial&quot;&gt;the Urbanedibles source code&lt;/a&gt;, downloading and installing Django, using Cygwin&#39;s setup to grab Vim and Sqlite3, running Django&#39;s syncdb, then runserver.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Result:  I&#39;ve got the the admin interface in my FireFox web browser at http://127.0.0.1/admin/.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lindsey got there at about the same time, doing these steps on Mac OSX.  We&#39;re both becoming commiters on this project, though I have nothing to commit from this meeting (too busy blogging).  Lindsey worked with Mark on some changes to the data model, is in the process of merging and committing those changes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here&#39;s an excerpt from the data model, under active development:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;class EdibleType(models.Model):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;    common_name = models.CharField(max_length=200)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;    formal_name = models.CharField(max_length=200)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;    edibility = models.IntegerField()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;    # region / Climate zone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;    Season_info = models.CharField(max_length=1*1024)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;    # media location for photo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;    ident_info = models.CharField(max_length=2*1024)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;    harvesting_info = models.CharField(max_length=2*1024)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;    prep_info = models.CharField(max_length=2*1024)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;    preserving_info = models.CharField(max_length=2*1024)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;    med_use = models.CharField(max_length=2*1024)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;    warnings = models.CharField(max_length=1*1024)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;    #&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;    def __unicode__(self):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:courier new;&quot;&gt;        return self.common_name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My contribution to the meeting was to suggest thinking of a calendar interface for a given fruit tree, such that the user could enter &quot;first three weeks in August&quot; in perpetuity, so said tree does not appear other times of the year.  Everything operates on a schedule no?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is just a big scheduling application letting users yak about resources they&#39;re at liberty to share about.  In addition to time coordinates, we need space coordinates.  Michael has actually thought this through in some detail.  Cyclists might report a tree or bush with fruit on it, with default seasonal data coming from lookup tables i.e. if it&#39;s not your tree, you may not want to commit the time data, but those fields probably shouldn&#39;t go blank.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Regarding space info, the way it works now is the street address goes against a server for lat/long.  People relying on cell phones often get the lat/long off the tower, which could be off by miles, while paying for real GPS makes your battery burn faster.  I didn&#39;t know that, don&#39;t have an iPhone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another dimension, besides time and space, is risk.  If these are wild dandelions, perhaps they&#39;ve been sprayed with toxins?  Does a mean dog live nearby?  Is tree climbing involved?  Definitely we&#39;ll need pictures, if not videos, and Mark is currently working on these media aspects of the data model.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m glad to be having a real Django app to sink my teeth into, complete with Mercurial code sharing.  I&#39;d been trying to wean one of my main clients off a 30 year old obsolete / dying research system costing an arm and a leg in favor of running Django against Postgres, got myself thrown overboard instead given the twisted politics of that place.  I&#39;m signed up for DjangoConf in September.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Providence Bridge Pedal was earlier today.  I&#39;m surprised Suzanne didn&#39;t go; I&#39;d mulled over joining her and Larry -- then &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/07/tinkerbell-swiped.html&quot;&gt;TinkerBell got swiped&lt;/a&gt;. Chris, on Keiko&#39;s team, had his new Powerbook stolen from &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Fine Grind&lt;/span&gt;, causing deeper pain than mine.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3796413036/&quot;&gt;Security cams&lt;/a&gt; have since been installed but that&#39;s not gonna solve the problem of rotted ethics.  Advice:  watch that laptop, or have a friend keep watch (post a guard); don&#39;t turn your back for long unless you&#39;re sure this is a fully trusted environment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tomorrow Razz goes to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3801688288/&quot;&gt;the body shop&lt;/a&gt;, c/o &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Farmer&#39;s Insurance&lt;/span&gt;. Even though my company took a dive in FY2009, I&#39;ve kept up with those premiums, praise Allah.  I&#39;m even covered for a rental from &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Enterprise&lt;/span&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9094252627870404797'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9094252627870404797'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/urban-edibles.html' title='Urban Edibles'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2569/3807729509_60ec269af1_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry></feed>