<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=351'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=326&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=376&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>351</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2301894739458879632</id><published>2019-01-23T15:05:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-23T15:21:31.574-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Does Your Truck Run Linux?</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HIXzJ3Rz9po&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Independent operator truck owners used to customize their own dashboards with various after market instruments.&amp;nbsp; Create your own GUI.&amp;nbsp; In hardware.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This capability has not gone away, but today&#39;s fleets tend to feature controls in a large display of some kind, per Tesla and others.&amp;nbsp; Behind those displays are the sensors and controllers, a small &quot;internet of things&quot; perhaps glued together using TCP / IP.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As a result, the truck&#39;s cab, the personal workspace (PWS) is starting to double as a kind of devops space.&amp;nbsp; In addition we get the navigation and business accounting apps, what it takes to keep up with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.volkswagenag.com/en/news/2016/9/operating_system.html&quot;&gt;the truck&#39;s businesses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not every PWS is running Linux, nor is every (any?) jet airplane (avionics is its own thing) -- when it comes to the in-flight movie service some do.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, the fact remains we need to give students &lt;a href=&quot;https://softwareengineering.stackexchange.com/questions/153266/what-operating-systems-are-used-in-airplanes-and-what-programming-languages-are&quot;&gt;&quot;cockpit&quot; experience&lt;/a&gt; (in the driver&#39;s seat) with whatever operating systems.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Even if your truck does not run Linux, Linux may run your truck, in the sense that remote platforms may be tasked with scheduling you&#39;re contracted to carry out, as a driver.&amp;nbsp; You meet Ubuntu in the cloud a lot. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CpyjoJPQs2o&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2301894739458879632'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2301894739458879632'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2019/01/does-your-truck-run-linux.html' title='Does Your Truck Run Linux?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/HIXzJ3Rz9po/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1682232190087887180</id><published>2019-01-12T11:03:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-12T11:12:04.697-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Time for Blender?</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lPVpg4_POww&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I woke up this morning to Youtubes about Blender Beta 2.8, perhaps to be out of beta by June, 2019?&amp;nbsp; Blender is a large open undertaking aiming at the 3D sculpting and animations market and has a large loyal following.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For many, it provides a training pen, sophisticated enough, for the less free commercial products they&#39;ll end up using, such as products by Autodesk or maybe ESRI.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I remember when Kenneth Snelson, a star developer of CGI, was expressing some distress over the prospect of tackling Maya. No matter how many peaks one has ascended, there&#39;s always another, and peaks are difficult by definition, and one is only getting older.&amp;nbsp; So should I learn Blender 2.8 in 2019 and work at getting really good at it?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The motivations would be many here: (1) I&#39;m a curriculum developer around the Bucky stuff (2) hypertoons were my invention and I should make more of them (3) for Coffee Shops Network (4) which is about pumping funding to the field.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
According to this workflow, the bottleneck between getting funding to the field, and the status quo, is my not knowing Blender nor having made those synergetics hypertoons yet.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This is probably where I start to rebel against myself (my own science fiction) as (a) I have done some simple synergetics hypertoons and had them on Youtube years ago (b) lots of folks are way better at that animation stuff than I am right now and (c) the field needs its funding now, yesterday, not in some fond future when Kirby has had time to reinvent himself yet again.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d rather jump on the advisory team doing the 4K IMAX type movies for science museums, that will pump out the Bucky stuff in super high def, and have those coffee shop reveries downloading right away.&amp;nbsp; So I keep looking around looking for who else is in the business and doing the work?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;When you can&#39;t be the best, buy the best&quot; is a slogan close to what I&#39;m getting at.&amp;nbsp; Let&#39;s not wait for Kirby, is the main idea.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That being said, Kirby has signed up for a Maker Space lesson, presumably in 3D printing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I have the STL files from Jeff and I&#39;m looking at Koski identities using phi-scaled S-modules as my opening topic, with a UVT (unit volume tetrahedron) used to scale everything else in this Sculpture Garden (SG).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7Qzd0Uw-HCM&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1682232190087887180'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1682232190087887180'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2019/01/time-for-blender.html' title='Time for Blender?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/lPVpg4_POww/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8405274391310003810</id><published>2019-01-08T20:41:00.003-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-09T17:45:10.288-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2019.1.8</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/511415516/in/album-72157600254540815/&quot; title=&quot;Looking Towards Hawthorne&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Looking Towards Hawthorne&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/199/511415516_197994ee27.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This was our first evening Wanderers (alternate weeks) in 2019. We&#39;re named Wanderers because we sometimes practice Open Forum, which means the conversation is allowed to wander, in a kind of Bohmian dialog, and takes on Ouija-board like qualities.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Especially if we have a critical mass, which I won&#39;t call&amp;nbsp; quorum as we&#39;re not following Robert&#39;s Rules or anything like that.&amp;nbsp; The Quaker practice of consensus is just beneath the surface.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re not doing business, usually, so it&#39;s closer to Meeting for Worship.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, tonight some business came up, as the estate / campus is under some pressure to do its nonprofit business of memorializing Linus Pauling and his contribution to humankind.&amp;nbsp; He received a Nobel Peace Prize among other prizes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
His wife Ava Helen was active in WILPF (&lt;i&gt;Womens International League for Peace and Freedom&lt;/i&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of WILPF, my mother has been a long time WILPF activist, even went to the The Hague for its centennial.&amp;nbsp; Today she got some copies of &lt;i&gt;Western Friend&lt;/i&gt;, January - February 2019, the &lt;i&gt;On Weapons&lt;/i&gt; issue.&amp;nbsp; She has an interview published in this issue.&amp;nbsp; She&#39;s what we call a weighty Friend.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of weighty Friends, I&#39;m back on beer as it&#39;s 2019.&amp;nbsp; Glenn just phoned to say Wanderers was finished and I could join the after party at his place.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, very public talks about ISEPP and the Pauling House, with &quot;strangers&quot; (members of the public) present, is very much in accordance with the spirit of nonprofit management.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re servants of the public, not shareholders.&amp;nbsp; As a socially responsible form of capitalism, we compete with the non-profits who set up around cost plus military contracts.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of government, Don came by early from the hospital to watch the president&#39;s speech on the telly.&amp;nbsp; We went through CBS.&amp;nbsp; President Trump was about done when Don arrived.&amp;nbsp; Then we heard the rebuttle from the other party.&amp;nbsp; Don visited with Carol a bit and then gave me a lift to the venue.&amp;nbsp; I took some time over at &lt;i&gt;Fred Meyer&#39;s&lt;/i&gt; to tweet, on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/4DsolutionsPDX/status/1082832040137961472&quot;&gt;@4DsolutionsPDX&lt;/a&gt;, one of my channels.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8405274391310003810'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8405274391310003810'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2019/01/wanderers-201918.html' title='Wanderers 2019.1.8'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4932096774159648774</id><published>2018-12-30T19:26:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-08T20:31:02.166-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Tweets</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
In the movie reviewed below, &lt;i&gt;Vice&lt;/i&gt;, we have a scene wherein they install offices for the veep all over town, which I found appealing.&amp;nbsp; People do that when they move around a lot.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, my two main perches are Blue House bound, in the sense that I have an outpost on each of two floors.&amp;nbsp; I have some work stations.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;re talking about a residential type of place, nothing unusual.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Work station&quot; is normal parlance for a home office and workspace, where a guest might have a laptop with WiFi.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve bounced around a lot and had a lot of offices, but as a single individual, I&#39;m bound to a sequential trajectory.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not in all places at once, unless we all are, in which case &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kirbyurner/feel-free-to-multitask-9fd7ab290bf3&quot;&gt;what point am I making&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Guests have departed.&amp;nbsp; I visited Peter&#39;s model train setup, which is truly cool.&amp;nbsp; Lots of pictures taken. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/4932096774159648774/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/4932096774159648774' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4932096774159648774'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4932096774159648774'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/12/tweets.html' title='Tweets'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4448136175541283330</id><published>2018-12-28T11:30:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-29T23:48:55.684-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Vice (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Movies that strive to make some sense of the recent past should be in high demand, if only as a source of mnemonic touch stones, memory devices, which this film is filled with.&amp;nbsp; The events come in as a jumble in time, and we piece it together through flashbacks (afterimages as we sometimes call them, in real life scenarios).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Clearly there&#39;s no way to reliably penetrate the cloak of secrecy that surrounds a high office that keeps mum.&amp;nbsp; The movie deals with uncertainty by breaking the fourth wall and otherwise reminding us of the impossibility of an omniscient viewpoint.&amp;nbsp; How does a dead man organ donor narrate a film from beyond the grave?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Clearly no cameras were present to document the intimate details of the Cheney bedroom, and there&#39;s a Lady Macbeth aspect to Lynne Cheney&#39;s role.&amp;nbsp; Having them break into Shakespearean dialog is a sure fire way to remind the audience they&#39;re watching theater, movies being an evolved form thereof.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Scenes are designed to tell a story.&amp;nbsp; During 911, Dick and Lynne head for the underground apartments and, from there, Dick insists on consuming raw, unfiltered intelligence.&amp;nbsp; Powell gets strong-armed, against his better judgement, into making his famous pitch for war to the UN, which in retrospect had the effect of lowering public confidence in so-called &quot;intelligence&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
DC has never really recovered its reputation for knowing what&#39;s going on in the world.&amp;nbsp; Justifications for recent cruise missile attacks against targets in Syria have met with derision outside of legacy media.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
From Cheney&#39;s angle, however, the challenge was to &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/09/lampoon-harpoon.html&quot;&gt;capitalize on 911&lt;/a&gt; in order to improve the prospects of the energy companies, with whom he liked to meet in secret.&amp;nbsp; The goal was not tit for tat, but to demonstrate overwhelming executive branch military power in conjunction with its power to shape pubic opinion.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Much of the innovative legislation, post 911, was focused domestically and internally, on building &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2014/11/citizenfour-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;a surveillance state&lt;/a&gt;, although the movie has only limited time to explore the ramifications of these developments.&amp;nbsp; Hollywood is still free to make and distribute questioning films like this, which put the inner workings of the White House under a critical director&#39;s eye.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kirbyurner/aluminum-tubes-b02edfdd06c0&quot;&gt;At the time&lt;/a&gt;, mid-career, I was one of those critical of the raw intelligence, such as we were privy to in the internet newsgroups (lots of spam), and questioning the rationale for &quot;shock &amp;amp; awe&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My focus (then as now) was preventing hanky-panky with nuclear waste products, with webcams and the like, about which science fiction planning I posted fairly frequently. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This wasn&#39;t my paid day job, as a coder and skills trainer &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/06/machine-world.html&quot;&gt;with CUE&lt;/a&gt;, so much as my volunteer service as a Quaker, a sect opposed to acting out with outward weapons.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But then we don&#39;t control the world now do we, and our views are easily dismissed as irrelevant by the outward war minded.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m used to being marginalized.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4448136175541283330'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4448136175541283330'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/12/vice-movie-review.html' title='Vice (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-456997288086567501</id><published>2018-12-22T13:12:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-27T11:52:23.078-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Ethnocentrism</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I&#39;m putting a positive spin on &quot;ethnocentrism&quot; here, which may surprise some readers, but I think it goes with education being &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kirbyurner/in-favor-of-place-based-education-21a3ea178177&quot;&gt;place based&lt;/a&gt;&quot; which I also favor.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Also, I see a lot of nuance when it comes to ethnicity, as one may easily adopt a fusion approach and combine several layers.&amp;nbsp; I tend to differentiate based on what&#39;s slow moving (slowly changing) versus what&#39;s potentially more fleeting, easy come easy go.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For example, in educating myself about Portland, I&#39;m always encountering its Asian aspects, and consider that a part of my ethnicity.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Ethnocentric&quot; need not mean conforming to some stereotype, in other words.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Negative vibes around &quot;ethnocentric&quot; stem from how people foist ethnicity on one another, insisting upon conformity to this or that norm.&amp;nbsp; People don&#39;t like being coerced, so the ethnocentrism of others may leave a bad taste, to say the least.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, one&#39;s ethnicity includes one&#39;s profession and the professions often require a lot of background and training.&amp;nbsp; Those resisting a hostile takeover of their corporate culture are unlikely to rise through the ranks of the invader.&amp;nbsp; You never know though; lots of fiction celebrates those who do.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/456997288086567501'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/456997288086567501'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/12/ethnocentrism.html' title='Ethnocentrism'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6676455644098333491</id><published>2018-12-18T20:59:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-11T11:47:24.079-08:00</updated><title type='text'>More T4P</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
The idea of truckers as citizen diplomats is not new, as camel trains, and ships&#39; crews, were always a medium of two way traffic, diplomatic and otherwise.&amp;nbsp; The technology has changed, certainly, in that camels were not equipped with ELD devices providing a log of the driver&#39;s up time, down time, sideways time.&amp;nbsp; A kind of quantum physics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The driver&#39;s upkeep and well being are not necessarily those of a truck&#39;s.&amp;nbsp; True, the custom is for a given driver to haul the load from end to end, but there could be a switching yard, where the driver gets to rest (as mandated), but the truck continues with nothing more than a refuel and driver-ready check / inspection.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Again, I&#39;m not being original, just borrowing from the airline companies, which vector crews and airplanes on different circuits.&amp;nbsp; Even the cockpit teams have their own autonomy, such that a given airplane my enjoy a lot of turnover in staffing in the course of a single day.&amp;nbsp; Truckers and pilots have always enjoyed many similarities.&amp;nbsp; I don&#39;t know if commercial routes are called lanes ever, but they could be.&amp;nbsp; Namespaces overlap a lot like that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In GST, the cockpit or truck cabin tends to meld with what we call the &quot;personal workspace&quot; or PWS. Sure, it might be mobile, even hurtling through space.&amp;nbsp; The PWS is distinct from the Control Room, as a place, in that the latter brings many people together to monitor the same stream of events.&amp;nbsp; They &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/12/truck-versus-rail.html&quot;&gt;provide overview&lt;/a&gt;, or what Quakers call oversight, and with supervisory powers come greater responsibilities for keeping aircraft safely separated.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/6676455644098333491/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/6676455644098333491' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6676455644098333491'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6676455644098333491'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/12/more-t4p.html' title='More T4P'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7788465833979952009</id><published>2018-12-12T19:51:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-12T20:13:08.632-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Reignition</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
In the process of dropping out of the middle class, upon dissolution of the partnership, owing to the death of the partner, I gave up heating the whole house.&amp;nbsp; I had a hole in the roof, and that took priority, as well as other bills.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, with a lot of company expected and Carol (mom) incapacitated, I was able to dedicate earmarked funds to a worthy line item:&amp;nbsp; resurrect the old Honeywell in the basement with a tune up ($229), a new master control board ($242.25 including labor) and of course fuel (200 gallons for a start).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fortunately, this winter is being very mild, with dips into the 30s.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ve gotten this far with only a few rooms heated, two downstairs and one upstairs.&amp;nbsp; The kitchen and (usually) main living area stayed in the 40s at least.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Portland, Oregon is close to snowy peaks, but is not itself at high altitude.&amp;nbsp; Our surrounding bedroom communities get more snow than the CBD (CBD = central business district, in case you didn&#39;t grow up in a planner family).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The First Call company inherited my account from Montag, which came with the house, as did the Honeywell, when we put money down on this place in 1995.&amp;nbsp; We had been renting just around the corner and despaired of again finding affordable digs we could invest in, as we knew then this was a trendy neighborhood. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Laurie, Dawn&#39;s first friend in Portland, showed us a property just going on the market.&amp;nbsp; We lucked out.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve lived here ever since.&amp;nbsp; Dawn (partner, DWA) died in 2007.&amp;nbsp; We still celebrate Hanukkah at Laurie&#39;s place.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I tried to keep DWA (the partnership) alive, not realizing a partnership with one partner was totally an oxymoron.&amp;nbsp; IRS was seeing double.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The H&amp;amp;R Block down the street helped me back out of my mistake and fly solo as a sole proprietorship.&amp;nbsp; I continued with the DWA sourced DBA:&amp;nbsp; 4D Solutions.&amp;nbsp; That part stayed by the book.&amp;nbsp; DWA held the business checking account.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Around then I met LW who was looking to anchor a career as a Portland-based musician, having given up a whole lifestyle in Savannah, Georgia working in high tech as a manager.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
She had a lot of good ideas for dropping below the poverty line and still surviving, having been saving all her money herself.&amp;nbsp; She was working at living on next to nothing when we met, and had a car she would no longer drive, because of her evolving ethics around Peak Oil.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Razz had been totaled. I was driving a loaner at that point.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fast forward, I got used to eating for free at Food Not Bombs servings, and also provided kitchen space, storage space, even freezer space, for the network, which meant having some inventory at home.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d fully entered the barter economy and started cutting back on any use of the furnace.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, somewhere in there, Steve Holden came to my rescue in putting my name in the hat as highly qualified to teach his Python 3 course, then in the making for the O&#39;Reilly School.&amp;nbsp; I was hired, and for the first time since the 1980s I had a salary with benefits.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d been winging it as an independent contractor, then partner, ever since.&amp;nbsp; Given Dawn was a skilled bookkeeper, that wasn&#39;t as hard as it sounds.&amp;nbsp; I could focus on programming for my many clients, and fine tuning my skills as a skills trainer.&amp;nbsp; My resume is online.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
By the O&#39;Reilly School (OST) closed its doors, some years later, I had paid to have my roof fixed and had helped a strong student through college (with help from her Quaker institution).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was looking at once again waving good bye to such middle class benefits as furnace oil heat.&amp;nbsp; Space heaters would have to do, and did.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I don&#39;t know that I&#39;ll be able to sustain this highfalutin lifestyle.&amp;nbsp; Will Earthlings want to learn Martian Math the way I teach it?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Will my productivity stay high?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Last year at this time, unbeknownst to me in December, I was just weeks away from an emergency room visit and lots of concern about my longevity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A year later, my vitals are looking like those of an overweight sixty year old, mas o meno.&amp;nbsp; My next doc appointment is six months out, which says something I hope.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7788465833979952009'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7788465833979952009'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/12/reignition.html' title='Reignition'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7192205155823126696</id><published>2018-12-09T11:24:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-09T13:15:23.672-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Physics in the First Person</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiWEHmt1qdMgGzAhAUl9RZiceZbOkaFnFG6399wZdhg0XZxaSIFwlLDoSbjSrVX8MuKufALSKs7XsVSSD3ENVKdQm82y80X3CYFEVex_4UKGDe2nIPiQxH3CXBYNz8rgndmqPfN/s1600/8006353506_3864822b72_z.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;480&quot; data-original-width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiWEHmt1qdMgGzAhAUl9RZiceZbOkaFnFG6399wZdhg0XZxaSIFwlLDoSbjSrVX8MuKufALSKs7XsVSSD3ENVKdQm82y80X3CYFEVex_4UKGDe2nIPiQxH3CXBYNz8rgndmqPfN/s400/8006353506_3864822b72_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;First Person Physics&quot; was a meme I started using on some listserv of physics teachers. Dr. Bob Fuller saw what I was driving at, including and especially the so-called &quot;energy slave&quot; concept.&amp;nbsp; The idea here was not to get rid of slavery but to not enslave humans or even mammals, but machines.&amp;nbsp; Don&#39;t make a horse lift the stone, let a diesel engine do it.&amp;nbsp; You enslave things like toasters and microwave ovens, which working humans in tandem with robots need to make in the first place.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Bucky Fuller was asking humans to pause and look around and see how many calories were being expended by machines every moment on their behalf.&amp;nbsp; But instead of reckoning in horsepower, lets take this opportunity to convert into work units humans could more easily relate to (&amp;lt; horses).&amp;nbsp; Some positive conversion constant might apply, and there you&#39;d have it:&amp;nbsp; a small army of robots (non-animal energy slaves) all working on your behalf.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You may need some assistance, at least at first, seeing where the work is being done.&amp;nbsp; Photons don&#39;t weigh much, and wiggling fingers over a keyboard is not a fast way to spend calories.&amp;nbsp; Better get up and make coffee frequently if that&#39;s your gig.&amp;nbsp; Lift weights.&amp;nbsp; Stay in shape.&amp;nbsp; Yet the internet is a vast energy slave army that produces lots of heat.&amp;nbsp; You, the one sitting in that chair, burn at about the rate of a one to two hundred watt bulb, which is the figure we were trying to get at, in place of horsepower.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Think about forklifts, warehouses, trucks on the freeway, stuff in your possession.&amp;nbsp; Non-slaves are allowed to possess (not be possessed), and humans typically think beyond their being 150 watt bulbs, to being this whole internet of things that burns, such as cars, trucks, trains and jets.&amp;nbsp; The internet of things comprises their lifestyle, which they value, whereas a &quot;daily bread&quot; of 150 watts burning 24/7 is no more sexy than enjoying a metabolism. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Your body heat needs to stay at roughly some level, pretty warm but not too hot, and just breathing and maintaining body temperature spends energy, which is work.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s right, in physics just staying alive one second to the next is considered work, and it&#39;s paid for.&amp;nbsp; You get about what you need to stay lit, or you don&#39;t, but in each case the requirement is in a bell curve between extremes. Getting enough calories to people is the bread game.&amp;nbsp; The truth is everyone requires about the same, even accounting the difference between babies and athletes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S4O5voOCqAQ&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Aside from measuring units of work in terms of humans (watt burners) replacing horses (also watt burners), First Person Physics is about being in the &quot;controller seat&quot; oneself (which doesn&#39;t connote omnipotence) as a &quot;first person&quot; (a viewpoint and presence) and experiencing acceleration.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Riding roller coasters helps make acceleration real, but then many roller coasters in life are not in the XYZt dimensions.&amp;nbsp; Precession is omni-dimesional.&amp;nbsp; We experience those deltas, as we traverse a less literally topographical phase space (a primordial soup), in a mix of Eulerian (spatial-visual) and Gibbsian (tactile-visceral) dimensions (more on that later).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In lieu of demanding a steady supply of expendable slaves, we harness the big calorie spenders such as the wind and downhill flowing water.&amp;nbsp; The sun is what lifts the water up again, and keeps the gases roiling.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Humans tap in to big dynamos to keep their wheels turning.&amp;nbsp; They burn stuff.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Windmills turn large radius rotation into smaller blade defined rotation of sufficient umph (power) to light a lot of bulbs.&amp;nbsp; Instead of ordering a servant to make an omelet, we switch on a stove and do the job of being a cook all by ourselves.&amp;nbsp; Humans have a wide repertoire.&amp;nbsp; They can type, talk, tinker.&amp;nbsp; Cooking is a fun pass time for some, an onerous duty for others.&amp;nbsp; Lets talk about Stoicism again.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Finally, I was nudged by something Keith Devlin said, about taking film more seriously, as a way of getting at those deltas.&amp;nbsp; The &quot;lights, camera, action!&quot; call of Hollywood, with stress on &quot;action&quot; (as the content of each frame), got me thinking &quot;action per time interval&quot; which is mvd/t or mvv or E or hf, units measuring what I considered &quot;energy buckets&quot; (or quanta), frames of film.&amp;nbsp; When the film runs too fast (E/t = power), it starts looking surreal.&amp;nbsp; We know from experience at what pace time goes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you&#39;ll be the star (first person) in your own film of action packed frames, in a &quot;scenario&quot; then that brings us to another definition of Universe in the literature:&amp;nbsp; as a set of eternally regenerative yet simultaneously aconceptual partially overlapping scenarios.&amp;nbsp; This definition was embedded in the American literature feeding into what I was calling Martian Math, nothing conventional within physics, yet a bridge to some of the memes some of the liberal arts people were convergent with, if into reading said literature.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhdj0M1TcDI_FTvHU106J_Fv5Ia1uHV-eQM629eaKqJUFo8bQSJsPqTyEHMqkk5dTTXyu1cEoaDH0Bi08sxHlva6wK4DeEbozxuHRphynvXMdXmddZuJQaYtJCldwHUly1UouWN/s1600/9298448736_ba22357756_z.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;640&quot; data-original-width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhdj0M1TcDI_FTvHU106J_Fv5Ia1uHV-eQM629eaKqJUFo8bQSJsPqTyEHMqkk5dTTXyu1cEoaDH0Bi08sxHlva6wK4DeEbozxuHRphynvXMdXmddZuJQaYtJCldwHUly1UouWN/s400/9298448736_ba22357756_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7192205155823126696'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7192205155823126696'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/12/physics-in-first-person.html' title='Physics in the First Person'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiWEHmt1qdMgGzAhAUl9RZiceZbOkaFnFG6399wZdhg0XZxaSIFwlLDoSbjSrVX8MuKufALSKs7XsVSSD3ENVKdQm82y80X3CYFEVex_4UKGDe2nIPiQxH3CXBYNz8rgndmqPfN/s72-c/8006353506_3864822b72_z.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6919688518022152891</id><published>2018-11-27T13:24:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-14T15:47:29.734-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Occupy University</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgioSHIMGHbFiVGPC3Q-IVppCFyljdEd8BI4feQPWGvXvF1HpUq9msvt8mlekOgPtypZEAFtrYXONiLU92oHQU78sPexIyqkH99qwt6uj5b0fwpScOjPnhGDaVlUETqVUZnzZba/s1600/opdx_map.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;281&quot; data-original-width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;175&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgioSHIMGHbFiVGPC3Q-IVppCFyljdEd8BI4feQPWGvXvF1HpUq9msvt8mlekOgPtypZEAFtrYXONiLU92oHQU78sPexIyqkH99qwt6uj5b0fwpScOjPnhGDaVlUETqVUZnzZba/s400/opdx_map.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;OPDX - Occupy Portland&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
Those of you looking for Occupy University (OU) have come to the right place.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve been out recruiting faculty, as I did when we staged &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/11/adult-discussion.html&quot;&gt;a non-virtual OPDX&lt;/a&gt; in downtown Portland, in the same place where WWI vets staged their March to Washington.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That led to the DC Hooverville which General MacArthur destroyed, in a misplaced show of bravado (a form of friendly fire).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the faculty lounge, one discussion is whether animation, both 2D and 3D, constitutes a form of &quot;coding&quot; or not.&amp;nbsp; These are the kinds of nitpicky debate one expects in Faculty World.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Clearly the art of television programming, the sequencing of shows to fill dead air space, is a kind of programming.&amp;nbsp; Think &quot;programme&quot; when it comes to theater.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
English makes a big point of not using &quot;programme&quot; to mean &quot;program&quot;, obscuring the fact that source code scripts actually orchestrate and direct platform action, much as a play does, or a musical score.&amp;nbsp; English is somewhat (horse and) buggy, we all know that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The word &quot;code&quot; is likewise ambiguous, as we have &quot;codes of conduct&quot; at geek events, which tend to be treated like Codes of Hammurabi, meaning they&#39;re enforced, with transgressions confessed or uncovered.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s &quot;code as law&quot; one might say, where &quot;obedience&quot; is a keyword.&amp;nbsp; However &quot;code&quot; also means what computers execute directly (we could say &quot;obey&quot; but usually don&#39;t for some reason).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you think the bottomline is &quot;it&#39;s all semantics&quot; you&#39;re correct.&amp;nbsp; &quot;There&#39;s semantics, and there&#39;s nothing&quot; is about as helpful as my other dictum &quot;There&#39;s science fiction, and there&#39;s nothing.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Both are meant to emphasize the universality of the leading term, in contrasting them with nothing.&amp;nbsp; The dialectic goes away at that point, but then tautologies provide no traction.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tautologies are more about emphasizing and underlining a grammar, and show more than say.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re not about making empirical claims so much as delineating the boundaries of sense-making.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This is what Wittgenstein meant when he said his philosophy was not about stating theses, as if it did so, they&#39;d by of the kind no one could disagree with.&amp;nbsp; In delineating sense, one borders on nonsense, by definition.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6919688518022152891'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6919688518022152891'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/11/occupy-university.html' title='Occupy University'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgioSHIMGHbFiVGPC3Q-IVppCFyljdEd8BI4feQPWGvXvF1HpUq9msvt8mlekOgPtypZEAFtrYXONiLU92oHQU78sPexIyqkH99qwt6uj5b0fwpScOjPnhGDaVlUETqVUZnzZba/s72-c/opdx_map.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7017122481900534362</id><published>2018-11-18T10:36:00.003-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-21T12:36:12.610-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Martian Math</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6lE-SVJ8fJE&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lyQDz-zmnRM&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7017122481900534362'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7017122481900534362'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/11/martian-math.html' title='Martian Math'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/6lE-SVJ8fJE/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6967373919324180449</id><published>2018-11-15T17:59:00.004-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-16T18:33:35.338-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Black Friday</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Black Friday is a day of mourning.&amp;nbsp; We lament that Christmas has nothing to do with &quot;peace on Earth&quot; anymore, if it ever did.&amp;nbsp; Crass commercialism has taken over.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/DGcVKNwzQWo&quot;&gt;Tastelessness abides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On Black Friday, we apologize to God for being a planet of spoiled brats. &lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6967373919324180449'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6967373919324180449'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/11/black-friday.html' title='Black Friday'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3624562204989389301</id><published>2018-10-31T13:46:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2018-11-14T13:01:00.169-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Time Management</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/31782490358/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Fall Garden&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fall Garden&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1921/31782490358_585d0fd622.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People go to school to learn about scheduling in the software sense.&amp;nbsp; The operating system&#39;s primary job is to protect processes entrusted to its care, meaning it gives them each attention.&amp;nbsp; We hope the OS is not stretched to capacity, as might be USA OS version 0.2, or whatever that is still running in the District. A former image.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Here in &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kirbyurner/intraquaker-dialog-9ac6102e2b1c&quot;&gt;Asylum District&lt;/a&gt; I talk to a leading expert in concurrency.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/07/parallel-processing.html&quot;&gt;Synchronous parallelism&lt;/a&gt; with multiple CPU cores is distinct from letting a coroutine sit on the shelf in pause mode, because it has no new work.&amp;nbsp; A lot of your bureaucracy consists of people waiting for results, and not pressing the matter, because already working with earlier requests.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Case in point:&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m heading down to county elections this afternoon, on behalf of my mom.&amp;nbsp; We stopped by in mid September to make sure her ballot would come here and not go to California.&amp;nbsp; It went to California.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If they try to mail another one today, it will also go to California.&amp;nbsp; No one in the bureaucracy has gotten that far in the queue.&amp;nbsp; The request is on file, but there&#39;s nothing immediate about updating the main database.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/31782492378/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;P1070234&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;P1070234&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1929/31782492378_d654a33c64.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was trying to strike up a conversation with other businesses on social media about whether gambling for charity is still gambling.&amp;nbsp; I see these restrictions against gambling over the wire, but in these games, the winnings go to the charity of your choice, and you get to be the one with a hero&#39;s profile.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People will commit to your potential winnings on the basis of your wise use (in their eyes) of their commitments.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve spelled out all the plans and protected them for the public, in &lt;a href=&quot;https://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2018/10/the-economics-and-psychology-of.html&quot;&gt;this sister blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of being a hero, I understand how people &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/03/unicode-experiments.html&quot;&gt;use the &lt;i&gt;I Ching&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as a mnemonic device.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s a pattern language to the hero&#39;s journey, and in being willing to have the &lt;i&gt;I Ching&lt;/i&gt; be &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/10/ppug-20081014.html&quot;&gt;the labyrinth&lt;/a&gt;, one gets a well trodden, spelled out adventure.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Welcome to LARP.&amp;nbsp; Live Action Role Playing.&amp;nbsp; Your life. What&#39;s wrong with feeding your inner hero?&amp;nbsp; Isn&#39;t that what psychologists say to do?&amp;nbsp; Lets be consistent.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The empiricists and frequentists cry foul, saying it&#39;s &quot;superstitious&quot; or &quot;magical&quot; thinking to consult the &lt;i&gt;I Ching&lt;/i&gt; or look at Tarot decks or whatever.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re not thinking of how reinforcing a Memory Palace using the events of one&#39;s day is simply taking up the raw material of everyday living and applying that as a kind of glue language, to something worth holding together (a model).&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Having a Memory Palace is not in itself a bad idea.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So what if a random billboard reminds you of one of its many rooms?&amp;nbsp; Would you rather just obey the billboard?&amp;nbsp; Some would prefer that you would.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/30716657927/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;P1070239&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;P1070239&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1978/30716657927_a5d00ceb90.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3624562204989389301'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3624562204989389301'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/10/time-management.html' title='Time Management'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1347821189105046684</id><published>2018-10-27T12:15:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2018-11-14T13:06:12.523-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Volume Formulas</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/41211295565/in/album-72157624750749042/&quot; title=&quot;Martian Multiplication&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Martian Multiplication&quot; height=&quot;312&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/907/41211295565_59145e2f63.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As a young adult, I was adamant that I wanted a Web to publish within, meaning I was salivating for hypertext, just at the time of its advent.&amp;nbsp; I was a fan of the Web before it popped up at CERN, my Higgs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So once HTTP was in vogue, I published to that &quot;medium&quot; (i.e. to cyberspace).&amp;nbsp; However, my peers in academia were schooled to channel their thinking to subscriber audiences through specific journals.&amp;nbsp; These were not using hypertext for the most part.&amp;nbsp; I felt my thinking required hypertext.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fast forward, and a lot of interesting mathematical results are rattling around in a volatile medium.&amp;nbsp; I say &quot;volatile&quot; because Forum 206, where I published over a decade of writing, was taken over by the NCTM, which appears to have killed the entire Math Forum website  [Followup: &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/forum.jspa?forumID=206&quot;&gt;it was kept&lt;/a&gt;].&amp;nbsp; The Web is more of a war zone in some ways. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For example, there&#39;s a lineage through &lt;a href=&quot;https://mathpages.com/home/kmath424/kmath424.htm&quot;&gt;Piero della Francesca&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to volume formulas for a Tetrahedron given only its six edges.&amp;nbsp; Euler came up with something like that too.&amp;nbsp; On Synergetics-L, a listserv that&#39;s gone belly-up, Gerald de Jong came up with something simple we could implement in code (see below). A lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/4dsolutions/Python5/blob/master/Computing%20Volumes.ipynb&quot;&gt;my tetravolume computations&lt;/a&gt; come from there.&amp;nbsp; Just today I was doing these:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/45586281061/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Volume Checks&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Volume Checks&quot; height=&quot;419&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1931/45586281061_8a0df0ef31.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Koski is on the other end of the line doing some work around the S-factor.&amp;nbsp; He fed me another test to try, which came out as expected.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/44695079795/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;45039331_10156668586278965_2426966880871776256_n&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;45039331_10156668586278965_2426966880871776256_n&quot; height=&quot;463&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1952/44695079795_8f195f202a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1347821189105046684'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1347821189105046684'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/10/volume-formulas.html' title='Volume Formulas'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1935822286042786768</id><published>2018-10-23T18:14:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2021-06-04T22:42:03.014-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Marxist?</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/44813098734/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;gst_vs_econ&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;gst_vs_econ&quot; height=&quot;395&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1961/44813098734_95b153ccdf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.datadriveninvestor.com/gst-versus-econ-28457f03ae9a&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;on Medium&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, I went to Princeton, so maybe you think I&#39;ve been steeped in Marx, given current stereotypes of what universities are like, cite Jordan Peterson et al.&amp;nbsp; However way back in the late 1970s, my thing was Freud and Jung.&amp;nbsp; Even in high school, psychoanalytic literature was my bag.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quakerquaker.org/group/liberal/forum/topics/the-earliest-quakers-and-liberal-quakerism-1?commentId=2360685%3AComment%3A162014&amp;amp;groupId=2360685%3AGroup%3A867&quot;&gt;the whole idea&lt;/a&gt; of &quot;mental illness&quot; rather fascinating, and I don&#39;t think in a creepy way.&amp;nbsp; What a vast landscape, this inner world, and how weird it could become.&amp;nbsp; Very Tantric (is how I sometimes think of it).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So yes, when I got to Princeton, I dove into Jacques Lacan, some Adorno, certainly Marcuse.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not like I didn&#39;t do any homework whatsoever.&amp;nbsp; I looked at the Hegelian system as a precursor to Marxism. The whole idea of Logic versus History seemed pretty special.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I do remember students protesting the one-sidedness of the Economics curriculum.&amp;nbsp; We used Samuelson for a textbook in 101.&amp;nbsp; Stagflation was a problem back then.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
Those hoping to get some Marxism in the mix were to be sadly disappointed, or so I gathered from the raging debates, which were printed in various issues of the &lt;i&gt;Daily Princetonian&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; I was housemates with the editor.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I do recall roaming the open stacks in the reserve reading room (is that an oxymoron?), and coming across collections of old high school textbooks.&amp;nbsp; Some of them were so biased, when it came to mentioning Marxism.&amp;nbsp; Having seen museums filled with textbooks from Nazi days, I&#39;ve taken to studying the history of ideas through the lens of what we share with kids.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was focused on philosophy as my long time readers know.&amp;nbsp; I felt I had a chance at international relations and applied to the Woodrow Wilson School.&amp;nbsp; However, during my interview I expressed some ambivalence.&amp;nbsp; I was talking myself into philosophy instead.&amp;nbsp; Dr. Kahler was disappointed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My early fascination with psychoanalysis and the inner world is likely what predisposed me to choose philosophy over international affairs, but then I&#39;ve never really seen these as all that separate, from psychology either.&amp;nbsp; I learned about James Hillman from Sue and Bryan.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Process Work, as developed by Arnold Mindell, somewhat expresses my own sense of unity in this area.&amp;nbsp; Logic &amp;amp; History...&amp;nbsp; Like Alex says, mathematics is everything.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People sound Marxist to me when they see someone getting public sector benefits as being supported by taxes, and in turn by their work.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Only the work of the working provides any value, so if others get value and aren&#39;t working, they&#39;re gaining at my expense.&quot;&amp;nbsp; Missing from this equation: (1) the great bounty of the environment, starting with the sun; (2) the fact that we&#39;re all working, regardless of our title and job description in whatever role playing capacity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m not saying taxes don&#39;t make a difference (I just wrote a check for $4,831.28 for property taxes). I&#39;m saying that World Game is not zero sum and public sector wealth owes more to the sun, wind and rain than to any issuer of debts.&amp;nbsp; Banks may pretend to loan us our cosmic heritage, but we&#39;re only gullible to a point.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1935822286042786768'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1935822286042786768'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/10/marxist.html' title='Marxist?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3672012064567317957</id><published>2018-10-20T11:58:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-20T13:00:40.103-07:00</updated><title type='text'>All Thumbs</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/2560279010/in/photolist-4Uf6Ky&quot; title=&quot;Stanley Theater&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Stanley Theater&quot; height=&quot;354&quot; src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3152/2560279010_8013fb3687.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m still all thumbs when it comes to CAD.&amp;nbsp; I have Rhino3D on a Windows tablet, thanks to C6XTY, and I&#39;m sharing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/10/animation-classes.html&quot;&gt;3D Animation curriculum&lt;/a&gt; through Coding with Kids.&amp;nbsp; Between the two of these, I imagine my skill set will improve.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When colluders conspire in Buckydom (as one might name it), what do they talk about?&amp;nbsp; In the case of Koski and myself, last night on Verizon, the topic was the four RTs in &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2018/10/welcome-to-sesame-street.html&quot;&gt;Sesame Street Synergetics&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; RT = a diamond-faced (rhombus-faced) zonohedron.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve been writing about it in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/10/first-stop-on-tour.html&quot;&gt;recent blog posts.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/4178618830/in/photolist-27mJSE2-9AU59Y-97TTvV-8dyvmP-8batBx-8awATh-7YZyV3-7nfvNf-7jzVRo-7jzVSm-5STUzp-5DsYfo-5zTRpB-Joybi-JoybP-6BkWWK&quot; title=&quot;Rhombic Triacontrahedron&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Rhombic Triacontrahedron&quot; height=&quot;456&quot; src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2717/4178618830_3bfa285a46.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Why don&#39;t we have IMAX or 4K or whatever large format films going over the basics of a concentric hierarchy of polyhedrons?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Koski&#39;s idea: We could go with a Greek motif and employ retro aesthetics, say those of a scrolling slideshow from the 1960s, where you get a cassette in the same box.&amp;nbsp; When the cassette goes &quot;beep&quot;, you advance to roll to the next slide.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Make each frame come alive using contemporary CGI.&amp;nbsp; A message we&#39;re sending:&amp;nbsp; we&#39;ve known some of this stuff for a long time.&amp;nbsp; Lets connect to the near and distant past, as we establish our heritage.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was writing about such IMAX movies in the 1980s, even before I had any clear conception of a volume 7.5 RT sharing vertexes with a volume 6 RD (rhombic dodecahedron).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I had &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/05/flash-back.html&quot;&gt;the Stanley Theater&lt;/a&gt; picked out in Jersey City.&amp;nbsp; Jehovah&#39;s Witnesses would buy it later.&amp;nbsp; At the time, it had no mission and I thought I might insert myself into JCNJ politics.&amp;nbsp; I phoned the IMAX company, wondering if &lt;a href=&quot;http://flavorwire.com/319131/10-movies-wed-love-to-see-in-imax/2&quot;&gt;an IMAX version of&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Koyannisqatsi&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;might be in the works.&amp;nbsp; They sent me a PR packet.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Actually, my Stanley Theater idea was more embracing:&amp;nbsp; students would come by PATH from NYU and other Manhattan-based institutions of higher learning (high schools too, why not), to see these movies for academic credit.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Learning to navigate around &quot;Cosmopolis&quot; as I called it, was part of growing up (the maturation process).&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve continued the theme of having public transportation systems, both the study and use thereof, be a part of a &quot;placed based&quot; curriculum.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Later, my Princeton and Jersey City housemate Selma would work on precisely such a &quot;maturation&quot; program for NYU students.&amp;nbsp; Help them overcome their fear of New York.&amp;nbsp; They didn&#39;t come over to the Stanley on the PATH though.&amp;nbsp; That project never materialized.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The RT and RD didn&#39;t make it to the big screen.&amp;nbsp; Nor did my proposed Fuller Projection made of tiny lights ever make it to the back wall of Loew&#39;s (also part of my Journal Square environment -- just outside my front door).&amp;nbsp; Instead, the internet took off, a decade later.&amp;nbsp; Fuller&#39;s stuff would go online, with no need to leave one&#39;s dorm room to gain access.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was fascinated by the internet back then too.&amp;nbsp; At the nearby New Jersey Institute of Technology, they were testing an early version of an electronic communications system.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d read &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/network-nation-Human-communication-computer/dp/020103140X/ref=tmm_hrd_title_2?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1540063102&amp;amp;sr=8-1-fkmr0&quot;&gt;A Network Nation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; by Starr Roxanne Hiltz &amp;amp; Murray Turoff and even managed to score a guest account on their prototype system.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I didn&#39;t have a modem at home, but I could visit St. Peter&#39;s College down the street and get on.&amp;nbsp; This was all pre HTTP (hypertext transfer protocol), the protocol later invented at CERN.&amp;nbsp; However I&#39;d read &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Computer-Lib-Dream-Machines-Revised/dp/0914845497?keywords=computer+lib+dream+machines&amp;amp;qid=1540063383&amp;amp;sr=8-1-fkmrnull&amp;amp;ref=sr_1_fkmrnull_1&quot;&gt;Computer Lib / Dream Machines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; by Ted Nelson and was fantasizing about hypertext already.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My larger &quot;Cosmopolis&quot; idea had to do with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.panynj.gov/path/path-extension.html&quot;&gt;extending PATH to connect with EWR&lt;/a&gt;, the Newark Airport.&amp;nbsp; NYC was already opening a &quot;Train to the Plane&quot; from WTC to JFK.&amp;nbsp; I was thinking how passengers might have a seamless rail connection from EWR to JFK and vice versa.&amp;nbsp; I sent out some letters.&amp;nbsp; I was continuing in my dad&#39;s footsteps, thinking like an urban planner.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/2560252636/in/photolist-9UAhMa-65aMfw-4UeXSE-4UeXPb-4UeXUQ&quot; title=&quot;Mom and Son&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Mom and Son&quot; height=&quot;353&quot; src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3270/2560252636_d1735fc19a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3672012064567317957'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3672012064567317957'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/10/all-thumbs.html' title='All Thumbs'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4674350114996657391</id><published>2018-10-18T12:20:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-18T12:29:05.220-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Learning Modes</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/45361645122/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;portland_fun&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;portland_fun&quot; height=&quot;345&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1919/45361645122_706423499f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When we&#39;re all together in a room, that&#39;s a time to help each other, if we can.&amp;nbsp; What have we gotten good at?&amp;nbsp; Maybe nothing so far?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You can just try stuff, read the docs, watch the instructional Youtubes.&amp;nbsp; Once you have mastered a skill, you&#39;re ready to demo your mastery to someone else.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In practice, &quot;homework&quot; is often reading the docs and watching the videos.&amp;nbsp; Time helping others directly is a variable.&amp;nbsp; Sometimes the people we call &quot;teachers&quot; are the ones spending more time showing others than learning himself.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I might be a teacher and student at the same time, which is the work / study picture in GST, the assembly language of the Global U.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/4674350114996657391/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/4674350114996657391' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4674350114996657391'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4674350114996657391'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/10/learning-modes.html' title='Learning Modes'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1170686109017243274</id><published>2018-10-14T12:08:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-14T13:58:41.383-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Hammer Man</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
What does it mean to develop a meaning &quot;operationally&quot;?&amp;nbsp; I first answer:&amp;nbsp; is there any other way?&amp;nbsp; Sometimes what&#39;s hardest to define is that for which we have no counter-example.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Let me switch topics and mention the &quot;hammer man&quot; in Synergetics, whom I tend to think of as an art deco Olympian, somewhat cartoon-like.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He hammers, as when pounding some metal towards greater flatness.&amp;nbsp; We read about the molecules sliding around in response to these blows.&amp;nbsp; Sometimes, he &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=Op4qDwAAQBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA159&amp;amp;lpg=PA159&amp;amp;dq=hammer+man+synergetics&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=jhQmSPs7s6&amp;amp;sig=cbxHNdYKW4PUDJBMZ7NdPdobJd0&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwij7uyI6YbeAhXhiVQKHbLUDDIQ6AEwCnoECAgQAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=hammer%20man%20synergetics&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;hammers it &lt;i&gt;thicker&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He swings his hammer, as an Olympian would, meaning he&#39;s to develop a lot of angular momentum as he swings the heavy device in a circular path, himself at the center, and then lets go in the direction of some eigenvector whereon every expended calorie counts for the most.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He sometimes is at the center of a gyroscopic device of many hammers, all radiating in a giant wheel, as he turns in place.&amp;nbsp; Tugging on the axis of this apparatus tilts the radial path into a dive, meaning the axis yields more at 90 degrees to the direction of your tug.&amp;nbsp; Such is precession.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The hammer man sees precession everywhere as he tucks himself in, after a long day.&amp;nbsp; Hammering, anchoring and letting go, getting hammered... time for some rest, before tomorrow&#39;s big adventures.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1170686109017243274'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1170686109017243274'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/10/hammer-man.html' title='Hammer Man'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1291764654765940652</id><published>2018-10-12T18:00:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-12T18:48:53.751-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Fed Up (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aCUbvOwwfWM&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This movie is in alignment with &lt;i&gt;SuperSize Me&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/03/got-facts-on-milk-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Got the Facts on Milk?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The vital organs of the USG (Department of Agriculture, FDA, Congress...) are as assaulted and degraded as the vital organs of any hooked-on-nachos-and-fries school child.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A weak and pudgy USA was a pushover when it mattered,&amp;nbsp; yet it still pretends to be a player, &quot;winning wars&quot; for its donor controllers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Smedley Butler era Business Plot against FDR was long ago successful, at least since Reagan&#39;s term.&amp;nbsp; Thinking some porky establishment in Washington DC is going to save us this late in the game seems pretty dated, not to mention unrealistic. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What world capital has that kind of power?&amp;nbsp; Against Coca-Cola?&amp;nbsp; Again Nestles?&amp;nbsp; You&#39;ve gotta be kidding me, right?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One idea I&#39;ve clung to over the years:&amp;nbsp; why don&#39;t we have private sector companies that specialize in edgy advertising, employing counter-intelligence the way we need,&amp;nbsp; and the production of which propaganda the USG is apparently incapable?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ll keep buying your coffee, and subscribing to your on-line games, if you promise to keep hitting out hard against junk food culture.&amp;nbsp; Deal?&amp;nbsp; Why can&#39;t it work?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The status quo is we somehow expect private sector media news companies to exercise their juice through channels.&amp;nbsp; But which such media have such juice anymore?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Who takes up the cause of youngsters against Diabetes Inc?&amp;nbsp; Pediatricians? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Obnoxico rules the roost and it&#39;s hard to see who has enough muscle to challenge the pervasive ideology of a soulless corporate personhood.&amp;nbsp; Not the World Health Organization it turns out.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Uncle Sam?&amp;nbsp; Is he still on life support?&amp;nbsp; Seems to me he flat-lined some decades ago.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m getting a strong Morlocks versus Eloi vibe.&amp;nbsp; A predatory intelligence, some Bell Curve&#39;s upper half, is quite willing to exploit its trusting victims, by means of cartoons.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Eat lots of sugar and become a basket case&quot; say the immortal cartoon characters, not physical beings themselves. We have the makings of a horror film here.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Did you know that FDA nutrition guidelines mandate no upper limit on calories from sugar? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That North Americans are among the most malnourished anywhere is raw ammo for those hoping to suggest some alternative wiring, experiments with other approaches. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Could we experiment more with &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kirbyurner/in-favor-of-place-based-education-21a3ea178177&quot;&gt;how we do food&lt;/a&gt; in schools?&amp;nbsp; What about &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/10/learning-to-cook.html&quot;&gt;those cooking shows&lt;/a&gt;, saved to the school server?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Various talking heads tell us that a foreign power and declared enemy of the USA, hellbent on its destruction, would be hard pressed to do as much harm as the junk food and junk science industries.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The logical conclusion is that some alien ideology is indeed entrenched.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Fed Up&lt;/i&gt; offers some hope, but as long as the answer involves looking towards DC for leadership, I question whether that hope is misplaced.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Expecting USG politicians to regulate from on high, to protect citizens and guests against predators, is expecting too much.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1291764654765940652'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1291764654765940652'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/10/fed-up-movie-review.html' title='Fed Up (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/aCUbvOwwfWM/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1676977822722290092</id><published>2018-10-09T12:13:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-11T13:12:47.966-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Animation Classes</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
The curated clips of high schoolers walking out in protest, in the Michael Moore film &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/10/fahrenheit-119-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;reviewed below&lt;/a&gt;, gets me thinking more about possible high schooler lifestyles.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m thinking beyond such questions as to whether to arm the teachers.&amp;nbsp; I look at the role of firearms in other writings.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lifestyle and curriculum content are not wholly separate, by any means.&amp;nbsp; Suppose you learn at home three days a week, visiting community school buildings less hours.&amp;nbsp; Does this make you a &quot;home schooler&quot;?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Maybe some of your time is &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=10168568&quot;&gt;in a studio&lt;/a&gt; for making videos, doing &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/09/community-kitchen.html&quot;&gt;cooking shows&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Video editing, camera work, health and nutrition, kitchen procedures (recipes and algorithms), all mixed together.&amp;nbsp; Store the videos to the school server.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not every video has to go to Youtube.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m picking up two animations classes this week, 2D and 3D, in two different schools.&amp;nbsp; We think in terms of age levels and running in parallel to existing curricula.&amp;nbsp; The early grades seem to be plane geometry intensive whereas later we go spatial?&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s a rough approximation.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In 1997 I attended the ISEPP-organized &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/mathsummit.html&quot;&gt;Math Summit at OSU&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; There, I heard a talk by Dr. Keith Devlin encouraging more connections &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/10/tweening.html&quot;&gt;between movie-making and calculus&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; A tiny delta t is like a frame of film, encapsulating some action.&amp;nbsp; Literally, action per time frame, in mechanics, is mvd/t, which is energy units (E).&amp;nbsp; But then how fast is the film playing?&amp;nbsp; Enter E per t, or Power.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Integration means accumulating small differences as governed by the changing variable, the dx or dt. I think of how &lt;a href=&quot;https://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2018-October/012024.html&quot;&gt;Fibonacci numbers&lt;/a&gt; are accumulative.&amp;nbsp; What &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/FibonacciPolynomial.html&quot;&gt;continuous curve&lt;/a&gt; fits those, I forget?&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1676977822722290092'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1676977822722290092'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/10/animation-classes.html' title='Animation Classes'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8672728365590860450</id><published>2018-10-01T22:00:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-02T12:41:58.358-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Fahrenheit 11/9 (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Michael Moore has been following Flint, Michigan through all of his movies.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s the saga of a city gone bust, amidst rulers who don&#39;t have much hope, given the priorities of their higher ups.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The timeline Moore follows starts with the 2016 US election, then jumps over to Michigan in 2010, when the state governor invokes emergency powers in several cities and replaces their local leadership with his people.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Around Flint, the engineering goes south when a working water supply gets monkeyed with.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Television did not turn out to be that medium for public debate we used to hear about, given who paid for it and why.&amp;nbsp; Will social media be any better?&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s a quick cut to Facebook, suggesting grassroots organizing but the internet and cryptocurrencies are not the order of the day (Alex Jones makes it in, but I was confused about what he was saying in that clip).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mostly the tech giants get left out of this telling, and there&#39;s no attempt to dive deep into hackerdom. Leave Putin another bad guy strongman, the way Trump likes his leaders, and move on.&amp;nbsp; This isn&#39;t Oliver Stone driving.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway it&#39;s jarring when we remember this lead poisoning is all happening during President Obama&#39;s time, the last great hope.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Trump presidency is already well established in the movie before we switch to Flint, which is deliberate, as the story is one of &quot;paving the way&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The larger picture is pretty bleak.&amp;nbsp; Young people need to do their own organizing, and are.&amp;nbsp; The adults aren&#39;t particularly able, when it comes to keeping democracy going.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One of the wise elders reminds us the US only started to experiment with democracy in the 1970s, with on-paper enfranchisement of non-whites and women, and that experiment may have reached its conclusion, in the wake of 911.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The flavor of the film is wistful.&amp;nbsp; Wouldn&#39;t a United States be a good idea?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Filmmaker Steve Bannon says on camera he appreciates Michael Moore&#39;s craft, though is at odds with his politics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s not Moore&#39;s fault that destiny would put him in the eye of the storm, nor Flint&#39;s either.&amp;nbsp; He has already looked at school shootings.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s trusted to observe the high schoolers in action.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sure he&#39;s heavy handed, because he&#39;s expressing his worries in strong terms.&amp;nbsp; He says out loud what a lot of people are thinking.&amp;nbsp; Lets get those thoughts on the big screen.&amp;nbsp; Yep, there&#39;s Hitler, buoyed by some of the same vibes; his ghost still haunts us.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The school teachers of West Virginia get a lot of recognition, for trying to hold together the fabric of their society in the midst of an opium crisis and infrastructure bled dry.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Bernie Sanders campaign, and its call for social programs, gets a lot of focus as well.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Moore is weaving a lot in.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s curating many &quot;Kodak moments&quot; assuming an audience in the future.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m not saying I&#39;m Moore&#39;s mouthpiece and would tell all the same stories he does.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re on rather different trajectories.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s not a criticism, just an observation bordering on a truism.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Here&#39;s another provocative film that is sure to provoke many.&amp;nbsp; I felt updated on many happenings.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8672728365590860450'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8672728365590860450'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/10/fahrenheit-119-movie-review.html' title='Fahrenheit 11/9 (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8630540765308757133</id><published>2018-09-28T14:08:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-28T19:35:22.982-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Home Schooling</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nnhjvHYRsmM&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Probably a lot of kids are staying home from school, with parental permission, because said guardians are persuaded that &lt;i&gt;Coding Train&lt;/i&gt; is providing a more personalized experience, in more useful skills, than the local commuter schools.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That sounds paradoxical because how would Youtubes over the wire be &quot;more personalized&quot;?  Well, it&#39;s not the student teacher interaction that&#39;s one-on-one, so much as the task at hand:  to customize the personal workspace.  Build your own file system.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Students herded from room to room, with or without a locker, don&#39;t get the same opportunity to outfit a workspace.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The homeschoolers are telling Dan to try pipenv instead of virtualenv.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s good feedback for me as well.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2018/03/youtube-teachers.html&quot;&gt;I&#39;m one of the home schoolers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8630540765308757133'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8630540765308757133'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/09/home-schooling.html' title='Home Schooling'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/nnhjvHYRsmM/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-56575052310867699</id><published>2018-09-23T21:25:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-24T12:35:18.819-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Party Time</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Hey, I&#39;m pleased &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/09/ironclad-logic.html&quot;&gt;the Idlib scenario&lt;/a&gt; didn&#39;t go straight to blood, like some shoot out in Westworld, or should I call it the Park?&amp;nbsp; Remember &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/12/punishment-park-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Punishment Park&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;?&amp;nbsp; Now there was a dark movie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I have some Proseco to celebrate, no not especially Islamic of me, but many ethnicities stand to gain, if we&#39;re able to move the Global U towards a more constructive set of rivalries.&amp;nbsp; Congratulations to everyone working on the rebuilding of Aleppo, especially that central mosque.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m also celebrating the Fall Equinox.&amp;nbsp; ISEPP hosted Wanderers at the Linus Pauling House.&amp;nbsp; Terry explained his research into the history of the philosophy of engineering.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s on a first name basis with Sadi (Nicolas Lonard Sadi Carnot) and Lazare Carnot&amp;nbsp; (Sadi&#39;s dad).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The latter was smeared in some circles because of his loyalty to French Republicanism.&amp;nbsp; Nietzsche respected him for his sticking to his guns.&amp;nbsp; Laplace was smeared too.&amp;nbsp; This happens to intellectuals, as their power and influence, including postmortem (especially postmortem), gains them enemies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Russian and Turkish commanders are working on the Idlib scenario.&amp;nbsp; Erdoan and Putin had hours and hours of meetings.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of Turks, I&#39;ve been picking on the Gulenists a lot, expecting them to advertise a future-friendly STEM through the charter schools, in tandem with the Quakers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However that&#39;s putting a lot on their shoulders, given they&#39;re transplants in many cases.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Raising the flag of some Verboten Math is just going to attract the spotlight, when they&#39;ve already been the subject of any number of FBI investigations.&amp;nbsp; Wading blindly into American politics is a recipe for getting in too deeply i.e. &quot;in over one&#39;s head&quot; as they say.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I think I&#39;ll give those Sufis a break and switch my focus to the Jesuits for a change.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s another religious sect with a commitment to education.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve worked quite a bit around Catholic schools (and teaching hospitals) and don&#39;t doubt the high level of commitment.&amp;nbsp; The decision to keep a tight lid on the Bucky stuff must trace to the highest levels.&amp;nbsp; Surely pure inertia can&#39;t be the explanation.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve taken up the investigation (inquisition?) on Gab.ai for the time being.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Terry has discovered some engineering literature we might have taken for granted would already be translated into English, but has not been.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Take &lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;Coriolis &lt;/span&gt; for example.&amp;nbsp; We may have learned about the effect, but what do we know about the actual guy?&amp;nbsp; A lot of his writings have never been published in English.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve never been put off by skin color, and mostly get along well with the dead.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not averse to learning more from the &quot;dead whites&quot; (and will soon enough be joining their number -- not to sound morbid or anything).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A long time ago, scientists argued about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vis_viva&quot;&gt;&quot;vis viva&quot;&lt;/a&gt; or the motive force.&amp;nbsp; They considered it a property internal to a moving body and akin to its inertia.&amp;nbsp; How to account for it mathematically, in symbols and computations, was a question for that day. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mass figures into the equations, most certainly, but then so does velocity, and perhaps to a second power?&amp;nbsp; Is a projectile with twice the velocity thereby empowered to do four times the work?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Jean Bernoulli contributed some clever reasoning showing why E = mvv was more likely to get us somewhere, and indeed it did.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Nowadays we have E = mcc (Einstein), as well as E = hf (Planck).&amp;nbsp; E is for Energy, v for velocity, m for mass, h for Planck&#39;s Constant and f is for frequency.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/56575052310867699'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/56575052310867699'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/09/party-time.html' title='Party Time'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1900601855660567730</id><published>2018-09-19T22:08:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-19T22:08:25.651-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Random Responder</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/10NV2tOlCoM&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Youtube&#39;s AI recommended I see this, and the reporter was hoping I would share the free information.&amp;nbsp; Here&#39;s me sharing it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
North Carolina was undergoing intense flooding, with the Brunswick Nuclear Reactor in the way of the storm.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Shades of Fukushima.
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1900601855660567730'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1900601855660567730'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/09/random-responder.html' title='Random Responder'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/10NV2tOlCoM/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5070535846938708443</id><published>2018-09-15T16:38:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-15T16:45:06.590-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Big in Japan</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kFFD4742Wfk&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Poppy&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C0X3CLJVMJU&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Kirsten Dunst&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/D-T5iytPjWM&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&quot;Potorando&quot;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5070535846938708443'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5070535846938708443'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/09/big-in-japan.html' title='Big in Japan'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/kFFD4742Wfk/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry></feed>