<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1676'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1651&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1701&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1676</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114827231083958702</id><published>2006-05-21T21:24:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2007-11-25T09:38:19.196-08:00</updated><title type='text'>RSA using Pythonic Notation</title><content type='html'>Euler&#39;s Theorem:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;if gcd(b, N) == 1: assert pow(b, totient(N), N) == 1&lt;/blockquote&gt;Also, if public key N = p*q with p,q being big probable primes per &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miller-Rabin_primality_test&quot;&gt;Miller-Rabin&lt;/a&gt;, then the totient(N) is simply (p-1) * (q-1).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extended_Euclidean_algorithm&quot;&gt;Extended Euclidean Algorithm&lt;/a&gt; (EEA), we compute:  d = inverse(e, totient(N)) such that (e*d) % totient(N) == 1.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So now d is the secret complement of public key N, presumably not derivable minus knowledge of factors p and q, and presumably N can&#39;t be factored in any reasonable amount of time (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rsasecurity.com/rsalabs/node.asp?id=2093&quot;&gt;win big bucks&lt;/a&gt; if you&#39;re able to crack these large Ns).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSA&quot;&gt;RSA&lt;/a&gt; works essentially as follows:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;ciphertext = pow( plaintext, e, N)&lt;br /&gt;plaintext = pow( ciphertext, d, N)&lt;/blockquote&gt;I&#39;ve got more discussion of all this at the Math Forum under the heading of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=1380445&quot;&gt;Gnu Math&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114827231083958702'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114827231083958702'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/05/rsa-using-pythonic-notation.html' title='RSA using Pythonic Notation'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114806237970466510</id><published>2006-05-19T00:50:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2007-11-09T14:57:31.915-08:00</updated><title type='text'>ISEPP Lecture (End of Season)</title><content type='html'>Dr. Louis Bucciarelli got his name in lights on the marquee of the Schnitzer last night. This low key MIT professor studies engineers almost through the eyes of an anthropologist, but I think he would argue, really more as a fellow engineer, self-aware on many levels.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;His general message was positive: end users are getting more into the loop as influencing the design process. Today&#39;s &quot;users&quot; are less passive than yesterday&#39;s &quot;consumers&quot; -- and we may expect this positive trend to continue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Engineers have the ability to implement many possible futures. There&#39;s no &quot;technological determinism&quot; at work, no predestination. So they need to be steered, even as they become more self- steering, as not all futures are equally possible nor equally desirable nor equally worthy of our allegiance and focus. Some futures, even if very possible, just aren&#39;t worth our time and energy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So we need to prioritize and consult the oracles, figuratively speaking, to divine just what we really want to get out of our engineering. Our powers of invention have a way of giving us what we ask for over time, including nightmarish scenarios with technologies to match, if terror is what we&#39;re into. Bucky Fuller posited &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;longing&lt;/span&gt; as equally motivational, and good at counter-balancing fear (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bfi.org/our_programs/bfi_community/design_for_sustainability_program_at_tu_delft&quot;&gt;Fuller credited Einstein&lt;/a&gt; for this &quot;fear vs. longing&quot; dichotomy, as well as for a non- anthropomorphic concept of God).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of Bucky, some young voice in the audience, belonging to no one I recognized, asked during the Q&amp;amp;A what would be the outcome of this whole Fuller thing (paraphrasing). Bucciarelli professed mostly ignorance of the Fuller corpus, though attempted an answer, hinting over-zealotry was more frequently a flaw in scientists than engineers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You see, in Bucciarelli&#39;s object world (his terms), we may divide scientists from engineers in that the former claim to be discovering lasting truth (capital T sometimes) or generalized principles, whereas the latter just want to make something work in special case, a goal that may require frequent redesign and a rather short life cycle (or half life) for one&#39;s products. A different mindset.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If Bucciarelli himself is any indication, the engineer&#39;s mindset breeds a certain quiet reserve, which I was not alone in finding congenial. Indeed, another young voice during the Q&amp;amp;A spoke to the entrancing quality of his voice and asked if maybe he hadn&#39;t read books on tape or something in a previous job. &quot;I was a rock star&quot; he said, &quot;next question?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I went to the microphone to ask whether engineering firms might more formally identify key assistive disciplines and hire people into the firms under those job titles e.g. as bona fide anthropologists and psychologists. Bucciarelli said many firms already do that, at which point I inserted a special plug for philosophers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Later, during the dinner at the Heathman, I asked if maybe the engineers and lawyers were on a collision course, given optimizing solutions to human problems would entail leveraging our newfound ability to faithfully copy digital assets ad infinitum, whereas many colonists want to fence off large regions of our shared intellect (an invisible landscape) much as they did on the physical plain, for their proprietary/branded cattle and/or horses (so-called &quot;livestock&quot; vs. the dead kind on Wall Street).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Having ideas stream freely, with no regard for fences or borders, makes a lot of private property minded lawyers feel antsy, to say the least. A freely copiable, high powered operating system like Linux seems like such a waste of a golden money-making opportunity to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Engineers, on the other hand, see all these new users being well served by these new circuits (e.g. the Internet), a marvel at how little the lawyers&#39; concept of money enters into it (which isn&#39;t to ignore the fact that our Internet is hosted and protected by monied institutions, DARPA for example).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bucciarelli&#39;s response mirrored my own thoughts on the matter: some lawyers will have a hard time keeping up with the changing times.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But it&#39;s not like we&#39;re planning to let go of the whole notion of lawful and ethical behavior (that&#39;s me thinking). On the contrary, engineers are taking an increasing interest in user values and ethics.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the case of design science, for example, what counts as engineeringly sound may even synch with our ethical predilections i.e. keeping our designs free and open is what leads to fixes and improvements (smarter engineering), &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; is what keeps end users increasingly in the loop, increasingly educated about what really goes on behind the scenes, and therefore more able to really contribute and help steer (stronger ethics).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All in all, this has been a great ISEPP season. The small cross-section of Oregonians managing to attend these lectures must now be among some of the most educated and up to date on our planet. My enduring thanks to Terry Bristol and Mentor Graphics especially (both the company and the foundation) for making it happen. The Wanderers have also played a vital and catalyzing role.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114806237970466510'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114806237970466510'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/05/isepp-lecture-end-of-season.html' title='ISEPP Lecture (End of Season)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114776036017568657</id><published>2006-05-16T10:20:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:18.362-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Fast Food Nation</title><content type='html'>I was at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/01/why-civilizations-fail.html&quot;&gt;First Congregational Church&lt;/a&gt; for a presentation by Eric Schlosser last night.  He&#39;s finishing up his tour promoting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0618710310/103-9549483-3779860&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Chew on This&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a book for children about the history and impact of &quot;fast fooding&quot; in America.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Calling it &quot;fast fooding&quot; is sort of an inside family joke: &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2006-June/006584.html&quot;&gt;in Bhutan&lt;/a&gt; we&#39;d sometimes see signs for &quot;Fooding and Lodging&quot; (a normal usage in India). However, the long term health effects of marketing junk food to children are no laughing matter.  Childhood obesity and diabetes have reached epidemic proportions in the USA.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I bought a copy for Tara, which Eric kindly autographed.  Tara is already into it, finding it cram packed with interesting facts.  She plans to make it the basis for a speech she&#39;s to deliver on Friday at her school.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Should teachers and students be free to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=3650153&quot;&gt;question media campaigns in class&lt;/a&gt;?  I&#39;d say that&#39;s the mark of a free society.  If you&#39;ve been intimidated into never questioning slick PR, you&#39;re not free.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/05/decoding-usa-culture.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Mad Magazine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, produced on Madison Avenue in the heart of New York&#39;s advertising district, was an early pioneer in this regard.  Vance Packard&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0007DQTNW/qid=1147798730/102-8834637-6402554&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Hidden Persuaders&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was another.  If a democracy is to withstand the test of time, it needs a strong counter-culture to keep questioning its integrity.  Democracy&#39;s enemies traditionally use &quot;national security concerns&quot; as their chief means of suppressing internal dissent.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The USA&#39;s politicians tend to be quietly respectful of capitalism&#39;s invisible army of child and adult psychologists.  Their media campaigns use the same clever tricks the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/&quot;&gt;artificial corporate personages&lt;/a&gt; use to inspire loyalty to their brands.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114776036017568657'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114776036017568657'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/05/fast-food-nation.html' title='Fast Food Nation'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114748436173179739</id><published>2006-05-12T18:28:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:18.277-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Personal Workspace</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/dwaindustrial.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/dwaindustrial.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;PWS: Turning the Wheel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dawn&#39;s new workspace is coming along nicely. We went from an empty room with a utility sink to a functional office in just three or four days.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;She&#39;s recycling old props: the desk from an area center garage; the rug (on loan); the small refrigerator; the kneeling chair. The metal frame futon and computer are new: I assembled both, while Derek helped with the heavy glass and frame.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The computer, TurningWheel, is a Hewlett-Packard Pentium 4, has a gig of DDR and a 19&quot; flat screen monitor. I drove out to Fry&#39;s for it, having seen the Mother&#39;s Day ad in the paper.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The building has wireless, other amenities.  Lots of artists and small businesses have set up shop here.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114748436173179739'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114748436173179739'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/05/personal-workspace.html' title='Personal Workspace'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114737850920074364</id><published>2006-05-11T13:09:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:18.194-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Memo To Math Teachers</title><content type='html'>I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=1380445&quot;&gt;this memo&lt;/a&gt; to math teaching community this morning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Based on prior experience, I expect little reaction from the USA-based teachers who currently frequent &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/forum.jspa?forumID=206&quot;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt;.  Developing a more sophisticated approach to math teaching, using recent computer technology, is pretty much the furthest thing from their minds.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After all, math through programming is not what the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edutopia.org/magazine/ed1article.php?id=Art_1195&amp;amp;issue=nov_04&quot;&gt;textbooks&lt;/a&gt; are about, and textbooks define reality to most teachers.  Anything outside of a textbook is seen as just pie in the sky dreamweaving, no matter how much &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/02/valentines-day-2006.html&quot;&gt;free and open source material&lt;/a&gt; is made available via the Internet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyway, I&#39;m not reporting any news here, just more of the same old same old.  We&#39;ve had to learn ways of working around the established math teacher &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/02/restoring-integrity.html&quot;&gt;networks and organizations&lt;/a&gt;.  They&#39;re entrenched in their ways and not really relevant to our work.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114737850920074364'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114737850920074364'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/05/memo-to-math-teachers.html' title='Memo To Math Teachers'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114724010217926281</id><published>2006-05-09T23:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:18.114-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Edubuntu</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/caroloffice.0.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/caroloffice.0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;(click photo for larger view)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Derek lent me an old Compaq Deskpro he bought recently, one of five workstations. He put Suse 10 on one of them, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/04/launch-pad.html&quot;&gt;Edubuntu&lt;/a&gt; on another, the one I&#39;m borrowing. I&#39;ve got it set up in Carol&#39;s office, which feels appropriate, given all the memorabilia she has from that part of the world, and from Lesotho especially.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Maybe I&#39;ll be able to get &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/05/panda3d.html&quot;&gt;Panda3D&lt;/a&gt; running on this thing.  I saw two Ubuntu download options at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://panda3d.org/download.php&quot;&gt;web site&lt;/a&gt;.  Which one should I choose?  Answer:  breezy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/panda3dedubuntu.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/panda3dedubuntu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Screen shot of Panda3d on Edubuntu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Carol Urner&#39;s Office&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;(by K. Urner, Olympus Stylus 500)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114724010217926281'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114724010217926281'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/05/edubuntu.html' title='Edubuntu'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114705076895693620</id><published>2006-05-07T18:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2013-07-28T00:16:48.283-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Making Coffee</title><content type='html'>I got this new Starbucks coffee-making appliance for &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/12/christmas-2005.html&quot;&gt;Xmas&lt;/a&gt;, from me to myself (with a loving endorsement from family), which I&#39;ve just &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.answers.com/stoke&quot;&gt;stoked&lt;/a&gt; with Celebes, a favorite bean.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Earlier I met Mark, Don&#39;s friend and former student based in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/11/wednesday-pauling-house.html&quot;&gt;Guatemala&lt;/a&gt;.  We three plus &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/03/wanderers-200637.html&quot;&gt;Micheal Sunanda&lt;/a&gt; watched &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0429573/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;An American Haunting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; this afternoon, which I&#39;ll likely review one day soon.  I&#39;m biased though, having always been a big Sissy Spacek fan (good seeing Sutherland again too, liked him in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0102138/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;JFK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; among others).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, I saw that front page article about &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.oregonlive.com/oregonianeditors/2008/03/sad_ending_to_provo_story.html&quot;&gt;the beautiful mind guy&lt;/a&gt; in Rm. 114, busting his brain to become famous.  Checked into his stuff.  Didn&#39;t see many hexagons (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/03/global-matrix-wanderers-meeting.html&quot;&gt;Glenn Stockton&lt;/a&gt;, on the other hand...). Maybe he&#39;d like to present to Wanderers some time.  Information gets lost going through newpapers and web sites, useful though these often are at providing valuable perspectives.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[ pause to pour coffee, chat with Dawn ]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was telling Mark I think a problem with USA culture is we don&#39;t accept aid workers from overseas, think our job is to only export basic expertise.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Think of this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nbc.com/Saturday_Night_Live/&quot;&gt;SNL&lt;/a&gt; skit:  zoom in on some cute uniformed Chinese girl, propping up an SWI (slumped while intoxicated) in some &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/11/post-thanksgiving.html&quot;&gt;Gotham&lt;/a&gt;, USA.  &quot;What are you doing?&quot; the curious camera man asks.  &quot;I&#39;m assisting a victim of western capitalism&quot; she replies calmly, and flashes her  badge: Communist Chinese Peace Corps.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/12/our-land.html&quot;&gt;Scream!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, you get my point.  People are way paranoid here, don&#39;t want to get any help, just give it, even where it ain&#39;t really needed (at least, not in the form offered).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Related reading:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theonion.com/content/node/47978&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;A Discussion of Human Capital Flows Through Semi-Permeable Membranes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (paraphrase) by some Yes Men at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Onion (&lt;/span&gt;May 3, 2006          | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theonion.com/content/index/4218&quot;&gt;Issue 42•18&lt;/a&gt;)</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114705076895693620'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114705076895693620'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/05/making-coffee.html' title='Making Coffee'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114687756796924779</id><published>2006-05-05T19:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:17.941-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Lucky Lab</title><content type='html'>So I just rushed back from this brew pub, a meeting of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.possepdx.org/&quot;&gt;POSSE&lt;/a&gt;, where the governor of Oregon made a brief appearance (David Pool, whom I know from our &lt;a href=&quot;http://business.newsforge.com/print.pl?sid=04/04/09/1854218&quot;&gt;CollabTech&lt;/a&gt; days at FreeGeek, pointed him out to me), and Erik Sten, a local city council member now running for re-election.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Erik shared for a good half hour actually, taking a question from me about industrial sector zoning of the east side hugging the freeway. Would a &quot;think tank economy&quot; featuring such as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lkl.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;London Knowledge Lab&lt;/a&gt;, but Portland&#39;s, be apropos?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Erik thought that&#39;d be a swell idea, matched his own vision quite a bit.  And no, I&#39;m not forgetting his &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Render_farm&quot;&gt;render farm&lt;/a&gt;&quot; idea either.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A TV camera with a separate boom microphone showed up later, during the presentation on open source business models. People got more intelligently talkative. I thought we cut a great tape.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m burning &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/02/adventures-in-radio-land-part-2.html&quot;&gt;Sunanda&lt;/a&gt; CDs from a master at the moment.  As yet I have no clue what he shared on KBOO last night.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/01/bumper-sticker.html&quot;&gt;Funny hippie psychobabble&lt;/a&gt; is how he characterized it, in the minds of his listeners at least.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Later:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I purchased Chinese food from &lt;a style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot; href=&quot;http://www.wcities.com/en/record/95,141400/159/record.html&quot;&gt;Fujin&lt;/a&gt;, rented &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0105417/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Sister Act&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0108147/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Sister Act 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from the nearby &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Hollywood Video&lt;/span&gt; for Dawn and Tara, and picked up medicines at the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Fred Meyer&lt;/span&gt; pharmacy.  My hope is to visit with &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/03/st-patricks-day-wanderers-retreat.html&quot;&gt;Jon Bunce&lt;/a&gt; (a Wanderer and musician) later this evening.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dawn spent much of the day working on her new studio space, which is rather near to the east side &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.luckylab.com/&quot;&gt;Lucky Lab&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114687756796924779'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114687756796924779'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/05/lucky-lab.html' title='Lucky Lab'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114667485223180668</id><published>2006-05-03T10:11:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:17.853-08:00</updated><title type='text'>General Systems Theory</title><content type='html'>Certainly economists compete with one another to become stars in their own field, but the discipline as a whole still suffers from a monopolistic mindset. When it comes to fixing spending priorities, economists still seem to think there&#39;s only one game in town, namely Economics.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;General Systems Theory aims to compete with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/02/econ-101.html&quot;&gt;Economics&lt;/a&gt;, by covering some of the same territory with a newer map, sort of the way astronomy gradually took over from astrology, when it came to such challenges as putting &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/01/some-space-program-history.html&quot;&gt;humans on the Moon&lt;/a&gt;. We needed to be more scientific, more deeply appreciative of nature&#39;s role. GST owes more to ecology than economics.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Contributors to our field include &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kenneth_E._Boulding&quot;&gt;Kenneth Boulding&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isss.org/lumLVB.htm&quot;&gt;Ludwig von Bertelanffy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Schlesinger&quot;&gt;James Schlesinger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.disinfo.com/archive/pages/dossier/id367/pg1/index.html&quot;&gt;Barbara Marx Hubbard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/bio.html&quot;&gt;R. Buckminster Fuller&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/4dsolutions/jackbio.html&quot;&gt;Jack Urner&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/&quot;&gt;myself&lt;/a&gt; (plus many more).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For further reading:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/gstuniv.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;General Systems Theory:  Brainstorming New Scenarios for our Global University&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Oct. 1996)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/motherboard.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;New Circuit Designs for Motherboard Earth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (CyRev Journal, Issue 3, 1995 etc.).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114667485223180668'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114667485223180668'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/05/general-systems-theory.html' title='General Systems Theory'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114645332277852797</id><published>2006-04-30T20:12:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:17.774-08:00</updated><title type='text'>The Kennedy School</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/urnerwiccalabyrinth.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/urnerwiccalabyrinth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/diademcenter.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/diademcenter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/114645332277852797/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/114645332277852797' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114645332277852797'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114645332277852797'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/04/kennedy-school.html' title='The Kennedy School'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114556734266903195</id><published>2006-04-20T15:43:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:17.698-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Back at the Zoo</title><content type='html'>I descended a flight of stairs to discover an austere table, board member names in plastic shields, LCDs on tripods on either side, heralding the event: a Saturday Academy fundraiser, a time to be generous towards tomorrow&#39;s Oregon&#39;s daughters and sons. I sat at a round table (21), flanked by staff, with the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Alien Landscapes&lt;/span&gt; instructor, and an OPBer.  A mother and baby were also present.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joyce Creswell set the tone, by invoking SA&#39;s 23 year long history -- coming upon a quarter century here. In these parts, 23 still counts as old, because our Silicon Forest is young, even though some of our oral traditions trace back to eye-witnesses to Mt. Mazama&#39;s decapitation (now she&#39;s named Crater Lake, and she&#39;s a deep one). My wife was here when Mt. St. Helens blew.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Illustrious captains of industry followed.  Our area is endowed with talent, let&#39;s pass that on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is the same room I&#39;d come to for a few CRIME meetings hosted by George Heuston of HPD, back closer to the time I was teaching at West Precinct with Jerritt (Mr. Linuxfund.org back then). We&#39;d only need the rearmost partition, and mostly did projector presentations about patterns of IP use (many applications register, bittorrent especially), or abstruse lectures about cryptography.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sam is chauffeuring for his sis (my wife), is also a pro poet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We celebrated mom&#39;s 77th at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Sweet Tomato&lt;/span&gt; last night, one of Tara&#39;s favorites.  For her birthday, mom let me buy her any &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Laughing Horse&lt;/span&gt; book of her choice, and she chose &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0439353793/sr=8-1/qid=1145567696&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Hitler Youth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from Scholastic, about what it was like growing up in the shadow of Nazism.  The &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/04/mom-laughing-horse-books.html&quot;&gt;resulting picture&lt;/a&gt; is comically surreal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also procured (and installed) those &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/04/our-wild-garden.html&quot;&gt;prayer flags&lt;/a&gt; (Guru Rinpoche was one of those incredibles I learned about on visits to Bhutan), plus watched that &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Squeakers&lt;/span&gt; DVD (thanks Kim), my two blog-announced goals for that day; plus I got a lot of other work done as well.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114556734266903195'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114556734266903195'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/04/back-at-zoo.html' title='Back at the Zoo'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114500117444162701</id><published>2006-04-14T15:25:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2008-07-25T16:52:05.378-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Shuttleworth Summit (day two)</title><content type='html'>Checking &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.python.org/community/sigs/current/edu-sig/&quot;&gt;edu-sig&lt;/a&gt; this morning, from the hotel lobby (Guido is in the chair next to me); &lt;a href=&quot;http://aroberge.blogspot.com/2006/04/thoughts-on-shuttleworth-summit.html&quot;&gt;André is proposing rur-ple&lt;/a&gt; as an alternative to Logo while &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.ianbicking.org/python-education-logo.html&quot;&gt;Ian blogged about his PyLogo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We had a fantastic dinner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.london-eating.co.uk/1620.htm&quot;&gt;E&amp;amp;O&lt;/a&gt; last night.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aspirationtech.org/about/people&quot;&gt;Gunner&lt;/a&gt; turns out to be a bigger country music fan than I&#39;d realized.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today&#39;s planning looked at timeline, tools, and content.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A first pass: develop in a fish bowl, in showcase settings, with others invited to adopt and adapt (within three years?). Second pass: package the &quot;final product&quot; for wider dissemination (within five?).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the tools front, a key question is whether we&#39;re tying this project to any major specific software development effort.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Loosely coupled tools, with a bottom-up, open source curriculum writing process, will leave the question of tools somewhat open-ended. The lesson plans will specify the software needed, with multiple paths possible.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Will we eventually have some sort of Python-based hypercard-like browser plug-in, facilitating easy publishing by students and incorporating what&#39;s already worked well in Squeak? If yes, then so much the better. Peers i.e. teachers (including the more advanced students) will write lessons around it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The content will translate a mind map of the whole ten year topics network to a repository of lesson plans, with lessons sortable by how technology intensive they need to be. The content will mostly assume some minimal level of infrastructure: a computer lab with or without the Internet for example. At the topical level, this curriculum should tie to the national standards, to facilitate widespread adoption.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We blitzed through a few five minute lightning talks, featuring South Africa&#39;s performance stats in TIMMS, primitive Logo in Javascript, Squeak, a book on Squeak, the Scheme approach to designing programs, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ofset.org/drgeo&quot;&gt;2D dynamic geometry project&lt;/a&gt; not unlike &lt;a href=&quot;http://pygeo.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;PyGeo in 3D&lt;/a&gt;, and me on Python, doing a &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;very&lt;/span&gt; abbreviated version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/04/london-knowledge-lab.html&quot;&gt;what I showed the London Knowledge Lab&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Robyn encourged me to look at what a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.logo.com/imagine/project_gallery/index.html&quot;&gt;contemporary Logo&lt;/a&gt; looks like.  The slickest stuff is neither free nor cross-platform, even if it runs in a web browser.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Momentum seems to be building for a stronger graphics engine, either 2D or 3D, with Python bindings, that&#39;ll run interactively from within a browser. The Squeak folks may be willing to contribute to this effort. Guido feels we&#39;ll need to recruit new talent for this, as the Python community is currently pretty maxed out on projects. Should such an engine be developed, turtle stuff would be incorporated therein.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114500117444162701'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114500117444162701'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/04/shuttleworth-summit-day-two.html' title='Shuttleworth Summit (day two)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114492243157132113</id><published>2006-04-13T14:15:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:17.517-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Shuttleworth Summit (day one)</title><content type='html'>Our plan is to write the next generation curriculum for the Shuttleworth Foundation&#39;s vision, and a process for doing so. &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.tsf.org.za/shuttleworthfoundationwiki/Project_20Summit&quot;&gt;Nineteen&lt;/a&gt; of us are sitting around the table, one is taking the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.tsf.org.za/shuttleworthfoundationwiki/Day_20one&quot;&gt;official notes&lt;/a&gt; (mine are not official). The essentials have been provided: coffee and tea, wireless.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Shuttleworth&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mark&lt;/a&gt;: How do students develop communications and analytical skills and how might technology catalyze the aquisition of these skills?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Problem: mathematics is increasingly failing to hook kids&#39; attention, with new math teachers ever harder to recruit. Yet technology is invading the education sector, plus students are spontaneously attracted to technology. How can we capitalize on both trends? How might we continue to deliver analytical capacity in this climate of declining interest in traditional mathematics learning and teaching?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There&#39;s no time to retrain the teachers, so the model should implement a peer-based system, wherein students are expected to mentor other students.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mark&#39;s current vision is to start kids with Logo, then maybe move on to Squeak, then Python. That&#39;s a rough first take. We have the Scheme community represented at the table as well.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My comment: if there&#39;s a lot of broadband in this picture, access to technologically literate teachers shouldn&#39;t be the bottleneck. We can project video clips at will, including of talking heads, and about any topic. So it&#39;s not like there won&#39;t be a variety of adult role models presented. Even live interviews are possible. Guido: assuming the presence of broadband or a projector may not be realistic. Mark: pervasively only in the long term. May we at least assume an ability to play DVDs, and to burn them? Yes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Other comments: we&#39;re talking about acquiring identity, not just skills, which relates to language and a cultural context. What is my role in the community, what are my community&#39;s values? The concept of &quot;literacy&quot; covers this, in that becoming literate involves creating one&#39;s life story. And this doesn&#39;t just happen in schools, especially given the Internet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let&#39;s focus on the analytical component, the mathematics. Computers enable kinds of mathematics that&#39;s difficult to do in other ways. And let&#39;s enlarge the analytic to embrace the sciences, which adds the modeling dimension, makes the math stories be about reality. Purely analytical capability may be perverse and/or shallow if not grounded.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Kay&quot;&gt;Alan Kay&lt;/a&gt; pointed out that a curriculum needs to include powerful ideas, not just turn students loose, expecting them to reinvent the calculus. Developing problem solving skills must include exposure to powerful cultural inventions. Cultural memory is important.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Alan sure talks about the 1960s a lot.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guido_van_Rossum&quot;&gt;Guido&lt;/a&gt; expressed some frustration with that.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My suggestion: set up test beds, modeling existing and expected conditions, and develop curriculum segments in the field (the test driven development model). Implement a prototype branded curriculum in a pure form and let others copy what works. I&#39;m hoping to avoid this pitfall: something imposed top-down on unwilling participants results in backlash and sabotage, or simply a diluted or distorted version, giving ammo to the curriculum&#39;s enemies and making outcomes hard to measure.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Alan thinks being able to script without having to type is super important, plus he wants a media rich experience, not just a turtle. He also advocates the one wireless laptop per child model, meaning you get to take them home. His emphasis is consistently constructing a &quot;world&quot; for children, some customized multimedia GUI ala Squeak, although he thinks this could just as well be done in Python. Alan is a big hypercard fan and is aware of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pythoncard.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;PythonCard project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m especially skeptical on this last point. Let&#39;s focus on a distro perhaps (like edubuntu) but not over-integrate the environment to make something more seamless then necessary. Leave the environment heterogenous, more like the real world. I&#39;m also finding that IM (instant messaging) motivates somewhat older kids to improve their typing skills.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I sense a tension between &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;inspiring&lt;/span&gt; teachers versus &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;bypassing&lt;/span&gt; them. Probably what we&#39;re doing is pioneering an open source culture devoted to curriculum development (not just software development) which includes and inspires some teachers, but leaves others feeling bypassed -- a typical outcome, not really a problem.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What Alan and I most agree on is the need for Wikipedia type content to mix with an interactive component. He showed me his recent Javascript implementation of Logo. I&#39;m reminded of our ability to create interactive &quot;labs&quot; in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jsoftware.com/&quot;&gt;J language&lt;/a&gt;. Python needs a more developed interactive teaching module: show some stuff, give students a command line, show more stuff, and so on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lunch activity:  demo of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lamsinternational.com/&quot;&gt;LAMS&lt;/a&gt; by its author, James Dalziel.  Good use of chat rooms to facilitate peer to peer communications.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The breakout sessions were on the following topics: landscape 2010 (what will the ecology be like?); implementation of innovation (how will these new memes spread?); the role of the teacher in this new technology-based curriculum.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The landscape group expects at least a computer lab in most schools. We can&#39;t assume students will have access to a computer at home.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The implementation group is faced with a somewhat monolithic set of scored national tests, and debated what balance of collaborative vs. subversive tactics would work best. Recruiting teachers would involve empowering them as peer contributors to a lessons repository.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The teacher&#39;s role group assumed universities would help with teacher trainings and managing the courseware repositories. Shall we hold on to the notion that teachers must &quot;know more&quot; than their students, in order to be effective?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Coffee break.  Warding off jet lag.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A branded distro, like edubuntu, with built-in links to further resources (LAMS workflows, moodles...), would give users access to a shared open source culture of curriculum development, not just software development. As a peer, I&#39;d be patched into an ecology, a network, as I am now, but with more people self-consciously contributing. The ecology will feature many competing brands, not one monolithic sequence. Some curricula will be more tailored to specific national, regional and/or company standards.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114492243157132113'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114492243157132113'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/04/shuttleworth-summit-day-one.html' title='Shuttleworth Summit (day one)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114446608352105632</id><published>2006-04-07T20:15:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:17.426-08:00</updated><title type='text'>V for Vendetta (movie review)</title><content type='html'>This film draws inspiration from Orwell, plus from all too familiar fascist &quot;reality TV&quot; fashions. Oppressive government is a nightmare and leads to dark paranoias, often leading to mass uprisings.  This sequence gets played out over and over again, never exactly repeating.  Like &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;1984&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Vendetta&lt;/span&gt; goes ahead and simply maps to some future distopia, vaguely (or not so vaguely) extrapolating troubling trends in our own time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&#39;s also &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Beauty and the Beast&lt;/span&gt;, a genre I&#39;ve not specialized in, although &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/king-kong-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;King Kong&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was an eye-opener.  V is certainly a monster, and for 20 years has occupied himself plotting a delicious revenge against his torturers.  Then he meets the girl, and the whole grotesque fantasy becomes surprisingly back burner.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But he goes through with it anyway; it&#39;s all he knows, what he&#39;s scripted to do.  Then he hands the baton off to a next generation (to which this girl belongs).  There&#39;s love between this girl and another girl too, under the masked one&#39;s auspices -- very complicated, yet touching and real (I couldn&#39;t believe those idiot parents disowning this most beautiful daughter, plus passing on getting another one).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dawn and I saw it together.  She said &quot;a little more gratuitous violence than I like&quot; and I got it. I took the whole thing as a sick and twisted fantasy piece, a simulator (OK, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/chronicles-of-narnia-lww-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;a wardrobe&lt;/a&gt;).  And the product of a feverishly fertile UKer imagination -- they really know how to make &#39;em, those &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ingsoc&quot;&gt;IngSoc types&lt;/a&gt;.  Actually, we&#39;re talking Wachowski brothers, of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Matrix&lt;/span&gt; fame.  Definitely a bold contribution to the literature.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114446608352105632'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114446608352105632'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/04/v-for-vendetta-movie-review.html' title='V for Vendetta (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114425716261956333</id><published>2006-04-05T13:48:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:17.347-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Today&#39;s Networking</title><content type='html'>Today I&#39;m busy working with Erica at Associated Oregon Industries (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aoi.org/&quot;&gt;AOI&lt;/a&gt;) on improving their database program (inherited Visual FoxPro code which I&#39;ve mostly rewritten by now).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I phoned Multnomah County to reschedule jury duty once again, this time for mid January 2007.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dawn is having many high level discussions with her care team.  She&#39;s the kind of patient many doctors like having:  she takes it straight, unvarnished, yet with sensitivity and grace.  Her professional care givers, in both eastern and western traditions, are among her biggest fans.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m planning to take Tara to AAA after school; we need to get her passport reactivated per family overseas travel plans.  I really want to show them Italy, Rome especially (many favorite boyhood haunts).  We&#39;ve ordered a copy of her birth certificate on-line, after not finding our earlier copy.  I&#39;ll also pick up a map of London, and maybe of the southwestern USA (Dawn&#39;s hoping for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/12/whats-bizmo.html&quot;&gt;bizmo&lt;/a&gt; trip).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I swung by the Linus Pauling House on Terry&#39;s invitation to meet with our ISEPP guest, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isepp.org/Pages/05-06%20Pages/Ulanowicz.html&quot;&gt;Dr. Ulanowicz&lt;/a&gt;, and maybe listen in on some fun conversation.  Apparently Wanderers had invited him to lunch some place (I found evidence of a meeting in progress).  Given time constraints, I elected to scrawl a &quot;Kirby was here&quot; on the board; I&#39;ll hope to catch his lecture tomorrow evening.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dawn ordered, and I picked up from the vet, a new bag of Moon Kitty&#39;s special cat food.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Arthur Seigel and I have another &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2006-April/006086.html&quot;&gt;interesting thread&lt;/a&gt; going on &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/&quot;&gt;edu-sig&lt;/a&gt;, which again explores the nature of my commitments and investments as a Fuller Schooler.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hugh Watkins, the Copenhagen-based fellow student of Wittgenstein&#39;s philo, excerpted some recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/07/kirbiania.html&quot;&gt;Kirbiania&lt;/a&gt; about Wittgenstein in his blog (&lt;a href=&quot;http://bloog2.blogspot.com/2006/04/wittgenstein-seen-from-usa.html&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nick Consoletti is staying in my basement again.  He wants me to write a recommendation for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.designsciencelab.org/&quot;&gt;Design Science Lab&lt;/a&gt;, which I currently know only a little about and am not involved with.  I have no problem recommending Nick though.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114425716261956333'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114425716261956333'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/04/todays-networking.html' title='Today&#39;s Networking'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114399967939512622</id><published>2006-04-02T17:37:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:17.264-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Wittgenstein Again</title><content type='html'>I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/03/wittgenstein-for-dummies.html&quot;&gt;a more comic book version of this&lt;/a&gt;, but let&#39;s try to be more serious.  The work for which Ludwig Wittgenstein (LW) first became well known, as the miracle-spawn of Bertrand Russell, was the pretentiously titled &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Tractatus Logico Philosophicus&lt;/span&gt; (TLP).  Except this wasn&#39;t so silly-sounding for that day, as Latin still connoted authority, as did the flat hats and gowns, all the gothic surroundings of a dark ages cathedral.  So the TLP fit right in, as more organ music.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Over time, however, LW became disillusioned with his tone in the TLP.  Yes, it was a lot of clever, glorified nonsense, which hooked the reader mainly on its aesthetic merits, but it was also too grandiose in retrospect, too full of the author&#39;s own vanity, perhaps for having mastered the logical crypticisms indulged in by the school masters of his day, and since superseded by electronified gate logic.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So the next generation philo (published posthumously as the PI) would be pretty much devoid of these crypticisms, even if the transition to patent nonsense was still a goal (same joke, just better told).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In calling both works &quot;a joke&quot; I&#39;m not attempting to deride or dismiss them in any way, which is why I think the link to Japanese style Buddhism tends to work, in that the Zen koan is likewise a relic or spin-off from trying to say the unsayable i.e. trying to point to the inside of Plato&#39;s Cave (as if it were just another concept, with convex and concave features).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In Fuller&#39;s philo, we&#39;re connected by this Void to his ongoing definings within an eternally aconceptual nonsimultaneous and only partially-overlapping scenarios Universe (or call it a centers network, with local spacetime coordinates in the eye of the beholder).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You don&#39;t get to take the world&#39;s snap shot and have it remain faithful to the original for long, not even with a beautiful logic.  We have to keep working at it, ever refining and polishing our communications to better fit them within the backdrop of our present day (or private sky).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114399967939512622'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114399967939512622'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/04/wittgenstein-again.html' title='Wittgenstein Again'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114376415130644924</id><published>2006-03-30T18:15:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:17.130-08:00</updated><title type='text'>From a Cube in Nashville</title><content type='html'>I&#39;m sitting in a large cube in Nashville, Tennessee, waiting for rush hour to finish.  Earlier today, I committed some &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=1356149&quot;&gt;autobio to the Math Forum&lt;/a&gt;, talking about my post Princeton years (early 1980s).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We visited the Nashville Zoo this afternoon. Lots of families had the same idea (great weather, no school). Many of the exhibited species had &quot;vanishing animal&quot; icons on their plaques. We&#39;d like to turn that around of course, hence my placement of the elephant clipart on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/gst2.html&quot;&gt;GST poster&lt;/a&gt; (in case you were wondering).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114376415130644924'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114376415130644924'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/03/from-cube-in-nashville.html' title='From a Cube in Nashville'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114331652723396164</id><published>2006-03-25T11:19:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-03-15T23:35:31.288-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Gnu Math</title><content type='html'>This is a pun on &quot;new math&quot; (aka &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lib.utexas.edu/taro/utcah/00284/cah-00284.html&quot;&gt;SMSG&lt;/a&gt;), developed within the cold war context to prod more Americans into a space age frame of mind. The Russians had launched Sputnik and paranoia was running high.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fsf.org/&quot;&gt;GNU&lt;/a&gt; = GNU&#39;s Not Unix, Richard Stallman&#39;s coin for a Unix-like command line environment, coded from scratch.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2006-March/006013.html&quot;&gt;Gnu Math&lt;/a&gt; integrates mathematics with a command line aesthetic, providing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cryptonomicon.com/beginning.html&quot;&gt;future Morlocks&lt;/a&gt; with tools of the trade.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For example, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2005-July/005025.html&quot;&gt;Pythonic Mathematics&lt;/a&gt; integrates algebra with OOP (the object oriented paradigm), a basis for many of our world game&#39;s models and simulations. The USG first got behind Python with its &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.darpa.mil/&quot;&gt;DARPA&lt;/a&gt; funding of Guido&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.python.org/doc/essays/cp4e.html&quot;&gt;CP4E initiative&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The civilian public education system was slow to catch on however, given the ideological priorities of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/03/why-we-fight-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;parasitical political machinery&lt;/a&gt;, which used the spectre of terrorism to keep Americans in a state of fear.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Internet, also originally military, helped Americans develop antibodies to this parasitical ideology.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=4586024&quot;&gt;the Internet&lt;/a&gt;, Gnu Math continued to make inroads, assisting the engineering community in its efforts to debug and restore integrity to a corrupted USA system.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114331652723396164'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114331652723396164'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/03/gnu-math.html' title='Gnu Math'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114296057696367614</id><published>2006-03-21T09:01:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:16.967-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Identity 2.0</title><content type='html'>My topic this morning relates to a talk I heard at OSCON 2005, from the main stage, by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.identity20.com/media/OSCON2005/&quot;&gt;Dick Hardt&lt;/a&gt;.  His brief:  we need identity servers that authenticate to the various services behind the scenes, so we don&#39;t have to always re-enter the same stuff.  Identity management would become the identity owner&#39;s responsibility.  Having it all gathered in one place would actually make its theft much harder, as you couldn&#39;t get by with only fragmentary data, e.g. just an SSN or credit card number.  Banks would &quot;go to the source&quot; and any hack of an Identity Server would be national news, not just run of the mill fraud, a cost of doing business.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of identity, I&#39;ve been trying on &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=4581466&quot;&gt;Silicon Forest exec&lt;/a&gt;&quot; for size.  I think that pretty well sums it up.  I wrote to Allegra yesterday that I didn&#39;t want to be on BFI&#39;s Shelter Committee just now, not because I&#39;m anti-shelter (duh) but because I&#39;m trying to clarify my role in the World Game theater.  I&#39;m like this computer geek with aspirations to invest more in multimedia (4D Studios), out of my desire to craft some &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?messageID=4581750&quot;&gt;dynamite curriculum&lt;/a&gt; for future &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=1351435&quot;&gt;Silicon Foresters&lt;/a&gt; (no, not exclusively).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In order to pass along this culture, a thriving one, we need to leap frog various bastions of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luddite&quot;&gt;Ludditism&lt;/a&gt;, including, I&#39;m sad to say, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=4582153&quot;&gt;within the education sector itself&lt;/a&gt;.  Too many teachers feel trapped in dead end jobs, and take it out on their wards.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In particular, I&#39;d like to see a stronger curriculum served through &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/02/pentagon-channel.html&quot;&gt;the Pentagon Channel&lt;/a&gt;, as I think military investments will make a huge positive difference, if there&#39;s real intelligence behind them.  The paramilitary gray zone between hot and cold war, is also the zone of disaster relief and emergency management.  We&#39;re looking to economize through dual-use technologies.  The same &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/01/location-scouting.html&quot;&gt;Fly&#39;s Eye Dome&lt;/a&gt; skeleton could contain a variety of hardware and software.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A military that knows how to perform civilian duties provides a stronger career path for would-be recruits, as they won&#39;t be irrelevant deadweight in peacetime.  And for &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conscientious_objector&quot;&gt;conscientious objector types&lt;/a&gt;, a purely civilian trajectory might be plotted, such that if war breaks out, they&#39;ll be tasked with the sometimes extreme services our nation has historically required of its peace-loving leaders.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114296057696367614'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114296057696367614'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/03/identity-20.html' title='Identity 2.0'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114253816784727588</id><published>2006-03-16T11:46:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-02-09T22:12:17.125-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Taking Stock</title><content type='html'>I taught &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/winterhaven/&quot;&gt;Python @ WHVN&lt;/a&gt; again today, focusing on nested data structures e.g. how to index into&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/python/gis.py&quot;&gt; a dictionary of some USA and Canadian cities, each with lat/long coordinates expressed as a list of two 3-tuples&lt;/a&gt;.  Here&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/winterhaven/worksheets/urner_whvn_worksheet1.pdf&quot;&gt;the worksheet we used&lt;/a&gt; (PDF).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/02/back-in-portland.html&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kessler&lt;/a&gt; has his &lt;a href=&quot;http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=491843388827305538&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Common Sense II&lt;/span&gt; pilot&lt;/a&gt; in Google Video, per my suggestion, bringing the count of&lt;a href=&quot;http://video.google.com/videosearch?q=%22Buckminster+Fuller%22&quot;&gt; Buckminster Fuller clips&lt;/a&gt; to five.   For a bigger stash, check the EIK site [defunct -- Feb 9, 09].&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Search results on &lt;a href=&quot;http://video.google.com/videosearch?q=polyhedron&quot;&gt;Polyhedron&lt;/a&gt;/Polyhedra within Google Video still returns zero, nada. Of course I could change that, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/02/morning-in-la.html&quot;&gt;I want to measure&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/02/restoring-integrity.html&quot;&gt;Ivory Tower&#39;s level of commitment&lt;/a&gt; to supplying relevant open source geometry clips, sans my input (drumming fingers, twiddling thumbs).  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=1347556&quot;&gt;Princeton&lt;/a&gt;?  Anyone?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our USA military families are expected to fight and possibly die for their country, with kids expected to part with their parents, perhaps permanently, and yet what support do they receive in return, in the form of relevant education and training? Precious little. Their own &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/02/octet-truss.html&quot;&gt;American history&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.medaloffreedom.com/RBuckminsterFuller.htm&quot;&gt;heritage&lt;/a&gt; is being denied them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So how is this not tyranny then?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[Addendum, February 9, 2009:  up to about 372 Google Videos with &quot;Polyhedra&quot; in the title, 291 on YouTube]</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114253816784727588'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114253816784727588'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/03/taking-stock.html' title='Taking Stock'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114227886238326056</id><published>2006-03-13T13:37:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2011-12-05T21:11:33.648-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Back @ Wired</title><content type='html'>So I&#39;m back to my usual haunts in Portland, having returned from haunts near Remote, Oregon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I liked what Bob Scheiffer said last Thursday (?), about working to earn our trust, not taking it for granted. This Mens Retreat was like that for me -- I had to work building relationships (&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/soc.religion.quaker/msg/5de3d876d06d6222?dmode=source&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;work&lt;/a&gt; I enjoy doing). We had a lot of new faces, plus many more familiar ones (e.g. mine in the mirror), and a lot to communicate, from each to many.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I did a good job anchoring my network I thought, but it&#39;s a somewhat nebulous network and I felt it taking me out of the room on occasion. I have so many to check in with. And I know I&#39;m not the only one with big responsibilities (duh).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fortunately, good Friends like Tom Head are out there doing a lot of checking. He got to the Dan Rather gig in Portland, reported back, and to China for a high level meeting on military matters, goes to London, Philadelphia...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He&#39;s an economist, Tom is, based at the nearby George Fox University. Tom couldn&#39;t make it to the retreat this year, as I couldn&#39;t last year, because he was off traveling some place per usual.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyway, I&#39;m glad Larry was around.  We talked iTunes and iPods (he had a new nano) -- plus I showed him an excerpt from &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/11/yes-men-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Yes Men&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (the &quot;leisure suit&quot; segment), a DVD I purchased and sometimes screen on my laptop or otherwise project e.g. when I&#39;m wanting to share about my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/gst2.html&quot;&gt;GST brand&lt;/a&gt; of economics.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This money talk reminds me: I need to be on my way, delivering some pay checks to a client for TBC. Derek is supposed to meet me here; the barista was busy when I arrived, so I don&#39;t even have a coffee. Maybe when I get back, it&#39;ll be time for a Guinness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Over an hour later&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;OK, so I met up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/07/wanderers-meeting-200575.html&quot;&gt;Ron Braithwaite&lt;/a&gt;, tooling around town in his new biodiesel VW. He wondered about lunch and here we were, in front of Than Thao near the Pauling House, so we ordered V8 and V9 respectively.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Derek looked after my Toshiba back at Wired (his is a Compaq), drinking coffee, waiting for Joan.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/summer-memories-picture-series.html&quot;&gt;Ron&lt;/a&gt; is steeped in Apple tech these days.  If he succeeds in today&#39;s mission, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/tillamook.html&quot;&gt;Tillamook Creamery&lt;/a&gt; should be a beneficiary (Helvetica fonts lady).  I was glad to meet up with Ron, who also missed our &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/03/mens-retreat.html&quot;&gt;Men&#39;s Retreat&lt;/a&gt; this year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I just got a call from Bernita about a death in the family (from natural causes).  My heart goes out to the grieving.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114227886238326056'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114227886238326056'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/03/back-wired.html' title='Back @ Wired'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114200906584155404</id><published>2006-03-10T08:40:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:16.734-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Candid Camera</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/terryandart.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/terryandart.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;font-size:85%;&quot; &gt;Art Kohn and Terry Bristol&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/03/isepp-presents.html&quot;&gt; ISEPP dinner&lt;/a&gt; for Roger Penrose&lt;br /&gt; (photo by K. Urner)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114200906584155404'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114200906584155404'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/03/candid-camera.html' title='Candid Camera'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114191642333900364</id><published>2006-03-09T10:37:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:16.653-08:00</updated><title type='text'>More from Quaker-P (revised)</title><content type='html'>So if the prez wants to advertise why a line item veto might be useful, now would be a good time.  You&#39;ve got a Congress happy to cave to mob anti-Arab psychology, and tacking its deal-killing legislation to a continued funding bill for the war in Iraq (oldest trick in the book -- bind what a president hates to what a president most wants).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The prez could say &quot;OK, I promised a veto, now here it is&quot; and then &quot;I guess that means no more war in Iraq huh?&quot;  Troops start coming home, the UAE closes harbors to military shipping unless it&#39;s to take hardware &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;out&lt;/span&gt; of the region (with other harbors to follow), and we celebrate the re-emergence of civilian control over the Pentagon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Pentagon would be only too happy to leave anyway, as what Iraq needs is better civilian infrastructure and more police of the non-death-squad variety.  American boys are starting to get cynical about any bright future in the armed services and that&#39;s bad for recruiting (helping tsunami victims, on the other hand, made our boys into heroes being all they could be -- girls too).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you can&#39;t back up that noble-sounding rhetoric about defending the Constitution, freedom, democracy, with logically consistent on-the-ground activities, well, that hurts both prospecting and recruiting -- even &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;given&lt;/span&gt; the devastation in New Orleans and a compliant not-lifting-a-finger FEMA (yes, if civilian life is made miserable enough, the recruits will keep coming, having nowhere else to turn).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Back to Coalition TV: we&#39;ve got John Bolton at the UN feeling &quot;a sense of urgency&quot; around Iran&#39;s low-level defiance of the IAEA.  Iran is at least dimly aware that a nuclear superpower has invaded and occupied the country right next to it, on false pretenses no less (forged documents from Niger, accompanying hype from Cheney).  Americans, on the other hand, are busy watching &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Survivor&lt;/span&gt; (so-called &quot;reality&quot; TV) and resent the distraction.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We already know that the UN hasn&#39;t the backbone to stand up to the USA&#39;s neocons (a principle established in round one) so I can see where Iran&#39;s defiance might enter the equations.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyway, since when did the Pentagon have any say in this war?  The whole show has been out-sourced to beltway bandits like Raytheon, home of the cruise missile (ka-ching) and &quot;no connection to Cheney&quot; Halliburton.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some days I wonder why we even send journalists to that 5-gon any more.  Who even buys the myth of &quot;an American people in control&quot;?  Nakedly imperialist aggression is the &quot;way of life&quot; we must defend nowadays.  Like, what&#39;s the fun in being the only superpower if they won&#39;t let you flaunt it?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;====&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;OK, time to go teach Python to 8th graders.  You might think I take a dim view of Americans, given my rhetoric.  But of course I&#39;m eagerly investing in a bright future for our kids, which means I&#39;m busy giving them basic survival skills, like computer programming (very needed in our urban jungle these days).  See my &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Bizmo Diaries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt; for more info.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And so what are &lt;/span&gt;you&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt; doing to help America today, if I may ask.&lt;/span&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114191642333900364'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114191642333900364'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/03/more-from-quaker-p-revised.html' title='More from Quaker-P (revised)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114183590542426748</id><published>2006-03-08T08:47:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:44:16.560-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2006.3.7</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/twin_hex_2_2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/twin_hex_2_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;font-size:85%;&quot; &gt;concentric hexapents by Tim Tyler using &lt;a href=&quot;http://springie.com/&quot;&gt;Springie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Last night we met with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.efn.org/%7Eecozma/sunergy/index.html&quot;&gt;Micheal Sunanda&lt;/a&gt; (yes, that&#39;s how he spells it, ea not ae) to learn of his adventures in Central America.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He was researching the state of organic homesteading, and ended up spending a lot of time on a coastal permaculture farm, where the infrastructure was good, but staff practices had been rather lame.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Trying to jump start the &quot;humanure&quot; composting system proved difficult because the staff had the usual cultural reluctance to discuss anything relating to poop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the whole, Micheal was rather unimpressed with the state of permaculture in Central America, including among &quot;alternative lifestyle&quot; types.  People are buying into the processed food economy, instead of perpetuating the older village-based system of complementary growing.  Possible costs:  loss of self-sufficiency and independence, some deterioration in health.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Micheal sent around little plastic containers of clay plus a mystery substance, which turned out to be cacao steeped in olive oil.  He told the story of the centipede &quot;tapping&quot; him on the eyelid (they don&#39;t really bite so much as tap), and the screamingly severe pain that caused, ameliorated with clay packs to some extent.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He slept in a cloth hammock, lost in the jungle on occasion.  Howler monkeys are &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;really&lt;/span&gt; loud.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We had some new faces tonight, mostly friends of Don&#39;s, including Chisler, who makes &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chisler.net/&quot;&gt;esoteric metal parts&lt;/a&gt; for Japanese furniture and such.  He liked to interject comments and Micheal got a little testy about that.  I appeared to be sleeping through much of the talk, but was actually concentrating or meditating -- I forget which.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Micheal also talked a lot about Earth&#39;s magnetic fields (he carries a little magnet on a gimble everywhere he goes) and about &quot;spirology.&quot; The conversation then turned to ley lines and the empirical basis for some of this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.answers.com/feng+shui&amp;r=67&quot;&gt;feng shui&lt;/a&gt; talk, if any.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/01/what-shall-i-do.html&quot;&gt;Art Kohn&lt;/a&gt;, back from DC, steered some of this discussion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then there was Rob, who wanted to know when he&#39;d be the same age as his dog, so he could have a party on that day.  We&#39;d been kicking this problem around for quite awhile (Jon Bunce had actually solved it, but I&#39;d lost the paper) so I finally turned to the open source community just hours before the meeting, hoping to give him a real answer.  This proved a success story, as chronicled in a thread on &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2006-March/005900.html&quot;&gt;edu-sig&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Still flush with this success, I sent out a call for concentric hexapental spheres to Synergeo, a Fuller School eGroup on Yahoo!, hoping to impress Glenn Stockton with how fast I could get back to him with some images of his Global Matrix.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This morning, I had two relevant images in my in box, plus helpful pointers on how to get more.  Tim Tyler&#39;s is displayed above, Adrian Rossiter&#39;s below.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This was the subject of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/oscon2005.html&quot;&gt;my OSCON talk last year&lt;/a&gt;:  how the open source community has made my work as a Fuller Schooler so much easier over time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another highlight:  Nirel cluing me in to &lt;a style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ashesandsnow.org/&quot;&gt;Ashes &amp; Snow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/hex_pents.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/hex_pents.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;font-size:85%;&quot; &gt;hexapents by Adrian Rossiter, using &lt;a href=&quot;http://packinon.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;Packinon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114183590542426748'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114183590542426748'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/03/wanderers-200637.html' title='Wanderers 2006.3.7'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114159960324471109</id><published>2006-03-05T17:11:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2023-04-16T08:32:28.693-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Politics @ Princeton</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/tank01.png&quot; onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/tank01.png&quot; style=&quot;cursor: pointer; display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&quot;think tank&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Matt and Mike plan to tease me over beers this evening, about my alma mater, thanks to the cover story in the most recent issue of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Nation&lt;/span&gt;:  &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Princeton Tilts Right&lt;/span&gt; by Max Blumenthal (March 13, 2006).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The article is about some well-funded conservative think tank based at the university, but getting no direct funding therefrom.  If you&#39;re reading from overseas, don&#39;t confuse &quot;conservative&quot; with &quot;conservationist&quot; -- two separate memes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Geeky aside:  if looking back from the magazine cover i.e. from &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;inside&lt;/span&gt; the depicted Ivory Tower (not really ivory), the tilt is actually to my &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;left&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As the movie &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/03/why-we-fight-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Why We Fight&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; points out:  think tanks have become pretty important of late, as government out-sources more of its brains, as well as its brawn, to become a pale ghost of its former self  (like a ring wraith?).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Well, I guess that&#39;s participatory democracy in action.  Plus thinking really doesn&#39;t cost that much (brains are quite energy efficient), so having a ton of money doesn&#39;t necessarily mean that much.  Like, I&#39;ve got my blogs, and they&#39;re world readable at no cost to me.  So what if I&#39;m not a billionaire like Bill?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But hey, what if Google gets taken over by Chinese ideologues and my blogs get deleted by busybody censors?  There&#39;s always room for angst.  Old Europe used to have an even &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;more&lt;/span&gt; drastic remedy for talking heads it didn&#39;t agree with:  it&#39;d cut &#39;em off or strangle &#39;em (or just burn the whole body alive, at the stake).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The USA&#39;s founding fathers tried to curb those Old Europe reflexes (didn&#39;t succeed entirely), by enshrining freedom of speech in the U.S. Constitution.  But did our founders forecast &quot;artificial persons&quot; having the same rights as the real ones, under the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thomhartmann.com/unequalprotection.shtml&quot;&gt;14th Amendment&lt;/a&gt;?  Obviously not.  But then, they didn&#39;t foresee the Internet either, which makes &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/&quot;&gt;my websites&lt;/a&gt; &quot;but a mouse click away,&quot; on a par with ExxonMobil&#39;s.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I interviewed two candidates for Princeton this year, like I did last year.  Impressive achievers, per usual.  I didn&#39;t hear a lot about community service though.  When do high school kids ever have the time to work with the less fortunate, the impoverished?  Why doesn&#39;t our public school system provide these opportunities?  Because there&#39;s no more poverty to worry about?  &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/01/dignity-village.html&quot;&gt;Someday maybe&lt;/a&gt;.  In the meantime, the wall around the privileged seems higher than ever these days, gated communities more the norm (like we had in the Philippines -- I lived in the somewhat ironically named Magellanes Village).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyway, as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/10/mark-satin-at-powells-books.html&quot;&gt;radical middle&lt;/a&gt; guy, I know people will probably cull through my many postings looking for words to use against me, if and when those &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/incomprehensible.html&quot;&gt;A &amp;amp; B modules&lt;/a&gt; ever start appearing in our nation&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/02/sixth-grade-geometry.html&quot;&gt;geometry classes&lt;/a&gt;.  Showing synergetic geometry on television (like in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/commercial-break.html&quot;&gt;Global Data&lt;/a&gt; commercial):  that&#39;d be like a match to the fuse of Bucky Fuller&#39;s long-running &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Mission Impossible&lt;/span&gt; thread.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Well, my would-be critics&#39;ll find plenty of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/whats-urner.html&quot;&gt;Urner&lt;/a&gt;-authored rants and diatribes, stuff to get angry about.  Like just today, look what I posted to Quaker-P (more context in the full version):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;There &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; leverage in having someone owe me a debt.  There&#39;s also the hypocrisy of the USA pushing the IMF to force other governments to repay debts, at great cost to social programs, while it simply sinks deeper and deeper into debt itself, never really forcing the same dynamics internally.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Yes, social programs get cut (FDR era programming has been gutted), but just enough is meted out to forestall a massive popular uprising or backlash -- a day-to-day calculation, requiring close collusion with the corporate media.  In the Third World, it&#39;s easier to use brute force intimidation, to make activists &quot;disappear.&quot; ....&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;I have this portfolio of investments.  It doesn&#39;t &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;have&lt;/span&gt; to have the USA in it for my operations to be profitable.  There&#39;s nothing the USA has that I couldn&#39;t get elsewhere.  Or that&#39;s how it might come to seem, if present trends continue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Besides, there&#39;s a sense of poetic justice in watching those USAers join the rest of &quot;the developing world&quot;.  I&#39;m tired of watching this self-righteous &quot;superpower&quot; strut about on the world stage, arrogant and stupid.  I would &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;love&lt;/span&gt; to have it go down, but in a controlled and intelligently managed way, such that it doesn&#39;t set off its nukes, the way Americans do whenever they feel threatened (sniveling cowards that they are).&lt;/blockquote&gt;Wow!  I sound like a dangerous dissident or something.  But keeping to the middle way means hanging ornaments in a balanced fashion over time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I veer left and right, but it&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=4508580&quot;&gt;design science&lt;/a&gt;, more than politics, which supplies &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/politics.html&quot;&gt;the gyroscope I steer by&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://genius.com/Animotion-i-engineer-lyrics&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;I Engineer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (downloading it now, from iTunes -- a song Matt turned me on to a long time ago).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Other developments&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mom just called, about to fly off to the New Europe.  Sunanda is back in town, from Costa Rica, Panama and Nicaragua, with lots of stories to share with Wanderers.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114159960324471109'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114159960324471109'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/03/politics-princeton.html' title='Politics @ Princeton'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>