<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=901'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=876&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=926&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>901</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4015829302941869791</id><published>2012-08-11T13:23:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2012-08-14T09:31:33.809-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Faster Forward</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/7762133468/&quot; title=&quot;DSCN2690 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCN2690&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8437/7762133468_a2d2af4945.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=2394614&amp;amp;messageID=7860925#7860925&quot;&gt;I&#39;ve continued to agitate&lt;/a&gt;, per usual, on behalf of STEM, contra the over-specializers.&amp;nbsp; I think feedback loops groom singularities and I&#39;m one of them, but so are a lot of people.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Calling me a &quot;spin doctor&quot; is quite accurate though.&amp;nbsp; The term usually has derogatory connotations, so I&#39;m not being boastful that much, except to acknowledge I&#39;m pretty good at it.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/08/name-collisions.html&quot;&gt;I had good teachers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The &quot;Happy Camper Brigade&quot; (HCB) as I call it took off for Patrick&#39;s place, thence to the coast.&amp;nbsp; They phoned HQS for an update about the detour.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;ll be going out of range.&amp;nbsp; I just texted a reminder to turn off cell phone power or the battery will drain.&amp;nbsp; I know Melody has a charger but they won&#39;t always be in a place to use that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Have a great trip Alex, if I don&#39;t see you again before you go.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I tried to get another basement involved as back up, which we&#39;d use today, given Lindsey is out of town.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ll see if that works, where food storage is concerned.&amp;nbsp; In the meantime, I&#39;m sure we can handle it (don&#39;t pass that back, if you read this in my blog).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Does thinking in nationalistic terms destroy an analysis to the point of unreadability? &amp;nbsp;Not usually.&amp;nbsp; You can still read the things, just they&#39;re not very smart.&amp;nbsp; Accounting for nationalism, on the other hand, is something else, and should always be done, if relevant.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m reviewing a lot of history these days, and not just through print media by a long shot.&amp;nbsp; Tara is in final count down.&amp;nbsp; Betsey from our Meeting will be visiting her in October.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4015829302941869791'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4015829302941869791'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/08/faster-forward.html' title='Faster Forward'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4724977313494562852</id><published>2012-08-01T00:54:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-08-01T01:01:49.945-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Fast Forward</title><content type='html'>&quot;Accelerating acceleration&quot; seems to be the name of the game, shades of Alvin Toffler.&amp;nbsp; One&#39;s own life is its own succession of &quot;future shocks&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m working with Saturday Academy again, to bring some of the latest technology into classrooms for young teens.&amp;nbsp; Mostly people don&#39;t provide that as a service.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m talking about Python 2.7 with Visual Python.&amp;nbsp; The computer lab is at a local university.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tonight Tara and I hopped a bus to see for ourselves what this vigil around City Hall is all about.&amp;nbsp; A corner of the park where Occupy was based last October serves as a compact little picnic area.&amp;nbsp; Many of those present are homeless.&amp;nbsp; Cities do not always tolerate gatherings of this kind.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/7689616000/&quot; title=&quot;Zucchini with Pesto by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Zucchini with Pesto&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7111/7689616000_9d08aa96c3_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This particular initiative has been going on for awhile.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve been reading up on the twists and turns in &lt;i&gt;Willamette Week&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Mercury&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Negotiating the status of R2D2 (&lt;i&gt;Right To Dream Too&lt;/i&gt;), a long-running occupation of a privately owned property -- with owner permission -- has been a part of it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Monday night I hauled food to Colonel Summers from St. David of Wales, and then headed over to &lt;i&gt;Barley Mill&lt;/i&gt; to catch up on reading.&amp;nbsp; Then I returned to the park to chat with some of the people I know there, such as the Jennings, Melody and others.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s too much going on to capture all the details, either for myself or these blogs.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m sure it&#39;s no different for others.&amp;nbsp; Lots just flows through the nets.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tara and I took the 14 back towards the neighborhood though she alighted early to catch some comedy at &lt;i&gt;Helium&lt;/i&gt; across from &lt;i&gt;Lucky Lab&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I went on to P&lt;i&gt;auling House&lt;/i&gt; where Bob McGown was holding forth, but decided I needed to work instead so wandered over to &lt;i&gt;Powell&#39;s Books on Hawthorne&lt;/i&gt; and jacked in.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Hours later, I&#39;m still working, though I&#39;ve shifted the venue.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I did find some time to post to the Wittgenstein list, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dir.groups.yahoo.com/group/WittrsEX/message/4865&quot;&gt;thinking about thoughts&lt;/a&gt; some more.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/7689614478/&quot; title=&quot;A Day Job by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;A Day Job&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7135/7689614478_dcf7522742_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: franz hall ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4724977313494562852'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4724977313494562852'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/08/fast-forward.html' title='Fast Forward'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4985271111858156286</id><published>2012-07-24T20:42:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-07-24T20:48:47.168-07:00</updated><title type='text'>The Hunger Games (movie review)</title><content type='html'>Not unlike &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/06/more-movies-mcmenamins.html&quot;&gt;Cabin in the Woods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; in that the enslavers, the urban elite, has untold technologies it seems to only share with its &quot;tributes&quot; from the districts, the rural feeder zones. &amp;nbsp;No wonder the King (Donald Sutherland) seems nervous. &amp;nbsp;This would have to be a tense situation, especially for the 1%, anytime a strong underdog comes along.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They have maglev, amazing powers to control the environment, so why are the district people starving? &amp;nbsp;Somebody has to do the dirty work and oppression is the only way? &amp;nbsp;Mining (in District 12) looks as bad as ever.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
OK, I admit it: &amp;nbsp;I was standing in line for food when the movie got started -- a little early by my calculations, plus this clueless couple got in front of me, not seeing the line behind. &amp;nbsp;Anyway, maybe it&#39;s all explained at the beginning. &amp;nbsp;Don&#39;t spoil it for me. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;ll see it again.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4985271111858156286'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4985271111858156286'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/07/hunger-games-movie-review.html' title='The Hunger Games (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3396627062394401882</id><published>2012-07-23T21:12:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2012-07-24T20:37:00.864-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Last of OSCON</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=2391310&quot;&gt;I&#39;ve been puzzling&lt;/a&gt; in the rear view mirror, ever since, like reading my new Go language programming book at &lt;i&gt;American Dream Pizza&lt;/i&gt; today.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oscon.com/oscon2012/public/schedule/detail/23186&quot;&gt;One of the best talks&lt;/a&gt; was this enthusiastic woman, Kirsten Jones, with a clear mission: &amp;nbsp;to make our use of the web APIs less frustrating. &amp;nbsp;And she did that very simply, by showing us the best software for snooping on web traffic and getting those request and response objects clearly mapped, complete with headers, parameters, whatever came or went. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That genre of software proves its value over and over in her experience and she gave a really clear exposition about that, to an appreciative room.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In reverie, I was &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/06/at-work-again.html&quot;&gt;taken back to West Precinct&lt;/a&gt;, Jerritt Collord presiding, starting our class in Open Source for Saturday Academy, courtesy of Hillsboro Police Department, geared for youngsters in their region. &amp;nbsp;He had them thinking about packet sniffers immediately. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Even though &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/03/wanderers-meeting-2005315.html&quot;&gt;Officer George Heuston&lt;/a&gt;, former FBI and white knight in good standing, was present and monitoring, he allowed Jerritt to proceed. &amp;nbsp; This was public information. &amp;nbsp;Geeks, and geeks in training, have a need to know -- especially if it&#39;s the web traffic through your own machine, not even talking about sniffing wifi.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The final keynote was amazing as well, all about fear and longing, motivation, &quot;mind hacking&quot;. &amp;nbsp;A skillful speaker that guy, head and shoulders above so many. &amp;nbsp;I was enthralled, even though I felt I knew the ideas already.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Slides are an art form and I don&#39;t think &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/06/another-omsi-pub.html&quot;&gt;that biomimicry guy&lt;/a&gt; made the right call, in opting out of sharing pictures in that &lt;i&gt;Bagdad&lt;/i&gt; setting. &amp;nbsp;The standup comics get away with not doing that, but is that what we were there for then? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The military has adopted the lightning talk standard, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/04/roller-coaster-at-reed.html&quot;&gt;per anthropological reports&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;I can see why. &amp;nbsp;With slides, and five minutes, you can say a lot. &amp;nbsp;But then blog posts let you read at your own pace and have &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=7852816&quot;&gt;more hypertext&lt;/a&gt; -- it&#39;s more pull than push. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Need to know? &amp;nbsp;Keep clicking.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3396627062394401882'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3396627062394401882'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/07/last-of-oscon.html' title='Last of OSCON'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8974561774189874085</id><published>2012-07-18T11:06:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-07-19T08:57:25.069-07:00</updated><title type='text'>OSCON 2012 Day One</title><content type='html'>I couldn&#39;t see squeezing past those people with Naga in a bag (Python mascot) &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; my satchel, so separated from Steve and moved to the side of the auditorium.&amp;nbsp; This was the opening event in some ways, tutorials over, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/07/oscon-2012-tutorials.html&quot;&gt;Camp OSCON&lt;/a&gt; behind us.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tim O&#39;Reilly&#39;s keynote had a simple message:&amp;nbsp; Open Source could do more to tell the story of how it&#39;s powering the ecosystem.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Like solar energy, it&#39;s often under-accounted (under-valued) because the sun drying clothes or growing food is unmetered.&amp;nbsp; Those little pie charts showing solar energy as a tiny fraction of the economy&#39;s input are talking about metered solar panel income.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s not the same thing as wealth or value.&amp;nbsp; Most economists don&#39;t grok &quot;cosmic accounting&quot; very well, no secret there.&amp;nbsp; Economics has been pretty weak in the STEM department.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Take Comcast for example.&amp;nbsp; Who is making billions from whom?&amp;nbsp; Customers are paying to view content they themselves provide in many cases.&amp;nbsp; Comcast gets access to all kinds of free content from the Internet, an open bastion of a kind.&amp;nbsp; How much of this revenue is attributable to &quot;open source&quot;?&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s a question to look at, a story to tell.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Hewlett-Packard (a presence here), other companies (Microsoft), both thrive in and contribute to, this shared ecosystem.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A first principle, says Tim:&amp;nbsp; reap less than you sew, create more value than you capture.&amp;nbsp; Feed the commons, don&#39;t operate as a net deficit to your community.&amp;nbsp; Seems like common sense to me.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m in another Go talk this morning, more about the history and management within the community than the syntax, which was a focus of the tutorial yesterday.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I may not get much time to develop either my Go language or Blender skills, but they&#39;re both a source of inspiration anyway, in terms of what they&#39;re contributing and how they show off what humans working together may accomplish.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The education track was dealing in some interesting heuristics, however they happened to map rather closely to the status quo.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=7851218&quot;&gt;a brand of positive futurism&lt;/a&gt; that envisions a new standard or protocol, but if you admit hybrids (diversity, multiplicity), then we&#39;re back to &quot;what&#39;s so&quot; -- meaning it boils down to whether we all want to march to the same drummer.&amp;nbsp; We do not.&amp;nbsp; Nor do we want all others to do so, bottom line.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Like &quot;metadata&quot; tends to just mean what we carry around &quot;in our heads&quot; i.e. the persona as filter is better (because real thinking is finely tuned) than any robotized search algorithm.&amp;nbsp; I think we all know that by now.&amp;nbsp; Hyperlinks are &quot;metadata&quot; in the sense that human beings find the most relevant links, even if machines are in on the act, aid and abet the experience in various ways.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oscon.com/oscon2012/public/schedule/detail/26001&quot;&gt;FERPA&lt;/a&gt;, ancestor of HIPAA in some dimensions, seems like a goofy law. &amp;nbsp;Students aren&#39;t bound by it, and may blab about so-and-so being a presence on campus. &amp;nbsp;Indeed, free speech rights conflict with the right to privacy sometimes. &amp;nbsp;My secrets need not be your secrets. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Democracies, for one, should be more into promising transparency and sharing data than clamping down on the free flow of info. &amp;nbsp;If you want your affiliation with an institution to remain classified, consider joining a private academy or LLC that makes secrecy a part of its culture, among other students / employees as well.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
State funded institutions should be looking at their student populations as closer to public servants. &amp;nbsp;Public schools are about preparing people for life in a democracy, and a democracy of necessity provides lots of transparency, as well as some secrecy i.e. no one says you can&#39;t encrypt or otherwise protect access to your files -- and feel free to opt out of on-line campus directories and/or other records the school server may ask you about.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Better to offer courses on identity management and countering stalkers by exposing them, than to promise some high degree of anonymity and absence from public records of all kinds. &amp;nbsp;That&#39;s to promise the impossible and to set up unrealistic expectations among students.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That being said, if you want anonymity, I recommend distance education academies.&amp;nbsp; Other students don&#39;t see you unless you choose to attend events where you come out of the closet, as it were, as a peer or alum.&amp;nbsp; Your affiliation is a lot easier to keep secret when you&#39;re never seen in the parking lot.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8974561774189874085'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8974561774189874085'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/07/oscon-2012-key.html' title='OSCON 2012 Day One'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8618081336562852051</id><published>2012-07-14T19:50:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-07-15T06:22:08.342-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Two Cameras</title><content type='html'>Two videographers capture the same performance in 2009, a Burning Man related event in Portland, Oregon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was videographer #2 with the trippy wandering camera.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Videographer #1 took an unwavering shot and got better sound.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Viewing suggestion&lt;/i&gt;:&amp;nbsp; roughly synch and play both at once, while muting the sound on #2 using the Youtube speaker control (then unmute #2 if you want to continue a little longer). &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/TpTYwh6PmSU&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
:: video 1 ::&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/h923W5h3-oM&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
:: video 2 ::&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The performer, Lindsey Walker, had recently moved from Savannah, Georgia.  She came in a Nissan with her own PA system (Bose), a keyboard, and a cat.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, for this performance she made use of the house sound system.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What you&#39;re hearing though, is hand held camera pickup, hardly studio quality.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I treasure this song all the more now that she doesn&#39;t play it anymore, or at least not in this form.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lindsey still performs in and around Portland, sometimes as a street musician.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You will see her (briefly) in &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/04/occupation-nation-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;the movie &lt;i&gt;Occupation Nation&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Portland&#39;s B-Media Collective.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8618081336562852051'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8618081336562852051'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/07/two-cameras.html' title='Two Cameras'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/TpTYwh6PmSU/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7206571140288651409</id><published>2012-07-12T20:38:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2012-07-14T22:55:53.583-07:00</updated><title type='text'>From The Open Bastion</title><content type='html'>The Open Bastion&#39;s CEO is &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/02/open-secrets.html&quot;&gt;back in PDX&lt;/a&gt;, just in time for OSCON.&amp;nbsp; In his luggage, the brand new and newly branded Raspberry Pi.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A first order of business today, his first back, was to hook up the full size projector via HDMI cable, attach keyboard and mouse the the USB jacks, and hit On.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Linux bootstrapping process percolated across the console to login, thence to startx, thence to the RaspberryPi desktop, this one with two versions of Python in IDLE, Scratch, a few games.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s a minimal world, what some might call &quot;structured&quot;, and ideal for kids.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
OK, there might have been a bit more fumbling about.&amp;nbsp; For one, we needed a nonwireless USB keyboard, and for that I needed to walk a short distance to a second floor of a supplier.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The model I chose, for about $13, has extra large letters on the keys, which makes it look both kid and old people friendly at the same time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s a US keyboard layout of course, whereas this device is from the UK.&amp;nbsp; Need a double-quotes?&amp;nbsp; Try Shift-2.&amp;nbsp; Wild. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Nor have we gotten audio out at the time of this writing, choosing Force HDMI but maybe not having the right settings on the peripheral, a work in progress.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Of course I was looking for photo ops, as Raspberry Pi is still quite a new item.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Here are some pictures (click through to Photostream):&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/7559588772/&quot; title=&quot;HDMI + USB x 2 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;HDMI + USB x 2&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8026/7559588772_fa589a9151.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: raspberry pi ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/7559586518/&quot; title=&quot;Peripherals Added by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Peripherals Added&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8160/7559586518_3a01d52c92.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: a tiny device ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/7559748942/&quot; title=&quot;DSCN2260 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCN2260&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7118/7559748942_cc59be67aa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: back in rose city ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/7559589566/&quot; title=&quot;X-Term by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;X-Term&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7118/7559589566_38d6388d95.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: projected desktop ::&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7206571140288651409'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7206571140288651409'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/07/from-open-bastion.html' title='From The Open Bastion'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4482455301451208437</id><published>2012-07-07T16:13:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2012-07-07T16:14:38.532-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Avatar Suits</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7523481130/&quot; title=&quot;Avatar Meetup by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Avatar Meetup&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8004/7523481130_56bc842721.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;:: STEM teachers meet ::&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7523195642/&quot; title=&quot;Platonic Realm = Micro Realm by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Platonic Realm = Micro Realm&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8011/7523195642_8b87edb1f1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
:: The Platonic Realm ::&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7523196618/&quot; title=&quot;STEM Text by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;STEM Text&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7269/7523196618_105559b694.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
:: STEM Text ::&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4482455301451208437'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4482455301451208437'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/07/avatar-suits.html' title='Avatar Suits'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6704238449079088712</id><published>2012-07-02T17:49:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2013-08-25T20:02:01.780-07:00</updated><title type='text'>More Movies @ McMenamins</title><content type='html'>McMenamins has been showing &lt;i&gt;Cabin in the Woods&lt;/i&gt;, and more recently &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chernobyl_Diaries&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Chernobyl Diaries&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, both horror films, and both featuring bizmos.&amp;nbsp; So you&#39;d think I&#39;d post this in &lt;i&gt;BizMo Diaries&lt;/i&gt;, but then they both featured Control Rooms as well.&amp;nbsp; You could say they were linked other tomorrows in that sense, via their control rooms.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the meantime, Glenn provided &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/news/2005/050808/full/news050808-4.html&quot;&gt;a happier backdrop&lt;/a&gt;, talking about the wild creatures of Chernobyl (ala Keith Lofstrom and Stewart Brand), and of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0384793/&quot;&gt;the light comedy &lt;i&gt;Accepted&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Cabin in the Woods&lt;/i&gt; has Joss Whedon all over it, going back to the Buffy sequence with the boyfriend from some subterranean government.&amp;nbsp; Shades of &lt;i&gt;Lost&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;ve got a hexafence, takes out an eagle.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s a hell mouth.&amp;nbsp; What&#39;s missing is the Catholic Church.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re all engineers down there, minding the store.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re actually the collective mind of the viewer as in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=djQ7WZlb140&quot;&gt;Woody Allen&#39;s control room&lt;/a&gt; in the movie about sex.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s today&#39;s control room in so many ways.&amp;nbsp; Of course Sigourney Weaver would be part of it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Chernobyl Diaries&lt;/i&gt; starts out with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/08/drinking-liberally.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Blair Witch&lt;/i&gt; jerkiness&lt;/a&gt;, prompting fears the movie will be all bouncing camera, but then she settles in under more confidant direction and I could relax and enjoy the ride more.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d had a long day and was still on duty, more like &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/06/our-week-in-indy.html&quot;&gt;in Indianapolis&lt;/a&gt;, which was also a barrel of monkeys.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The bizmos are quite similar in both films and serve as conveyances into Other Tomorrows.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve been thinking a lot about &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/03/high-desert.html&quot;&gt;my high desert schools&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The planetarium (you need one &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/08/escaping-light-pollution.html&quot;&gt;even there&lt;/a&gt;) looks a lot like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.harrogate-news.co.uk/2011/07/03/protest-planned-for-independence-from-america-at-nsa-menwith-hill/&quot;&gt;those golf balls&lt;/a&gt; in the UK countryside, big ones, so as you round the corner, perhaps in a van, but maybe on foot, you see like colonizers from another somewhat higher civilization.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re living up to our heritage, more a maritime set?&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re not near the ocean necessarily.&amp;nbsp; Bhutan was like this (Druk-yul as they call it), minus the golf balls (back then).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Both bizmos met a similar fate, and neither proved a secure shell against danger.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What I found myself thinking, is when you have intelligent young people like this, at their peak in abilities in many dimensions, why not have some serious work in store, rather than all idle vacation.&amp;nbsp; Hard work actually builds skills.&amp;nbsp; Not that these troops didn&#39;t end up working hard -- much too hard, almost in compensation.&amp;nbsp; We resent they get a vacation I suppose, when all we could afford was a movie ticket.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, a &quot;business mobile&quot; is deliberately not portrayed as a &quot;recreational vehicle&quot; (RV).&amp;nbsp; That doesn&#39;t mean the work can&#39;t be fun, but this is expensive equipment and lots of communities have &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/more-bizmo-tech.html&quot;&gt;some serious needs&lt;/a&gt; that need documenting.&amp;nbsp; The teams get to swap around a lot.&amp;nbsp; This was also a topic with Glenn -- like time shares in Orlando but really nomadic sometimes: few possessions, yet institutionally wealthy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of work, I was hitting the queues more than usual for a weekend, having an unusually occupied work week.&amp;nbsp; We got a lot done, turned a lot of corners.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Cabin...&lt;/i&gt; suggests it&#39;s helping us turn over a new leaf in that the horror film formula is not unconsciously / religiously followed: the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shaggy_Rogers&quot;&gt;Scooby Doo guy&lt;/a&gt; gets away with it. His smoke actually helps in the fight against Satan -- game changing.&amp;nbsp; He and the virgin somewhat turn tables on the eager voyeurs (deep out of site) as we don&#39;t see them ritually punished any more than we are at the end of the day.&amp;nbsp; The creatures of the deep become restless.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6704238449079088712'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6704238449079088712'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/06/more-movies-mcmenamins.html' title='More Movies @ McMenamins'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5320187364309275211</id><published>2012-06-19T22:26:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-06-19T23:38:16.615-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2012.6.19</title><content type='html'>Lew was focused on finding the right technology for the meetinghouse. &amp;nbsp;Our acoustics are actually quite good now, with music events quite doable on the 2nd floor. &amp;nbsp;We&#39;re mostly interested in keeping it quiet for our neighbors, not because the room can&#39;t handle music. &amp;nbsp;However Lew&#39;s challenge is the spoken voice, occasional singing. &amp;nbsp;He&#39;s looking at array microphones and their ability to direction-find a sound source. &amp;nbsp;Not a dumb idea.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d CC&#39;d Lew earlier today, when &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/10/halloween-2011-2-of-3.html&quot;&gt;SDW&lt;/a&gt; sent a memo on the kitchen. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/08/board-games.html&quot;&gt;FNB kitchen use&lt;/a&gt; is more my focus than Pauling House scheduling, where I&#39;m nominally a listowner on the shared calendar (a Yahoo! gadget). &amp;nbsp;That was a solution from another era. &amp;nbsp;In SDW&#39;s case, it&#39;s the new baker we&#39;re seeking to accommodate. &amp;nbsp;Luckily, FNB doesn&#39;t do meat or lard. &amp;nbsp;We&#39;re not about to fill the atmosphere with grease. &amp;nbsp;A gluten-free baker has nothing to fear, and indeed it&#39;s a synergetic combo.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, I CC&#39;d Lew because I was sharing about meetinghouse history. &amp;nbsp;We have some overlap with St. David, in terms of current and former members. &amp;nbsp;Chatting about our presence on Google Earth, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/6854605156/&quot;&gt;thanks to Lew&lt;/a&gt;, is something of an ice breaker, when working with these other neighborhood religious groups.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The link between the Pauling House and the Meetinghouse is Doug Strain&#39;s company, ESI. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/planting-seeds-in-silicon-forest.html&quot;&gt;The corporate booklet&lt;/a&gt; gives 1958 as a date, whereas other sources say ESI vacated the building in 1956. &amp;nbsp;But remember: &amp;nbsp;the fire at the place on Macadam. &amp;nbsp;ESI moved out, then lost the new place in a fire. &amp;nbsp;Did they need to move back, temporarily? &amp;nbsp;I&#39;m not privy to corporate archives, but the meeting archivist (Dr. Carl Abbott) might have some of those records.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
More discussion of UAVs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Cameras producing pictures that let you &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lytro.com/&quot;&gt;change the focus&lt;/a&gt; after the fact were another topic.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As a courtesy to one of the tenants, involved in alcohol counseling, we no longer bring alcohol to our meetings. &amp;nbsp;We&#39;ve been &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/wanderers-2010511.html&quot;&gt;criticized in the past&lt;/a&gt; for allowing it, but then wine is a social drink in this region, with OMSI lectures taking advantage of the &lt;i&gt;McMenamins&lt;/i&gt; license to run a full bar. &amp;nbsp;We were like a &lt;i&gt;Spaghetti Factory&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;Red Robbin&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;in allowing minors, but with like a TED talk going on (no, not pole dancing -- that would have been down the street). &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/11/think-tank-techniques.html&quot;&gt;Private party rules&lt;/a&gt; applied, with no selling to the public either expected or implied.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;re getting ready for the Summer Retreat. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/06/wanderers-summer-retreat.html&quot;&gt;That time of year again&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I had lunch at &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/01/quick-recap.html&quot;&gt;Laughing Planet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; on Belmont. &amp;nbsp;Yesterday: &amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yelp.com/biz/toney-bento-portland&quot;&gt;Toney Bento&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/5320187364309275211/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/5320187364309275211' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5320187364309275211'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5320187364309275211'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/06/wanderers-2012619.html' title='Wanderers 2012.6.19'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3699185740895670262</id><published>2012-06-17T19:52:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2014-05-02T12:08:08.780-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Touring Earlham College</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;375&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;flashvars&quot; value=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157630169978668%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157630169978668%2F&amp;set_id=72157630169978668&amp;jump_to=&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=143270&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;embed type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; src=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=143270&quot; allowFullScreen=&quot;true&quot; flashvars=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157630169978668%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157630169978668%2F&amp;set_id=72157630169978668&amp;jump_to=&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: starting with parent / prospectives tour... :: &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3699185740895670262'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3699185740895670262'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/06/touring-earlham-college.html' title='Touring Earlham College'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4064061791876396896</id><published>2012-06-10T12:40:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2012-06-19T12:44:57.672-07:00</updated><title type='text'>A Quaker Face</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7403270428/&quot; title=&quot;Interlude by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Interlude&quot; height=&quot;340&quot; src=&quot;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5450/7403270428_75f341baf6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4064061791876396896'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4064061791876396896'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/06/quaker-face.html' title='A Quaker Face'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3735121978720515089</id><published>2012-06-07T13:00:00.005-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-27T16:45:58.122-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Consumer Story</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157630014045833&quot; title=&quot;Plumbing Saga&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/7072/7349592418_e039ab9816.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Plumbing Saga&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Finding a yellow toilet is not the easiest thing in the world.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d fatally weakened the old one, by adding a big rock to the tank.&amp;nbsp; The rock swelled, making it impossible to remove without shattering the tank.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aboysupply.com/t-hollywoodstore.aspx&quot;&gt;The Hollywood Aboy&lt;/a&gt; located a yellow Kohler, following up on some sleuthing by other household members.&amp;nbsp; Today, the new toilet arrived but minus one critical washer in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/note.php?note_id=341296099258401&quot;&gt;Accessory Pack 1024390&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Mick tried to find a kit at George Moreland but no dice.&amp;nbsp; The washer is somewhat special in slipping over the screw head, making the tank flush (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/11/flushed-away-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;heh, English&lt;/a&gt;) against the bowl.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Aboy had too many in the queue to field my call for help in anything close to real time (my call was returned late the next day), so Mick stopped his clock and just made it his business to locate the part.&amp;nbsp; Kohler is a big name, you would think there&#39;d be such a supply in this town.&amp;nbsp; Lets see what tomorrow brings.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
No wait, Mick just called.&amp;nbsp; He thinks he&#39;s found a compatible washer.&amp;nbsp; Lets see if this story has a happy ending today then.&amp;nbsp; Today is Tara&#39;s 18th birthday for real (legally / officially), although we celebrated big time &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/06/another-big-day.html&quot;&gt;last night&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[ Brief interlude helping the daughter of an emeritus stats prof at University of Illinois, Urbana-Champagne.&amp;nbsp; He didn&#39;t know Jerry Uhl well (an inspiration &lt;a href=&quot;http://netmath.illinois.edu/coursesoftware&quot;&gt;behind NetMath&lt;/a&gt;) but they did go the first grade together in Pittsburgh.]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Hey &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.micksplumbing.com/sinks-faucets-toilets.html&quot;&gt;Mick&lt;/a&gt;, good job.&amp;nbsp; Thanks for being a cheerful, hard-working and patient guy.&amp;nbsp; The new toilet looks like it will use a lot less water, even compared to when the other tank had a rock in it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Coincidentally, my sister Julie is having toilet work done today as well, in her abode within Greater LA. &amp;nbsp;Carol flew off to Philadelphia. &amp;nbsp;We were &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7163402917/in/photostream&quot;&gt;at PDX&lt;/a&gt; by 6 AM sharing breakfast &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7163404039/in/photostream/&quot;&gt;at &lt;i&gt;Beaches&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;She&#39;s on her way to &lt;i&gt;Pendle Hill&lt;/i&gt; for the AFSC board members retreat.</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/3735121978720515089/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/3735121978720515089' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3735121978720515089'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3735121978720515089'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/06/consumer-story.html' title='Consumer Story'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-440251874270524038</id><published>2012-06-03T13:59:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-14T20:04:49.146-07:00</updated><title type='text'>At Tom&#39;s</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/is-dFvEZDlA&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Tom&#39;s&lt;/i&gt; is a good place to think of my grandpa Tom, the linotype operator who I knew as a champion shuffle board and solitaire winner. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/01/cracker-dog.html&quot;&gt;He and grandma Margie&lt;/a&gt; were major characters of my childhood and youth. &amp;nbsp;I lived with them for an especially long stretch during my freshman year at Southeast High, in Bradenton, Florida.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve been &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/group/mathfuture/msg/c22653f9b619e6a1&quot;&gt;diving into fractals&lt;/a&gt; with wild abandon, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mandelbulb&quot;&gt;the Mandelbulb&lt;/a&gt; especially, and then &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/is-dFvEZDlA&quot;&gt;this other solution&lt;/a&gt;, which I&#39;ve watched I don&#39;t know how many times, comparing machines for smoothness of performances (though some of the glitches are in the production, which is eerie and gorgeous... enough positive adjectives to keep it a source of fascination, talking about the music here too).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The thing about school now, is you get a lot out of staying home if you&#39;re self disciplined and have a pretty good Internet connection. &amp;nbsp;And shouldn&#39;t your community be providing ways to get together and share with friends? &amp;nbsp;Yes, these houses are themselves pretty good in many cases, I don&#39;t deny it. &amp;nbsp;If you&#39;ve got one of those places, consider having it made (whatever that means), in terms of having a great setup for learning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The thing about learning, though, is it&#39;s interactive, not a spectator sport (though spectating may be part of it).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My order just came. &amp;nbsp;I don&#39;t usually eat in the bar section with the pool tables, but we thought that&#39;d be fun so why not. &amp;nbsp;SH got liver. &amp;nbsp;Me, just some blueberry pancakes, nothing else, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/02/wandering-in-psu.html&quot;&gt;a &lt;i&gt;Dead Guy&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tara is at &lt;i&gt;Laughing Planet&lt;/i&gt; celebrating her time with the Nicaragua contingent. &amp;nbsp;Betsey, an Earlham alum (as is &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/more-adventures-in-quakerdom.html&quot;&gt;Annis&lt;/a&gt;, some others in our extended meeting, Cradlers, Merkins...), likes us getting another Friend for that place, so we&#39;re celebrating that too.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I missed having my camera on me during these last great gatherings, most amazingly (for a host of reasons) the grand party at the Travis household. &amp;nbsp;Congratulations to both girls (of course women), Rachael (college) and Luci (high school). &amp;nbsp;Lynn and Tim are fantastic people with very admirable children.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Snyders have pretty much finished their move to Portland; Joe sold his sheep. I haven&#39;t met their kids in awhile, all grown up.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The deep dive into fractals was not all together unprofessional; having authored my minimalist CropCircle Tractor Art in 2011, a Python module that does a Mandelbrot in ASCII, using &quot;tractors&quot; instead of &quot;turtles&quot; in wavy plains (planes) of grain (pixels). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/07/checking-in.html&quot;&gt;Hyzy&lt;/a&gt; swept through, allowing the gossip that she&#39;s transitioning away from &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://westernfriend.org/&quot;&gt;Western Friend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, 2012 being her last as its chief -- a very responsible role in our community (means she&#39;s brilliantly skillful). &amp;nbsp;Hadn&#39;t seen Ron, or Dave in awhile, or Gayle. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/03/corporation-meeting.html&quot;&gt;Tom&lt;/a&gt; I&#39;d seen in Philadelphia. &amp;nbsp;Or Rachael... like a big family reunion. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;d originally just come as&amp;nbsp;chauffeur for Tara, not realizing I&#39;d been invited, but Lynn said my invite had bounced. &amp;nbsp;Hey, nice. &amp;nbsp;Good fun.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Today, Quaker meeting was packed to the gills. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7012978349/in/photostream/&quot;&gt;Lew&#39;s 99 chair layout&lt;/a&gt; was pushed passed the limit most likely. &amp;nbsp;We remnant of Bob Smith&#39;s books was for sale at modest prices and I picked up one by an Anglo, exultant about some kind of Anglo race by the sound of it, somewhat ignoring the Philippines. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;ll use it as a reference sometimes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
From Southeast High in Bradenton, where I was living with Tom and Margie, then in a motel -- me and sis both, going to respective schools -- I moved to Manila. &amp;nbsp;We were a UN family back then, with fancy blue passports. I was happy with the change of channels, even it meant less &lt;i&gt;Star Trek&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Boltons are who I really think about though. &amp;nbsp;I haven&#39;t seen Chuck or Mary in a long while, and it was like the first thing I said to Carol when she got off the plane, is that we should get by there soon, in this time of so many milestones.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/440251874270524038'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/440251874270524038'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/06/at-toms.html' title='At Tom&#39;s'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/is-dFvEZDlA/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6496740065655199765</id><published>2012-05-29T09:42:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2012-09-11T15:22:53.838-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Sharing Ideas</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7292261272/&quot; title=&quot;OPDX HQS by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;OPDX HQS&quot; height=&quot;334&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7211/7292261272_9693bebc1c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: a spooky hqs ::&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7291748242/&quot; title=&quot;Bats on the Loose by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bats on the Loose&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7098/7291748242_3c8d9d5ed0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: ideas go forth ::&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7291747040/&quot; title=&quot;Color Coded by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Color Coded&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7225/7291747040_1e5cb684f4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: color coded concepts ::
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6496740065655199765'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6496740065655199765'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/05/sharing-ideas.html' title='Sharing Ideas'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6573101159812953400</id><published>2012-05-27T14:13:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2012-05-27T14:13:53.543-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Well Hello There</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7276024654/&quot; title=&quot;Thinking about Objects by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Thinking about Objects&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7086/7276024654_9efc2dfd51.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Thinking about Objects&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
objects get allocated within the heap, a finite space for objects. The Python interpreter thinks through partially overlapping namespaces connected by dot notation in temporary tree structures (import hierarchies). The top-level namespace is identified with the interpreting process.</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/6573101159812953400/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/6573101159812953400' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6573101159812953400'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6573101159812953400'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/05/well-hello-there.html' title='Well Hello There'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5738436737370406829</id><published>2012-05-25T16:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2012-06-19T12:29:45.740-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Juggling Hats</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7271348774/&quot; title=&quot;Brochures by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Brochures&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8019/7271348774_87b0f599c0_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m somewhat wearing &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/12/base-tours.html&quot;&gt;my AFSC hat&lt;/a&gt; these days, having been drawn back to my foci from &lt;i&gt;Asia-Pacific Issues News&lt;/i&gt; days, when I was editor. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I drove Carol to the meeting this morning, but didn&#39;t attend. &amp;nbsp;She&#39;s continuing to meet with one of our program committee in this coffee shop, where I&#39;m doing my day job. &amp;nbsp;I can&#39;t help but listen in a bit. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/05/afsc-program-committee-meeting.html&quot;&gt;I&#39;ll be joining this same committee&lt;/a&gt; for its first formal meeting, now that we&#39;ve recruited our new Regional Director. &amp;nbsp;She&#39;ll be based in SF instead of Seattle, the way Susan was.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/03/temple-to-athena.html&quot;&gt;The neocon ideology&lt;/a&gt; goes on the rocks of hypocrisy quite often, most especially when &quot;the spread of democracy&quot; is proffered as a goal, but then what happens is non-democratically managed permanent cities are dropped in and stuffed with Americans living in slavery (stop-loss) or deliberately escaping from freedom (per Fromm). &amp;nbsp;No, it&#39;s not officially a POW camp (usually), but it&#39;s hardly a democracy, hardly one of &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/07/pets-as-gifts.html&quot;&gt;Disney&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; experimental &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/07/epcot-makeover.html&quot;&gt;prototypes of tomorrow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Case in point: &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/closethebase&quot;&gt;the island of Okinawa&lt;/a&gt; is riddled with non-democracies, which gives Japanese the impression that USAers are nothing but a bunch of Roman soldiers who don&#39;t realize the war is over (lots of jokes at the Romans&#39; expense). &amp;nbsp;Or they think they&#39;re a part of the Fourth Reich or some foolish business (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/09/arabs-gone-wild.html&quot;&gt;stand up comics&lt;/a&gt; are having a field day).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The curriculum is weak and kids graduate with little sense of history. &amp;nbsp;They get sent off to Occupy (one of the bases), and end up thinking, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/10/esozone-talk.html&quot;&gt;Gen. Smedley Butler&lt;/a&gt;, that &quot;war is a racket&quot; and/or some kind of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=7832027&quot;&gt;Business Plot&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;But is it even &lt;i&gt;that &lt;/i&gt;well thought out?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So the best place to focus on improving the curriculum, if the Feds plan to walk their talk, is right there on the bases, where Feds have the most control. &amp;nbsp;Show us how your curriculum is paving the way for a bright future, for the Okinawans included. &amp;nbsp;Don&#39;t just kick the can down the road, like Gen. Colin Powell did, by making militarism the solution for yet another decade.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Getting kids in base schools to report back should not be a problem. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;m sure some enjoy the lifestyle and wouldn&#39;t want it to end. &amp;nbsp;But I&#39;m not saying so-called &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/70136&quot;&gt;Girl Scout Math&lt;/a&gt;&quot; (an operation) &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/12/wanderers-20101229.html&quot;&gt;and the like&lt;/a&gt; has to mean giving up access to airstrips. &amp;nbsp;Small planes would come and go. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The new base wouldn&#39;t be needed, but that was a lavish and unnecessary expense anyway, on the chopping block like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7274911630/in/photostream&quot;&gt;Manas&lt;/a&gt; (easier to chop given it doesn&#39;t belong to the Russians and Kyrgystanis the way Manas does).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5498420758/&quot; title=&quot;Youth Service by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Youth Service&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5218/5498420758_7099733d82.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: old recruiting poster (click for larger view) ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/5738436737370406829/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/5738436737370406829' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5738436737370406829'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5738436737370406829'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/05/juggling-hats.html' title='Juggling Hats'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2265101521062871792</id><published>2012-05-18T10:44:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2012-05-28T00:04:08.856-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Loneliness</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7251756414/&quot; title=&quot;Overcast Day by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Overcast Day&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7211/7251756414_68f85e0684_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;Dr. John Cacioppo was given a highly laudatory introduction by &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/10/civil-rights.html&quot;&gt;Dr. Art Kohn&lt;/a&gt; of Portland State. &amp;nbsp;I ran into Art at &lt;i&gt;Peet&#39;s&lt;/i&gt; recently. &amp;nbsp;He&#39;s a Wanderer like me. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Art made the case that humans suffer more for psychological than technical reasons these days. &amp;nbsp;He saw this as a potential snub to engineers, but I didn&#39;t take it that way. &amp;nbsp;Means we&#39;re doing our job. &amp;nbsp;If your physical needs are being met and your remaining issues are psychological and/or metaphysical, that&#39;s a huge step.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dr. Cacioppo doesn&#39;t exactly draw a mind/brain line like Bucky does, but the same dichotomy between conditioned reflexes on the one hand, and consideration / reflection on the other, bears some similarities, especially where mind-over-brain is concerned i.e. reprogramming or upgrading one&#39;s pattern of responses (or response-abilities).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The empirical studies John has been engaged with over the years have sharpened the focus on &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/10/psychiatry-today.html&quot;&gt;humans as social animals&lt;/a&gt; who tend to waste away when self perceived as cut off from their fellows. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Perceived&quot; because sometimes so-called objective measures of one&#39;s degree of isolation come out differently, and in any case never correlate as closely with diseases and discomforts the way self perceived isolation does. &amp;nbsp;One is one&#39;s own best judge and/or worst enemy in these situations. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Heart attacks are more deadly when induced in lonely rats, he warns.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How to fight back against loneliness? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you&#39;re forced into masking your identity and getting reinforcement for a persona you&#39;re not, that may be alienating. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I felt the absence of philosophy, which used to have more to say about the human condition, before getting run over by computer science. &amp;nbsp;Philosophers would tease apart the many components of loneliness and help build vocabulary, in itself a way of fostering communication and fighting back.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I wanted to ask &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/04/roller-coaster-at-reed.html&quot;&gt;an anthropological question&lt;/a&gt; about ethnicities that accepted communication with the dead. &amp;nbsp;You&#39;re a lot less lonely when you have lots of ancestors to chat with, or at least feel observed by. &amp;nbsp;To what degree are belief systems isolating? &amp;nbsp;Might not &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/01/wanderers-2007123.html&quot;&gt;belief in ghosts&lt;/a&gt; mean less loneliness, greater mental health?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Instead I picked up another thread in anthropology: &amp;nbsp;his recent service to several US Army forts, to help them study and deal with high suicide and depression rates. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Given the way Madison Avenue and others leverage the herd instinct to boost insecurities, with various products the answer, and given wars are sold to the public as products, with the same appeal to our insecurities and worries (nurtured and refined for this purpose), I was wanting some reassurance that he wasn&#39;t just a motivational psychologist in disguise, trying to get soldiers to escape from freedom as dutiful slaves with no minds of their own.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dr. Cacioppo replied that the army was sincere about its concern and responsive to his requirement that all the research stay open and unclassified. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Another questioner asked if he was &quot;embedded&quot; and he demurred, saying that&#39;s not how it was. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The loneliness suffered by insurgents, insurrectionists and subversives, might also be addressed by his trainings (he doesn&#39;t lead them himself and they go for eight hours). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He&#39;s not trying to stop that percentage of humans who buck the herd, deviate from norms, uphold new ethics. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Terry explained I was Quaker, so stereotypically concerned about the treatment of freaks (including peace freaks) and weirdos at the hands of so-called &quot;normal&quot; people (&quot;the herd&quot; to crib from Nietzsche).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Trevor joined me for this event, including the Heathman dinner (where much of this dialog occurred). &amp;nbsp;This was also my birthday dinner (54). &amp;nbsp;The waiters were kind to me, gave me lots to drink (Trevor and I were bussing home anyway, took the 15).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Elizabeth Braithwaite, in the meantime, joined Tara at Cleveland High, to experience debate culture and bid on a cake at silent auction, a fundraiser for the &lt;i&gt;Cleveland Cannibals&lt;/i&gt;. &amp;nbsp;They got me a good one &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/02/neverland-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;from Helen Bernhard&#39;s&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I liked it that Dr. Cacioppo recommended serving food to people in need as a way to enjoy the benefits of community. &amp;nbsp;It&#39;s a two way street in that you get to eat too, on many levels. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/events/290202364406597/&quot;&gt;FNB&lt;/a&gt; has been like that.</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/2265101521062871792/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/2265101521062871792' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2265101521062871792'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2265101521062871792'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/05/loneliness.html' title='Loneliness'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-361359885430672824</id><published>2012-05-08T17:27:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2012-05-08T18:30:27.085-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Segue</title><content type='html'>I continued with the theme below on &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/WittrsEX/message/4807&quot;&gt;the Wittgenstein list&lt;/a&gt; (Sean&#39;s). &amp;nbsp;The Yahoo! archives is as valuable as what&#39;s in any bank vault, from some points of view. &amp;nbsp;Where the word &quot;securities&quot; comes from in some degree: scraps may be treasure, a phone number, a key name.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The distance education world is one I&#39;ve frequented in several roles: &amp;nbsp;current and former high school teacher (back then it was current); contributing editorial consultant with McGraw-Hill; and then more as a lobbyist / reformer / geek about town. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Oregon Curriculum Network grew out of the latter efforts, subsequent to five or so years with CUE (Center for Urban Education).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These days, I provide instruction via distance education circuits, to a faceless crowd. &amp;nbsp;Having everyone veiled, not just the women, and because of technology, not garments, makes this a somewhat different experience. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The narrow bandwidth is nevertheless right where it needs to be, in terms of advancing learners towards their goals. &amp;nbsp;The annual staff meeting is underway. &amp;nbsp;Last night some of us stayed up to watch &lt;i&gt;The Birds&lt;/i&gt; (Hitchcock) which mentions Sebastopol. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Russian River is also nearby (check Google Earth).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The school has its origins in the University of Illinois and Ohio State. &amp;nbsp;Lots of thinking about andragogy and what helps students get real results, led the school&#39;s founders, a core team, to implement a &quot;useractive&quot; approach which emphasizes active (versus passive) engagement. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Active&quot; might just mean typing and mousing around, versus watching videos or taking in text. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Only some disciplines are narrowly focused to this set of skills. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
No, this is &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; appropriate circuitry for all kinds of learning, obviously. &amp;nbsp;That&#39;s why the teachers themselves need to get together in person, in clumps or as an almost complete crew. &amp;nbsp;We did something like this a year ago, and so on going back, though I only joined in the winter of 2010.</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/361359885430672824/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/361359885430672824' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/361359885430672824'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/361359885430672824'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/05/segue.html' title='Segue'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1904084943451826177</id><published>2012-05-05T21:55:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-05-05T21:57:37.897-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Transitions</title><content type='html'>I huddled with parents of other prom goers.&amp;nbsp; We snapped our cameras furiously, capturing these precious moments.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was happy to get to know these people better, even as we come to the end of a chapter. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then I drove to the pharmacy with only seconds to spare.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In my book it&#39;s not sinful to hate the suffering in this world.&amp;nbsp; In this case, hate is a kind of furious fighting back.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A sword of compassion is a sword nonetheless.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A scenario, or time tunnel, is both a tunnel of sorrows, and a tunnel of joys.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Much sadness and grieving is with us at all times.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There is no need to paper over this reality.&amp;nbsp; Why waste energy in denial of what&#39;s real?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Joys are real also.</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/1904084943451826177/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/1904084943451826177' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1904084943451826177'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1904084943451826177'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/05/transitions.html' title='Transitions'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6340924695942549024</id><published>2012-05-01T17:32:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2013-11-15T22:47:36.764-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Beltane</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/04/hb2u-lw.html&quot;&gt;Wittgenstein&lt;/a&gt; actually wrote about Beltane some. &amp;nbsp;Not everyone knows that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He investigated disturbing aspects of the Highlander ritual, finding echoes of pointless cruelty. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
An &quot;echo&quot; need not be interpreted as meaning &quot;from distant times&quot; ala Frazer.&amp;nbsp; These associations have an immediacy in everyday grammar.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
See Brian R. Clack&#39;s &lt;i&gt;Wittgenstein, Frazer and Religion&lt;/i&gt; (Palgrave, 1999), 135-54, Chapter 8: &lt;i&gt;Frazerian Reflections:&amp;nbsp; Wittgenstein on Beltane and Human Sacrifice&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Uncle Bill Lightfoot came by for lunch at &lt;i&gt;Bagdad&lt;/i&gt;. &amp;nbsp;I gave him the Bayard Rustin DVD, &lt;i&gt;Brother Outsider&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Good to see &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/urban-edibles.html&quot;&gt;UE&lt;/a&gt; starting up again (picture below). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve had an engagement with Multnomah Friends to present about AFSC as a part of the Quakers 101 workshop that&#39;s ongoing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I spoke about &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/WdbQKjr9Bu4&quot;&gt;Bayard Rustin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quakerquaker.org/forum/topics/smedley-butler&quot;&gt;Smedley Butler&lt;/a&gt; as two pivotal Friends.&amp;nbsp; The study of their lives will connect many dots, if you&#39;re looking to construct your own reality.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then a fire later. &amp;nbsp;It&#39;s Beltane, after all. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7134775167/in/photostream&quot;&gt;HB2U Trevor&lt;/a&gt;, good to share those cigars.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhjLW0eaKjZZXK6vUP2wjrHIWaA-J8dRU52u-8Rhi4sHf32VoUAXF8ZsQieSQ1Rn9ykTBUT3EhBfSvnw1261RWkGiUbvlJzxd68Exz0XRWQK5ykgMFiF8Cb5MDNCxFGjGVLu0_t/s1600/calagator.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhjLW0eaKjZZXK6vUP2wjrHIWaA-J8dRU52u-8Rhi4sHf32VoUAXF8ZsQieSQ1Rn9ykTBUT3EhBfSvnw1261RWkGiUbvlJzxd68Exz0XRWQK5ykgMFiF8Cb5MDNCxFGjGVLu0_t/s320/calagator.png&quot; width=&quot;282&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6340924695942549024'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6340924695942549024'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/05/beltane.html' title='Beltane'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhjLW0eaKjZZXK6vUP2wjrHIWaA-J8dRU52u-8Rhi4sHf32VoUAXF8ZsQieSQ1Rn9ykTBUT3EhBfSvnw1261RWkGiUbvlJzxd68Exz0XRWQK5ykgMFiF8Cb5MDNCxFGjGVLu0_t/s72-c/calagator.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-9195556203888285299</id><published>2012-04-26T08:58:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-05-26T11:05:28.064-07:00</updated><title type='text'>HB2U LW</title><content type='html'>Paying my respects to Dr. Wittgenstein, a philosopher of strong character and commitment.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://ludwig.squarespace.com/lecture-topics/2012/3/29/026-wittgensteins-psychology-and-idiosyncratic-manner.html&quot;&gt;A really serious guy&lt;/a&gt;, as Sean points out.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
HB2U, from Kirby.&amp;nbsp; PS:&amp;nbsp; here&#39;s some Religious Art FYI, from today:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhhP102BKzEnEdg7MfcMC_RO81AqTLmFCyQr9gwhThzZvARNZ7E7h5UYkT2LVrD0DbITiElyjh16Hzd_frmeGJtBQkzOj44FUrw7Rq3wD6uPXpNKZvEamyH1Yg_TmODqaKpmWA_/s1600/subgenius.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhhP102BKzEnEdg7MfcMC_RO81AqTLmFCyQr9gwhThzZvARNZ7E7h5UYkT2LVrD0DbITiElyjh16Hzd_frmeGJtBQkzOj44FUrw7Rq3wD6uPXpNKZvEamyH1Yg_TmODqaKpmWA_/s640/subgenius.png&quot; width=&quot;352&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/9195556203888285299/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/9195556203888285299' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9195556203888285299'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9195556203888285299'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/04/hb2u-lw.html' title='HB2U LW'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhhP102BKzEnEdg7MfcMC_RO81AqTLmFCyQr9gwhThzZvARNZ7E7h5UYkT2LVrD0DbITiElyjh16Hzd_frmeGJtBQkzOj44FUrw7Rq3wD6uPXpNKZvEamyH1Yg_TmODqaKpmWA_/s72-c/subgenius.png" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5184377634860654715</id><published>2012-04-20T14:13:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-04-20T14:23:56.831-07:00</updated><title type='text'>New Atlantis</title><content type='html'>That&#39;s a heavy-hearted title.&amp;nbsp; Who knew, when they built this city in the forests, made a Stump Town, then Portlandia, that they were building atop jello pudding.&amp;nbsp; Shake time is roughly 300 years mas o meno.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s a sense of the past tense in living here, sweet mortality.&amp;nbsp; As if we&#39;re already gone.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What happened in Japan is haunting as we feel next in line.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/12/forces-of-nature-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;At OMSI&lt;/a&gt; we watched some places in Turkey in the danger zone, a film.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Is this what they call &quot;escapism&quot;?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Is it only an &quot;ism&quot; because it doesn&#39;t really work?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our zip code might shake a little less, being on the Mt. Tabor shield.&amp;nbsp; The local martial arts studio has already reinforced.&amp;nbsp; People take training classes, watch movies of their impending doom.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Life is sweeter in that light, which no doubt accounts for some of the atmosphere.</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/5184377634860654715/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/5184377634860654715' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5184377634860654715'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5184377634860654715'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/04/new-atlantis.html' title='New Atlantis'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3634330508438114396</id><published>2012-04-12T10:29:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2012-04-12T10:36:34.241-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Exit Through the Gift Shop (movie review)</title><content type='html'>I got back from Wanderers to find Lindsey and Melody exulting over this documentary, saying it was right up my ally.&amp;nbsp; I had just been exposed to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CDukCTcITLY&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Drunk History&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; at the meeting and was still reeling from all the fun there, so went upstairs to the Ikea (my mattress -- way better than the pile I had before).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The very next morning though, I was abrim with schemes to view this thing and do work at the same time.&amp;nbsp; An exercise in multi-tasking.&amp;nbsp; I took it to Glenn&#39;s place (it&#39;s a library borrowing).&amp;nbsp; The story was so compelling I had to shut the laptop and just watch.&amp;nbsp; Glenn was highly amused also.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This is a movie about street art.&amp;nbsp; Two of the artists are already in my book collection:&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/05/other-russia.html&quot;&gt;Shepard Fairey&lt;/a&gt; and Ron English.&amp;nbsp; Banksey is here in my blogs as well.&amp;nbsp; So many dots connected, by Mr. Brainwash, the French guy videographer who then joins their ranks as &quot;one of them&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The DVD has great extras but pointedly does not get into &quot;the making of&quot; the main feature, even though much of the feature was about how the film had been made -- up to a point, then we&#39;re left guessing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I learned so much from this film.&amp;nbsp; My thanks to Melody for her &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/03/connected-campaigns.html&quot;&gt;excellent tastes&lt;/a&gt; and information.</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/3634330508438114396/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/3634330508438114396' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3634330508438114396'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3634330508438114396'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/04/exit-through-gift-shop.html' title='Exit Through the Gift Shop (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7435620203542413852</id><published>2012-04-09T17:28:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-04-09T17:32:16.586-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Comic Aside</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg74JLh259e7xcEiko57kUnpFuSPudRPTiSFBeJ13jSoyrAcOYkCrWUYBtPQjG0Jyuw9IplHfX0CNTNIFcv6KkcwqB5am-RoyQcS21zclqO54h2RhGsNrvySvzlItjDvPxuskB1/s1600/sillyquakes.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg74JLh259e7xcEiko57kUnpFuSPudRPTiSFBeJ13jSoyrAcOYkCrWUYBtPQjG0Jyuw9IplHfX0CNTNIFcv6KkcwqB5am-RoyQcS21zclqO54h2RhGsNrvySvzlItjDvPxuskB1/s400/sillyquakes.png&quot; width=&quot;388&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: FaceBook chatter ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgfDuahDzc5YeXvNzelqBe32N2LYjQeaUvnUvFeB7iukZuBDr4bkOzVuNDMX_hw-rOUf-cl2khutWXkEoTCEaUEnngeeSDAJEgrA-0sTKRWMqTJLFBOwnNw8mYBWgLnP01Hfs8l/s1600/sillyquakes0.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgfDuahDzc5YeXvNzelqBe32N2LYjQeaUvnUvFeB7iukZuBDr4bkOzVuNDMX_hw-rOUf-cl2khutWXkEoTCEaUEnngeeSDAJEgrA-0sTKRWMqTJLFBOwnNw8mYBWgLnP01Hfs8l/s400/sillyquakes0.png&quot; width=&quot;330&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: political analysis ::
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/7435620203542413852/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/7435620203542413852' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7435620203542413852'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7435620203542413852'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/04/comedy-club.html' title='Comic Aside'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg74JLh259e7xcEiko57kUnpFuSPudRPTiSFBeJ13jSoyrAcOYkCrWUYBtPQjG0Jyuw9IplHfX0CNTNIFcv6KkcwqB5am-RoyQcS21zclqO54h2RhGsNrvySvzlItjDvPxuskB1/s72-c/sillyquakes.png" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry></feed>