<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1126'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1101&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1151&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1126</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4202433132259291991</id><published>2009-12-09T08:43:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-12-09T08:44:12.934-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Study Group</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4170171652/&quot; title=&quot;Study Group by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2705/4170171652_34b9c9f9fa_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Study Group&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; width=&quot;232&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: paper on mechanics ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ve formed a new triangle twixt &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/ignite-portland.html&quot;&gt;Phil Earnhardt&lt;/a&gt;, the Wanderers and myself (4D guy), for purposes of discussing &quot;chaos mathematics&quot; (in some ways an anagram for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikieducator.org/Casino_Math&quot;&gt;Casino Math&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks to Phil&#39;s cue, we&#39;ve been looking at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The recently recognized failure of predictability in Newtonian dynamics&lt;/span&gt; by Sir James Lighthill F.R.S. of University College London (1986, The Royal Society).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Chaos occurs with a phase change aspect, corresponding in some ways to the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergetics&lt;/span&gt; distinction between Newtonian and non-Newtonian inter-relations between bodies, the latter termed &quot;precessional&quot; in his signature blend (vs. &quot;gravitational&quot; as a perfectly inverse square rule governed co-orbital affair).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These unpredicted and sometimes synergetic behaviors, such as strange attractors, are not forbidden or in violation of the laws of Newtonian Mechanics, is what this paper is about (with an apology on behalf of anyone clueless who says otherwise).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Terry chimed in from the coast, where he&#39;s working on a book, reciting much of his operating thesis.  He&#39;s a lot like Wittgenstein in the way he grinds through various presentation formats, same as me come to think of it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m alluding to a recent thread twixt Sean and SWM regarding LW&#39;s &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Blue and Brown Books&lt;/span&gt; and the role they played, not as drafts of something for publication, but as field manuals for his elite &quot;troops&quot; (first generation Wittgensteinians).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The story of Chaos Mathematics is fascinating and has been developing since at least the 1960s.  It suggests that our seagoing crews may get a 10-15 day horizon for reliable weather prediction, with no way to effectively grow that bubble.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One needn&#39;t reach into quantum mechanics or talk of some Copenhagen interpretation to get all the uncertainty one needs -- in a mathematical sense with real world consequences.  These are macroscopic realities involving suns and planets, not just subatomic particles, albeit the former come with longer predictability horizons w/r to their strangely attractive trajectories.  We have those lunar and solar eclipses mapped out for &lt;a href=&quot;http://eclipse.gsfc.nasa.gov/SEcatmax/SEcatmax.html&quot;&gt;quite a long time&lt;/a&gt; into the future, although with increasing delta T).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4170187854/&quot; title=&quot;Using Gmail by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2720/4170187854_3cf112f388_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Using Gmail&quot; height=&quot;135&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: using gmail ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4202433132259291991'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4202433132259291991'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/12/study-group.html' title='Study Group'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2705/4170171652_34b9c9f9fa_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-9209730161705441435</id><published>2009-12-07T08:00:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2019-03-29T12:01:53.734-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Illiberal Liberals</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
[author&#39;s note:&amp;nbsp; Google decommissioned the knol infrastructure (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knol&quot;&gt;see &lt;i&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The oxymoronic character of my title is a consequence of reading through &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Liberalism&lt;/span&gt; - a knol by Paul.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A &quot;knol&quot; is Google&#39;s invention for &quot;a unit of knowledge&quot; -- not quite the same as a &quot;meme&quot; because potentially more complex.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Paul&#39;s portrayal of the VVD, FDP and PVV parties, the first and last being Dutch, the middle German, suggests Liberalism is anti-diversity, anti-utopian and  anti-Islamic.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Regarding the policies of the PVV party he writes:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Immigration from non-western countries would be banned, as would double nationality. Any foreigner convicted of a crime would be deported. If naturalised, they would be stripped of their Dutch nationality, and then deported. If ethnic-minority children repeatedly commit crimes, then their &lt;i&gt;parents&lt;/i&gt; would be stripped of their Dutch nationality and deported. Moroccan &#39;street terrorists&#39; would be deported on a second conviction regardless of nationality. Speaking any language except Dutch in a government building would be prohibited.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
The semantic tension in the title may stem from seeing business class entrepreneurs as innovative, and yet &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; socio-politically, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; at the level of institution building.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This class of innovator considers the &quot;free market process&quot; the only legitimate driver of social change.  In this model, the entrepreneur responds &quot;freely&quot; to market forces, but is not charged with designing new institutions outside of that market (a job no one should have, too much like central planning, a cardinal sin).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
By this analysis, the attack by some elements on the notion of &quot;corporate personhood&quot; is considered anti-liberal.  Returning to an &quot;artificial persons&quot; model, potentially software-defined, subservient to real (authentic) humans, undermines the dominant ethnic fiction.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Paul points out how the American usage of &quot;liberal&quot; in contrast with &quot;conservative&quot; is somewhat counter-intuitive to a European.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
In most of the world, the term &#39;liberalism&#39; refers to the general ideology described here, and to that type of political movement. That is how it is generally used in political science. In common &lt;b&gt;US usage,&lt;/b&gt; however, it is an antonym of &#39;conservative&#39;, or a synonym for &#39;left&#39;. This is confusing, especially seen from Europe, where liberalism is generally classified with &#39;the right&#39;. From the perspective of history and political science, however, the United States is clearly a liberal society, and its two main political parties are liberal in terms of ideology. In fact the United States is the primary agent of the global expansion of liberal democracy, since 1918.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
In the US context, neocons and libertarians are not that far different, are basically subtypes of liberal by Paul&#39;s analysis.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My inclination is to invoke the notion of &quot;namespaces&quot; (akin to &quot;language games&quot; in Wittgenstein&#39;s philo) in order to distinguish among contexts.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;My&lt;/span&gt; brand of liberalism, stemming from the liberal arts tradition (&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/WittrsAMR/message/828&quot;&gt;Vienna an influence&lt;/a&gt;) and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/11/quaker-politics_110167340290091180.html&quot;&gt;Quaker&lt;/a&gt; concept of &quot;Liberal Friend&quot; is primarily a counter to mono-culture, is a commitment to diversity in a live and let live context (a root meaning of &quot;catholic&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The consequent &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/11/about-secularism.html&quot;&gt;commitment to secularism&lt;/a&gt; is not anti-religion so much as protective of multiple religions (many as yet uninvented) by assuring them shared access to public infrastructure and the levers of power.  A religion may well be non-theistic.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
By my lights, Paul&#39;s liberals are actually illiberal or anti-liberal.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That being said, many secularist liberal arts majors &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; end up as Paul describes, both &lt;a href=&quot;http://knol.google.com/k/paul/nationalism/m3hpd3552jcv/3#&quot;&gt;nationalistic&lt;/a&gt; and triumphantly expansionist in their outlook.  In the US, this is largely a consequence of their being indoctrinated into a &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/some-analysis.html&quot;&gt;military-industrial mindset&lt;/a&gt; with its hallmark &quot;last / only superpower&quot; meme.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3292186750/&quot; title=&quot;World Views by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;World Views&quot; src=&quot;https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3289/3292186750_e0411c448e_m.jpg&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; width=&quot;180&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: new, improved: nation free! ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9209730161705441435'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9209730161705441435'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/12/illiberal-liberals.html' title='Illiberal Liberals'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4777042266189457270</id><published>2009-12-06T10:57:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-12-06T17:44:47.720-08:00</updated><title type='text'>How Radical?</title><content type='html'>In my &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/12/district-standard.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;District Standard?&lt;/span&gt; post&lt;/a&gt; I visually summarized a module I think is long overdue for insertion somewhere in K-12.  Like most math topics, if they&#39;re important at all, it&#39;d crop up here and there, not just once for all time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ve taken the time to invent, in overview form, an entire &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/12/dm-rfc.html&quot;&gt;Digital Math course&lt;/a&gt; in which I&#39;m keen to include said &quot;concentric hierarchy&quot; (above) as a part of what I call Martian Math (because it&#39;s futuristic, also somewhat unfamiliar i.e. alien).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;However, even minus this new way of possibly satisfying Oregon&#39;s three year math requirement (for a high school diploma), isn&#39;t this just standard fare we should expect through our Math Learning Center or any professional body of math teachers (e.g. NCTM, MAA)?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The question is somewhat rhetorical, as the answer is no, this is not heritage our math teachers currently see fit to share.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That&#39;s a bone of contention of course i.e. we&#39;re not all on the same page in accepting this verdict.  I&#39;m teaching math, and my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/&quot;&gt;Oregon Curriculum Network&lt;/a&gt; has been a consistent champion of this material.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My credentials are enough in order to make this not dismissible as the work of a kook, plus this isn&#39;t really just a matter of relying on my own credentials as I come to these ideas through inheritance, am not their primary source.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m not seeing myself as some kind of fringe or marginal figure in suggesting this hole in the curriculum be filled.  I&#39;m seeing myself as being rather conservative and in cahoots with other thoughtful curriculum designers responding to needs in industry and commerce, wanting to have a robust education system, a goal I assume we all share.  At no point have I suggested shoving other important content aside.  Yet we need to make room, need to upgrade pronto.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I actually think we&#39;re paying a really high price for dilly dallying any longer.  This stuff isn&#39;t that hard to talk and write about, coherently.  I challenge us to at least some intelligent debate.  Too much to ask?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Curious to read more?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Maybe you&#39;re a newcomer to these blogs.  Here are some more links for ya:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/iq-test.html&quot;&gt;IQ Test &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/09/focal-points.html&quot;&gt;Focal Points&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4777042266189457270'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4777042266189457270'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/12/how-radical.html' title='How Radical?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7700115921450920397</id><published>2009-12-04T13:14:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-12-07T15:26:59.614-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Some Storytelling</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiY82RlFrcIN4680sP4VjnCEE1ewxrY6VAYpq6HJJeU3yh6Y-YiTQ74E39sz5-rBdh8HCWIHwcrTYTEyAU3JQLKAH9qPwMRKUaKj3RYiQnrHYCkbzDrT4BRnvB3BcWkywkiuucV/s1600-h/Est_The_Steersman_Handbook.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 212px; height: 320px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiY82RlFrcIN4680sP4VjnCEE1ewxrY6VAYpq6HJJeU3yh6Y-YiTQ74E39sz5-rBdh8HCWIHwcrTYTEyAU3JQLKAH9qPwMRKUaKj3RYiQnrHYCkbzDrT4BRnvB3BcWkywkiuucV/s320/Est_The_Steersman_Handbook.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5411495956413039730&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;[ fair use, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Est_The_Steersman_Handbook.JPG&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In retrospect, I&#39;m finding out on Wikipedia about this &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Est:_The_Steersman_Handbook&quot;&gt;science fiction novel&lt;/a&gt; featuring a brand of geek called an &quot;est person&quot;.  These foreshadowed the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/04/cywar-in-cyberia.html&quot;&gt;world dominating types&lt;/a&gt; who came to fame later (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/10/whiteboard-doodles.html&quot;&gt;Stallman&lt;/a&gt;, Torvalds et al), while also inspiring the young Werner Erhard to develop his &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;est&lt;/span&gt;, a training I&#39;ve written about in these blogs before, having &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/12/superman-returns-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;followed Walter Kaufmann&lt;/a&gt; in doing it, then tracking over to Bucky (e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/12/doing-less-with-more.html&quot;&gt;at Madison Square Garden&lt;/a&gt;, read about it in a magazine), a shared point of fascination for both me &#39;n Erhard.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;An &quot;est person&quot; wasn&#39;t necessarily rich I don&#39;t think (I admit to not reading the book yet) but had a code of ethics one might characterize as philanthropic, loyal to humans.  That was a theme in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;est&lt;/span&gt;: going from disloyalty to loyalty towards being human was a feasible outcome and was discussed explicitly (philosophically).  Misanthropists might reform, which doesn&#39;t mean transform into secular humanists necessarily, like I stayed a Quaker throughout the process, while others stayed with other stuff.  This wasn&#39;t a swap meet, where you got to trade stuff a lot (mostly the trainer got the floor, though it mostly wasn&#39;t a monologue -- except when it was).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Who gets the luxury to study these stories anyway?  I wish my journalism was better compensated (sigh), if that&#39;s what we call this.  Quakers keep journals by tradition and in this day and age, that means keeping a journal on-line if you dare (many do).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So by that thinking, I really shouldn&#39;t be peddling my blogs as a source of income (it&#39;s a religious practice).  Hire me to train your teachers, is what I suggest, or let &#39;em test out (not saying I&#39;m a gatekeeper so much as an efficient communicator of some basics worth sharing with others).  That&#39;s what I was doing in Chicago this year, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/03/urner-workshop.html&quot;&gt;delivering a workshop&lt;/a&gt; at a Pycon.  I don&#39;t know if I&#39;ll make it to the one in Singapore but given cyberspace and our new way of doing posters (thanks to Vern Ceder, Steve Holden et al), I think that&#39;s a matter of secondary importance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What happened to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/08/lookin-good.html&quot;&gt;the old IS&lt;/a&gt; in Makati then?  Did they tear it down? (Yakking about Manila again).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7700115921450920397'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7700115921450920397'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/12/some-storytelling.html' title='Some Storytelling'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiY82RlFrcIN4680sP4VjnCEE1ewxrY6VAYpq6HJJeU3yh6Y-YiTQ74E39sz5-rBdh8HCWIHwcrTYTEyAU3JQLKAH9qPwMRKUaKj3RYiQnrHYCkbzDrT4BRnvB3BcWkywkiuucV/s72-c/Est_The_Steersman_Handbook.JPG" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-851152050152452928</id><published>2009-12-03T16:30:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2013-09-19T00:05:06.621-07:00</updated><title type='text'>4D Studios on Myspace</title><content type='html'>If when you go to Myspace.com/4Dstudios, all you see is this...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjXrkmxK8gHiPsFmClPHdq6GrN9idH6Pov6gxo7tjPBM0MfRXQXUlL2EpsAmv_HI9uDwcOdYWb-Z4p4WFwmZByuPz2z0f807RW6ZYA3YiD9MOhSnuMqkCwd7fBsS0GVXa2rSuVN/s1600-h/myspace9.png&quot; onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5411092974012937314&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjXrkmxK8gHiPsFmClPHdq6GrN9idH6Pov6gxo7tjPBM0MfRXQXUlL2EpsAmv_HI9uDwcOdYWb-Z4p4WFwmZByuPz2z0f807RW6ZYA3YiD9MOhSnuMqkCwd7fBsS0GVXa2rSuVN/s320/myspace9.png&quot; style=&quot;cursor: pointer; display: block; height: 257px; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; width: 320px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;lite view&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
and not this...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgUhvvos-vHQROHqe1-wO5Fv7xbiamSlvWn8wwZZR75rUWxSmPx_koh-ul2i65PVHXpWztiGjzug6R2IHcrzziJZiJIMU-TXnAIdTnK-UOHrYrTBq_Qa-z1b60f1C2TlQWm0GoH/s1600-h/myspace8.png&quot; onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5411092883351860514&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgUhvvos-vHQROHqe1-wO5Fv7xbiamSlvWn8wwZZR75rUWxSmPx_koh-ul2i65PVHXpWztiGjzug6R2IHcrzziJZiJIMU-TXnAIdTnK-UOHrYrTBq_Qa-z1b60f1C2TlQWm0GoH/s320/myspace8.png&quot; style=&quot;cursor: pointer; display: block; height: 257px; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; width: 320px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;full view&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
... then look for a Full versus Lite View control on the upper right.  If you don&#39;t find that, try a different browser like Chrome to see if there&#39;s a difference, and/or dump a Myspace cookie that&#39;s keeping your view Lite.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Here are the video clips currently embedded in my profile:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;CSN Esoterica&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt; by 4D Studios&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;344&quot; width=&quot;425&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/CPNhLpeK6-o&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/CPNhLpeK6-o&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;344&quot; width=&quot;425&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
An early pilot developed for &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Coffee Shops Network&lt;/span&gt;, for sharing some geometrical information of special interest to our self schooling clientèle.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;Darwin at Home&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt; by Gerald de Jong&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/0RpQ1MsjZJ8?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This is a video of animations of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Darwin at Home&lt;/span&gt; creatures which result from survival of the fittest and random mutation.  Narrative by Gerald de Jong the author of the software behind the project.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;Lindsey Walker at Angelo&#39;s&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;344&quot; width=&quot;425&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/Bj-oPP1lcm0&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/Bj-oPP1lcm0&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;344&quot; width=&quot;425&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Candid outtakes from one of several diverse venues frequented by a rising star from 97214, keeping Portland weird (strong, edgy). Check Friends list for link.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;A mathcast by Russell Towle&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;344&quot; width=&quot;425&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/_Bl91r8DOl8&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/_Bl91r8DOl8&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;344&quot; width=&quot;425&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Russell Towle (1949 - 2008) was a mathcaster of high caliber, adding magnificently to our shared metaphysical treasure chest.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;Electronic Behavior Control System&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt; by EBN&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/GRj7-Ymrh5E?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A video from EBN&#39;s 1995 album &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Telecommunication Breakdown&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;Kirby Addresses Wanderers&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/DXQ9cxWz8JI?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I delivered this talk about design science, Buckminster Fuller etc. sometime soon after the movie &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Die Another Day&lt;/span&gt; was released first run in local Portland malls, years before this posting to Google Archive in 2005 (November).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;Mathematics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt; by The Nobility&lt;/span&gt; (formerly JetPack):&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/7bltdboohZI?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Mathematics&lt;/span&gt; music video.  From the EP &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Art of Building a Moat&lt;/span&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/851152050152452928'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/851152050152452928'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/12/private-language.html' title='4D Studios on Myspace'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjXrkmxK8gHiPsFmClPHdq6GrN9idH6Pov6gxo7tjPBM0MfRXQXUlL2EpsAmv_HI9uDwcOdYWb-Z4p4WFwmZByuPz2z0f807RW6ZYA3YiD9MOhSnuMqkCwd7fBsS0GVXa2rSuVN/s72-c/myspace9.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3972320401016681687</id><published>2009-12-02T09:17:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-12-02T09:40:59.871-08:00</updated><title type='text'>DM RFC</title><content type='html'>RFC is Internetese for &quot;request for comments&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I figured I&#39;d start a new debating process on math-teach so math teachers could more fully express their reservations regarding the digital math track (DM) I&#39;ve been laying out for inspection &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikieducator.org/Digital_Math&quot;&gt;on Wikieducator&lt;/a&gt; and places.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So far, we&#39;ve had &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=6918691&amp;amp;tstart=0#reply-tree&quot;&gt;a lively thread&lt;/a&gt;.  I&#39;ve been in conversation with these people for a long time (Lou, Haim, Wayne... Michael, Hansen more recently).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Most high schools today are teaching what I&#39;d call analog math (AM).  There&#39;s an ancient tension twixt analog and digital, continuous and discrete, perpetuated in our talk about the high energy particle that is also a wave. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks to the advent of digital computers starting around the mid-1900s and their subsequent personalization and semi-ubiquity, DM is making more inroads, changing the character of what&#39;s on tap.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sunny day in Portland, lots of chauffeuring to do.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3972320401016681687'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3972320401016681687'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/12/dm-rfc.html' title='DM RFC'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2606521751969162618</id><published>2009-11-29T15:05:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-12-04T21:10:22.600-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Back in the Saddle</title><content type='html'>Yes it&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/01/quiet-first-day.html&quot;&gt;a First Day&lt;/a&gt; and so in theory I shouldn&#39;t be working.  However, yesterday, Saturday (Seventh Day) was pure entertainment:  an easy drive from closer to Canada along I-5, and time with Matt and Lindsey watching Michael Hagmeier and his band, opening for a really good Blues bunch.  This was at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Roots&lt;/span&gt; on 7th in their bigger venue.  Oh yeah, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/11/galumphing-back.html&quot;&gt;I cut my face&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So today I need to keep getting it out there, lobbying to upgrade Earthling Math with something more palatable, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/spice-trade.html&quot;&gt;spiced up a bunch&lt;/a&gt;, like with a little &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Dave&#39;s Insanity Sauce&lt;/span&gt; (a popular kitchen condiment in this household, in small doses).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/10/playing-with-blocks.html&quot;&gt;T-modules&lt;/a&gt; seem boring to you, that&#39;s probably because we don&#39;t have a lot of good quality geometry animations about them yet, much as I&#39;ve been agitating for same for commercial purposes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We also have the E modules with h=1, really close to T&#39;s radius 0.99948333226... &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2009-November/009678.html&quot;&gt;as computed by Python&lt;/a&gt; just now and obtained by scaling &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/11/re-k-mods-etc.html&quot;&gt;phi/root2&lt;/a&gt;, which latter radius gives us &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/10/nclb-polyhedron-memo.html&quot;&gt;a rhombic triacontahedron&lt;/a&gt; of 7.5 (in tetravolumes).  That&#39;s what&#39;s showing in the screen shots below.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So here&#39;s a little Show &amp;amp; Tell with links to the cited graphics for more background, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/python/tmod.py&quot;&gt;also source code&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEghzw-PM7xu2IWTqCRmid3X5pOeeIKwKTiGaq8Oq_VEDJOmWyWt7hhe16HCcSfl1RB5j_quNlIIFa4g4y6VmuORr9PgwBb4pz_BEKIU-qTE-W_188vt5v0N_NrwPSztlp6GxBwr/s1600/tmod3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 400px; height: 364px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEghzw-PM7xu2IWTqCRmid3X5pOeeIKwKTiGaq8Oq_VEDJOmWyWt7hhe16HCcSfl1RB5j_quNlIIFa4g4y6VmuORr9PgwBb4pz_BEKIU-qTE-W_188vt5v0N_NrwPSztlp6GxBwr/s400/tmod3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5409684869794181026&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;font-size:85%;&quot; &gt;&lt;span&gt;:: lengths AC, BC, OC from linked &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/synergetics/s09/figs/f86411a.html&quot;&gt;figure &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/synergetics/s09/figs/f86411a.html&quot;&gt;986.411A&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt; ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEj0w0oCBFfdD-EsAoX8ATBPJaxjlvAouVKq2FuM8398zsDEp8ogM5S_QDl0x01UiQr8G8Tsf0lObezfqKF9HikqRSW9ZAEd8ug6kmbbkRjQeooDZn7X_HP-cDhXiDIQ3IPcHLVc/s1600/tmod2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 400px; height: 170px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEj0w0oCBFfdD-EsAoX8ATBPJaxjlvAouVKq2FuM8398zsDEp8ogM5S_QDl0x01UiQr8G8Tsf0lObezfqKF9HikqRSW9ZAEd8ug6kmbbkRjQeooDZn7X_HP-cDhXiDIQ3IPcHLVc/s400/tmod2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5409667750130468562&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: using Python&#39;s Decimal type, setting context to 31 digits ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgvF1nRLrJX7BB2_QrkL-16PFQ4mkukUggEQOGEbUs8pQVU5HEuMOU1mUFy8qVauN4iqxsov1RX1z24z9hE5WySRdDcrw8Vc4FySwlNevgBQj9cmx4jJMxoia8hh7B9Qyoa0RwE/s1600/tmod4.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 387px; height: 400px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgvF1nRLrJX7BB2_QrkL-16PFQ4mkukUggEQOGEbUs8pQVU5HEuMOU1mUFy8qVauN4iqxsov1RX1z24z9hE5WySRdDcrw8Vc4FySwlNevgBQj9cmx4jJMxoia8hh7B9Qyoa0RwE/s400/tmod4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5409984308690385394&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: T-mod plane net &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4147429781/sizes/o/&quot;&gt;using turtle.py&lt;/a&gt; in Python 3.1 (WinXP) ::&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgb3a2jCDQ_xa7r59nkmHzv6DWu-Hu0-GCNm-gZV5cnhvaZq7BjL-8hADV0tzG8Ws5XO7wkqDo5SSGcHdEpiSrmTtqUjLux55OVJlTPntOUbdfcRBgGxU3PZQJhl2mDJ8xIiL65/s1600/tmod5.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 400px; height: 311px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgb3a2jCDQ_xa7r59nkmHzv6DWu-Hu0-GCNm-gZV5cnhvaZq7BjL-8hADV0tzG8Ws5XO7wkqDo5SSGcHdEpiSrmTtqUjLux55OVJlTPntOUbdfcRBgGxU3PZQJhl2mDJ8xIiL65/s400/tmod5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5409986242331398418&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: controlling a &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2009-November/009682.html&quot;&gt;standard library turtle&lt;/a&gt; ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cited Figures:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/synergetics/s09/figs/f86210.html&quot;&gt;Synergetics Constant&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/synergetics/s09/figs/f86411a.html&quot;&gt;986.411A T-Mod Edges&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/synergetics/s09/figs/f86411b.html&quot;&gt;986.411B T-Mod Angles&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2606521751969162618'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2606521751969162618'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/back-in-saddle.html' title='Back in the Saddle'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEghzw-PM7xu2IWTqCRmid3X5pOeeIKwKTiGaq8Oq_VEDJOmWyWt7hhe16HCcSfl1RB5j_quNlIIFa4g4y6VmuORr9PgwBb4pz_BEKIU-qTE-W_188vt5v0N_NrwPSztlp6GxBwr/s72-c/tmod3.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-810370847721743026</id><published>2009-11-27T11:41:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2009-11-28T11:34:11.251-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Post Thanksgiving</title><content type='html'>Mirage hasn&#39;t been off her feet in like four months, even when sleeping.  Today she lay down and dozed off, lots of twitching.  Mirage is an adult female horse.  I am off of I-5 enjoying staying with our casino boss and horse masseuse family.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Casino_Math&quot;&gt;Casino Math&lt;/a&gt; balances &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Supermarket_Math&quot;&gt;Supermarket Math&lt;/a&gt; in providing a special case institution for anchoring generic math concepts.  We get inside the business of X, as a way of learning math associated with doing X&#39;s job.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We might have gone with Banking Math but that takes some of the edge off, is less nakedly suggestive of our probability themes, lacks the entertainment value to compete on today&#39;s TV.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Supermarket_Math&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Supermarket Math&lt;/a&gt; is prosaic enough.  Too prosaic? We might have said Mall Math.  Bazaar Math could be good (yes, opposite Cathedral Math perhaps).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mirage is back on her feet, pacing about in her paddock.  I&#39;m not far from Camano Island, where I met up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/10/roz-savage.html&quot;&gt;Roz Savage&lt;/a&gt; that time, a day and some years ago.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tribes in this region were suffering homelessness, were in need of methadone clinics.  Today, many more are in line for academic degrees.  The casinos have provided the modicum of prosperity needed to jump start other enterprises, will continue to provide seed funding.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another theme of &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Casino_Math&quot;&gt;Casino Math&lt;/a&gt; is that what goes on under that heading (of risk taking or gambling) is not a constant, despite the persistence of old favorites.  Not only do the games themselves change, but so does their ostensible purpose.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3560666108/&quot;&gt;Many USA states&lt;/a&gt; use a lottery to fund some of their education and prison systems.   Many churches use bingo.  The tribes are no different in this respect.  Indian gaming is about playing world game effectively, and that&#39;s not a bad thing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One axis for further development involves pushing the decision-making to a more democratic micro-level, letting anyone register their philanthropic model by donating proceeds (one&#39;s winnings) to worthy causes (registered beneficiaries).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&quot;Approved causes&quot; doesn&#39;t necessarily exclude one&#39;s self (the traditional worthy in old school casinos) but also allows character building in the sense of investing in the qualities and traits of one&#39;s avatar.  Play your heart out to raise funds for your school, not just yourself personally, and win more kudos thereby.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For readers just joining and wondering WTF, I am referring to some modules on WikiEducator:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Martian_Math&quot;&gt;Martian Math&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Neolithic_Math&quot;&gt;Neolithic Math&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Casino_Math&quot;&gt;Casino Math&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Supermarket_Math&quot;&gt;Supermarket Math&lt;/a&gt;.   One may envision this as a tetrahedron of six relationships and then discuss each of these relationships.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In this blog post, I&#39;m mostly harping on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=6915098&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;the Casino-Supermarket edge&lt;/a&gt;, being defensive about my choice of &quot;Casino&quot; by providing some historical context (a &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Neolithic_Math&quot;&gt;Neolithic Math&lt;/a&gt; spin).  I&#39;m also reintroducing my Coffee Shops Network &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/03/open-source.html&quot;&gt;open source business model&lt;/a&gt;, which revolves around philanthropic game playing in a relaxed ambiance.</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/810370847721743026/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/810370847721743026' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/810370847721743026'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/810370847721743026'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/post-thanksgiving.html' title='Post Thanksgiving'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2538520369932428847</id><published>2009-11-24T19:55:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2009-11-25T22:52:59.093-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Parent Teacher Conferences</title><content type='html'>This would normally be a Wanderers post, especially given Keith Lofstrom is doing a formal presentation on ServerSky, much more polished since &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/03/psychometrics-today.html&quot;&gt;the last time&lt;/a&gt; we saw it.  However, I was at parent teacher conferences at Cleveland this evening, came in to a packed house.  Rather than disturb the assembled (except for a glass of wine), I planted myself in the pantry, or whatever we call this room between... Don just summoned me to the &quot;great hall&quot; again.  Keith&#39;s pictures shore are purty.  LW can fill me in later (she&#39;s an engineer, been here the whole time with a front row seat).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Regarding PT conferences, I found myself consumed with jealousy, as the State of Oregon has seen fit to make use of the talents of my comrades.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/&quot;&gt;My stuff&lt;/a&gt;, on the other hand, is &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/incomprehensible.html&quot;&gt;too avant-garde&lt;/a&gt;&quot; even though it&#39;s like 30 years late, overdue.  I paid into the system as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/&quot;&gt;a for-profit business&lt;/a&gt;, using my surplus to develop Oregon Curriculum Network (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/cp4e.html&quot;&gt;OCN&lt;/a&gt;), to brainstorm Coffee Shops Network (&lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;CSN&lt;/a&gt;), but both are too esoteric apparently, too hard to understand.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Geometry and philosophy just don&#39;t cut it with the masses anymore.  We&#39;ve all got better things to do.  From each according to his ability, but not if he&#39;s a &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;teacher&lt;/span&gt; (sneer), not a &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/11/ieee-presentation.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;dymaxion didact&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, oh no.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That being said, I immediately got better insight&#39;s into my daughter&#39;s world.  I was grateful for this and said so repeatedly.  As a dad, I&#39;m not trying to remain aloof in any way.  If I seem passive and distant, I&#39;m sure it&#39;s because I&#39;m preoccupied about some grand strategy.  Today it&#39;s Wikieducator and a possible geodesic dome class (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikieducator.org/Martian_Math&quot;&gt;Martian Math&lt;/a&gt;) at Reed College (Trevor?).  Tomorrow... consulting my over the horizon radar.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2538520369932428847'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2538520369932428847'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/parent-teacher-conferences.html' title='Parent Teacher Conferences'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7901556605350942288</id><published>2009-11-23T18:03:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-11-23T21:17:51.066-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Secret Honor (movie review)</title><content type='html'>This is a one-actor monologue, in that sense highly reminscent of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/12/its-show-time.html&quot;&gt;the D.W. Jacobs play&lt;/a&gt;, going on here in Portland around this time last year, with Bucky played by Doug Tompos.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In this Robert Altman directed version, Philip Baker Hall delivers a paroxysmal almost epileptic performance, a Nixon of inter-connected seizures, of complexes.  America has really wrought itself one helluva native son this time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The contrast with the Bucky character (also fictive) is pretty obvious, but then New England Brahmans were Nixon&#39;s arch nemeses right?  He brought more of that Havana-Vegas crime boss sheen to his office, given whom he looked up to (&lt;a href=&quot;http://foia.fbi.gov/foiaindex/rebozo_charles_g.htm&quot;&gt;Bebe Rebozo&lt;/a&gt; and like that).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This rendition of Nixon is hilariously confused about recording equipment; he&#39;s in over his head with technology right from the get go.  He&#39;s always asking the off-screen Roberto to erase this or that confession or outburst, and yet the security camera is rolling the whole time and he&#39;s on candid camera.  There&#39;s something transparent about a man who tries so hard to cover up.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What a fascinating period, even when &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/01/assassination-of-richard-nixon-movie.html&quot;&gt;presented as fiction&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7901556605350942288'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7901556605350942288'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/secret-honor-movie-review.html' title='Secret Honor (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8315450327275482521</id><published>2009-11-20T07:46:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2021-07-18T11:03:26.581-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Ignite Portland</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157622719474211&quot; title=&quot;Ignite Portland 7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/2768/4120824520_9d94435b37.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Ignite Portland 7&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: ignite portland 7 ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Ignite&lt;/span&gt; events occur in Boulder, Denver, Fort Collins, Phoenix, likely some others I&#39;m forgetting, besides here in Portland, at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Bagdad&lt;/span&gt;. Budapest, other places in Europe.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Phil Earnhardt was &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/11/kudos-or-karma.html&quot;&gt;our company MVP&lt;/a&gt;, 4D Studios his first stop off the 75 bus. He&#39;s somewhat the anthropologist of this &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Ignite&lt;/span&gt; phenomenon and had interesting insights regarding recipes for success. Mainly (and I paraphrase): if it doesn&#39;t all anchor to one solo individual, then personality conflicts, though sure to happen, won&#39;t have as much impact on the final result, which will be more sustainable and magical precisely because it&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/08/elitism.html&quot;&gt;a Ouija Board&lt;/a&gt; (i.e. there&#39;s no one in charge).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That being said, though anarchist, this &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Ignite&lt;/span&gt; was tightly choreographed, with speaker wranglers designated to keep the workflow flowing. The Lightning Talk format was strictly held to. Our &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/11/think-tank-techniques.html&quot;&gt;experiments at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Duke&#39;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, in varying the segments, adding music tracks, need these more structured events for context and contrast. Phil&#39;s words for our Portland brand mix: authentic and eclectic. I would concur.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Presentations: I won&#39;t recount them all, except to say none of them fell flat. Some were spiritual journeys: an escape from a cultic gravity well, memories of &lt;a href=&quot;http://blip.tv/file/2875122&quot;&gt;a long lost friend&lt;/a&gt;, realizations from a hospitalization. When another pretty person takes the microphone, you won&#39;t guess she&#39;s been an anthropologist in Papua New Guinea, has a taste for road kill, wants to share about that doe, in an engaging and completely canderous manner. Phil&#39;s talk was on robot motion. He&#39;s of the school that musculo-skeletal matters have a &quot;tensegrity&quot; aspect and twitters as @FloatingBones.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Of course &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tensegrity&quot;&gt;tensegrity&lt;/a&gt;&quot; is considered a &quot;fringe word&quot; in many vocabs (namespaces), even though it has clear meaning in the art world, where &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/11/linus-pauling-in-news.html&quot;&gt;Kenneth Snelson&lt;/a&gt; staked turf. Another domain is architecture, where floating compression is a recognized technology. Micro-architecture, e.g. cellular, is more Ingber&#39;s domain, per a past cover of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Scientific American&lt;/span&gt;. Then you have those focused on the spinal chord, on movement, which gets us more into First Person Physics the way I think of it, or into Carlos Castaneda country by another route. Extrapolating a more graceful kind of robot motion, with tension notched up, isn&#39;t too off the wall sounding, is already a hot topic for mathcasts per Gerald de Jong&#39;s Darwin @ Home clips (embedded below).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One of the talks, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blip.tv/file/2875272&quot;&gt;by Marcus&lt;/a&gt;, had a lot on expectant waiting, or active waiting, a way of engaging with the world common to many disciplines. He wasn&#39;t citing the Quakers specifically, but wasn&#39;t unfamiliar with them either (we talked after).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We were encouraged to photograph, shoot video, and to tag our media IP7 (as this was Portland&#39;s seventh such event).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What I take away from this is: Show &amp;amp; Tell, a classroom exercise a lot of us got to practice growing up, is as important as ever. Today, show and tell involves slides, projected content. There&#39;s a darkened room much of the time. When we&#39;re outdoors, in the bright light of day, we have other formats less reliant on projection. LCDs as dashboard control panels (e.g. embedded in cameras, ATVs) still make an appearance. Add a smattering of XOs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I chauffeured Phil back to his hotel by way of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Circadia&lt;/span&gt;, corner of 47th and NE Columbia, though we didn&#39;t pull over, no &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/10/burn-out.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Burn Out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; this evening. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Back Stage&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Bagdad&lt;/span&gt; had a lot of great conversation during the informal gathering following &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Ignite&lt;/span&gt;. Bram (fonts fanatic), &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/08/oscon-2005-tutorial-day-one.html&quot;&gt;Randal Schwartz&lt;/a&gt; (Perl cruiser), Ward Cunningham (&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/06/gnu-math-on-synergeo.html&quot;&gt;wiki guy&lt;/a&gt;)... lotsa luminaries, lotsa omnidirectional halos. Some adjourned to the eatery trucks around 12th and Hawthorne.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the mean time, Tara was out with Elizabeth Braithwaite while mom was patched in to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/07/2nd-life-2nd-world.html&quot;&gt;the 2nd world&lt;/a&gt; and Lindsey was chompin&#39; on more Chomsky on some studio monitor (many miles of video).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8315450327275482521'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8315450327275482521'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/ignite-portland.html' title='Ignite Portland'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5328483048404820054</id><published>2009-11-17T20:43:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-11-17T20:54:23.348-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Spice Trade</title><content type='html'>By &quot;spice trade&quot; I refer to something positive, namely our bid to up the IQ around our spanking new C.P. Snow chasm-spanning curriculum.  Getting the right wiring takes time, as we test the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/01/physics-update.html&quot;&gt;various subsystems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To &quot;spice it up&quot; means to &quot;kick it up&quot; i.e. &quot;to take it up a notch&quot;.  These are idioms associated with adding more hot sauce to make a dish less bland.  Another idea is you don&#39;t need a lot.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5328483048404820054'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5328483048404820054'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/spice-trade.html' title='Spice Trade'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2935821104091611187</id><published>2009-11-16T02:30:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-11-16T11:05:30.969-08:00</updated><title type='text'>The World Without US (movie review)</title><content type='html'>Inspired neocon nuttiness; don&#39;t forget to watch the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1223900/&quot;&gt;Latin America bonus&lt;/a&gt;, complete with commie takeover.</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/2935821104091611187/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/2935821104091611187' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2935821104091611187'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2935821104091611187'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/world-without-us-movie-review.html' title='The World Without US (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3837211641407899613</id><published>2009-11-15T23:45:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-11-16T11:34:01.209-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Rethinking Afghanistan (movie review)</title><content type='html'>This documentary, directed by Robert Greenwald, ends on an upbeat note, showing how international aid organizations, doctors without border types, are making a positive difference in Afghanistan.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/05/carrier-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;The LAWCAP puppet&lt;/a&gt; (or so-called USA (see &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Grunch of Giants&lt;/span&gt;)) has completely lost the war for hearts and minds, has no hope of victory whatsoever (not news).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3837211641407899613'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3837211641407899613'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/rethinking-afghanistan-movie-review.html' title='Rethinking Afghanistan (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3815212233154378096</id><published>2009-11-13T15:43:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-11-14T09:52:58.670-08:00</updated><title type='text'>The Spook Who Sat By the Door (movie review)</title><content type='html'>This &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0070726/&quot;&gt;1973 classic&lt;/a&gt; came with a thumbs up from Dominic and I can see why.  Not only do we get a kind of &quot;aggressive response&quot; movie, as the analyst introducing it suggests (he&#39;s giving background about the book version) but we get a sneak peak at this CIA business, a chummy frat house having problems integrating, succumbing to political pressure.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Freeman, poetically so named, is forever being told he&#39;s a credit to his race, as he rises through the ranks in the copying facility, duplicating state secrets.  He feels some frustration with the glacial pace of change, which dino guy says&#39;ll be for 10K years or something geological.  So he goes back to Chicago to use his CIA skills to incite his old gang, now a generation into shooting pool and floating hookers.  Freeman fits right in and before ya know it, all hell breaks loose.  The point being:  you white guys had better figure out what to do around spooks in the paramilitary.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The movie is kind of old.  Fast forward and it&#39;s not about breaking the color barrier so much as ending the &quot;fraternity&quot; mindset.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/alt.politics.org.cia/msg/4f6417a62000e1a5?pli=1&quot;&gt;Lindsay Moran&lt;/a&gt; has much more to work with, including a more bucolic training grounds, not just the urban game of dodge &#39;em, which this movie explores.  There&#39;s still lots of bomb making, getting the wires right.  Freeman has interesting skills, succeeds in scoring a lot of recruits.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the real world, you had an epidemic of drug scandals involving Central America, with DCI Deutch showing up in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/12/quaker-business.html&quot;&gt;that LA high school&lt;/a&gt; to confront parents over the issue, not wanting his agency to take any guff for these Rambo crack heads.  He&#39;d been like an MIT prez or something, was more into &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;One Laptop per Child&lt;/span&gt; type thinking &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/03/stress-tests.html&quot;&gt;ala G1G1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But Freeman couldn&#39;t be expected to know any of this (he&#39;s not some kind of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/02/incredibles-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Incredible&lt;/a&gt;, looks stupid doing judo), didn&#39;t get much overseas experience, had never seen the inside of any Banana Republic besides his own and Langley&#39;s bright whites&#39;.  All that being said, he&#39;s a smart operative and this movie probably did end up helping with integration, anticipating the later removal of any glass ceiling.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m one and a half times through, as I caught myself dosing off a few times during fight scenes, needed to go back.  I admire the small budget, clever dialog.  More attention deserved, when you&#39;ve got time to &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/alt.politics.org.cia/msg/d306769d8a09b52a?hl=en&quot;&gt;come in from the cold&lt;/a&gt; and watch stupid spy movies (a term of endearment you understand).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3815212233154378096'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3815212233154378096'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/spook-who-sat-by-door-movie-review.html' title='The Spook Who Sat By the Door (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8854235430068050202</id><published>2009-11-12T10:49:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2011-10-27T18:16:58.030-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Game Night</title><content type='html'>Sometimes when Quakers want to share juice (coffee, whatever) they huddle around folding tables and play board games long into the night (maybe even to &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/01/random-trip-pix.html&quot;&gt;Quaker midnight&lt;/a&gt;, about 9 PM on the USA west coast).  Yes, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Monopoly&lt;/span&gt; is such a game, but I suspect they&#39;re playing something rather more clever, such as &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Scotland Yard&lt;/span&gt;, or &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Stratego&lt;/span&gt;, or even &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Chess&lt;/span&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Chess&lt;/span&gt; you say?  Isn&#39;t that a war game?  Are Quakers hypocrites then (snicker, sneer)?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ever since our Alternatives to Violence Program (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/02/avp-again.html&quot;&gt;AVP&lt;/a&gt;) embraced &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/10/random-thoughts.html&quot;&gt;computer games&lt;/a&gt; in some editions, I&#39;ve had an easier time explaining how metaphorical violence still falls under the heading of &quot;not using outward weapons&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/03/high-school-melodrama.html&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mercutio and Tibalt&lt;/a&gt; have their face-down on Facebook, playing &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Mafia Wars&lt;/span&gt;, don&#39;t &quot;take it outside&quot; in a blood and guts kind of way, too messy for real theater.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The audience doesn&#39;t seem to mind that the actors get up and live to act again another day.  Since Greek times, we&#39;ve gotten away with that, although some &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/05/defending-homeland.html&quot;&gt;Roman audiences&lt;/a&gt; got greedy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of board games, what about games with playing cards? &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2009-November/009639.html&quot;&gt;Like &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Wa&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for example (sarcasm)? Do Quakers smoke, drink and play poker then?  Chuckle.  &quot;What kind of religion is that?&quot; asks the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Church Lady&lt;/span&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you&#39;re &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/07/more-on-usa-os.html&quot;&gt;a Puritan&lt;/a&gt;, then maybe the whole idea of religion for you is &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/12/repeal-day.html&quot;&gt;to prohibit stuff&lt;/a&gt;, prove your soul is saved by how you&#39;re able to avoid the temptations, which include just about everything except reading the Bible while rocking back and forth and muttering curses.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As a matter of fact, many Quakers consider smoking an unhealthy, nasty habit, don&#39;t need to blow a lot of money on expensive drugs and alcohol (unless you count fine wines and cheeses... and chocolate), and always lose at poker on principle, and so won&#39;t play (wisely, saves pennies).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Quakers in &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/11/about-branding.html&quot;&gt;our Pacific Rim clime&lt;/a&gt; have been known to shake and shuffle the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/67015&quot;&gt;Mahjong tiles&lt;/a&gt; quite a bit, lots of clicky noises.  I&#39;ve played that in the Philippines and would consider it identical to a playing card game.  Indeed, playing cards are no more than a poor man&#39;s Mahjong chips.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So by this (dubious?) reasoning, yes, it is obvious to me that our &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Faith &amp;amp; Practice&lt;/span&gt; permits the use of playing cards, though only in moderation and not while wearing too much mustache wax or lipstick (there&#39;s what I&#39;d call a bias against cosmetics, if not an outright prohibition -- more about banking on natural beauty and saving pennies, less about moral condemnation of those who &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; happen to love tattooing themselves (which some Quakers have done (though sometimes only discreetly))).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of game nights, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.myspace.com/4dstudios&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;4D Studios&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; set up at E-Room on Division last night, where the main hall is sometimes given over to bingo or whatever.  LW did her podcast recording from the anteroom, a busy enough venue where customers have some screens to ogle at as well (our first TV ad?).  She got through the whole thing on one pint, saving the 2nd for schmoozing.  Sometimes, with enough vodka, even &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Freedom Train&lt;/span&gt; derails, however tonight was not about goofing off.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I took in the final minutes of the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Blazers&lt;/span&gt; game in Minneapolis right before show time, a victory for Portland&#39;s team, then read the interview with Gorbachev in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Nation&lt;/span&gt;, before queuing Howard Zinn.  That&#39;s life in and around the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Laughing Horse Collective&lt;/span&gt;, where you&#39;ve got access to Dominic&#39;s professional grade video library.  Lots of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/makeover1.html&quot;&gt;Chomsky&lt;/a&gt; on earlier, some Michael Parenti.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After the show, LW huddled with some special guests, inviting them to our &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/11/think-tank-techniques.html&quot;&gt;private party&lt;/a&gt; for prototyping&quot; in our bat cave or sandbox, where we&#39;ll notch it up a bit with the multi-media (experimental), looking ahead to future venues around Gotham.  That&#39;s Saturday.  Pssst to Wanderers, Pythonistas, Intel friends... videographers.  Tonight:  another gig, at the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Roots&lt;/span&gt; place on SE 7th, check &lt;a href=&quot;http://myspace.com/lindseywalkermusic&quot;&gt;web site&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4098967376/&quot; title=&quot;Egyptian Room by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2490/4098967376_801f241154_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Egyptian Room&quot; width=&quot;180&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8854235430068050202'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8854235430068050202'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/game-night.html' title='Game Night'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2490/4098967376_801f241154_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7366764452297075543</id><published>2009-11-10T18:35:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-11-11T11:37:43.413-08:00</updated><title type='text'>PPUG 2009.11.10</title><content type='html'>I&#39;m rejoining &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/portland/2009-November/000853.html&quot;&gt;my tribe&lt;/a&gt;, tip of the iceberg in a 16th floor big room with round tables, coffee robot (fixed position), Jason miked.  He&#39;s been using his &quot;all you can fly&quot; JetBlue pass, ever since DjangoConf just about.  He&#39;s announcing about us.pycon in Atlanta, for those not &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2009-November/009661.html&quot;&gt;eskeered o&#39; Georgia&lt;/a&gt;.  Then there&#39;s always &lt;a href=&quot;http://apac.pycon.org/&quot;&gt;apac.pycon&lt;/a&gt; for those of us on the Pacific Rim.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gotta check into &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Nedspace&lt;/span&gt; more?  There&#39;s one above &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Back Space&lt;/span&gt;, and another downtown. Co-working zones.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Robin Dunn is here next to me, popped over from Vancouver, got caught in the sudden downpour twixt the garage and here.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;News: Guido&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://python.org/dev/peps/pep-3003/&quot;&gt;PEP 3003 Language Moratorium&lt;/a&gt; has been accepted.  Pretty soon, the language will enter a kind of ice age where the focus is on something other than changing the language.  Make it run faster, create new virtual machines, add libraries, APIs to modeling engines, while accepting the language itself as a constant, a fait accompli.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lecture on the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;subprocess&lt;/span&gt; module, another on Pyflakes &amp;amp; Pep8.py.  Pyflakes in svn trunk is abreast 2.6.  Pep8 is under new management and lots of bugs have been fixed rather recently.  Jason showed us &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/FlyMake&quot;&gt;flymake mode for emacs&lt;/a&gt;, which will let the coder run both of these checkers in real time and apply highlighting.  Better than Intellisense?  I&#39;m an emacs virgin almost (just a little bit pregnant).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The longest talk is on Mercurial Queues, however my daughter and her friend were locked out and I needed to duck out to make some calls, missed some details on this one.  Thanks Bret.  About 22 of us: 21 xy, 1 xx.  Rowley out ill, Pelletier just plain skipping.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jason on Mercurial pbranches.  Lots to know.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7366764452297075543'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7366764452297075543'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/ppug-20091110.html' title='PPUG 2009.11.10'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3194318371365945200</id><published>2009-11-08T10:31:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-09-04T20:01:56.139-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Go Humans Go</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/GcMowpjf_B8&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/GcMowpjf_B8&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I attended Quakers&#39; &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/02/adult-first-day-program.html&quot;&gt;Adult Education session&lt;/a&gt; this morning, Bridge City Friends Meeting.  We had a large group, including some out-of-towners attending a steering committee meeting at the Annual level (Quakers rank their meetings in terms of their business meeting&#39;s frequency, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/07/interest-group.html&quot;&gt;from yearly&lt;/a&gt; (like NPYM) to &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/10/wqm-day-one.html&quot;&gt;quarterly&lt;/a&gt; (like WQM) to &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/10/wqm-fall-2005.html&quot;&gt;monthy&lt;/a&gt; (BCFM being a monthly meeting)).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our topic was &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Witness&lt;/span&gt;, sections thereon heading into our new &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Faith and Practice&lt;/span&gt; (rewrite in progress).  I was pleased to show up with this crumpled and creased &quot;Quaker guts&quot; poster, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/11/local-activism.html&quot;&gt;thanks to Dan Stutesman&lt;/a&gt;.  We explored our Beanite beginnings, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4082002716/&quot;&gt;as diagrammed&lt;/a&gt;, with Miriam Laing showing me a more swoopy (less swampy?) version from another text (she&#39;s quite the scholar).  I sat between Larry Ferguson (happy birthday!) and Rocky Garrison during the meeting.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I mentioned at one point being a student of marketing and realizing from my hours of research for &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/02/eclectic-crew.html&quot;&gt;that Youtube survey&lt;/a&gt;, that the meme complex centered around that &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Quaker Oats&lt;/span&gt; guy, a kind of figurehead known as &quot;William Penn&quot; in some blogs, is widely associated with our practice and so it&#39;d behoove Friends to pay some attention to the various marketing campaigns launched by that company.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I congratulated them on the non-misanthropic tone of their latest &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Go Humans Go&lt;/span&gt; slogan, as tacked on at the end of the above commercial.  Ron Braithwaite cited &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4086832496/&quot;&gt;Jerry Garcia&lt;/a&gt; for inspiring his practices around kindness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yes, you could say Quaker oats was our idea: Floyd Schmoe&#39;s grandmother gets the credit -- see &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Lives That Speak&lt;/span&gt;, ISBN 2-888305-32-0, pg. 116.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our discussion was expertly clerked (not be me -- I retired as clerk of Adult Education last cycle, have only the AFSC liaison role these days, plenty time-consuming).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We filled the white board with notes, which I&#39;m chronicling here with two shots by my Olympus Stylus 720SW, uploading to my Photostream for Jane Ewert&#39;s expert note taking (another serious scholar on our most talented and gifted crew).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Those two shots then:  [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4086081807/&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4086836546/in/photostream/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4086898656/&quot; title=&quot;Hello World by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2772/4086898656_c913f6315e_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hello World&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;65&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgQkjz-Jas6ubqNU_HdYR6IDIbFKurfiGDQlnxwsdh31A1JGyEhzlAfEF014u3wDJvr5tkbk6l_5U5HeMOFinrvwCSjWarVdjFe531hYQ8MfPX4-WrHXkt8fizY0qXAqFXRWPip/s1600-h/quaker_dude.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 200px; height: 147px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgQkjz-Jas6ubqNU_HdYR6IDIbFKurfiGDQlnxwsdh31A1JGyEhzlAfEF014u3wDJvr5tkbk6l_5U5HeMOFinrvwCSjWarVdjFe531hYQ8MfPX4-WrHXkt8fizY0qXAqFXRWPip/s200/quaker_dude.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5402316069707276754&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3194318371365945200'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3194318371365945200'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/go-humans-go.html' title='Go Humans Go'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2772/4086898656_c913f6315e_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2060984844623164090</id><published>2009-11-06T09:56:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-11-08T08:23:41.077-08:00</updated><title type='text'>More On Textbooks</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;im&quot;&gt;[ fixing some of the typos in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=6889155&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;the original&lt;/a&gt;, adding hyperlinks... ]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On Thu, Nov 5, 2009 at 5:19 PM, Robert Hansen wrote:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;&gt; Kirby, you haven&#39;t really made an argument for why online would be better than text books. The only argument I have seen so far is that they would be much cheaper. I am all for giving text books some competition, but if a district went online entirely the parents that could afford them, would buy text books for their kids. And then people would cry foul because yet again the affluent get ahead.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt; &gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;I&#39;m skeptical that your model would hold true in every district.  Many in my neck of the woods are down on harvesting trees for trivially wasteful activities such as toilet paper, newsprint and textbooks. Of course the lobbies come in and explain about recycling (a responsible activity), plus toilet paper is a tremendous convenience, so the average tipping point is still &quot;lets waste lots of paper&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;However the peer pressure to be cool, to walk and talk like an environmentalist, is &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/06/saving-trees.html&quot;&gt;pretty keenly experienced&lt;/a&gt; here in Portland, YMMV.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Affluent kids put their textbooks on memory sticks as PDFs, read &#39;em on Ubuntu Starling-1s from System76 running Karmic Koala or, in my case, Jaunty Jackalope.  I need to check if there&#39;s a fix for &lt;a href=&quot;http://ubuntuforums.org/showthread.php?t=1303542&quot;&gt;the wifi glitch&lt;/a&gt; (or troll, gremlin) along the upgrade path.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;im&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;&gt; They have been testing the Kindle in some schools and it is bombing. And I know you are talking about something better than the Kindle but text books are going to have the edge for some time for subjects that require more than a vocational glancing blow. That is what makes your career academically based or not. Whether you only got a vocational understanding of the subject or an actual understanding.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt; &gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;The deeper questions revolve around the school intranet and whether the server is robust enough to store edited versions of last year&#39;s football games and theatrical performances, the occasional lecture, some instructional cartoons, lots and lots of student work.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We should remember our history:  textbooks arose when industrial standards were still new and could not be taken for granted.  States had this idea of a centralized Paris time or Moscow time and everyone was to march to the same drummer, get with the same beat.  You hear echoes of that from national standards people of today, most of whom we feel it&#39;s safe to ignore.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fast forward to the age of Michael Jackson and &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/04/meeting-math.html&quot;&gt;Britney Spears&lt;/a&gt; and you see we&#39;re glued together not by shared textbook boilerplate so much as our electronic media, and these include so-called &quot;infotainment&quot; as well, not just 1-800... Ginsu Knife commercials but Discovery, History... And then there&#39;s simply having a DVD player and access to stores of videos, such as &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Laughing Horse Books&lt;/span&gt; (lots on the Spanish Civil War, for those beginning a study of the early modern period e.g. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Pan&#39;s Labyrinth&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/11/into-fire-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Into the Fire&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;...).  Read about Ernest Hemingway, with a look back at Mark Twain (likewise not into sorrows of empire).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We&#39;ve got &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Sesame Street&lt;/span&gt; as an on-ramp, then shows for older kids like &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Bill Nye the Science Guy &lt;/span&gt;(dated yet timeless material in many ways, as basic science hasn&#39;t changed that much).  The screen has been competing with the live performance educator for several decades by now and it&#39;s looking more and more that the screens won, and in the process have liberated future generations from needing to synchronize their schooling on the backs of some fleet o slave ships (aka the public schools), which newly unburdened institutions will now be more free to &quot;roll their own&quot; in the sense of coming up with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/11/not-following-detroit.html&quot;&gt;&quot;place based&quot; education&lt;/a&gt; (one sourced by local experts and faculty, in cahoots with private industry, not beholden to anyone &quot;back east&quot; as some still say, (sounding retro), not waiting for the next edition of some mass published textbook offering (yawn, not interested sorry)).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What your affluent kids are learning today is how to explain parabolas to each other (as cross-sections of parabolic dish antennae -- that was a bad idea to lose focus on a principal application of those 2nd degree curves) on the school intranet, or simply via YouTube if your school is liberal enough to provide unfettered access (some Portland schools are).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In sum:  because our culture is now glued together outside the classroom, by electronic media, the classroom is free to localize more and make the math story problems be, you guessed it, vehicles for teaching about the local infrastructure and history.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;The aqueduct &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/11/wanderers-20081119.html&quot;&gt;from Bull Run to Mt. Tabor&lt;/a&gt; is x miles long and on June 1, 2011 see y gallons per second holding steady for five hours.  How many gallons of clear, clean Bull Run water did the Mt. Tabor reservoirs receive in those five hours, neglecting to factor in evaporation or leaking?&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;I realize many math teachers see real world content as a drag on the subject, as math is supposed to point to this Ivory Tower world wherein the concerns of the reality-minded have been left outside the gates.  The outsiders are, by definition, not privy to some inner circle set of abstractions (aka &quot;pure&quot; math -- versus &quot;dirty&quot; is the snobbish implication).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But it&#39;s not that either/or in this picture either, as the abstract stuff still comes across better if  you work &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=6681184&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;with Java applets&lt;/a&gt;, watch Flash movies, listen to competent narrations of spheres turning inside out (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/11/topological-sandbox.html&quot;&gt;a two part series&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube featuring input from Bill Thurston, one of my profs), and otherwise partake of your electronic heritage.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Schools that stay based in wood pulp are quite literally &quot;dark ages&quot; comparatively speaking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;im&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;&gt; I would like to see some better quality videos and smart board presentations out there but it is hard to create classics that fit everyone in that medium. That is why good teachers will always be an asset. You have to reach the kids.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Maybe we don&#39;t want anymore &quot;classics that fit everyone&quot;?  We already have so many, under-appreciated.  This may be the sea change some still haven&#39;t grokked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Out here in the Silicon Forest, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikieducator.org/Martian_Math&quot;&gt;the math we want to teach&lt;/a&gt; is simply not in any of the textbooks, period.  We simply have no choice but to go somewhat cold turkey, because we have serious economic concerns which involve knowing more discrete math and having more software literacy than is anywhere available from the big publishers you may be thinking about.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But hey, we have Intel, Nike, Wieden + Kennedy, Spirit Mountain... PPS, 4D.  So that&#39;s a lot of talent and even funding.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We invite the State of Oregon to join us, to help us compete with other states, but also collaborate (as we&#39;ve been doing with Alaska).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We could leave the State of Florida to organize its own internal affairs why not?  You&#39;ve got &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/07/epcot-makeover.html&quot;&gt;The Mouse&lt;/a&gt;, NASA, shouldn&#39;t have any trouble keeping your schools up to date, at least around Satellite Beach.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We don&#39;t think Obama is on the hook to deliver anything, not even stimulus checks, although we do like the WPA as a model and think Public Works ala the Roosevelts were going somewhere constructive before the derailing occurred (aka WWII).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Those of us using &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/08/education-planning.html&quot;&gt;the Litvins text&lt;/a&gt; know there&#39;s a PDF version.  That&#39;s on my other Ubuntu laptop which is mostly just a carcass, though I could still use that hard drive...  anyway, just saying we appreciate it when a publisher just makes an agreement with the district, lets the district apply its own logo, other watermarks.  Then at least if there&#39;s unauthorized redistribution, we&#39;ll have some sense of the source.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2060984844623164090'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2060984844623164090'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/more-on-textbooks.html' title='More On Textbooks'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3100144207490779929</id><published>2009-11-04T11:03:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-11-04T11:11:19.957-08:00</updated><title type='text'>4D House</title><content type='html'>&lt;object width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/Veli7iwqSuA&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;color1=0x3a3a3a&amp;amp;color2=0x999999&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;fs=1&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowScriptAccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/Veli7iwqSuA&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;color1=0x3a3a3a&amp;amp;color2=0x999999&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;fs=1&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: by Trevor Blake, &lt;a href=&quot;http://synchronofile.com/?p=301&quot;&gt;Synchronofile&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Related viewing:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/01/about-habitats.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;About Habitats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/11/more-adult-education.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;More Adult Education&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/3100144207490779929/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/3100144207490779929' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3100144207490779929'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3100144207490779929'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/4d-house.html' title='4D House'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1632817623620502421</id><published>2009-11-03T06:45:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2009-11-03T07:05:02.894-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Socialist Victory (satire)</title><content type='html'>Although dubbed the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;USS White Elephant&lt;/span&gt; by some skeptics, the fact is our people have inherited a glorious and spanking new floating city, suitable for volunteer staffing and operating, not to mention perpetual refueling.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This communally owned property further bolsters the psychological power of our mostly-male, world-dominating &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/07/back-in-ussa.html&quot;&gt;USSA&lt;/a&gt; socialist hierarchy and its veneer of nominally &quot;private sector&quot; companies at the service of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/12/iron-mountain-revisted.html&quot;&gt;our hive-mind collective&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Empire State is suitably thrilled, according to all patriotic news sources.  Making payments for the foreseeable future, against a billion dollars and counting, to whatever &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/03/stress-tests.html&quot;&gt;Chinese banks&lt;/a&gt;, will &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; be a problem.  The floating city itself is ample collateral.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1632817623620502421'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1632817623620502421'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/socialist-victory-satire.html' title='Socialist Victory (satire)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1953752579816131857</id><published>2009-10-29T21:47:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2009-10-30T14:52:41.143-07:00</updated><title type='text'>A Short Talk</title><content type='html'>On the Logic of Object Oriented thinking.  Click slides for enlargements, or captions for the Flickr-saved originals.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgvjs9pUSXTcHt1aws3mwxVnXSxST0akXY-47frB50nwA2SZc4CtI9XyKBa0bbvzyNFxpkFsFxMi4ZH8zY_MB5tY2p7igreuLw3n_oag-yX2ZVeIMKoKRUV7JrnslkcI7LNILxa/s1600-h/slide0.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 320px; height: 298px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgvjs9pUSXTcHt1aws3mwxVnXSxST0akXY-47frB50nwA2SZc4CtI9XyKBa0bbvzyNFxpkFsFxMi4ZH8zY_MB5tY2p7igreuLw3n_oag-yX2ZVeIMKoKRUV7JrnslkcI7LNILxa/s320/slide0.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5398250557590553506&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4057682752/sizes/o/&quot;&gt;slide 0&lt;/a&gt; ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/02/regarding-objectifying.html&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Object oriented languages&lt;/a&gt; distinguish between a blueprint, which defines the generic aspects of a whole class of objects, such as houses or fish, and the special case instances of that blueprint, the specific houses or fish, each occupying its own time and place, taking up room in memory.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh-kpdWepSFvPs8V49P6O_EG9zxZ-RJ9PKs4Gb9CDeY9wSmzNwq7nXs6eduC85UnW8ej-vEoQdMjixtXObiNqx2OGeUfrlMv8G24dzCgxbQ9zqQ3qJ3neV8CVqGZRlD-KCIzp6o/s1600-h/slide1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 286px; height: 320px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh-kpdWepSFvPs8V49P6O_EG9zxZ-RJ9PKs4Gb9CDeY9wSmzNwq7nXs6eduC85UnW8ej-vEoQdMjixtXObiNqx2OGeUfrlMv8G24dzCgxbQ9zqQ3qJ3neV8CVqGZRlD-KCIzp6o/s320/slide1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5398251455113562530&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4057682782/sizes/o/&quot;&gt;slide 1&lt;/a&gt; ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Above is some code for a generic Animal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The blueprint defines only two behaviors, one for giving birth to an instance of itself (&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(0, 0, 153); font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;__init__&lt;/span&gt;), and another for representing itself to the public (&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(0, 0, 153); font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;__repr__&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There&#39;s an attribute called &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;species&lt;/span&gt; which will get assigned a random value, choosing from the list [ &lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(0, 102, 0);&quot;&gt;&#39;Dog&#39;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(0, 102, 0);&quot;&gt;&#39;Monkey&#39;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(0, 102, 0);&quot;&gt;&#39;Philosopher&#39;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(0, 102, 0);&quot;&gt;&#39;Bird&#39;&lt;/span&gt; ] as the four possibilities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For now, the species is unspecified.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Because the philosopher Descartes famously said &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;cogito ergo sum&lt;/span&gt; (I think therefore I am), the logician writing this code chose the name &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;cogito&lt;/span&gt; within the birth method, and &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; within the representation method (because they&#39;re roughly synonymous).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Those of you who already know Python will agree this is &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2009-October/009638.html&quot;&gt;somewhat pathological&lt;/a&gt;, but does serve to illustrate the positional nature of this handle to the specific instance, more traditionally and consistently called &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt; across all methods.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhkj_Ljb4mD1WgYguy706gnw8YiT_Ng8AXPLJyXJwpDXbCdDCNc8hyphenhyphennsrfKJKXeJL5y2E6lnRJFc1jNgBawzLT60fKJDF2ucCYYk-Vi9x1BpjozaiyF5SW2ltdMX_IAkXN-YyKg/s1600-h/slide2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 320px; height: 271px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhkj_Ljb4mD1WgYguy706gnw8YiT_Ng8AXPLJyXJwpDXbCdDCNc8hyphenhyphennsrfKJKXeJL5y2E6lnRJFc1jNgBawzLT60fKJDF2ucCYYk-Vi9x1BpjozaiyF5SW2ltdMX_IAkXN-YyKg/s320/slide2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5398250505487577874&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4056943415/sizes/o/&quot;&gt;slide 2&lt;/a&gt; ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What you see above is not another blueprint, but a function.  In this particular brand of logic, the level of indentation is significant.  The function begins with the orange signifier &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic; color: rgb(255, 102, 0); font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt;, and ends with the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic; color: rgb(255, 102, 0); font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; statement.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The &lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(0, 0, 153); font-weight: bold; font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;many&lt;/span&gt; function &quot;eats&quot; two arguments (the parentheses are like a mouth turned sideways -- think of emoticons).  It expects to know &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;howmany&lt;/span&gt;, and what &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;species&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These two parameters are like &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/12/car-czar.html&quot;&gt;guards at the castle gates&lt;/a&gt;, or like butlers at the door, waiting for a hand-off, for incoming values, which they&#39;ll circulate internally to said function.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the code below, this function &lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(0, 0, 153); font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;many&lt;/span&gt; is invoked three times, each time to fill a zoo_cage with additional animals.  The &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;extend&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;append&lt;/span&gt; methods, both used in this code, are built in to each list instance, thanks to the blueprint for the list type.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&quot;Dot notation&quot; of the form &quot;noun.verb(arguments)&quot; and &quot;noun.adjective&quot; is what we use to interact with our blueprints and instances.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The equal sign (&quot;=&quot;) is an assignment operator in this Logic and is used to bind names to objects in memory.  Other symbols are used to compare values for equality (&quot;==&quot;) or to test whether two names actually specify the same object (&quot;is&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhR46I9tpyz2T4fagp62PU1b1CphV2bnQvYZvkXV5a1NUacN7hOU1_hAiy_4ihzh-ruxEvNBqlUc7ZKMmNEbXEsNADCSQID9pZtKkjrX_hrC9F0vj0syd1a8jsEykQVAiUmmajJ/s1600-h/slide3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 320px; height: 260px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhR46I9tpyz2T4fagp62PU1b1CphV2bnQvYZvkXV5a1NUacN7hOU1_hAiy_4ihzh-ruxEvNBqlUc7ZKMmNEbXEsNADCSQID9pZtKkjrX_hrC9F0vj0syd1a8jsEykQVAiUmmajJ/s320/slide3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5398250450335223154&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4057682834/sizes/o/&quot;&gt;slide 3&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Secondary characteristics of color and sex get added after the zoo_cage is already full with our full complement of instances.  They&#39;re set for each animal individually, irrespective of the fact that neither quality was mentioned at the blueprint level.  Not every brand of object oriented logic has such a liberal (forgiving) grammar.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Note that if you trigger the representation method (&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(0, 0, 153); font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;__repr__&lt;/span&gt;) before color and sex attributes have been assigned some values, you will get an error message, as the returned self description is counting on having that information available, even if the sex is &quot;unknown&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;choice&lt;/span&gt; function, imported from the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;random&lt;/span&gt; module, is not obligated to choose uniquely, only randomly.  In other words, after some runs of this program, we might have only Monkeys, even all white ones, whereas other times we might have a mix of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/02/pauling-house-meeting.html&quot;&gt;Birds and Philosophers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiTDm3o6R-bS_TNhxD9JVAni2vmqbIQ-fWBgujCSIuxesl_YWZchK1jEZgj9yvKVBHer3RHrak5khytAIql4F6RthtkwsVAnj2JTKV03Xzvb2-fM75uOrsYBIx_dcdnO7egPUxF/s1600-h/slide4.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 320px; height: 318px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiTDm3o6R-bS_TNhxD9JVAni2vmqbIQ-fWBgujCSIuxesl_YWZchK1jEZgj9yvKVBHer3RHrak5khytAIql4F6RthtkwsVAnj2JTKV03Xzvb2-fM75uOrsYBIx_dcdnO7egPUxF/s320/slide4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5398250393199801474&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4056943489/sizes/o/&quot;&gt;slide 4&lt;/a&gt; ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What you see in the square brackets, denoting a list, is our &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;zoo_cage&lt;/span&gt; of animals.  Because of how the representation method was written, one sees the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;species&lt;/span&gt;, with the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;sex&lt;/span&gt; in parentheses.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Run this over and over to get a different mix of animals.  Notice the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;shuffle&lt;/span&gt; function in Slide 3, also imported from &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;random&lt;/span&gt;, keeps the animals in a jumble, instead of a sequence of Dogs, then Monkeys or whatever.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Comment out this line (with a &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold; color: rgb(153, 0, 0);&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;) and run the script again, to see what difference &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;shuffle&lt;/span&gt; makes.  You might see where we&#39;d use it to shuffle a deck of cards, with &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2009-October/009608.html&quot;&gt;both Deck and Card&lt;/a&gt; more blueprints for specific instances.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For further reading:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/trends2000.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Trends in Early Mathematics Learning:  Looking Beyond Y2K&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/cp4e.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;More curriculum writing featuring Python&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1953752579816131857'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1953752579816131857'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/10/short-talk.html' title='A Short Talk'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgvjs9pUSXTcHt1aws3mwxVnXSxST0akXY-47frB50nwA2SZc4CtI9XyKBa0bbvzyNFxpkFsFxMi4ZH8zY_MB5tY2p7igreuLw3n_oag-yX2ZVeIMKoKRUV7JrnslkcI7LNILxa/s72-c/slide0.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4541831682482937030</id><published>2009-10-28T12:20:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2013-08-22T21:57:20.418-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Open Source Dot Gov</title><content type='html'>In the course of discussing Python vs. PHP &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/10/wanderers-20091027.html&quot;&gt;last night at Wanderers&lt;/a&gt;, someone brought up the fact that the White House has &lt;a href=&quot;http://radar.oreilly.com/2009/10/whitehouse-switch-drupal-opensource.html&quot;&gt;switched to Drupal&lt;/a&gt;, a PHP application.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Likewise the DoD has been &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.informationweek.com/news/government/enterprise-apps/showArticle.jhtml?articleID=221100039&amp;amp;subSection=All+Stories&quot;&gt;touting open source&lt;/a&gt; as more of an answer to its prayers.  &quot;Just because a proprietary solution is way more expensive, doesn&#39;t mean it&#39;s that much better, or even could be worse&quot; is a message to military intelligence personnel.  Many in the commercial sector have already learned this lesson.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You might think that all this talk of automating medical records and/or &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/09/open-source-within-health-care.html&quot;&gt;outcomes research&lt;/a&gt; might yield some new open source assets, even outside the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.disa.mil/forge/&quot;&gt;Forge dot mil&lt;/a&gt; domain.  If there&#39;s tax money involved, then shouldn&#39;t the code be of, by and for the people?  &lt;a href=&quot;http://goscon.org/&quot;&gt;GOSCON&lt;/a&gt; is a traditional forum for such rhetoric, lots of &lt;a href=&quot;http://site05.goscon.org/panels.html&quot;&gt;Portland people&lt;/a&gt; already on board with that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of Portland, OSCON is &lt;a href=&quot;http://ostatic.com/blog/oscon-2010-returning-to-portland-after-brief-jaunt-to-san-jose&quot;&gt;coming back here again&lt;/a&gt; next year, after bouncing down to San Jose in 2009.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Slate&lt;/span&gt; has been &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/id/2233719/&quot;&gt;making fun&lt;/a&gt; of the WH decision to go with Drupal.  I&#39;m not sure the CIA&#39;s use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cmspowered.info/blog/cia&quot;&gt;of Plone&lt;/a&gt; ever got &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/06/control-rooms.html&quot;&gt;such attention&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/01/other-news-blips.html&quot;&gt;NSA&lt;/a&gt; put out it&#39;s own &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.upi.com/Top_News/Special/2008/03/24/NSA-releases-new-version-of-Linux-software/UPI-99181206371622/&quot;&gt;SELinux distro&lt;/a&gt; a long time ago, is still putting out new releases, like in March of last year.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then of course we should remember DARPA&#39;s role in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/05/more-developments.html&quot;&gt;helping Guido&lt;/a&gt; get IDLE off the ground, a big step in making Computer Programming for Everybody (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.python.org/doc/essays/cp4e/&quot;&gt;CP4E&lt;/a&gt;) seem a little bit more real.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4541831682482937030'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4541831682482937030'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/10/open-source-dot-gov.html' title='Open Source Dot Gov'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5385114743349704042</id><published>2009-10-25T16:13:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-10-28T16:45:36.434-07:00</updated><title type='text'>From Fred Meyer</title><content type='html'>I&#39;m in the downstairs dining area sitting with Leslie H. who is busy grading papers for the health studies class she&#39;s teaching.  We&#39;re catching up a little.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Last night I joined a large group of well wishers at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Mississippi Pizza&lt;/span&gt; to say bon voyage to Nirel, about to launch on one of the big adventures of her life, which she&#39;s planning to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nirel.mobi/India/&quot;&gt;blog about&lt;/a&gt;.  She&#39;d shaved her head in preparation, called it &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4045532502/&quot;&gt;a &quot;mohawk&quot;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There I met a science teacher from the new high school in Hillsboro, which has a state of the art facility &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/11/town-meeting.html&quot;&gt;for home economics&lt;/a&gt;.  I shared my concept of producing &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/06/cooking-show.html&quot;&gt;cooking shows&lt;/a&gt; ala Julia Child, multi-ethnic, imparting a mix of culinary and TV-making skills.  You could even see it as chemistry.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I then headed home for my Ubuntu laptop, the Starling-1, so I could maybe get some work done from &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Muddy Waters&lt;/span&gt;, while Lindsey brute forced through her set, despite a rather nasty cold.  Greg and I got to talking about geometry, paper folding, pin ball machines and computer programming among other things, also &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Kodak&#39;s&lt;/span&gt; reputation for being rather &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/07/epcot-makeover.html&quot;&gt;slow to adapt&lt;/a&gt;.  Future shock is &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/power-of-nightmares-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;sometimes shocking&lt;/a&gt;, even for futurists.  Get ready for a next generation of &quot;3D&quot; movies (director Cameron of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Titanic&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Aliens 2&lt;/span&gt; fame has one in the wings; science fiction).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of futurists, Dr. Bolton (emeritus) filled me in on some of the latest thoughts in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Futurist&lt;/span&gt; over Thai food the other day.  We&#39;d missed the surprise party in their honor, mom just back from lobbying Congress in Washington DC.  Chuck and Mary are old family friends, were aware of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/01/about-chicago.html&quot;&gt;my dad&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Chicago before I was born there.  The Boltons used to own &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/04/morning-mail.html&quot;&gt;that rustic getaway home&lt;/a&gt; overlooking Hood River from the Washington side of Columbia Gorge, where Dawn and I went on our brief honeymoon in September of 1993.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I posted one of my &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2009-October/009616.html&quot;&gt;once again, from the top&lt;/a&gt;&quot; kinds of posts to edu-sig, explaining what I think I&#39;m up to regarding education reform.  You&#39;d think &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Futurist&lt;/span&gt; would have explained the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/02/valentines-day-2006.html&quot;&gt;concentric hierarchy of polyhedra&lt;/a&gt; by now.  I recall Applewhite writing an article in that mag many moons ago, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/synergetica/eja1.html&quot;&gt;pre &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Chemical Intelligencer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  Next time I&#39;m in a well endowed library, I should try digging that up.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ve been digging out my basement, having gutted the garage, coming across some old papers, including the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4033639605/sizes/l/&quot;&gt;rejection letter&lt;/a&gt; from the Guggenheim Foundation (Ed had encouraged me to apply).  I&#39;m reminded of an episode of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Family Guy&lt;/span&gt; when I see that (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/05/recap.html&quot;&gt;fifth paragraph from the end&lt;/a&gt;).  I may be smart, but I also sometimes come off as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4047493858/&quot;&gt;kinda kooky&lt;/a&gt;, or quirky as Ed put it.  Or just call me a freak of nature, helping to &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/06/staying-weird-in-portland.html&quot;&gt;keep Portland weird&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ll end with a quote from Wittgenstein (many thanks to Sean, for digging these up):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;From &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Culture and Value&lt;/span&gt;, 1931:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt; “The solution of philosophical problems can be compared with a gift in a fairy tale: in the magic castle it appears enchanted and if you look at it outside in the daylight it is nothing but an ordinary bit of &lt;span class=&quot;il&quot;&gt;iron&lt;/span&gt; (or something of the sort).” CV 1931, 11.&lt;/blockquote&gt;... and with this Youtube about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bestofyoutube.com/story.php?title=cross-country-snowboarding&quot;&gt;a new extreme sport&lt;/a&gt; (with thanks to Dave Koski).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5385114743349704042'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5385114743349704042'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/10/from-fred-meyer.html' title='From Fred Meyer'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8646098120337975480</id><published>2009-10-22T00:12:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2016-12-13T17:21:31.880-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Hubbert&#39;s Peak: The End of Oil (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
You might have trouble finding this one.  Thanks &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/08/walking-tour.html&quot;&gt;to &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Laughing Horse Books&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for stocking it.  The &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/02/illahee.html&quot;&gt;Illahee Lecture Series&lt;/a&gt; is locally produced, similar to the ISEPP lecture series in that way.  Kenneth Deffeyes is speaking in the First Congregational Church, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/01/why-civilizations-fail.html&quot;&gt;as Jared Diamond did&lt;/a&gt;, and in some ways about the same topic:  why civilizations fail (or not, as the case may be).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, this is the &quot;peak oil&quot; guy, an engaging and avuncular teacher who asserts we hit peak production around December 2005.  He sketches some of the alternative sources of energy humans have developed, as well as ways to stretch what we have (remember to turn out those lights, a 100 watt bulb is like Lance Armstrong riding a bicycle, in terms of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/10/roz-savage.html&quot;&gt;power requirements &lt;/a&gt;-- per an apparatus at Princeton he remembers).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Especially interesting to me was his mention of Richard Smalley, who had recently died of lukemia at the time of this talk (Kenneth was visibly saddened).  Smalley was one of the Nobel Prize recipients for the discovery &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/08/hp4e.html&quot;&gt;of buckyballs&lt;/a&gt;, and had been working on buckytubes in connection with high efficiency electrical current transmission.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This project was close to the heart of Bucky himself, who spent a lot of time/energy focusing on &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/01/more-about-geek-tv.html&quot;&gt;the global grid&lt;/a&gt;, work carried on by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geni.org/&quot;&gt;GENI&lt;/a&gt;, at least in terms of PR.  Would that the popular media pay more attention to these memes, not just back office engineering firms.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This mention of buckyballs prompted me to dig out my Pergamon Press satchel from the first international conference on buckminsterfullerene in Santa Barbara &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4034394482/sizes/l/in/photostream/&quot;&gt;in 1993&lt;/a&gt;, where I had the privilege of meeting both Richard Smalley and Harold Kroto.  I found a fun stash of documents therein and am uploading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4034393802/in/photostream/&quot;&gt;some of them&lt;/a&gt; to my &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/11/trevors-talk.html&quot;&gt;chronofile&lt;/a&gt;&quot; (Flickr Photostream).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of Bucky, I enjoyed chatting &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/12/its-show-time.html&quot;&gt;with D.W. Jacobs&lt;/a&gt; at some length by cell yesterday.  He was driving along Hwy 101 from the Bay Area to LA.  His play opens next June in Washington, DC.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8646098120337975480'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8646098120337975480'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/10/oil-water-movie-review.html' title='Hubbert&#39;s Peak: The End of Oil (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>