<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=51'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=76&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>51</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5608948149874482713</id><published>2024-08-15T11:32:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-16T06:06:05.444-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Drone Fun</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/53921614198/&quot; title=&quot;P1370528&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;P1370528&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53921614198_25581b3374.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got some valuable drone training in, on my latest visit to the XRL facility, more a prototype in being farm bound, rural, but hardly eXtremely Remote. Mostly flat farmland is a perfect setting for drone training.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given GST’s immersion into Active Inference, I was quick to appreciate the “sensory input” versus “action output” model, with a Markov blanket wrapping that me-ball self, controlling the aircraft. I brought that up with the Institute during &lt;a href=&quot;https://coda.io/d/Math4Wisdom_d0SvdI3KSto/Meetings_suxmi#Meetings_tuvz5/r46&amp;amp;view=modal&quot;&gt;the most recent Coda session&lt;/a&gt;, and sure enough, the “drone model” as already well developed, in the Julia programming language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However Markov comes up in another way where drone action is concerned. Quadcopters easily take the place of “sea turtles” in those “random walk” demonstrations. When only the present position counts, in terms of imparting momentum going forward, then notions of randomness come into play, as what we have is always a probability distribution, perhaps sharp, perhaps diffuse. Markov chains enter the picture, along with some history of &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/CIe869Rce2k&quot;&gt;Russian greats&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those sea turtles, you may recall, all start at (0,0,0,0) but then each picks from twelve options, or thirteen if “staying put” is an option. Role the dice. To each option, a permutation of {2, 1, 1, 0}, there corresponds a hop through space to a neighboring zonohedron, with twelve compartments or “voxels” around each. Each hop is through a diamond faced center. We call them K-points, as they’re where the closest packed spheres “kiss”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So the goal here is to have the drones hover in such a matrix, with illumination patterns signifying the wandering sea turtles, four of which make a tetrahedron. Drones light up or go dark depending on whether the corresponding zonohedron, conceptual only, would be occupied. Variations on that theme. I’ve cast the neutral buoyancy IVM nets in other action frames. In both cases we might take advantage of unique (a, b, c, d) whole number addressing for matrix positions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An ideal gas may be modeled in a static moment as gas molecules in IVM positions, with random offsets, although you’ll likely put science mag editors in an uncomfortable position if you do that; “IVM” (or “isotropic vector matrix”) is verboten terminology within the sphere of capitalist realism. Don’t say “A-” or “B-particle” either, or risk accusations of promulgating “&lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.io/g/synergeo/message/2674&quot;&gt;the BEAST&lt;/a&gt;” (a specific geometric vocabulary, considered&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5608948149874482713'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5608948149874482713'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/08/drone-fun.html' title='Drone Fun'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3441758549186679273</id><published>2024-08-08T09:12:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-01T12:44:38.106-07:00</updated><title type='text'>GST Meets Neuroscience</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiU1Ce7fv3Y9iZm4OLpzoiOKOCJ0nNDyBrfzMasBZyGNz_51kGIzAbNe6Nivx2tn8E-_4TGZEj4zcFbtdLYl5LwbP2fJAqoX57pUlhi8GWvUs4ltQX6bfn6vAyYVjvHQWwo4oOn3fYv78MSF8TTCkBN8QZXOk7Th5Xdqli09SCvOAlUvRRyUoYz/s1536/contained_container.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1536&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1536&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiU1Ce7fv3Y9iZm4OLpzoiOKOCJ0nNDyBrfzMasBZyGNz_51kGIzAbNe6Nivx2tn8E-_4TGZEj4zcFbtdLYl5LwbP2fJAqoX57pUlhi8GWvUs4ltQX6bfn6vAyYVjvHQWwo4oOn3fYv78MSF8TTCkBN8QZXOk7Th5Xdqli09SCvOAlUvRRyUoYz/w400-h400/contained_container.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;:: enclosed enclosure ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whatever happened &lt;a href=&quot;https://grunch.net/synergetics/gst2.html&quot;&gt;to GST&lt;/a&gt; after it featured in my science fiction as the planning discipline behind our Global Data Corporation, amalgamated outside &quot;whiteman law&quot;? In that form, it stayed on the periphery, affiliating itself with Synergetics, and thereby drawing us closer to Discordians and Subgenii, usually avoided by university faculties and prosperians, as too wild and risky for purely academic treatments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Synergetics, in the meantime, got picked up by the Markov Blanket tribe, &lt;a href=&quot;https://coda.io/d/Math4Wisdom_d0SvdI3KSto/Active-Inference_suIkP#_lu7Cz&quot;&gt;the Active Inference folks&lt;/a&gt; with their Bayesian brains. Markov membranes feature here in two contexts:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(a) nothing makes it to the future from the past but through the present (where change is made)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(b) the Markov blanket divides an inside from an outside in an agent-based model of any self + other&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes (a) may be regarded as a truism, and (b) is likewise part of a framework, a setup, and one consistent with the Omnidirectional Halo pattern of &lt;i&gt;No More Secondhand God&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.io/g/synergeo/message/2694&quot;&gt;Markov blanket&lt;/a&gt;, in this (b) case, encloses the neural network we like to probe, seek clues from, a black box in many respects, but also protective, like a skull casing, keeping our delicate modeling systems from damage by the rough and tumble outside.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sensory organs mediate between these two worlds (outer and inner), bringing in news. From that inner black box, full of unknown unknowns, then spring the agent&#39;s actions, responses to what&#39;s incoming, robotic and reflex-based, or perhaps thoughtful and considered, or maybe initiated from out of the blue.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our own models may find another&#39;s actions rather impossible to predict, or even our own may elude explanation sometimes. We rationalize, after the fact.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our models may adapt and improve, or get hot swapped (radically updated), over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the older (a) sense, GST long included &quot;edit/recombine&quot; as shorthand for &quot;value adding&quot;, a correlate of the old economics concept of &quot;doing work&quot;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incoming are all the &quot;factors&quot; that make up one&#39;s circumstances including a &quot;free energy&quot; allotment, so-called &quot;disposable (or discretionary) income&quot; i.e. what&#39;s left to a worker to work with in an uncompelled, not automatic manner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We typically symbolize the incoming as a pie chart, with slices as mundane as air and water, in a temperature controlled space. Do we have bandwidth? What inventory?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outgoing is our performance, including all manner of communications: vocalizations, facial expressions, gestures of all kinds. Perhaps one paints, writes poetry, programs, plays roles in theater, all of the above. Perhaps one is a craftsman and makes beaded necklaces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neuroscience and computer science have knit themselves together rather inextricably, which stands to reason, given the cell-silicon interface is highly populated with busy devices, with more in the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With machine and deep learning, we now have what we call &quot;neural networks&quot; on both sides of that same interface, with many analogies bridging the two flavors: chemical wetware versus software on hardware.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://physicsworld.com/a/introducing-python-for-electrochemistry-research/&quot;&gt;Electrochemistry&lt;/a&gt; has bonded what at one time were separate disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3441758549186679273'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3441758549186679273'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/08/gst-meets-neuroscience.html' title='GST Meets Neuroscience'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiU1Ce7fv3Y9iZm4OLpzoiOKOCJ0nNDyBrfzMasBZyGNz_51kGIzAbNe6Nivx2tn8E-_4TGZEj4zcFbtdLYl5LwbP2fJAqoX57pUlhi8GWvUs4ltQX6bfn6vAyYVjvHQWwo4oOn3fYv78MSF8TTCkBN8QZXOk7Th5Xdqli09SCvOAlUvRRyUoYz/s72-w400-h400-c/contained_container.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3670089713154502294</id><published>2024-08-04T18:09:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-04T18:13:16.159-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Python: Still Relevant</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/7xkYfq2OBL4?si=vJPza5q9xG7fNXHw&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This professor works in the same ballpark as I do: &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/06/just-use-it.html&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; as applied to data science, Machine Learning (ML) and Deep Learning (DL: a subtype of ML) in particular.  However my bailiwick has been earlier in the pipeline, between data gathering and feeding said data to Machine Learning models. That includes: preliminary analysis, normalization, standardization, cleaning, reorganizing, visualizing.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Statisticians didn&#39;t have all these fancy ML tools until recently and their discipline up until then hasn&#39;t faded so much as abetted what has of late become center ring: deep learning.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In practical terms, what used to be managed in spreadsheets (volatile) and databases (more secure) is now managed with a hybrid of the two: the programmable DataFrame. Bring your rows and columns into a single complex object, and work with it in code, rather than with fleeting mouse clicks or other unreplicable magic dust.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Why am I plugging Python in the philosophy blog? For many obvious reasons, but let&#39;s just say because the School of Tomorrow, powered by latter day American Transcendentalism (a kind of intuitionism), is using Python to yak up the 4D meme. Yes, I&#39;m referring to Quadray Coordinates and so on, not to be confused with (x, y, z, w) coordinates within the hypercube, or Quaternions. Disambiguation is important at this point, or you&#39;ll get rather lost in the 4D jungle.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A less obvious reason: I think the philosophers&#39; obsession with such as propositional calculus, ala Russell, Wittgenstein, Frege et al, was really about laying the groundwork for Turing and Von Neumann types to add the electronic dimensions. Logic meets circuit boards, giving us logic boards, and eventually the CPUs and GPUs we think about, and program, today. Philosophers should learn to program, in other words, if only to keep in touch with the atomic layer, the domain of Democritus.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3670089713154502294'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3670089713154502294'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/08/python-still-relevant.html' title='Python: Still Relevant'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/7xkYfq2OBL4/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8942379032413363533</id><published>2024-08-03T21:15:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-04T21:11:18.776-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Homer Davenport Festival</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72177720319312983&quot; title=&quot;Homer Davenport Festival 2024&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Homer Davenport Festival 2024&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53900084091_0f4d032b6d_w.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What may &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/07/keep-portland-queer.html&quot;&gt;feel eerie&lt;/a&gt;, and more as an absence than a presence, is deja vu. What&#39;s absent is a secure memory which the current episode clearly resonates with, such as the last time one waited for the bus at this very stop. &quot;Deja vu&quot; is not the correct term in this situation, just as when I show up for work every morning, same bat time, same bat station, I don&#39;t say &quot;deja vu!&quot; unless maybe I&#39;m trying to be funny.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My car trip with Derek (Deke the Geek) to Silverton this afternoon, was not so much deja vu as an opportunity to reminisce. Glenn Stockton and I had come to Silverton at least once before, to that building with the Norman Rockwell paintings, blown up big, outside. A community center, right? We passed it on the way out of town, after the lecture, and by way of Mt. Angel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This time, &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/12/toontown-revisited.html&quot;&gt;the Gus Frederick lecture&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/12/wanderers-20061212.html&quot;&gt;Homer Davenport&lt;/a&gt; was in the Silver Falls Library, two doors down from the museum, which I thought about visiting, but what about the soundstage across the river? That was the more anomalous event. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.silvertonmuseum.org/museum/&quot;&gt;The museum&lt;/a&gt; is but an hour away by car, open weekends, from 1 to 4 pm.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the lecture was over, around 3 pm, we decided to roam back over the wooden foot bridge to the soundstage, the festival booths, the rides. This was a family friendly beer-oriented festival, one of several to grace the region. Mt. Angle has a big one, in October. Here we were in early August, inaugurating the beer festival season. Not that either of us had any beer. We ended up not spending any money at all, only gas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who was Homer Davenport again? I&#39;ve blogged about him before. He lived during a more civilized age, before the weapons got so much uglier, with psyches to match. We&#39;re safe in calling him a political cartoonist, but he was also an influencer, someone with a keen eye for the critical elements within some story of the day, in the public eye.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Davenport also did some &quot;straight&quot; journalism, meaning not so cartoonish, although still with the hand drawings, high quality and precise, because photography was still difficult to include in daily newspapers. In his younger years, he was sent to New Orleans to cover a prize fight featuring a native son of Silverton, who lost. In his older years, he had a front row seat at the Paris, France trial of Dreyfus, of Dreyfus Affair fame.&lt;/p&gt;I filled in that hole in my knowledge, regarding &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dreyfus_affair&quot;&gt;that Dreyfus business&lt;/a&gt;, from another angle when viewing the French language film &lt;i&gt;Antisémitismes&lt;/i&gt;, by Ilan Ziv. The Ziv documentary weaves together a number of threads, many of them on the theme of demonizing Jewish people as scapegoats or simply as uber-rich. In the case of Germany and Poland, one senses envy, mixed in with various other flavors of unconsciousness.&amp;nbsp;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Psychoanalysis was still a new science. The public was even less in control of &lt;i&gt;projection&lt;/i&gt; as a psychological phenomenon, we may project.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Davenport&#39;s &quot;He&#39;s Good Enough for Me&quot; meme, starting with Uncle Sam saying that of Theodore Roosevelt (a campaign slogan), got picked up by others, to where one sees the British analog of Uncle Sam (John Bull) so saying of prime minister Balfour, of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Balfour_Declaration&quot;&gt;Balfour Declaration&lt;/a&gt; fame.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;These &quot;synapses&quot; are apt even today, in 2024, so many decades later, as life in the eastern Mediterranean region becomes less civilized than in Homer&#39;s day, around the time of the Chicago World&#39;s Fair, followed by Portland&#39;s Lewis &amp;amp; Clark Exposition. Homer was really into animals (as in nonhumans) and sometimes traveled with a whole menagerie, such as when exhibiting the family farm at said exposition, as part of a living diorama.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8942379032413363533'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8942379032413363533'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/08/homer-davenport-festival.html' title='Homer Davenport Festival'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7281286450413016186</id><published>2024-07-29T12:38:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-13T18:31:51.762-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Working Out</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgz4zS4jMk0GBPwthZXUFq7gAERX2gVPlZn96mEUNN2unYGGRj8s94rVKgoFFmf9Y9cK8u1e3aqDTx8X64YBc-Ylu4dyrEnIL88QRBQhSQENawEVUeMM9eqaJC0Zu1i-zvE8z_0SIk3pigUAnavsMbMz1XKmELwEZbT8QhSvYDRCDfcpHQRKzVn/s1536/buddha_in_gym.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1536&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1536&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgz4zS4jMk0GBPwthZXUFq7gAERX2gVPlZn96mEUNN2unYGGRj8s94rVKgoFFmf9Y9cK8u1e3aqDTx8X64YBc-Ylu4dyrEnIL88QRBQhSQENawEVUeMM9eqaJC0Zu1i-zvE8z_0SIk3pigUAnavsMbMz1XKmELwEZbT8QhSvYDRCDfcpHQRKzVn/w400-h400/buddha_in_gym.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ve probably had the same thought I have, when working out in the gym: gee, here&#39;s a lot of energy expenditure going nowhere, a lot of wasted watt-hours. One has fantasies of hooking those exercycles directly to the power grid, at least the building one, and keeping the lights on or something. Those espresso machines take power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A better solution for some demographics, a Venn Diagram intersection of identity components: age, gender, occupation, current state of health, set goals, expected outcomes, is probably doing housework. This way, you&#39;ll kill multiple virtual birds with one stone, reaching moving and standing goals, while adding negative entropy to your space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re anything like me, a guy with internal real estate (several rooms, basement, attic, detached garage), then housework is an endless spigot of chores of varying size and duration, and I&#39;m not only counting or thinking about stereotypical &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/07/homeowner-talk.html&quot;&gt;guy work&lt;/a&gt;&quot; just because I&#39;m a male.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m talking about vacuuming, sorting books, dusting, excavating old storage piles periodically and recycling their contents from inventory. That all takes work and also hand-eye coordination.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, enough tasks are repetitive to permit daydreaming, and its within these structured daydreams that we plan out what to do next. Unless, that is, you want to surrender your daydreaming time to the studios. Sometimes that&#39;s a refreshing alternative, given how professional daydreamers know their business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s set the actual physical tasks aside for a moment and suggest that no matter what your line of work, there&#39;s some way to plan your workflow ahead of time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As with exercising in the gym, &quot;mental muscles&quot; come in groups (work together) and get tired with overuse (a tautology almost).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your faculties benefit from a round robin approach, a spiral staircase, wherein you upgrade gently and gradually when you can, which doesn&#39;t close the door on relatively more jarring overhauls and stress tests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Workout-aholics know to come in with a &quot;lesson plan&quot; or &quot;to do list&quot; and it will likely involve a well-planned sequence of &quot;stations&quot;, meaning exercise machines each with a specific muscle group focus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In computer world, the webserver has to allocate some amount of total bandwidth to each client browser that connects with it. In operating system jargon, you might allocate a process or a thread. A whole process subdivides into threads and is therefore in principle &quot;heavier&quot; than a thread.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you have an intense dislike for meetings wherein the way to gain or regain the floor is to interrupt others, even mid-sentence, interjecting somehow?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Women, on average, trained to be more demur within the patriarchy, were suddenly in management roles without the right default level obstreperousness, and had to take trainings in how to up their level of &quot;bitchiness&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think about mostly male engineers working all day with operating systems that are indeed &quot;interrupt driven&quot;. Everything just chugs along, until the next interruption, in which case the operating system may switch its attention to some other process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think of doing housework and getting a call on your cell. Or the doorbell rings. Cell calls go to voicemail but doorbell rings may be harder to ignore, especially if a knock follows.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Planning models that do not allow for unforeseen interruptions in their conceptualization likely lack enough sophistication for many types of operation, both military and civilian.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember, it&#39;s &lt;i&gt;your&lt;/i&gt; attention span. Consider carefully, not only which machines you&#39;ll visit, and in roughly what order (making it up as you go is OK, as long as you know when you&#39;ve fallen off the path), but also what you&#39;ll be doing in your head, with regards to earbuds, VR goggles, or whatever else your workout space comes with.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it&#39;ll just be you alone with your imagination. You&#39;re ignoring the overhead TVs. What do you plan to think about? Multi-tasking? Event planning? Cosplay? Protein-folding? Your next blog post or YouTube? Explorations in the geometry of thinking?&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7281286450413016186'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7281286450413016186'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/07/working-out.html' title='Working Out'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgz4zS4jMk0GBPwthZXUFq7gAERX2gVPlZn96mEUNN2unYGGRj8s94rVKgoFFmf9Y9cK8u1e3aqDTx8X64YBc-Ylu4dyrEnIL88QRBQhSQENawEVUeMM9eqaJC0Zu1i-zvE8z_0SIk3pigUAnavsMbMz1XKmELwEZbT8QhSvYDRCDfcpHQRKzVn/s72-w400-h400-c/buddha_in_gym.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-631860487932019491</id><published>2024-07-22T08:36:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-07-22T22:38:33.353-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Keep Portland Queer</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi8K_v6BmjdWXS088Whyphenhyphenx1cCB5I5y4jcVl0Cn3busyrLybcXTFdOCh_nmNnHBO6b3DbHyNZC22hvnM3R9YNKSeJYgKVts-Wm5M2YRscwaVhSEODH1k-dijSuI0Xf4R6HC630urswWi9w0aP-z4CFgzSl6VAP1C-0ddicMA-fEiogqVqi13GMC38/s1024/1024px-Keep_Portland_Weird_(17658598119)%20copy.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;615&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi8K_v6BmjdWXS088Whyphenhyphenx1cCB5I5y4jcVl0Cn3busyrLybcXTFdOCh_nmNnHBO6b3DbHyNZC22hvnM3R9YNKSeJYgKVts-Wm5M2YRscwaVhSEODH1k-dijSuI0Xf4R6HC630urswWi9w0aP-z4CFgzSl6VAP1C-0ddicMA-fEiogqVqi13GMC38/w400-h240/1024px-Keep_Portland_Weird_(17658598119)%20copy.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As some of my correspondents are aware, I&#39;ve finally stumbled across &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Fisher&quot;&gt;Mark Fisher&lt;/a&gt;, the philosopher and commentator on contemporary culture. He extends my study of punk music, which in my curriculum links to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/4dsolutions/School_of_Tomorrow/blob/master/School_of_Tomorrow.ipynb&quot;&gt;School of Tomorrow&lt;/a&gt; and of course solarpunk as an antidote or counter to cyberpunk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mark does a lot to dissect the meaning of &quot;weird&quot; versus &quot;eerie&quot; in his book on these two concepts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The weird involves a presence, not necessarily horrific or terrifying, but off kilter, eliciting a sense of not belonging or, if it belongs, then our priors (Bayesian speak) must be what&#39;s off. We may live in a different world than we expected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The eerie is more about a rekeying of intentionality, shifting the emphasis from human agents with free will, to tricks and flips of fate. Again, the eerie might be employed or evoked by a writer of horror genre fiction, but the eerie need not be scary so much as haunting, as if by dim memories or a sense of deja vu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mark dives into various authors (Lovecraft...) and filmmakers (David Lynch... Hitchcock), as well as musicians (Brian Eno...) to make his points and tease apart these meanings. I&#39;m enjoying such investigations as they jibe with my own philosophical background as a Wittgensteinian. When we want to know the meanings of words, running to a dictionary is the lazy option.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Naturally, the unconscious is not far below the surface in Mark&#39;s analysis, and Freud figures prominently, in part as an authority to overcome, as Freud&#39;s use of &quot;uncanny&quot; has tended to obscure the nuances Mark is attempting to capture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I wrote to a friend in the background:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Is &quot;queer&quot; insulting though?&amp;nbsp; Deja vu we might&#39;ve had this conversation?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;I&#39;m watching old lectures by one Mark Fisher, philosopher, author of&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Real Capitalism&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;and other books, including one on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.amazon.com/Weird-Eerie-Mark-Fisher-ebook/dp/B01DHWAMCI/&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1721747097031000&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw02e_TSvqycHd8T7BEm2q6Z&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Weird-Eerie-Mark-Fisher-ebook/dp/B01DHWAMCI/&quot; style=&quot;color: #1155cc;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;eerie and the weird&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(just purchased).&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s adjacent to the old meaning of &quot;queer&quot; as in &quot;odd&quot; or &quot;different&quot;, but oftentimes in a positive sense as in &quot;novel&quot; or &quot;out of the box&quot; (&quot;the box&quot; being stuffy and stultifying).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Speaking for myself, I like being called an &quot;odd duck&quot; and stuff like that, &quot;a martian&quot; one of my favorites.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Again, summarizing some of my thinking, to another friend I wrote:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Podcast taking up Mark Fisher&#39;s book on the eerie and the weird:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://youtu.be/4gSpNIct1-0&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1721748649078000&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw3OLdWM-WpnvrnkOAESr6H0&quot; href=&quot;https://youtu.be/4gSpNIct1-0&quot; style=&quot;color: #1155cc;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://youtu.be/4gSpNIct1-0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;They explicitly address obtuse / dense academic language and how Mark steers clear of it for the most part.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;My focus has been&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Martian Math&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;as embedded within or serving as a portal to science fiction as a genre, which sometimes borders on the eerie / weird as well as on horror (adjacent / overlapping genres).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;The sense of humans embedded in an inhuman (nonhuman) intelligence comes through in episodes featuring uncanny synchronicity for example.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Human writers could not have written this&quot; is the sense.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Or it&#39;ll be a combination:&amp;nbsp; an outlandish human project goes wrong, or not as planned, thanks to the surreal aspects of life itself.&amp;nbsp; That can be a good thing, if the human project was misguided or nefarious in the first place.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;The sense of divine intervention, angelic or demonic, is a counter to human hubris. Humans may have had a hand in world affairs, but are ultimately not in control. The Ouija Board comes to mind, and that sense everyone has that they&#39;re not the ones moving the planchette.&amp;nbsp; The (collective) unconscious versus the ego persona.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;There&#39;s a whole segment towards the end of the podcast about how it sounds weird or strange to remind people that the country they imagine they live in is all make believe e.g. the line between the USA and Mexico or the USA and Canada, is all imaginary-fictional. To remind people that their &quot;world&quot; is a fantasy based in social conventions, is to elicit an alien viewpoint, which I&#39;ve called ETPV (ET point of view) in other writings.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;In the background:&amp;nbsp; Bucky&#39;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Grunch of Giants&lt;/i&gt;, about untethered capitalism versus cosmic evolution.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/631860487932019491'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/631860487932019491'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/07/keep-portland-queer.html' title='Keep Portland Queer'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi8K_v6BmjdWXS088Whyphenhyphenx1cCB5I5y4jcVl0Cn3busyrLybcXTFdOCh_nmNnHBO6b3DbHyNZC22hvnM3R9YNKSeJYgKVts-Wm5M2YRscwaVhSEODH1k-dijSuI0Xf4R6HC630urswWi9w0aP-z4CFgzSl6VAP1C-0ddicMA-fEiogqVqi13GMC38/s72-w400-h240-c/1024px-Keep_Portland_Weird_(17658598119)%20copy.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4239594069826031414</id><published>2024-07-18T10:58:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-07-18T11:19:43.392-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Government Issue</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m juggling more balls, or spinning more dishes (a different circus act), thanks to my ramping up within my Clarusway work environment again. I get a different email account and access to the various company drives containing courses I&#39;ll be teaching and/or have taught previously. Having both accounts active and switching back and forth means blocking / unblocking various Google drives and so on, as I switch identities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m thinking back to my childhood and growing up and how &quot;government issue&quot; took this weird turn such that &quot;GI&quot; meant a lot to people, in terms of both &quot;the GI Bill&quot; and &quot;GI Joes&quot;, the latter being plastic dolls with more of a social role &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/03/hb2u-barbie.html&quot;&gt;than Ken dolls&lt;/a&gt;, being soldiers. None of the Kens were military if I&#39;m not mistaken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In some alternative worlds, Uncle Sam issued &quot;GI phones&quot; as a kind of fallback smartphone anyone could get with sufficient proof of need, maybe not income based. Simply claim one. The apps would offer courseware deliberately tailored to groom (not a bad word) future government personnel.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to keep living in a democracy, you have to plan ahead, and having everyone grow up in non-democratic hierarchies (not every church or corporation is an unprogrammed Quaker meeting recall) is hardly a way to nurture the relevant skill sets. No wonder we&#39;re &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/06/all-american.html&quot;&gt;all out of diplomats&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When all you have are amateur paramilitary types (&lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/10/truisms.html&quot;&gt;Ollie North types&lt;/a&gt; as I call &#39;em), then all you get are covert operations. You need real statesmen to preserve a civilization, vs having rogue gangland mercenaries commit &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2022/07/antsy-engineers.html&quot;&gt;NS2 type&lt;/a&gt; terrorism, by definition not the game of proudly overt states.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve fallen below threshold, perhaps because we no longer have &quot;GI anything&quot; anymore. GI just means &quot;gastro-intestinal&quot; today, and just about every joe or jill has a tract like that. No government can take credit for such basic gear and equipment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&#39;t be the first to suggest &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/01/playing-with-dolls.html&quot;&gt;Ken&lt;/a&gt; needs to learn from GI Joe, in terms of knowing how to fly a helicopter and lift stranded hikers off mountains. EMTs in general like adjacent to the Coast Guard, in turn adjacent to the other branches.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We learned during that South Pacific tsunami during Dan Rather&#39;s tenure that the GI people enjoy responding to natural disasters, helping people, regardless of &quot;race, religion or credo&quot;. That&#39;s a hint, I think, about how to rebalance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We need &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2023/11/wheres-magic.html&quot;&gt;a breed of GIs&lt;/a&gt; that aren&#39;t cannon fodder for the grand strategist wannabes who still think like its the 1900s.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4239594069826031414'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4239594069826031414'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/07/government-issue.html' title='Government Issue'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2120982967756291826</id><published>2024-07-08T16:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-07-09T12:30:28.683-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Turning Back the Clock</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Per &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/uMXYxeVhliI&quot;&gt;my intake interview&lt;/a&gt;, as I think of it, I mentioned my goal of &quot;turning back the clock&quot;. I was referring to the so-called &lt;a href=&quot;https://thebulletin.org/doomsday-clock/current-time/&quot;&gt;Doomsday Clock&lt;/a&gt; of the atomic scientists, the ones who tell us how &quot;close to midnight&quot; we might be (really close in their estimation). &quot;Midnight&quot; means WW4 (per &lt;i&gt;Critical Path&lt;/i&gt;, I&#39;m going with &quot;WW3&quot; as the cold one, still ongoing).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rather than manufacture a ton of consensus around the clock turning back, let&#39;s say to a quarter &#39;til, I should offer my thesis as to why I&#39;m right about where we&#39;re at, relatively far from WW4, based on something other than majority rule (oxymoron?) or majority perception.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, we&#39;re not on the brink of nuke war because both the Russian and American elites (and I&#39;m not talking about average rich people, as clueless as they come) are at ease with where we appear to be going, in terms of World Game and energy sharing. The Chinese too.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We all read &lt;i&gt;Operating Manual for Spaceship Earth&lt;/i&gt; in the 1970s. We &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/12/global-data-global-matrix.html&quot;&gt;didn&#39;t forget&lt;/a&gt; our thinking and plans when the helpless children, grownups in name only, took command of the various dashboards now disconnected from reality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No, I&#39;m not saying the elites enjoy a level of telepathy the muggles don&#39;t experience, or that our oracles at Delphi give us the insider view. I&#39;m saying if you do your homework, you&#39;ll find that legacy media tend to waste people&#39;s time with low quality narratives designed for know-nothings. More glimmers of the truth shine through here and there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a world wherein the default is to get force fed a nasty diet of drivel and bad info, one can&#39;t then turn around and blame the hoi polloi for not being able to follow. Of course they can&#39;t. Let&#39;s hope at least a few find their way out of that cesspool.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I sound like &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/08/elitism.html&quot;&gt;an elitist snob&lt;/a&gt;, that&#39;s by design. At least I&#39;m not a mindless hawk like &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/08/city-of-morons.html&quot;&gt;those morons&lt;/a&gt; in the US congress, or like those so-called &quot;justices&quot; (no longer respected), or like the dysfunctional executive branch. If I&#39;m not a hawk, does that make me a dove? Why so little imagination? I&#39;ll be a crow instead.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2120982967756291826'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2120982967756291826'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/07/turning-back-clock.html' title='Turning Back the Clock'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6801381619606965772</id><published>2024-07-03T06:15:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-07-15T08:20:24.899-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Attitude Tuning</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;If you poke around in my blogs, you&#39;ll know I&#39;m big into &quot;citizen diplomacy&quot;. But what does that mean? Humans learning to be diplomatic took time. Diplomas had to be invented first, meaning universities. Instead of Universe, call it University why not?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays we have all these personal workspaces (PWSs) using Zoom every day, or perhaps they use other channels. Or they&#39;re recording straight to YouTube, via live stream or as completed, likely edited, projects. By this means, diplomacy proceeds, in the form of continual &quot;attitude adjustments&quot;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re in an activist role, then &quot;attitude&quot; has to do with observation and orientation in an OODA loop sense. You&#39;ll be taking active measures based on updates to the cockpit (fighter jet talk). If you&#39;re passive, you may yet be following closely. These terms come with so many shades of meaning.&amp;nbsp; As a &quot;passivist&quot; you may feel you&#39;re studying for a more active role later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Americans with relative expertise and education have more powers than before, thanks to the more evolved telecommunications infrastructure. We see the trend is really with respect to Earthians in general. Earth is still becoming more like America, but that doesn&#39;t mean &quot;led by the Beltway Mafia&quot; so much as &quot;benefitting from unbridled communications&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &quot;motherboard&quot; (if we might call it that -- think &quot;the grapevine&quot; if old school) is better able to keep pace with change, in a virtuous circle, to the extent we&#39;re all able to participate in the important business of being citizen diplomats. Or shall we say &quot;layman diplomats&quot;? To what extent is citizenship required, to travel the globe? Does every trucker crossing a border someplace have a passport?&amp;nbsp; Is every gypsy caravan &quot;from a country&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve always had &quot;the masses&quot; and / or &quot;public opinion&quot;, or have for a long time. The process of &quot;manufacturing consent&quot; might have been more top-down in an age before we all became &quot;channelers&quot; (in the sense of having a channel).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, the processing has to run deeper, and maybe for longer, but the outcomes are proportionally better anchored in real mindsets. Crummy propaganda becomes less effective in proportion to &quot;influencers&quot; becoming familiar with &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2022/12/of-sex-and-gender.html&quot;&gt;PR techniques&lt;/a&gt;. The audience (active and/or passive) has become so much more sophisticated.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6801381619606965772'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6801381619606965772'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/07/attitude-tuning.html' title='Attitude Tuning'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6486600036956933210</id><published>2024-06-24T14:48:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-06-27T07:47:00.828-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Don&#39;t Look Up</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjKUjcQs9yLpEBKYkJcMTvaeicsblVYUsQs2l5qZxK6Gggil8dhEfUqFcmsa8X8Z1RGcuyCr0igEL6D0Za77_97HijtyFRp-BqlTnLdlvGmzXdS9fj7hYtk4_H3OnbfnUdPKdkknLZUSVApjpL6_oAOWDp1j3MHulU_mQD7JLkEZ2fdXJZ4-OHK/s1024/epcot_ball_6.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjKUjcQs9yLpEBKYkJcMTvaeicsblVYUsQs2l5qZxK6Gggil8dhEfUqFcmsa8X8Z1RGcuyCr0igEL6D0Za77_97HijtyFRp-BqlTnLdlvGmzXdS9fj7hYtk4_H3OnbfnUdPKdkknLZUSVApjpL6_oAOWDp1j3MHulU_mQD7JLkEZ2fdXJZ4-OHK/w400-h400/epcot_ball_6.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Spaceship Earth by AI&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/06/emerging-ethnicities.html&quot;&gt;ethnicities and culture wars&lt;/a&gt; (aren&#39;t all wars about cultures, or between them?), one reason &lt;i&gt;Star Wars&lt;/i&gt; fans might be taking out their frustration on Papa Disney is escapism just isn&#39;t working across the board. We&#39;re in the middle of a hot war between superpowers and the message &quot;don&#39;t look up&quot; is ringing hollow. The billionaires are already moving into their luxury apartment bomb shelters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mad Max (&lt;i&gt;Furiosa&lt;/i&gt;) didn&#39;t attract big audiences either. &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/05/high-desert-circuits.html&quot;&gt;I saw it&lt;/a&gt;. A well made film, for what it was, but what it was, was too close for comfort. Showing a post-apocalyptic idiocracy on the big screen is somewhat triggering, not conducive to escapism.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Dune 2&lt;/i&gt;, on the other hand, was in a convincingly different alt universe, and that&#39;s what we need, if seeking anti-realism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As of this writing, the Pentagon, circuitry &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/06/all-american.html&quot;&gt;controlled by outsiders&lt;/a&gt;, is busy using high powered weapons to strike inside Russia, with no permission or understanding from the American people.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The calmness in the streets has to do with their not really following the action. It might also have to do with countervailing media, which throw ice water on the whole business, playing up the war game escapism currently underway and offering a more credible, less dystopian, world game instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The stridently arrogant of this world want to plunge us into conflagrations. The result is not surprising: the circuitry is rewiring to lock out the outsiders, if possible, to disconnect them from their arsenals, to which their continued access is now unauthorized.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When people believing themselves to be insiders wake up to their actual NPC status, that&#39;ll be a good day. In the meantime, we&#39;re being victimized &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/08/city-of-morons.html&quot;&gt;by morons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6486600036956933210'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6486600036956933210'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/06/dont-look-up.html' title='Don&#39;t Look Up'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjKUjcQs9yLpEBKYkJcMTvaeicsblVYUsQs2l5qZxK6Gggil8dhEfUqFcmsa8X8Z1RGcuyCr0igEL6D0Za77_97HijtyFRp-BqlTnLdlvGmzXdS9fj7hYtk4_H3OnbfnUdPKdkknLZUSVApjpL6_oAOWDp1j3MHulU_mQD7JLkEZ2fdXJZ4-OHK/s72-w400-h400-c/epcot_ball_6.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8412894223952005489</id><published>2024-06-18T02:47:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-27T08:48:35.392-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Emerging Ethnicities</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;My vision of the world rallying to the needs of the besieged in Gaza and setting up an evacuation flotilla was counter what borders are all about: restricting freedom of movement, penning people in, subjecting them to the authority of whomever happens to be exercising jurisdiction over whatever region they happen to be trapped in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the SimU game, campuses dot the globe and students, faculty, admins flit about more freely, engaged in work-study. The question &quot;where are you from?&quot; is considered fairly bogus, unless it means &quot;where were you born?&quot;. Obviously we&#39;re all from Planet Earth and each of us wanders its surface to some degree.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&#39;t expect any top down &quot;world government&quot; to take care of these movements. Migration patterns are not always subject to tight regulation by bureaucracies. On the other hand, campuses with liberal intake policies may nevertheless be able to track enrollees. I&#39;m able to write science fiction about it all, drawing from existing patterns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll find people deliberately confusing &quot;genocide&quot; with &quot;ethnic cleansing&quot; all the time, because they don&#39;t want to think too hard. Nor is ethnicity a static attribute. If your ethnic group has been bombed or otherwise attacked by another one, that tends to change your ethnicity.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may now have a permanent grudge, an ax to grind, that you didn&#39;t have before. Or perhaps your ethnicity is about not carrying grudges. Your discipline is about working through negative emotions and finding ways to transform them. A lot depends on what anchoring religions and/or metaphysical disciplines you want governing your life, which preferences change with time, as possibilities are revealed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I still envision mixed-use skyscrapers and other buildings, some of which identify as New Palestine University (NPU) or simply Palestine, but it&#39;s more a corporate logo than a national flag, in the sense that no contiguous boundary around a large geographical region is presumed. &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/03/diaspora-nations.html&quot;&gt;Diaspora nations&lt;/a&gt; (the best kind) dot the world with assets.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contiguous boundaries have mostly been replaced with credentials and access to specific goods and services, specific facilities, such as on a US military base in the Philippines, and/or through a university.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Am I saying I&#39;m a practitioner of &quot;zionetics&quot; or one of those, meaning I&#39;m eager to cleanse Palestine of Palestinians?&amp;nbsp; No. All these ethnicities are already globally distributed. I don&#39;t have to lift a finger.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let Palestinians come and go as they please, via &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palestinian_Airlines&quot;&gt;Palestinian Airlines&lt;/a&gt; or whatever. But with an early emphasis on &quot;go&quot; i.e. to get away from toxic neighbors. Return when the neighborhood improves? It&#39;s up to individuals, unless they break too many rules. Banishment remains a practice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m free, as an American, to laugh at &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2021/08/from-quaker-website.html&quot;&gt;the Louisiana Purchase&lt;/a&gt; as the science fiction it was and is. I&#39;m free to make light of ethnicities that take the idea of nation states so uber seriously, or that believe in &quot;races&quot; at the cost of sacrificing an ability to think globally. I don&#39;t have to brainwash myself the same way they do, nor am I compelled to respect their choices, as many Jews and/or Christians and/or Muslims etc. likewise do not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;My ethnicity also doesn&#39;t feel compelled to always agree that &quot;space is 3D&quot; even if we&#39;re well-versed in that metaphysics. We have our own namespaces. That&#39;s in part how we bond. Given telecommunications, we don&#39;t feel compelled to all move to the same base in Arizona or Utah or whatever. We might build a school in Gaza, perhaps near to a McDonald&#39;s or a&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #111111;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/2pY729b&quot;&gt;Vkusno i Tochka&lt;/a&gt;, the way schools are in Oregon (next to fast food joints).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8412894223952005489'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8412894223952005489'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/06/emerging-ethnicities.html' title='Emerging Ethnicities'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5659996299181967944</id><published>2024-06-03T14:59:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-06-18T08:44:20.902-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Journaling Freely</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;One would imagine a city of screenwriters like LA could work backwards from our wanting that &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2023/04/mixed-use-high-rises.html&quot;&gt;mixed use floor space&lt;/a&gt; in office towers yesterday. Does that mean remodeling every floor into apartments? Does it mean hauling a sleeping bag to your office? How about a cot?&amp;nbsp; Where does a family find its privacy barriers?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Zoom revolution helped, and was coming with or without covid, but yes, the sars2 virus helped catalyze killing the commute for many a &quot;cube farmer&quot;, planners know this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s needed are high functioning managers who know how to work with others from the inside out, as resident advisers. We used to call them community organizers, but the stereotypes there exclude most business sector talent.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What holds these groups together is less a religion and more an economics theory, such as GST, which is personal workspace centric and conversant with &quot;global university&quot; networking.&amp;nbsp; Such &quot;faculty&quot; will be among the first &quot;boots on the ground&quot; in the back rooms or liminal spaces of virtual community formation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not everyone is cut out for such work, to state the obvious, and when it comes to drug rehab, lets admit that outdoor settings are oft preferred.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting penned up with people undergoing withdrawal is impractical. This isn&#39;t prison we&#39;re talking about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deke the Geek has been studying UIs forever, so you might think we&#39;d have the knowledge engineering dashboards by now, but he&#39;s not sufficiently integrated within campus circuitry / security.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The programming curriculum is a joke, I say as an insider, because it&#39;s starving the right brain, even if you don&#39;t believe right brains might be starved, or what the consequences might be for doing so. Nevertheless, the hegemony of the lexical lefties is sometimes palpably oppressive.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We need more of a movie industry around all the good stuff happening in human services, made by the humans served.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For readers just joining us, you won&#39;t have the context of QuarterWorld style gamification floors where we experiment with those alternative curricula y&#39;all have been sending us, at least in idea form. I&#39;d get first dibs at the trough sometimes, meaning I&#39;d be one of the first to promote it if I thought it worthy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who knows what the world might have been like, had&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Strange Attractors&lt;/i&gt; seen the light of day (a toy I worked on, and which got as far as a shrink wrapped box).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhrqQhexb9zUoNowgqah7FTr2r7KiTZDeMAs2vi6NYsb-XqvCpKaaGFOMYqTD54kiHXJJ_811jikGhBc86J2bWr2iA8ONj6FdrzD7YvDhtSLZ8PbDDn1wKw4S1pMspCJRBSNKl2F3GtoSijxvvil0ZeldzUQR6Oo75GypmHcsu2H-EPQN72Fdv7/s640/3059391246_4f39f287fe_z.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;480&quot; data-original-width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhrqQhexb9zUoNowgqah7FTr2r7KiTZDeMAs2vi6NYsb-XqvCpKaaGFOMYqTD54kiHXJJ_811jikGhBc86J2bWr2iA8ONj6FdrzD7YvDhtSLZ8PbDDn1wKw4S1pMspCJRBSNKl2F3GtoSijxvvil0ZeldzUQR6Oo75GypmHcsu2H-EPQN72Fdv7/s320/3059391246_4f39f287fe_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deke would still need to drive around and recruit for these shelters, by which I mean these former office towers downtown, some of which have suitable facilities for these different levels of refugee. We have the local clientele, and we have the more globally routed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Portland has long served as a refugee resettlement business, with my place of employment (CUE) providing some of the framework. A lot of my Palestinian connections trace to that chapter, adding to my already robust ties to the Jewish community, although I admit to not knowing many Israelis (I&#39;ve not visited since the 1970s, and by now it&#39;s a different country they tell me).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Portland needs to experiment with various levels of world livingry service industry logistical assistance, as I&#39;ve been brainstorming as a kind of &quot;outdoor Ikea&quot; around the Port Authority somewhere, I thought &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/08/affordable-utopias.html&quot;&gt;Dignity Village&lt;/a&gt; might be eager to branch out.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NGOs and prototyping go together. I called it &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2023/08/project-renaissance.html&quot;&gt;Project Renaissance&lt;/a&gt;, but NATO took things in a different direction. I chalk that up to cultural illiteracy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some people in government have less than a high school level education, when you factor in what [real] high school looks like in the 2020s. Adults need it badly, as much or more than the teens.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boomers who didn&#39;t get lucky with Bucky the first time (almost all of them) deserve another crack at the synergetic singularity, a boat they&#39;ve hitherto missed, no thanks to the hypercross dogmatists.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5659996299181967944'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5659996299181967944'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/06/journaling-freely.html' title='Journaling Freely'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhrqQhexb9zUoNowgqah7FTr2r7KiTZDeMAs2vi6NYsb-XqvCpKaaGFOMYqTD54kiHXJJ_811jikGhBc86J2bWr2iA8ONj6FdrzD7YvDhtSLZ8PbDDn1wKw4S1pMspCJRBSNKl2F3GtoSijxvvil0ZeldzUQR6Oo75GypmHcsu2H-EPQN72Fdv7/s72-c/3059391246_4f39f287fe_z.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5895758416560351826</id><published>2024-05-26T18:55:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-06-24T15:53:20.543-07:00</updated><title type='text'>High Desert Circuits</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/53749072454/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Near Smith Rock&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Near Smith Rock&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53749072454_a2e1a49218.jpg&quot; width=&quot;449&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&#39;m back in KPOV country, in what we call high desert Oregon. People take music seriously in proportion to what else is going on, it seems to me. In any case, here and in the midwest I&#39;ve discovered some of the most seriously music-oriented subcultures. Shout out to WEFT in Champaign-Urbana.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m hopeful I&#39;ll get to meet with The Other again for a spell, the host of the Saturday noon Psychedelic Rebellion, one of my favorite shows. I tune in just about any radio station via Radio Garden, an app on my iPad. I&#39;m listening to KPOV right now in fact.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last night, our party made it &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/05/mad-max-fury-road-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;to &lt;i&gt;Furiosa&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the latest mega-movie epic extravaganza in the Mad Max post apocalyptic idiocracy series. We caught it at &lt;i&gt;The Bagdad&lt;/i&gt;. All I&#39;ll say here is the transition to a more Smith Rock style environment the next day felt prefigured, although we&#39;re still in a Land of Abundance here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This computer book I picked up for free from a Lil Library (curbside) in the hood (foreword by Ward Cunningham), reminds us that Party is a great moniker, akin to Entity in allowing for many subclasses, such as families, any table of clientele at a restaurant. I&#39;m thinking of the famous little tips database. Smokers? Really? We&#39;re biased to think in terms of &quot;political parties&quot;, not so much &quot;party lines&quot; (as in telephony, a forgotten meaning, not as in &quot;toeing the party line&quot;). These &quot;biases&quot; get reflected in word2vec type data sculptures (slowly moving, heavy mobiles in the wind, tubular bells).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been into helping Judy catch up on the various Art World advances occurring on a broad front collectively referred to as EayEai in the literature i.e. &quot;AI&quot;. I&#39;ve just added &quot;EayEai&quot; to my dictionary as I can see reasons to clutter my namespace with such a monstrosity. Right up there with &quot;egg-zist&quot;. She&#39;s a musician, more into country folk than &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Q8VfA2ev9ok&quot;&gt;goa trance&lt;/a&gt;. We share a love of &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/G-z0XxOigPs&quot;&gt;Swingle Swingers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; doing Bach numbers. We were both nerdy as kids I guess.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Part of my demo involved prompting &quot;Giant King Kong gorilla climbs smith rock in Oregon with mountains in the background and surprised hikers in the foreground&quot; and getting the above. No post production editing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, we stopped at &lt;i&gt;Eagle Crossing&lt;/i&gt;, although I didn&#39;t take Sydney inside. That&#39;s a family favorite, a great place to get fry bread.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5895758416560351826'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5895758416560351826'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/05/high-desert-circuits.html' title='High Desert Circuits'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-254828433468449317</id><published>2024-05-22T01:34:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-22T15:25:48.531-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Cryptic Crossing</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;The problem with the unit edge unit volume tetrahedron is it came up against the Bayesian priors. &quot;We can&#39;t be wrong about the unit cube&quot; and indeed that&#39;s true, and therefore we can&#39;t be right about it. Truisms ain&#39;t true in the empirical sense. One doesn&#39;t discover such a tetrahedron, one defines it into existence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However there&#39;s a popular understanding around mathematics in particular, that adheres to orthodoxies more generally: that there&#39;s one right way with some bemusing alternatives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This attitude started to waver in maths with the invention of so-called non-Euclidean geometries. What appeared as cracks in the structure, the edifice, were coming from Cantor&#39;s corner too.&amp;nbsp; The priesthood was all about closing ranks and plugging the holes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The only window open, through which to discuss incompleteness, would become Godel&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The way to counter the Bayesian priors was incremental. We had to keep adding to the apparatus, showing applications and advantages. The natural sciences were cooperating. What would the world have to be like for this model to explain this evidence?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What evidence?&amp;nbsp; The nucleocapsid of the virus at first. 10FF + 2 got some airplay in the &lt;i&gt;NY Herald Tribune&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Positive whole number addressing of CCP balls looked pretty interesting. The &quot;quadrays&quot; apparatus provided those. Linear combinations of {2, 1, 1, 0} would get us to the Waterman Polyhedrons (a set I helped name, with no objections from Steve).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That children might work with fractions such as 1/8 (Mite) and 1/24 (A &amp;amp; B), with the concept of congruence abetted by chirality (left and right, inside out), while getting more comfortable scaling and rotating polyhedrons, was exciting to a few teachers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/02/sixth-grade-geometry.html&quot;&gt;Very few&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In these terms, of internal modeling and inferencing, we&#39;ll be addressing &quot;bleeped over the Bucky stuff&quot; as an historical topic, the whys and wherefores.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;People have these Bayesian brains deeply stuck in some ruts, and for good reasons. Until those reasons grow stale and the brain&#39;s neuroplasticity gets called upon. Time for an update sleepyheads.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t let those three horses, Height, Width and Depth, drag your bandwagon off the road. Make the sign of the Z (zig zag zig).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: verdana;&quot;&gt;Z + Z&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.87);&quot;&gt;⋈&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;4D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can keep saying &quot;space is 3D&quot; though, as XYZ is mucho useful. Then dive off the deep end into any number of Coxeter (spatial) dimensions. You&#39;ll wash up on the shores of Natural Language Processing, ready for Word2Vec (and Doc2Vec). King - male = Queen - female etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What has to go is the &quot;room for only one way of thinking&quot; school (mindset). Share the road. Impoliteness on behalf of &quot;absolute truth&quot; is nothing if not butt-ugly zealotry. Sometimes God&#39;s little monsters ain&#39;t pretty to contemplate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back to the bleeping: being overspecialized, most boomers assumed other boomers were looking into it, but few were, certainly not the most self admiring. The resulting vacuum or dead spot (dead air) only grew, adding a phony hollowness to an already crumbling (shall we say charlatanical) world view.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once it became safer to question boomer authority, people under thirty started to pick up on what had been censored, made verboten, deplatformed. That was an eye-opener.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So does all this cultural crumbling mean all the old orthodoxies are about to be swept away? Of course not.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heavy stones with high inertia never turn on a dime, let alone the &lt;i&gt;Titanic&lt;/i&gt;. Enjoy the ride!&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/254828433468449317'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/254828433468449317'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/05/cryptic-crossing.html' title='Cryptic Crossing'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1401226442411830725</id><published>2024-05-15T10:47:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-16T11:00:56.086-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Knowledge Engineering (KE)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/53723825035/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;City Emblem&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;City Emblem&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53723825035_01e3a5d933.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge Engineering (KE) is a source of mnemonic devices, and we discussed a few of them. Such devices may be literal objects from everyday experience, such as prescription lenses (personalized to correct for distortions), &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/05/more-lore.html&quot;&gt;or more fantastical&lt;/a&gt; or abstract.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, under Geometry we find the Coupler or &quot;crazy diamond&quot; as some would call it. The combinatorics of A and B modules, in their assembly of the space-filling Coupler matrix, is where Bucky himself expected to find particle physics minded proteges, in search of their GUTs and TOEs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An entire city may become infused with mnemonic signifiers, both in consensus reality (CR) in the form a statues, memorials, proper named streets, and in non-consensus realities (NCRs), perhaps special to an individual author of specific novels. I&#39;m thinking of &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/05/closing-gap.html&quot;&gt;James Joyce&lt;/a&gt; and Dublin of course.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Portland, favored by the movie and TV industries, has been weirdly lensed through several fictional series, most famously &lt;i&gt;Portlandia&lt;/i&gt;, officially comic satire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea of an entirely open source farm becomes pretty all-encompassing once we factor in the computer chips we&#39;re using.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The apps target smartphones, so those have to be open as well.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The apps control or at least schedule the tractors, the irrigation systems, some of the bookkeeping. Transparency in accounting is also required.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who would do this? A university wanting to show off the &quot;model farm&quot; with no deceptive tricks, perhaps. Or a government in the business of proving ideal cases, which the private sector might learn from.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1401226442411830725'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1401226442411830725'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/05/knowledge-engineering-ke.html' title='Knowledge Engineering (KE)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4803266913238211194</id><published>2024-05-13T14:14:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-06-02T11:53:10.519-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Spirit of Portland</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72177720316905545&quot; title=&quot;Portland Timbers&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Portland Timbers&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53712546504_3d79eb7d64.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;(embedded slides, takes longer to load sometimes)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4803266913238211194'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4803266913238211194'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/05/spirit-of-portland.html' title='Spirit of Portland'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3960538028102905699</id><published>2024-05-10T09:55:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-10T17:06:46.503-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Articulating Globalism</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;As some of my readers might recognize, I invest in &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2019/02/what-is-globalism.html&quot;&gt;globalism&lt;/a&gt;&quot; as a term, given it&#39;s out of fashion at the moment, meaning few are using it for anything positive, which leaves the field to risk takers like me.&amp;nbsp; TV personalities get to sneer when they say globalism, as if we all share the same meaning. I find their sneering attitude on the incomprehensible side sometimes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;If anyone is gonna carry on with the &quot;globalist&quot; label, it oughta be &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2016/11/thinking-globally.html&quot;&gt;a guy like me&lt;/a&gt; (right?), with an expat background and massive exposure to the Dymaxion™ product line aka the Bucky stuff.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Our family even had United Nations passports there for a bit, when dad took a job with UNDP vis-a-vis Manila Bay reclamation and associated projects. I&#39;m a product of international schools, a poster child for &quot;growing up around the world&quot; (yes, there&#39;re a lot of us).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;So how does a globalist react towards nationalism?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Firstly, we need to pluralize. Just as we have many religions, not one religion, we have many flavors of nationalism and globalism, and they&#39;re &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;all logically interchangeable.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;So let&#39;s speak of nationalist and globalist mindsets with respect for variety.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;We have &quot;nationalisms&quot; and &quot;globalisms&quot; to compare and contrast.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Let&#39;s look at two Telegram messages I put out there recently, in random conversation:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot; style=&quot;font-feature-settings: normal; font-kerning: auto; font-optical-sizing: auto; font-stretch: normal; font-variant-alternates: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-position: normal; font-variation-settings: normal; line-height: normal; margin: 0px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;; font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;Nations have always been virtual and dependent on networks. The power of the British Empire gave us a last opportunity to agree on borders for classroom globes. Those days are done.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;And:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;; font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;...the supranational corporations showed how immense power and wealth may be secured using networks of campuses versus contiguous borders and the age of “diaspora nations” (network nations, virtual nations) was born.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Given telecommunications, air travel and so on, it&#39;s not science fiction fantastic to think in terms of Virtual Nations (VNs), as another name for Diaspora Nations or Network Nations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;That&#39;s why I&#39;m more likely to advocate for global dispersion and regrouping as a way of handling the Gaza crisis: New Palestine University is about curating, preserving, and establishing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/05/dream-state.html&quot;&gt;new patterns&lt;/a&gt; associated with global living and citizenship in the VNs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;The new &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/02/network-nations.html&quot;&gt;NPU&lt;/a&gt; campuses will in theory be outside the radius of menacing ethnic enclaves armed with WMDs. I&#39;ve been brainstorming about having one or more &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2023/10/gazans-to-guantanamo.html&quot;&gt;in Cuba&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;As for &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2022/09/statecraft-crafting-of-states.html&quot;&gt;classroom globes&lt;/a&gt;, any teacher with historical awareness and an understanding of current affairs has to bring all kinds of caveats to bear when sharing a political map of the world, whether flat or spherical.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Calling the political layer a &quot;data layer&quot; and recognizing its virtual nature, bespeaks my globalist approach to Google Earth type projects. Users get to pick their skins.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;In Moscow, the newly federated oblasts show up in the Russian Federation already. In London, they might disallow such skins for classroom use and still show Crimea as part of some British-Roman Empire or whatever.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;In my School of Tomorrow, we flip through skins from around the world, showing there&#39;s no United Nations consensus reality (CR) anymore, as we might have once enjoyed under Pax Americana (remember Pan Am?).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Then we zoom back and understand there has rarely been any kind of consensus reality regarding borders. Sovereigns simply claim territory, and some may get enough agreement to then sell it, as the French did to the USG (Thomas Jefferson et al), of Louisiana and environs (the so-called Louisiana Purchase). Napoleon needed the dough.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;CR and NCR (non-consensus reality) come from Process Work and the Process Work Institute here in Portland. Check&amp;nbsp; out&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Quantum Mind&lt;/i&gt; by Dr. Arnold Mindell.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;At the coffee shop yesterday, in addition to speaking up for Palestinians who want to voluntarily leave Gaza (a hell hole, who wouldn&#39;t want to leave at this point?), I cast aspersions on the kind of nationalism that keeps people penned in even when their local situation is untenable.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Seeing nations as open air prisons that only privileged elites are allowed to escape from, thanks to having the right Grunch credentials, is characteristic of many nationalisms I&#39;ve encountered.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Ultimately, I&#39;d say my flavor of globalism is compatible with &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt; flavors of nationalism.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;If you see the human animal as highly programmable, and see the political layer as a way of conditioning reflexes, creating civilized pockets and polite societies, a layer characterized by the rule of law and diplomacy, then we see somewhat eye to eye. Pax Americana was better than Pax UK or Pax Rome in my view. We improved our powers to co-exists, thanks to growing literacy, communication skills and, dare I say it, shared global perspectives.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Better &quot;social engineering&quot; -- I know, I know: people fear that term, but it&#39;s somewhat inevitable given etymological meanings, plus it adds a spin or bias (weight) to &quot;engineering&quot; that&#39;s potentially Silicon Forest compatible -- is always a possibility.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;We (the forestry engineers -- solarpunk influence) have room to let people hold on to their &quot;bag of beliefs&quot; whatever the bag. Live and let live.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;One needs cognitive frameworks, simply to get out of bed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Why go around shooting down others&#39; belief systems if the true believers seem satisfied with their lifestyle?&amp;nbsp; This liberal attitude applies to belief in nation-states as well. Let them believe in their Caesars.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Why turn it into a story of &quot;us against them&quot; especially when we (the globalists) seem highly outnumbered?&amp;nbsp; Lets even &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/04/satori-states.html&quot;&gt;nurture&lt;/a&gt; the best nationalist fantasies, and have our nations get along! Idealism has its place as a morale booster.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;The influence of &lt;i&gt;Star Trek&lt;/i&gt; and the Prime Directive is also coming through (thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/02/sociology-day.html&quot;&gt;Anthropology Department&lt;/a&gt;) meaning it&#39;s not necessarily my job and/or business to talk people out of their programming, even if I had the wherewithal. You&#39;ve got your bag, I&#39;ve got mine.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;My primary guinea pig is me, and if that means if I &quot;talk funny&quot; (or use &quot;silly skins&quot;) then maybe I&#39;ve been making some headway.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: white; font-family: &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;; font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;tions, virtual nations) was born.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot; style=&quot;color: white; font-family: &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;; font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3960538028102905699'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3960538028102905699'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/05/articulating-globalism.html' title='Articulating Globalism'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8686228509213595227</id><published>2024-04-25T17:05:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-04-25T19:48:45.112-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Tetrahelix</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhOkitZN5fY6-GBT621GqAC8A-e9OFqH9ld5vFuZI4xBHzYD2kZzelE8Y0uunUT_IVVPxyDUYj0pl_xim5EfY9J0EnE4fKthhvCTHcnMewBACwa11MaQvVqZliAycgB_IIHxqlJJAPgMt2bcwe8XSglFJJGPCCujDEzVs94K0xcjMKiIqHNWzIf/s759/Screen%20Shot%202024-04-25%20at%207.00.29%20AM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;433&quot; data-original-width=&quot;759&quot; height=&quot;229&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhOkitZN5fY6-GBT621GqAC8A-e9OFqH9ld5vFuZI4xBHzYD2kZzelE8Y0uunUT_IVVPxyDUYj0pl_xim5EfY9J0EnE4fKthhvCTHcnMewBACwa11MaQvVqZliAycgB_IIHxqlJJAPgMt2bcwe8XSglFJJGPCCujDEzVs94K0xcjMKiIqHNWzIf/w400-h229/Screen%20Shot%202024-04-25%20at%207.00.29%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re still waiting for some &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/05/the-blockchain-and-global-u.html&quot;&gt;enterprising blockchain company&lt;/a&gt; to choose the tetrahelix for a core animation. The successive blocks form the twisting path of face-bonded tetrahedra why not? Blocks are blocks. No one said the chained &quot;blocks&quot; have to be orthonormal, an aesthetic considered &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/07/mining-cartoons.html&quot;&gt;uncool in some circles&lt;/a&gt;, given the alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gary Doskas is one of the current masters of tetrahelix lore &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2022/07/a-saturday-fsi-meetup.html&quot;&gt;and I ran the idea by him&lt;/a&gt;, but maybe he doesn&#39;t straddle the geomtech - fintech divide. Few do apparently, or we would have a lot more better toyz by now, counting computer games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clearly I&#39;ve got tetrahedrons on my mind again, as I recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freelists.org/post/math4wisdom/Math-4-Wisdom-event-April-24-Wednesday-Evolution-in-Biology-and-Physics-and,1&quot;&gt;published a narrative&lt;/a&gt; to a couple listservs talking about the so-called &quot;Goldberg Table&quot; wherein Michael Goldberg summarizes what was known about space-filling tetrahedra up to the time of his publishing his paper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The point of my Goldberg story was that Buckminster Fuller is repeatedly cut out of accounts where he&#39;s making serious contributions, either to virology, geometry, architecture or whatever, because there&#39;s always a convenient &quot;inhouse luminary&quot; better positioned to take the credit. From TrimTab (April 25, 2024):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;-webkit-tap-highlight-color: transparent;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: verdana; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;blockquote style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: verdana; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;It just so happened that Fuller&#39;s research carried him over territory being surveyed by professionals in many walks of life at the same time. Virology, the discipline, was bringing them together even more than architecture.&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: verdana; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: verdana; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;The price RBF paid for his comprehensivity (anticipating CJ&#39;s book) was not being best of the best in any of the various fields he was visiting, meaning one could always swap in a home team star come trophy day [1], leaving &quot;good at skipping rocks&quot; his only real claim&amp;nbsp; to fame (I say that whimsic-sarcastically).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote style=&quot;font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The dismissive attitude I&#39;m circling is well-demonstrated by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freelists.org/post/math4wisdom/Parting-with-Kirby-A-new-era&quot;&gt;the lengthy reply&lt;/a&gt; we saw &lt;a href=&quot;https://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2024/04/philosophy-talk.html&quot;&gt;from Andrius&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote style=&quot;font-family: verdana;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;The best we have is this Goldberg table. The point would be to show that polyhedra can fill space. Perhaps that would be useful for a model of dividing up conceptual space, which is actually what I do. But no, you have no interest in actually applying this math scientifically. Your interest is to validate Buckminster Fuller. An honest investigation would dive into that, what is that all about?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;I have not been at all reticent to discuss my interest in validating Fuller&#39;s research. That America&#39;s premier futurist of the 1900s has been deplatformed by so many universities, after their milking his popularity when he could draw the big crowds, and paying students, is somewhat scandalous to say the least. &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2020/04/wrong-again.html&quot;&gt;Applewhite&lt;/a&gt; was always wondering how they got away with it, with impunity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Quoting more from my TrimTab post:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: verdana;&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;Apologies if the ordering was confusing, between Fuller&#39;s compact vocab (mite, rite, bite...) and the Goldberg table of tetrahedral space-fillers coming to be known at the time. That slide (in my&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/13QLfgKo6kyX0j0K0RJ7W0uisB0ZyeBiK-_qbzytipck/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;BEAST deck&lt;/a&gt;) is still evolving.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of Michael Goldberg, Applewhite said he&#39;d met him (I recall asking him about Goldberg specifically, given his key role in our narrative) adding &quot;he didn&#39;t have a mean bone in his body&quot; meaning in that context Ed didn&#39;t believe the guy had any malevolent intention of deliberately messing with Fuller&#39;s self promotion / reputation i.e. he was no kind of villain or foe. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Easy to believe I&#39;d say. &quot;Space filling tetrahedrons&quot; is a pretty obvious topic, when you get right down to bare bones and/or brass tacks, as are subdivisions of a sphere using variable frequencies. &quot;Aristotle was right, remember the MITE&quot; could be are our high school chant, in some weird sci-fi School of Tomorrow. Cue cheerleaders.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;This was the footnote (see above):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;-webkit-tap-highlight-color: transparent; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.87); font-family: verdana, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;[1] per Ed, Fuller was especially hurt when a certain Scientific American article summarizing recent breakthroughs in the field of virology, skipped mentioning him completely. I got to see some of the primary materials.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8686228509213595227'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8686228509213595227'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/04/tetrahelix.html' title='Tetrahelix'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhOkitZN5fY6-GBT621GqAC8A-e9OFqH9ld5vFuZI4xBHzYD2kZzelE8Y0uunUT_IVVPxyDUYj0pl_xim5EfY9J0EnE4fKthhvCTHcnMewBACwa11MaQvVqZliAycgB_IIHxqlJJAPgMt2bcwe8XSglFJJGPCCujDEzVs94K0xcjMKiIqHNWzIf/s72-w400-h229-c/Screen%20Shot%202024-04-25%20at%207.00.29%20AM.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3816312478400324905</id><published>2024-04-17T05:45:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-04-19T17:36:24.774-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Catacombs</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/50023403992/&quot; title=&quot;c6xty lattice&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;c6xty lattice&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50023403992_e83ccd07a2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As some of you know, I&#39;ve donned &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/02/sociology-day.html&quot;&gt;a Sociology hat&lt;/a&gt; and have been focusing on shaping relationships among &quot;meetup-based&quot; subcultures. I use &quot;scare quotes&quot; because of connotations around &quot;meetup-based&quot;. Of course using Zoom a lot (a characteristic) is a recent development, galvanized by the SARS2 outbreak, and many of these subcultures were chugging along, sometimes famously, without the benefit of internet-based meetups for decades, if not centuries. Think churches, temples...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In tandem with these studies, I&#39;ve taken up the topic of insect mentality, or shall we say dynamism. What are the deltas associated with an ant hive in particular? The metaphor of &quot;tunnels under Disney World&quot; has again arisen. I have to add: Catacombs. We&#39;re into &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2023/07/god-talk.html&quot;&gt;the chthonic&lt;/a&gt; around here.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2018/09/boosting-python-computer-language.html&quot;&gt;Mount Parnassus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My thinking around the ants, inspired by Active Inference Institute faculty, DAF in particular, left me wide open to the sudden discovery of miner bees in my front lawn, at the base of the Tetrahedron, the pyramid of C6XTY beneath my front porch that makes helps Keep Portland Weird. Miner bees don&#39;t build a hive in a tree; they build individualized residences. Tiny mounds of dirt pop up, as a result of excavation. How catacombed these tunnels may be is a topic. Current answer: unknown. I&#39;ll read up on it sometime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A household down the street was convinced it had a wasp infection and little warning signs went up everywhere, however I think it&#39;s likely merely a miner bee visitation for them as well, as the signs are now gone and, walking home last night, I saw a few tiny dirt mounds in the grass. This seemed to happen all at once around town (I say that now based on two data points), as if on a timer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;YouTube says the world has over a thousand species of miner bee. They&#39;re not aggressive towards humans, don&#39;t or can&#39;t sting, and they cross pollinate. Gardners love them. They&#39;re not honeymakers though, so they&#39;re not usually &quot;kept&quot; in the beekeeping sense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Catacomb Codas. I&#39;ve stuffed many a deep chamber with some of this Synergetics stuff. Detractors (or even entomologists) might picture me barfing up pabulum, weighed in tetra-somethings, anticipating this nurturing content will empower the colony going forward, the hive mind or whatever.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At what level of consciousness does a hive operate? Put like that, the question is still a mirage, suggestive of a real question, still but a fevered dream. However, other questions might still be worth asking. Prompts get fine tuned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though I&#39;ve favored a Dark Theme in the Codas, a personal setting, I&#39;m working to keep the subject matter non-turgid and easy breezy, partly because the purpose, architecturally, is transit, or liminal. Let&#39;s say vestibular. I&#39;m meaning to sweep you onward, to your next flight, while providing a pleasant environment in the meantime. &lt;a href=&quot;https://coda.io/d/Math4Wisdom_d0SvdI3KSto/Topics_sueSi#_luR99&quot;&gt;Enjoy your visit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3816312478400324905'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3816312478400324905'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/04/catacombs.html' title='Catacombs'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3933573779126947464</id><published>2024-04-12T09:03:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-04-18T09:23:23.622-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Think Tank Meetup</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/53634614563/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;At Bar Carlo&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;At Bar Carlo&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53634614563_021e8c3505.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of humans get born into high density population centers and scarcely have the opportunity to experience the opposite: low density areas. A theme in my blogs over the years has taken inspiration from Portland, Oregon&#39;s &quot;outdoor school&quot; institution: the public schools include an out-of-town camp-based experience wherein presumably &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/08/escaping-light-pollution.html&quot;&gt;light pollution&lt;/a&gt; is low enough to make the Milky Way visible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve tacked on the &quot;make the Milky Way visible&quot; tagline, i.e. I don&#39;t believe I&#39;m cribbing it from official outdoor school literature, but if that&#39;s explicitly part of that program&#39;s mission statement, so much the better. Bill it as a psychological health requirement. You need outdoor living experience for that high school diploma.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to our topic last night at the Think Tank (what we&#39;ve taken to calling it): housing around Portland. My long term readers know I&#39;ve hoped to get Portland into the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2023/09/the-refugee-biz.html&quot;&gt;Refugee Tech&lt;/a&gt;&quot; business, where &quot;refugee&quot; fades in and out with &quot;camper&quot; and &quot;nomad&quot;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some people hit the open road by choice, in a high end RV they&#39;ve been saving for, and now have, in retirement. Others might fancy a pre-retirement business oriented vehicle that doubles as a place to stay, the so-called &quot;business mobile&quot; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/04/buckaroo-bizmo.html&quot;&gt;BizMo option&lt;/a&gt;. Then you get people forced out of their homes by natural and/or economic disaster (e.g. war), and becoming reliant on social engineering, i.e. back to the &quot;refugee&quot; paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Portland has done some pioneering work along these lines, according to our guest, especially when it&#39;s not too proud to learn from other metro areas, and not just San Francisco and Seattle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My approach focused on enrolling people into the business of &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2020/07/experimental-prototype-communities.html&quot;&gt;shelter testing&lt;/a&gt;, with ideas flowing from the prototyping front lines to the commercial market as finished products. I used to send my little diagrams about it under the rubric of &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2023/08/project-renaissance.html&quot;&gt;Project Renaissance&lt;/a&gt;. This was before public-private partnerships got such a negative reputation (long story).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/51191141607/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Tiny House Village&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tiny House Village&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/51191141607_f0ff5542c1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3933573779126947464'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3933573779126947464'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/04/think-tank-meetup.html' title='Think Tank Meetup'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1414002083557295507</id><published>2024-04-03T20:56:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-04-04T11:21:56.634-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Integrity Testing</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/lWDqEVLOWKo?si=vBqMjO8PAdVE9rz0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Welcome to my journals. Welcome back if you&#39;re returning.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Let&#39;s recap:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Facts I use as evidence, that&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/08/vml-verboten-math-lab.html&quot;&gt;Verboten Math&lt;/a&gt; is subversive include:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;(a) it&#39;s not taught&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;(b) it won&#39;t go away&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;(c) it has practical applications&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Most candidates are revealed to be (i) nonsensical (ii) false or (iii) trivially true. No such verdict has been established in this case, ergo it won&#39;t go away.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;However, most people have no clue what Verboten Math even is (it&#39;s not taught), and calling it Martian Math instead doesn&#39;t really help matters.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In fact, Verboten Math is a source of good ideas for the mainstream, once these ideas are sanitized, their&amp;nbsp; radical roots obscured.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In today&#39;s meetup (recorded) I mentioned &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/04/civil-war-history.html&quot;&gt;Quakers&lt;/a&gt; had a history around creating schools, and with schools come their hallmark curricula and faculties. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/03/about-quakers.html&quot;&gt;Quakers&lt;/a&gt;, we need to compete in order to enhance our brand, and bring glory to God. We&#39;re not afraid to share Verboten Math. On the contrary, we relish the opportunity.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The New England Transcendentalist aspects, Margaret Fuller and so on, were always conducive to Quakers taking an interest, as is the inbuilt skepticism regarding Manifest Destiny style imperialist mindsets, a skepticism shared by Andrew Carnegie and Mark Twain of the Anti-Imperialist League.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In a move to repair the damage brought on by a narrow-minded and short-sighted global plutocracy, wrapping itself in the Stars and Stripes, American schools overseas have a special incentive to phase in elements of Martian Math, given both its highly geographic content, and its potency as positive PR, &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/02/americana.html&quot;&gt;as Americana&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;as a vanguard for USA OS.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/53631820894/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;doodles&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;doodles&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53631820894_42b337dfd1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;424&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1414002083557295507'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1414002083557295507'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/04/integrity-testing.html' title='Integrity Testing'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/lWDqEVLOWKo/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-9126251657593465105</id><published>2024-03-28T16:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-28T16:01:55.807-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Refugee Planet</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/RwCburZmCLo?si=MXO-hX23V_hNWfYO&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;first published Oct 21, 2023&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9126251657593465105'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9126251657593465105'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/03/refugee-planet.html' title='Refugee Planet'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/RwCburZmCLo/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4511744896156625922</id><published>2024-03-19T06:33:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-19T06:36:51.057-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Meeting Notes</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/53119715884/in/album-72177720302441116/&quot; title=&quot;Summit Meeting&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Summit Meeting&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53119715884_65af46d872.jpg&quot; width=&quot;390&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was admiring &lt;a href=&quot;https://coda.io/d/Math4Wisdom_d0SvdI3KSto/Ants_suI6n#_lu0i7&quot;&gt;the curriculum materials&lt;/a&gt; shaping up around ant colonies, their study. Daniel knows a lot about ants, and yet humanity on the whole still has a lot to learn. The study of ants is somewhat humbling, in terms of revealing our own ignorance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Picture a queen ant, surrounded by layers of caretakers and apparent hangers on. We say &quot;apparent&quot; because in some theories the seeming passive crowds may store collective memories, ready to be expressed if triggered. The queen never ventures forth and workers tainted with experience of &quot;the outside&quot; don&#39;t get anywhere near her. If she serves a decision-making role (unclear) it&#39;s from within an abstracted layer where experience consists of pheromones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remembering that Andrius wants to &quot;know everything&quot; (the answer to the prayers of those with boundless curiosity), I&#39;m eager to introduce him to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cjfearnley.com/CfC/&quot;&gt;CJ&#39;s work on comprehensivity&lt;/a&gt;. The commitment to &quot;learn everything&quot; is inherently problematic, and sounds like empty chutzpah unless qualified with self awareness and acknowledgement of the inherent paradoxes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Tackling it all&quot; is not only possible, but what we all do every day. It&#39;s just that, depending upon strategy, resources, and the practice of specific disciplines, how much we accomplish towards our impossible goal varies by orders of magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took some time this morning, after feeding the dog, adding to &lt;a href=&quot;https://nbviewer.org/github/4dsolutions/m4w/blob/main/M4WTOC.ipynb&quot;&gt;my M4W repo&lt;/a&gt; on Github, where I chronicle recent progress. I haven&#39;t expressed a &quot;know everything&quot; goal, but I do value &quot;comprehensivity&quot; as CJ calls it, as many of the levers one needs to discover, as an activist, come to light only through considerable experience. Those into ML (machine learning) have a lot of concrete mathematics to show why quantity, not just quality, matters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a Quaker journalist, i.e. blogger, I need to keep twisting my strands together, and pulling tight, making a strong alloy, the way we often talk about our metaphorical language. The &lt;i&gt;No More Secondhand God&lt;/i&gt; approach to religion means cutting out the middleman, a Buddhist teaching as well. We might be able to come up with more neurological-sounding explanations for why individuation is a positive. Transcendentalism here we come.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But we&#39;re also talking &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/11/asylum-city-project.html&quot;&gt;about sanitation&lt;/a&gt; and fish farms and Global Village communities. Where might we get to go, to gain all this leveraging experience?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On my end, I follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2024/03/a-trimtab-presentation.html&quot;&gt;David Koski&#39;s research&lt;/a&gt; into phi-related topics. Phi (the golden mean) is already a hugely popular topic, but combined with Verboten Math it provides a goldmine of new material.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4511744896156625922'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4511744896156625922'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/03/meeting-notes.html' title='Meeting Notes'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5738138510018279499</id><published>2024-03-13T16:29:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-18T08:45:54.340-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Knowledge Engineering Study Group</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/zYCe2R-kDWM?si=Tn-8vcMZjftqknpX&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The story behind this meetup is we&#39;ve started &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freelists.org/post/math4wisdom/Data-flow-for-building-tables-of-conceptual-frameworks,1&quot;&gt;playing around with Coda&lt;/a&gt; more, &quot;we&quot; being the math4wisdom clique based around &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freelists.org/post/math4wisdom/more-notes-after-Mar-12-steering-committee-meeting,1&quot;&gt;a figurative memory castle&lt;/a&gt; in Lithuania (not &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/06/literary-investigation.html&quot;&gt;Transylvania&lt;/a&gt;).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5738138510018279499'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5738138510018279499'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/03/knowledge-engineering-study-group.html' title='Knowledge Engineering Study Group'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/zYCe2R-kDWM/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3295813404975462957</id><published>2024-03-11T05:57:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-11T15:17:48.344-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Spring Retreat</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/52866258468/in/album-72177720307981496/&quot; title=&quot;High Def&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;High Def&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52866258468_6fe6299c36.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve seen my &lt;a href=&quot;https://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2023/11/graph-theory.html&quot;&gt;Graph Theory slides&lt;/a&gt;, you might remember I toss my high school yearbook picture onto a slide next to Sam, likewise a younger man then, in the company of Bucky Fuller. They flew to the Philippines together, as guests of the Marcos family. I was living in Manila at the time, or perhaps was away for college. I was in Class of 1976 at International School Manila (ISM), which still exists but in newer digs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sam and I didn&#39;t know each other then. I learned of Sam Lanahan through &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2019/01/mini-confab-fuller-friends.html&quot;&gt;Trevor Blake&lt;/a&gt;, who tracked him down as one of the owners of an original &lt;i&gt;Tetrascroll&lt;/i&gt;, a very limited edition artifact. We set up an appointment to see it (but have yet to do so (it&#39;s still in its case)) and drove to Corvallis to meet the guy. We continued to hang out sporadically and undertake collaborations well into the future, especially during a chapter wherein Sam lived in Portland itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sam&#39;s grandparents were pretty famous: F. Scott Fitzgerald and his wife Zelda, their daughter &quot;Scottie&quot; (Frances) being his mom and one time columnist for the &lt;i&gt;New Yorker&lt;/i&gt;. Sam&#39;s dad, Jack Lanahan, had been a boxer in his Princeton years. After Frances died, he remarried.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After moving from Corvallis to Portland, Sam moved a few more times, winding up in a well appointed farmstead in the Willamette Valley. Which is where I am right now, on retreat, working on projects, such as on Quadrays for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/4dsolutions/m4w/blob/main/M4WTOC.ipynb&quot;&gt;M4W&lt;/a&gt; (math4wisdom).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My backyard in Portland is an outdoor museum for c6xty exhibits. The plastic sculptures become somewhat brittle after years in sunlight so we probably won&#39;t move them.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These prototypes were meant to provide lots of feedback, about stressability, durability, replicability, constructability and so on. Several test materials were employed: plastic, steel, copper, aluminum.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The farmstead is likewise decorated with specimens of each. C6XTY is a subtype of Flextegrity, which is adjacent to Tensegrity (ala &lt;a href=&quot;https://grunch.net/snelson&quot;&gt;Kenneth Snelson&lt;/a&gt; et al) but is more lattice-oriented.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What I&#39;ve done around Flextegrity is develop my Python code base to render computer graphical versions, sometimes in the form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/4dsolutions/School_of_Tomorrow/blob/master/Flextegrity_Lattice.ipynb&quot;&gt;animated GIFs&lt;/a&gt;. My graphics generating pipeline involves using Quadrays sometimes, a type of vector akin to XYZ but featuring &quot;basis vectors&quot; at 109.47 degrees to one another. They&#39;re designed to make lattice work easy, as in closest sphere packing arrangements (Conway: Barlow packings). All the CCP balls (that&#39;s a specific packing pattern) have whole number 4-tuple coordinates, such as (2,1,1,0).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays I&#39;m collaborating on Quadrays via &lt;a href=&quot;https://coda.io/d/Math4Wisdom_d0SvdI3KSto/Synergetics_su5DS#_luecx&quot;&gt;the M4W Coda&lt;/a&gt;. We&#39;re seeing to what level AI might get involved, among other &lt;a href=&quot;https://coda.io/d/Math4Wisdom_d0SvdI3KSto/Synergetics-Language-Code-Models_suW8a#_lujw6&quot;&gt;experiments&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;m taking advantage of the high level of fluency around mathematics I&#39;m encountering at math4wisdom, which is anchored by Andrius Kulikauskas, a math PhD.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does a &quot;vector space&quot; have to have a dot product? Even if it doesn&#39;t, might it still include Euclidean Distance?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Must basis vectors be unit length by definition?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if they span space without relying on negative mirrors of themselves, shouldn&#39;t that count for something?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In XYZ, we have three positive basis vectors that may be scaled by -1, which means reversed, which some might classify under rotation (i.e. to &quot;face the other way&quot; is to rotate by 180 degrees).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to negation, -X, -Y, -Z will also participate in space-spanning, but as secondary, non-basis vectors. They&#39;re second bananas.&amp;nbsp; (4, -1, 0) entails adding an X basis vector, stretched to 4 times its original length of 1, added to a negated Y (so a -Y), and no Z involvement, giving this point in space, now uniquely addressed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to vector reversal, the three positive basis vectors (X, Y, Z), abetted by their second bananas (-X, -Y, -Z), span all of space by means of addition and further stretching or shrinking, but without further need for rotation. (4, -1, 0) = 4X + 1(-Y) + 0 where X and -Y are vectors (pointy arrows, directed rays of definite length (i.e. not rays &quot;to infinity&quot;)).&lt;/p&gt;In the IVM, &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/03/pattern-matching.html&quot;&gt;using Quadrays&lt;/a&gt;, we have four positive basis vectors that may optionally be scaled by -1 (reversed), but we don&#39;t need that &quot;rotational&quot; feature to have adding with scaling span our space. We never needed the help of a supplementary cast of negated basis vectors, to reach all the stars in our universe (points in our spatial volume). Just stretch or shrink at most three of these four Quadrays, without changing direction, add, and you&#39;re done. (4, -1, 0) is equivalently (4 sqrt(2), sqrt(2), 0, 5 sqrt(2)).&lt;p&gt;IVM = Isotropic Vector Matrix, Fuller&#39;s coin, but not unrelated to the Matrix of science fiction, since aberrations of Fuller&#39;s IVM give it &quot;frequencies&quot; (think of wind chimes) which are like immersive radio channels or scenarios in those Matrix cubicles.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IVM is like the &lt;i&gt;Star Trek&lt;/i&gt; holodeck in other words, but with no exit or off switch.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, more prosaically, it&#39;s simply the skeletal scaffolding one gets from the aforementioned CCP (cubic close packing), a ball packing pattern of ball:space density of about 74%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sam&#39;s C6XTY (or c6xty) lattice places a compressive soccer-ball-looking element (same Adidas Telstar hexapent geometry) at every IVM hub, such that those most immersed all have twelve balls around one. But unlike in the CCP, these plastic balls do not touch one another. They&#39;re suspended in a network of connecting armatures, adding lots of flexibility, permeability and variability to the design.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Flextegrities could be more like jellyfish, with thin yet stiff enough filaments holding sensors in a neutral buoyancy lattice submerged in water, perhaps in the open ocean. The sensors might be whole number addressed, as by Quadrays, and selectively illuminated or otherwise activated by Wi-Fi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My dad and I took up scuba diving in the Philippines, so it&#39;s not unusual for my mind to drift to these undersea vistas. Sam had some experience in marine biology as well, as did my cousin Mary (who went on to get a medical degree). Therefore the posters Sam had made &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/02/convergent-trajectories.html&quot;&gt;for Lattice Gallery&lt;/a&gt; (a West Broadway popup in that winter of 2019), showing off Flextegrity in its underwater context, did not seem as far-fetched to me as they might have for other visitors. Experiments with immersed flextegrity lattices could be undertaken today, and/or may already be underway without my knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3295813404975462957'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3295813404975462957'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/03/spring-retreat.html' title='Spring Retreat'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>