<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1076'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1051&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1101&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1076</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4390558402153035652</id><published>2010-04-05T20:08:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-04-11T23:07:13.877-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Workshop News</title><content type='html'>Randy, lets call her, at first found the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;CubeIt!&lt;/span&gt; &quot;creepy&quot; because of the magnets, but then took to exploring it with gusto, while taking in my explanation of its 24 Mites as minimum space-fillers.  Another guy, lets call him Kyle, was likewise comprehending.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&#39;s not that this stuff is particularly hard; it&#39;s just not shared very widely, &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/57935&quot;&gt;not even on &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Math World&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (a situation we have &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/04/suggesting-change.html&quot;&gt;recently addressed&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All talk of irregular polytopes aside, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/04/sao-meeting.html&quot;&gt;this educational tool&lt;/a&gt; from the Huntar Company is simply fun to play with.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The octahedral Flextegrity model triggered some discussion of a landmine detector / destroyer.  One of our number, a company president and sponsor, had worked on a prototype at a national lab in his spare time some years ago, basing his design on a clever kids&#39; toy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A rotating weight caused the scaled up version to flip from face to face unpredictably, generating a random walk across a field, possibly detonating a charge along the way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These devices would be inexpensive / dispensable and could be put to work in large numbers.  But would they find them all?  Landmines are another legacy technology today&#39;s world despises.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The motorcycle engineer also shared a few thoughts with our group, though I had some trouble with his accent, wish I were better with languages.  Speaking of which, here &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/02/more-musings-about-television.html&quot;&gt;some Japanese kanji&lt;/a&gt; I&#39;ve been getting recently:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;polyhedra       多面体&lt;br /&gt;tetrahedron     正四面体&lt;br /&gt;decahedron      10面体&lt;br /&gt;dodecahedron    正十二面体&lt;br /&gt;rhombic dodecahedron    菱形十二面体&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;many    多&lt;br /&gt;surface 面&lt;br /&gt;body    体&lt;br /&gt;regular 正&lt;br /&gt;twelve (ten, two)       十二&lt;br /&gt;four    四&lt;br /&gt;diamond shape 菱形&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A reporter from Baghdad shared horrific stories.  People blame the political process, but such levels of violence are hardly political, or a process.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/02/proposal-baghdad-grid-monitor.html&quot;&gt;The electrical grid&lt;/a&gt; is still in a shambles, city services are greatly impaired, despair is running high.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Colin Powell &quot;you break it you buy it&quot; policy cannot be enacted from a purely military standpoint.  The Coalition will probably need something more like a Marshall Plan (ERP), making use of those &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/03/world-lifestyles.html&quot;&gt;bases as staging areas&lt;/a&gt;.  Some of the same &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/03/morning-meetings.html&quot;&gt;logistics used in Haiti&lt;/a&gt; might apply, including emergency evacuations to better medical facilities (the &quot;mega hospitals&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Scholarships for future health care workers will be needed across the board just to deal with America&#39;s aging boomers, many of whom currently seek quality care overseas.  Anyone now in the military who qualifies, and wants to follow in the footsteps of Air Force hero Charlie Clements, should get a boost.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The know-how to build and repair civilian infrastructure is in danger of being lost, in America too.  Per a voice from Denver, both Hewlett-Packard and TRW CEOs were suggesting decades ago that out-of-control military spending is economically and ecologically ruinous.  Civil society is under attack, and quasi-defenseless around the world.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Python component is &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/04/mapping-gnu-math.html&quot;&gt;still under development&lt;/a&gt; and probably needs more Numpy.  Dick and I were discussing the nuances in Cyberia.  The functional programmers object to polyhedra changing &quot;in place&quot; and returning None, akin to going some_list = [&#39;a&#39;, &#39;b&#39;, &#39;c&#39;]; some_list.sort( ).  They hate stuff like that. I expect the Scheme camp will continue to compete.  Congrats to MF for getting that award by the way.  I sure could use some big prizes (jealous).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Not all of this &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=2059352&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;Radical Math&lt;/a&gt; occurred on the Pauling Campus.  97214 offers other facilities, though we hardly compete with Reed College when it comes to computer labs.  The Java workshop the other night (related to work in genetics) &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/03/campus-household.html&quot;&gt;the Pauling Campus&lt;/a&gt;, as was my Python workshop.  Today though, I didn&#39;t once set foot in that board room.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4390558402153035652'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4390558402153035652'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/04/workshop-news.html' title='Workshop News'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1158099532049982406</id><published>2010-04-03T15:20:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-04-03T15:33:45.597-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Suggesting a Change</title><content type='html'>I proposed augmenting a page at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;MathWorld&lt;/span&gt; yesterday, using &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/contact/contribute.html&quot;&gt;the contribution form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This morning, Dave Koski phoned to let me know I&#39;d misused the term &quot;orthoscheme&quot; in my initial submission.  The text below is from today&#39;s newly revised version.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I  posted the text  of both submissions to &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergeo&lt;/span&gt;, as echoed back to me from the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;MathWorld&lt;/span&gt; web server.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The page I am talking about is &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/Space-FillingPolyhedron.html&quot;&gt;the one on Space-Filling Polyhedra&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Existing text:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&quot;A space-filling polyhedron, sometimes called a a plesiohedron (Grünbaum and Shephard 1980), is a polyhedron  which can be used to generate a tessellation  of space. Although even Aristotle himself proclaimed in his work On the Heavens  that the tetrahedron fills space, it in fact does not.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Proposed addition:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;However an irregular tri-rectangular tetrahedron, named the Mite by R.  Buckminster Fuller (for &quot;minimum tetrahedron&quot;), does fill space by  itself, with no need of left and right handed complements.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Discussion:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The space-filling polyhedra page curiously avoids any mention of space-filling tetrahedra, simpler than hexahedra.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fuller&#39;s contribution is more nuanced than just offering nomenclature (Mite). In Fig 950.12 he cites pg. 71 of &#39;Regular Polytopes&#39; to complement Coxeter&#39;s treatment of this shape with original modular dissections thereof.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Two additional space-filling tetrahedra may be assembled from Mites.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Presumably Michael Goldberg&#39;s treatment enumerates space-filling tetrahedra, suggesting another sentence in the 2nd to last paragraph summarizing his findings?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Coxeter, D. \titleisbn{Regular Polytopes.}{0486614808} New York, New York: Dover Publications, p.~71, 1973.\par&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fuller, R. B. \titleisbn{Synergetics: explorations in the geometry of thinking.}{0020653204} New York, New York: Macmillan, Fig.~950.12, 1975.\par&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Inchbald, Guy. &#39;&#39;The &quot;cells&quot; of the Archimedean honeycomb duals&#39;&#39; 1996.  \url{http://www.steelpillow.com/polyhedra/AHD/chart_lg.gif}.\par&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;You&#39;ll find I was &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/03/view-from-abroad.html&quot;&gt;ranting a little&lt;/a&gt; recently (not for the first time) about the fact that so few mathematicians include any mention of Fuller&#39;s Mite, or minimum tetrahedron, in their catalogs of space-fillers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I continue registering my &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/58193&quot;&gt;more generic consternation&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergeo&lt;/span&gt; this afternoon, in the context of discussing &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/58179&quot;&gt;nuclear disarmament&lt;/a&gt; with other contributors.  I write in terms of a &quot;global university&quot; as that&#39;s what Spaceship Earth has shaped up to become.  Fuller&#39;s &quot;final exam time&quot; metaphor, for this time in history, is consistent with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/06/our-global-u-advertisement.html&quot;&gt;this imagery&lt;/a&gt;.  I also point back to this journal entry &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=2057893&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;from math-teach @ Math Forum&lt;/a&gt;, where I explicitly tie my concerns to those of the current administration.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1158099532049982406'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1158099532049982406'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/04/suggesting-change.html' title='Suggesting a Change'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3043330300510031678</id><published>2010-03-31T23:45:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2010-04-01T23:45:14.443-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Arts and Crafts</title><content type='html'>Mr. Lanahan bought me breakfast this morning at Mt. Tabor Cafe.  We talked about his book.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Later I joined Mr. Stockton in his studio on the Pauling Campus to continue building my instructors kit.  The assembly process takes time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I picture diplomats sitting around, doing something crafty together, shooting the breeze, talking of worldly matters.  The Paulings&#39; commitment to peace, science and health sets the tone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One of the benefits of this workshop:  the other people here.  Here is an opportunity to compare notes, form bonds in a rarefied setting.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mr. Blake had not visited this studio before, nor seen this particular version of flextegrity.  He shared some lore regarding the technocracy movement, having recently had coffee with a local representative.  Trevor is a student of social movements and ideologies.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Glenn and Trevor also talked about moss, a native species.  Both have been using it in urban gardens.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A rack of gold icosahedra sit like cookies, baking in the sun on the porch.  The bright red Alpha Helix, a sculpture not far away, provides contrast.  Tourists stop and ask questions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/05/lost-in-oregon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My uncle Bill Lightfoot&lt;/a&gt; stopped by.  He enjoyed checking out the flextegrity pyramid over dinner with Glenn and I at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Bagdad&lt;/span&gt;.  He shared about dog sledding in Wyoming recently.  Bill is 85.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Back in the library, we talked at some length about Kenneth Snelson, the artist and a friend.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Although best known for his awesome tensegrity sculptures, Kenneth has created some &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/07/more-curriculum-cartoons.html&quot;&gt;truly amazing computer graphics&lt;/a&gt; and 360 degree panoramic photographs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg4T1Um6n3tx-py8ZV0wTui0CnwvOGlfbQQQRn1hBkks7eHuLp1Z7Ib2I_43C6DEYKAWsAk5PgWrsSkjw95gW4VPq1UvsGkVC8f-nD7cmKPcpH35WGLhuv1kdZgc0iMV_GTMRdr/s1600/047.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 150px; height: 200px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg4T1Um6n3tx-py8ZV0wTui0CnwvOGlfbQQQRn1hBkks7eHuLp1Z7Ib2I_43C6DEYKAWsAk5PgWrsSkjw95gW4VPq1UvsGkVC8f-nD7cmKPcpH35WGLhuv1kdZgc0iMV_GTMRdr/s200/047.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5455427413872256130&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3043330300510031678'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3043330300510031678'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/arts-and-crafts.html' title='Arts and Crafts'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg4T1Um6n3tx-py8ZV0wTui0CnwvOGlfbQQQRn1hBkks7eHuLp1Z7Ib2I_43C6DEYKAWsAk5PgWrsSkjw95gW4VPq1UvsGkVC8f-nD7cmKPcpH35WGLhuv1kdZgc0iMV_GTMRdr/s72-c/047.JPG" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1193002631928739349</id><published>2010-03-29T19:38:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-03-30T12:51:43.771-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Workshop Scenarios</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiSIkxt1rvJc-jE_uX-I0dd72QkwOBe4si1k-zYUwYbZ_QLV-ik9UTCKJgOnLrR_yW845GUg8POIis1P5oLWBnmnSh1ijRe9Kars1z0VZTrBgQQonfo7rdMdV6VhZXbFR80nFtP/s1600/037.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 320px; height: 240px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiSIkxt1rvJc-jE_uX-I0dd72QkwOBe4si1k-zYUwYbZ_QLV-ik9UTCKJgOnLrR_yW845GUg8POIis1P5oLWBnmnSh1ijRe9Kars1z0VZTrBgQQonfo7rdMdV6VhZXbFR80nFtP/s320/037.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5454512341030484626&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Glenn unveiled a Flextegrity kit of 100 pieces at Wanderers the other day.  I missed the event, heard favorable reports.  The kit provides a step-by-step sequence from one icosahedral hub to a four-frequency tetrahedron of 35 icosahedra.  The resulting construction is sturdy and all weather.  The hubs are fixed in place with customized stretched springs, do not touch one another.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One might call this &quot;floating compression&quot; however the springs also serve a compressive function under load, meaning we do not file this applied material under the &quot;tensegrity&quot; heading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Students may wish to compare and contrast, as tensegrity is an important concept in contemporary art and engineering.  The title by R. Motro is a part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/12/borrowed-books.html&quot;&gt;the Flextegrity company library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sam has been running some numbers, on what it might cost to keep more of version 3 coming through the pipeline.  B2C sales of kits to end users, perhaps bundled with a workshop might emerge as a co-venture.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For the time being, supply is limited and the kits are for workshop instructors.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Glenn&#39;s forte is what I call &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Neolithic_Math&quot;&gt;Neolithic Math&lt;/a&gt;, which involves working with tools, including hand-made ones.  His brand of math provides a strong hands-on component consistent with learning various skills and crafts.   His workshop includes such raw materials as antler, shell, many kinds of stone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Flextegrity adds a more futuristic component (&lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Martian_Math&quot;&gt;Martian Math&lt;/a&gt;), plus is a one of a kind, giving us a niche.  My time slot, in the Linus Pauling house board room, or in a computer lab, has tended to feature commercially available supplies, along with free and open source software.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I am looking forward to adding more flextegrity to the mix, as I move about Portland.  You might find Glenn and I at some coffee shop near PSU, assembling icosahedra and passing out our Radical Math (rad math) literature pointing back to these workshop opportunities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also have a tensegrity sculpture, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/05/barrel-tower.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Barrel Tower&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a gift from Kenneth Snelson himself.  I consider it too valuable to lug it around as an educational supply however.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Schools sending their teachers our way have an interest in joining a more world class network wherein tetrahedral accounting and 60-degree coordination (e.g. graphene) inform the geometry curriculum at all levels.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Schools which include more of this heritage (including &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/antarctic_m/103413991/in/set-186523/&quot;&gt;Fuller Projections&lt;/a&gt; in some contexts) have a more cosmopolitan aura.  Portland&#39;s international business community tends to encourage schools to move in this direction.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1193002631928739349'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1193002631928739349'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/workshop-scenarios.html' title='Workshop Scenarios'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiSIkxt1rvJc-jE_uX-I0dd72QkwOBe4si1k-zYUwYbZ_QLV-ik9UTCKJgOnLrR_yW845GUg8POIis1P5oLWBnmnSh1ijRe9Kars1z0VZTrBgQQonfo7rdMdV6VhZXbFR80nFtP/s72-c/037.JPG" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4457049118659729399</id><published>2010-03-27T18:04:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-03-28T00:00:34.036-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Geometery + Geography</title><content type='html'>Here&#39;s how I&#39;m thinking:  the emergence of high definition screens (HDTVs, LCDs etc.) will drive a resurgence of &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/58095&quot;&gt;spatial geometry&lt;/a&gt;.  One could say it already has, given &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/more-from-97214.html&quot;&gt;the NFL&lt;/a&gt; is simply &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/05/show-me-polyhedra.html&quot;&gt;polyhedra on steroids&lt;/a&gt; (each player like a Sim, in the sense of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/02/regarding-objectifying.html&quot;&gt;an object&lt;/a&gt; with attributes and methods).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With this Renaissance in the foreground, we&#39;ll have the option (so far not much availed of), to streamline and simplify the teaching of said spatial geometry.  This will occur in tandem with a more explicit embrace of high technology (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/03/math-wars-continued.html&quot;&gt;HDTVs&lt;/a&gt;, LCDs etc.), in place of the current Calculator Limbo, the dominant paradigm in many a school.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Those schools embracing the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/08/mathcasting-about-phi.html&quot;&gt;NCLB Polynomial&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/12/synergeo-57035.html&quot;&gt;NCLB Polyhedron&lt;/a&gt; (both literary devices, students of American Literature take note) will have more of a world class flavor and will prove more attractive to an international cast.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Diplomacy will get a boost from these developments, as the USA recovers from &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/03/why-we-fight-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;its withered years&lt;/a&gt;, as a mere puppet of Eisenhower&#39;s aptly named &quot;military industrial complex&quot; (a psychological complex characterized by some infantile belief in &quot;superpowers&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As science fiction, this forecast makes some sense.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m not talking about a done deal of course, as the slumdog millionaires fight change at every turn, grasping at whatever straws.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nostalgia for the 1900s and its Flatlander belief systems is still running high in some segments.  Some believe in the end of history.  Others believe in no tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Geometry-Geography nexus is where to focus.  Geography at the medio-level is one&#39;s local ecosystem, neighborhood, bioregion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Going in, it&#39;s your body and the chemistries it depends on, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/11/physics-emergent-isepp-lecture.html&quot;&gt;the quantum mechanics it obeys&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Going out, it&#39;s the solar system, a fusion furnace with client planets, outward and onward to the stars, the galaxy, other galaxies.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Geography is all that has energetic significance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Geometry, on the other hand, may be size-and-time independent, what we in the Synergetics namespace call &quot;prefrequency&quot; or energy-free.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here is our familiar Platonic Realm, where our philosophical faculties like to anchor themselves, as observers of the eternal verities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/08/4d.html&quot;&gt;U = MP&lt;/a&gt; in other words, i.e. to communicate this curriculum, one needs both vocabularies, the geometric and the geographic.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Geography is about the playing field shared by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/synergetica/veil.gif&quot;&gt;we world game players&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Geometry is about the generalized principles that connect all the special case dots.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These broad brush stroke heuristics may come across as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/images/ohman12192004.jpg&quot;&gt;too esoteric&lt;/a&gt; to  have pragmatic consequences.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What&#39;s true though is that geography and geometry have always developed hand in hand, so lets remember that &quot;radical&quot; and &quot;root&quot; have much the same conservative and/or anchoring meaning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When it comes to providing civilizations with secure origins, serving up a mix of geometry and geography has generally been the most successful approach.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4457049118659729399'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4457049118659729399'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/geometery-geography.html' title='Geometery + Geography'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2620629136903877427</id><published>2010-03-23T19:53:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-03-24T11:49:20.632-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Connecting Dots</title><content type='html'>I&#39;m developing more curriculum around 2 * P * F**2 + 2, which &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/02/valentines-day-2006.html&quot;&gt;R. B. Fuller&lt;/a&gt; sees relating two kinds of twoness: concave / convex multiplicative two (x 2) and spinnable additive two (+ 2).  The letter F stands for &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/12/angle-frequency.html&quot;&gt;frequency&lt;/a&gt;, whereas P is some prime number or product of low order primes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Quoting from &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergetics&lt;/span&gt; (a philosophy):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;1073.11 Since unity is plural and, at minimum, two, the &lt;i&gt;additive&lt;/i&gt; twoness of systemic independence of the individual system&#39;s spinnability&#39;s two axial poles, the latter&#39;s additive twoness must be added to something, which thinkable somethingness is the inherent systemic &lt;i&gt;multiplicative&lt;/i&gt; twoness of all systems&#39; congruent concave-convex inside-outness: this additive-two-plus-multiplicative-two fourness inherently produces the interrelationship 2 + 2 + 2 sixness (threefold twoness) of all minimum structural-system comprehendibility.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1073.12  All systems are conceptually differentiated out of Universe.&lt;br /&gt;System + environment = Universe&lt;br /&gt;Universe - system = environment&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1073.13 The environment is dual, consisting of the macro and micro (outsideness and insideness). Ergo, a &lt;i&gt;fourth twoness&lt;/i&gt; of all prime structural systems is synergetically accountable as &lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt; 2 + 2 + 2 + 2 = 8. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=7018329&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;On math-teach&lt;/a&gt;, I came up with a kind of game, developed in part to generate appreciation for the different meanings of these operators (+ and * i.e. addition and multiplication).  There&#39;s the abstract algebra topic of groups, rings and fields, which is customarily not broached until college, except in a cursory manner that goes by pretty fast.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;However, as we import more segments to our alternative track, newly lightened by not having as much heavy calculus, we&#39;ll find the time for more of this material, which is actually somewhat fun and intuitive for many a demographic (depends on how taught, I favor some cartoons, animations, even claymations).  The idea of an entire track sounds ambitious at this point, as we&#39;re still looking for single course pilots to pop up around the state, on reservations or wherever.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/58077&quot;&gt;On &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergeo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I&#39;m linking to Fuller&#39;s omni-directional halo concept, which is perhaps most brilliantly defined in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;No More Secondhand God&lt;/span&gt;.  The topic is Descartes&#39; Angular Deficit, the difference between 360 around each vertex, and a chordal polyhedron connecting the same dots.  One tetrahedron&#39;s worth of angle needs to be taken away.  Then, once you get such a system, most simply a tetrahedron, you have the ability to expand it through the jitterbug phases.  At the icosahedral and cuboctahedral phases, the number sequence 1, 12, 42, 92, 162... kicks in, as generated by the above 2 * P * F**2 + 2, with P = 5.  Per Donald Coxeter, this exquisite result was worth memorializing.  He wrote a professional paper about it, in his inimitable style.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The above shape-governing formula might be likened to &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/03/towards-nanoscience.html&quot;&gt;some seed molecule&lt;/a&gt; placed in a dendrimer, anchoring its growth.  However the more formal visualization of said formula involves sphere packing, and that&#39;s something we&#39;d like to talk about more, not because they form a practical applied material, but because the mathematics opens doors.  You might want to move to hyper-dimensional sphere packing, which has practical applications in optimizing communications channels, while keeping conversations separate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is rich cooking, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/11/spice-trade.html&quot;&gt;lots of spice&lt;/a&gt;.  The flavor is still esoteric for 2010 as no one is much interested in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/synergetica/synergetica2.html&quot;&gt;2 * P * F**2 + 2&lt;/a&gt;, especially as written, in some non-standard Pythonic notation (** is the exponentiation operator).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of Python, I was &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2010-March/009867.html&quot;&gt;on edu-sig today&lt;/a&gt; chatting with Bill and company about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cse.msu.edu/%7Ecse231/PracticeOfComputingUsingPython/index.php&quot;&gt;a fine page of exercises&lt;/a&gt;, drawn from many walks of life.  These are like &quot;cave paintings&quot; in their relative simplicity, yet project some useful ideas.  I jumped in on the Caesar Code exercise in particular, partly just to reiterate some earlier work, exercise my skills with a dictionary.  Bill wanted uppercase letters and punctuation to make it through unsubstituted, and my version achieves that.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Last night Dave Koski went over some of his more recent discoveries.  I find them interesting and relevant.  We&#39;ve both been cogitating on a lot of the same themes. phi/radical(2) has come up again, in connection with a scaled-up S-module (one might say).  More later on this.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/03/responding-to-op-ed.html&quot;&gt;My editorial on the NYT op-ed piece&lt;/a&gt; is not supposed to sound too alarmist, yet I am looking for ways to register some serious concerns.  Bill Gates and I might be on the same side this time, in thinking more radical reforms are needed.  The trick is to not have teachers get completely defensive in reaction, as if any wish to institute change were an implied criticism of the work of dedicated professionals.  On the contrary, I expect these professionals themselves to agree:  that change is truly necessary.  This is a partnership opportunity, not an attempt to vilify an entire profession.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Finally, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2010-March/009867.html&quot;&gt;my posting to edu-sig&lt;/a&gt; revisits the feud in computer science, twixt a lambda calculus wing and other factions.  I&#39;m worried that discrete math is the can we keep kicking down the road, when instead we need to be developing a new track that looks a lot more like Bill&#39;s.  The high school aged would ride these rails, but so could adults, including their teachers.  Other curriculum writers, such as Edward Cherlin, go further back into childhood.  We&#39;re somewhat spread out along this railroad and its many switching yards.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I anticipate lots of new positions will open up if we invest in this future.  But will needed  engineering occur if the focus is on some soap opera between &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/03/two-track-solution.html&quot;&gt;contentious camps&lt;/a&gt;?  Perhaps this is not an either / or proposition?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The same questions might be asked around just about any low level conflict I suppose.  Sometimes competition helps whereas other times it drives away skittish investors, not sure what to think, but disliking the sense of acrimony?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&quot;If the people are feuding, will they forget to grow food and stockpile for the future?&quot; That might be the more civilizational question.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/spring-retreat-continued.html&quot;&gt;The Native American lore&lt;/a&gt; in this region chronicles times when people tried to take short cuts and paid a high price.  We&#39;d rather learn from our mistakes than repeat them.  Perhaps more philosophers will get involved?  More Chiefs?  Chieftesses?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the home front, Quinn stopped by with Nick, also Gideon, also Rose.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3859887882/&quot; title=&quot;CUE in Bhutan by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2444/3859887882_6142be6454_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CUE in Bhutan&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; width=&quot;180&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2620629136903877427'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2620629136903877427'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/connecting-dots.html' title='Connecting Dots'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2444/3859887882_6142be6454_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8897056031467016132</id><published>2010-03-20T13:55:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-03-20T18:51:47.826-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Spring Retreat (continued)</title><content type='html'>I joined the group late, missing the breakfast.  Discussions of energy policies continued.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David&#39;s take, and he&#39;s in a position to know, is that energy companies these days are mostly trying to avoid the capital expense of actually building new generating plants, of any description.  They&#39;re riding an increasingly decrepit energy grid into the ground, doing their best to prolong its viability by paying major customers, the industrial users, to lower their loads by increasing efficiency wherever possible.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Household consumers take a back seat.  Our Sims-like grid management games would have ways to model this strategy.  Students need access to such games through their school systems.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Long ago, as a part of the Portland district&#39;s talented and gifted program, an experiment was tried wherein kids were exempted from regular classes and bussed to a facility on Marine Drive, where private sector professionals might interact with these students, on the theory that some of their real world experience would rub off.  This was maybe like once a week from the kids&#39; point of view?  I&#39;m hazy on details.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A weakness of this program was the district administration was pretty strict with the curriculum, telling these not-full-time teachers what activities to provide, mostly computer games.  &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Oregon Trail&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Sim City&lt;/span&gt;, early versions of both (low resolution screens, not much RAM) were the among the most popular choices.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The games we&#39;re brainstorming (storyboarding, looking for realism from energy companies) are in this genre.  Whether its grid management (macro-economic) or household management (micro-economic), we&#39;re wanting to find segments of the population willing to partner in considering these challenges.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Although my focus is the pre-college classroom in much of my curriculum writing, I&#39;m as interested in giving adult populations access to these simulations, along with more access to realistic global data.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steve (crystallographer, gemologist) came by and brought up Julian&#39;s work regarding double-slit experiments with buckyballs, showing they exhibit quantum effects, as do &lt;a href=&quot;http://physicsworld.com/cws/article/news/42019&quot;&gt;even larger particles&lt;/a&gt;, per a story on NPR yesterday (per Steve).  I have Julian&#39;s paper in my gmail stash.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Glenn wiped some graffiti off &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Alpha Helix&lt;/span&gt; just this morning, one of Julian&#39;s early sculptures, a tribute to one of Linus Pauling&#39;s discoveries.  People routinely stop to have their picture taken next to it, read the placard.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On a break for a walk around the block, I met up with Elizabeth and David Braithwaite, heading towards a book store.  I&#39;d just read Laurie&#39;s kind email, remembering Dawn.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mom and I spoke twice by cell.  She wanted to be sure her part time residency was reflected on our census form, still due to go back.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On another break, I checked back with the household.  LW was immersed in Native American lore, a &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Laughing Horse&lt;/span&gt; video recording of an elder giving the history of groups in this region, such as the Multnomah.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These groups suffered the consequences of short sightedness and greed sometimes, do not portray themselves as saints, do not over-romanticize.  Their Creator would take away core competencies sometimes, until the people repented and buried whatever hatchets.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;TU is doing some spring cleaning today.  NC, another guest, joined us at Pauling House today, but was not in evidence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4448527847/&quot; title=&quot;Rad Math Props by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2441/4448527847_5507193815_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rad Math Props&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8897056031467016132'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8897056031467016132'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/spring-retreat-continued.html' title='Spring Retreat (continued)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2441/4448527847_5507193815_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-63769346955426172</id><published>2010-03-19T20:55:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-03-20T17:35:58.530-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers Spring Retreat</title><content type='html'>Don Wardwell is singing &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Angel from Montgomery&lt;/span&gt; to our party, accompanied on guitar by Jon Bunce, a professional musician.  Lynne Taylor introduced her upcoming talk on eco-tourism.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nick and I joined somewhat late, though in plenty of time to partake of salads.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lindsey is playing at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Laughing Horse&lt;/span&gt; tonight, was at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;E-room&lt;/span&gt; last night, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Laughing Horse&lt;/span&gt; again the night before, at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Roots Brewery&lt;/span&gt; tomorrow (a fundraiser to supply more books to prisoners).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was challenged to do a lot of big picture thinking today.  I&#39;ve been reflecting on my most recent meeting &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/07/wanderers-2006725.html&quot;&gt;with Patrick&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.portlandenergystrategies.com/&quot;&gt;Portland Energy Strategies&lt;/a&gt;.  He&#39;s seeing the same thing a lot of us are seeing:  a way to make the &quot;smart grid&quot; a reality, that depends on the active and conscious participation of many of those served.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Smart grids are related to smart meters, also appliances that report on their own energy use, smart houses, intelligent systems for load balancing.  I&#39;m not an expert.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These ideas have been the stuff of science fiction for decades.  By around 2000, a lot of writers (analysts, forecasters) anticipated we would have these technologies.  But would people learn how to use them?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So far, a lot of smart meters have been deployed, but the smart grid has yet to materialize, perhaps correlating with public unawareness of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/wanderers-spring-retreat.html&quot;&gt;the global grid&lt;/a&gt; in general (a grid which includes communications transmissions, not just power transmission).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Imagine your rate changing by the hour.  Run your clothes dryer in the middle of the night, and take advantage of a lower cost per kilowatt-hour.  What if you had grown up playing simulation games wherein you&#39;d trained a family of Sims to so optimize?  Patrick&#39;s games would have both macro- and micro-economic dimensions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;An open question, in my own mind anyway, is to what extent energy companies, public utilities, want to get back into public education.  Do they worry about consumer backlash, accusations that they&#39;re playing big brother?  If there&#39;s a commitment to sharing some substantive data, giving consumers more of an over-the-shoulder look, then the sought-for partnership relationship might materialize?  What&#39;s the interface with public schools?  Where does local government enter the picture?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Obviously I&#39;m neither the first nor only person to be asking these questions.  Patrick has been in the energy business for much of his career, has been pondering such matters and with a lot of grist for his mill.  His proposals are more definite and refined than I&#39;m getting across here.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Trevor came by &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/58038&quot;&gt;with a new template&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://grunch.net/&quot;&gt;the Grunch web site&lt;/a&gt;, so named for Fuller&#39;s whimsical, satirical, subversive, radical &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Grunch of Giants&lt;/span&gt; (St. Martin&#39;s Press, 1983).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The site looks more like a Wiki now, which is apropos, given my work in Wikieducator on &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Digital_Math&quot;&gt;Digital Mathematics&lt;/a&gt; (mostly heuristics, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/03/towards-nanoscience.html&quot;&gt;like Dr. Tomalia is into&lt;/a&gt; -- though different ones).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Earlier:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/03/another-day.html&quot;&gt;our meeting&lt;/a&gt; about supporting educators on the front lines.  Getting a better handle on this 60-degree coordination business is a top priority for all of us.  What&#39;s the best strategy?  We&#39;re talking about art schools, schools of design, liberal arts colleges... &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/03/world-lifestyles.html&quot;&gt;war colleges&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I worried later about too many gray icosahedra cluttering the ecosystem, some Dr. Seuss like fantasy based on a possible classroom workflow.  Glenn assured me that PVC is easily reground and recycled.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There&#39;s no danger of an over-abundance at the moment, as the supply is quite limited, with artist-engineers resorting to recycling what few icosahedra are already in circulation.  The assembly process itself makes lights go on, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/03/public-policy-2-of-2.html&quot;&gt;those lucky few&lt;/a&gt; getting to participate in the process.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If students are learning something, are developing a stronger grasp of geometric principles for academic credit, yet are also producing some in-demand good as a result, then do we worry about child labor laws, exploitation?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/2560278266/in/set-72157605485853546/&quot;&gt;touring China in the early 1970s&lt;/a&gt;, I saw elementary school kids doing what looked to be circuit board assembly.  Were those usable circuits?  I don&#39;t actually remember.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m also contemplating David Koski&#39;s work.  He seems to be mining a rich vein in polyhedral geometry, sending a lot of gold my way.  How much slips through the cracks, because I&#39;m only an average interpreter?  I turned two recent emails &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/koski_ennea.html&quot;&gt;into a web page&lt;/a&gt;, with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/58034&quot;&gt;follow-up to &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergeo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There&#39;s always the hope that we&#39;ll get some more help.  Animators could be having a field day, is my sense of it, but are missing the boat as we&#39;re not investing in work / study sufficiently.  Findings need to be disseminated, not shelved, but then where&#39;s the audience &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2010/01/coffee-shop-schools.html&quot;&gt;for esoteric geometry&lt;/a&gt;, especially where &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synergetics_%28Fuller%29#Tetrahedral_Accounting&quot;&gt;tetrahedral mensuration&lt;/a&gt; is concerned (relates to 60-degree coordination).  Universities?  Mostly not yet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tara is with her sister this evening, plans to come home rather late on public transportation, fairly safe and convenient in Greater Portland.  To tourists, other visitors, I recommend taking the Max to the Oregon Zoo.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4448527859/&quot; title=&quot;Rendering by Me by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2789/4448527859_e5420ae0ca_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rendering by Me&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/63769346955426172'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/63769346955426172'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/wanderers-spring-retreat.html' title='Wanderers Spring Retreat'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2789/4448527859_e5420ae0ca_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2170665528040221397</id><published>2010-03-18T12:16:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-03-18T12:19:05.572-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Marketing Math</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiF4O8ax4iR8CpCaZIIv66NIx7IfVDroKhH-T1YXFZSxNgrLBCxWav7ZIfI5v4wSZsLe53o_RAMz741pe-k7DfgcR-TXd2yun8hEZgPEdU6229F9OrFIxlF5uFmY0mVD0bB72Ff/s1600-h/ch5a.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 280px; height: 240px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiF4O8ax4iR8CpCaZIIv66NIx7IfVDroKhH-T1YXFZSxNgrLBCxWav7ZIfI5v4wSZsLe53o_RAMz741pe-k7DfgcR-TXd2yun8hEZgPEdU6229F9OrFIxlF5uFmY0mVD0bB72Ff/s320/ch5a.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5450055467404304114&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=7013554&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;Responding to a questionnaire&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2170665528040221397'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2170665528040221397'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/marketing-math.html' title='Marketing Math'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiF4O8ax4iR8CpCaZIIv66NIx7IfVDroKhH-T1YXFZSxNgrLBCxWav7ZIfI5v4wSZsLe53o_RAMz741pe-k7DfgcR-TXd2yun8hEZgPEdU6229F9OrFIxlF5uFmY0mVD0bB72Ff/s72-c/ch5a.gif" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8928241874881086314</id><published>2010-03-16T18:54:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2010-03-17T21:33:36.879-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2010.3.16</title><content type='html'>This is a meeting regarding the Parliament of World Religions, take two in some ways (I missed the first take).  We&#39;re here to learn about the most recent convergence, which took place in Melbourne (Australia) recently.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I plan to tell a couple stories about my experiences at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4439344723/&quot;&gt;said parliament in 1999&lt;/a&gt;, in Cape Town, when we go around the table.  I attended with &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/03/celebrating-wicca.html&quot;&gt;my late wife Dawn&lt;/a&gt;, my daughters, my parents.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We were a Quaker family, with mom &amp;amp; dad based in Maseru, Lesotho.  Dawn flew solo to Durban for a workshop with the Dalai Lama.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/12/coffee-shop-talk.html&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We stayed with Nosizwe Madlala-Routledge&lt;/a&gt; and family while in Cape Town.  She was Deputy Minister of Defense for the RSA at the time, and a Quaker -- not necessarily an inconsistent role.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Later, we got to meet with Tenzin Gyatso, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/07/10-questions-for-dalai-lama-movie.html&quot;&gt;DL XIV&lt;/a&gt; in a Cape Town government building (a parliament building).  I use a familiar name because, as Quakers, we&#39;re sometimes avoiding of titles.  Noziswe asked us how she should introduce this great man and we suggested including his familiar name as a part of the introduction.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He looked slightly askance when he heard her intro, but took it in stride.  Weird stuff happens when you&#39;re the DL, goes with the job description.  In the meeting, he expressed the fond hope, based on analysis, that future wars would become increasingly regional, not turn global so easily.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In his keynote to the assembled Parliament of World Religions, his message was to &quot;be skeptical&quot;, not just buy in to whatever beliefs.  Some might consider that ironical, given the source, but Tantric Buddhism is actually quite experiential, experimental and empirical, so I wasn&#39;t that surprised.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The first Parliament, in 1893, was a huge breakthrough by many measures.  This was the first time that leaders in certain faith groups had shared a podium and spoken to the same audience. Approximately 10% of the presenters were women, which for that time was a benchmark.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It took almost 95 years for a next Parliament to reconvene. Swami Vivakananda made a big difference in this regard.  Parliament basically means &quot;a safe place to come to talk about important things&quot; i.e. this isn&#39;t a legislative body.  The space is open to the participation of people from all walks of life, provided they&#39;re not there to convert and/or prostelytize -- except in your own booth.  The next Parliament took place in 1993, again in Chicago.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/02/wanderers-2009211.html&quot;&gt;Helen&lt;/a&gt;, our presenter, has been on the board of the Parliament since 1990.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Parliament in Cape Town had a lot to do with the contributions of the various religions in ending apartheid.  We had something real to celebrate.  South Africa has been an example to us all.  I&#39;m reminded now of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/05/time-for-reconciliation.html&quot;&gt;Bishop Desmond Tutu&#39;s appearance at the University of Portland&lt;/a&gt; and his clearly expressed affinity for the Dalai Lama.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Parliament in Barcelona in 2004 had a lot to do with terrorism, the events of 911, of March 11 in Madrid.  Ending religiously motivated violence, the debt of most impoverished nations (such as Haiti, the USA), assuring access to sanitary water supplies, were among the chief concerns.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Australia&#39;s changes in immigration policy, with more commitment to diversity, were something to celebrate in 2010.  I asked about &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/02/notes-from-lunch.html&quot;&gt;the Doctrine of Discovery&lt;/a&gt;, whether that came up (I know it did).  Like Glenn Stockton, I&#39;m focused on &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/07/some-quaker-pr.html&quot;&gt;the representation of indigenous peoples&lt;/a&gt; at the Parliament.  Aboriginal peoples, who have been treated genocidaly, were a focus of this 2010 event.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Doctrine of Christian Discovery (manifest destiny) has been cited by the US Supreme Court as recently as 1995 (some case from upstate New York).  The slave trade depended on this kind of thinking as well.  Australia has had the common decency to forswear appealing to such lame and obsolete principles in future.  The decrepit USA, backward and impoverished, has been unable to keep pace.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Parliament is not about converging all the religions into one, nor about judging what is and what is not a religion.  Consensus is not a goal.  Finding common ground, looking for ways to work together, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a goal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our presenters were Helen Spector, Don Benson, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/02/wanderers-201022.html&quot;&gt;Milt Markewitz&lt;/a&gt; and Lynne Taylor, all of whom attended the Parliament in Melbourne.  Some of the pictures were spectacular.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8928241874881086314'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8928241874881086314'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/wanderers-2010316.html' title='Wanderers 2010.3.16'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-212541603890831725</id><published>2010-03-15T16:34:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2013-04-21T09:13:59.926-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Serene Scene</title><content type='html'>Dr. Tag stopped by today, and prepared a fava bean lunch in our kitchen.  I&#39;d been taken to lunch earlier by the Boltons, so just stayed with black coffee.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lindsey, working on gardening, came inside to join us.  We sat around the living room table, sharing food, yakking about this and that.  We talked about the Middle East and those domain names it hosts (Jordan, Lebanon etc.).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tagrid was with her Yemeni friend earlier, knows quite a few people in Yemen, a great place at least in the old days.  She&#39;s likely to travel in the Middle East again soon, though not in Yemen.  I&#39;ve added her resume (as distinct from her c.v.) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/presentations/Taghrid_Khuri_resume.html&quot;&gt;to my 4D directory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Boltons and I talked about Powell&#39;s Books, its roots in Chicago (where Chuck and Mary first met my dad, independently of one another).  They also wanted to talk about domain names (Israel, USA etc.).  Chuck is a sociology professor emeritus with Portland State, which he came to from UC Davis, having trained at University of Chicago after WW2.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
After lunch with the Boltons, I stopped by to visit Glenn&#39;s workshop on the Pauling Campus.  He let me hold, and take pictures of:  elk antler, pipe stone, manzanita root, abalone, walrus teeth, and a few other assorted raw materials he uses to make things.  Glenn knows a lot about craftsmanship, teaches the subject.  He&#39;s well versed in some of the Native American lore, like where much of the pipe stone came from (Minnesota).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
After lunch, I helped Tag with some domain name issues, and burned a copy of her nephew&#39;s music CD.  She&#39;s still working in my living room as I blog this, doing some banking.  Later this evening, she&#39;ll teach her Arabic class at PCC.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lindsey is back to gardening in the side yard, digging a new bed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Tara, home from school, had the split peas and rice Lindsey cooked yesterday and is up in her room.  We&#39;ve turned the heat on for the evening hours, are mostly keeping the house chilly, trying to conserve peak oil.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The radical math ideas I espouse trickle out by osmosis during some of these conversations, but really I&#39;m too into esoterica to make much political sense, don&#39;t sound like a pundit.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The other radical math teachers I&#39;m working with tend to be pretty spacey as well, a breed of circus geek maybe?  I&#39;ve been developing some of &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/57991&quot;&gt;the mythos&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergeo&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of radical math, our Saturday venue is quitting the scene so don&#39;t expect to find it on your next Portland tour.  &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Muddy Waters&lt;/span&gt;, around the corner is also gone, has been replaced with &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Bare Bones&lt;/span&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/212541603890831725'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/212541603890831725'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/serene-scene.html' title='Serene Scene'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-917305626771851581</id><published>2010-03-07T10:59:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-03-07T19:38:08.745-08:00</updated><title type='text'>More Negotiations</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/fullerproject.1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/fullerproject.1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;rtl&quot; style=&quot;;font-family:&amp;quot;;font-size:85%;&quot;  lang=&quot;he&quot; &gt;יִשְׂרָאֵל&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ve had lots of contract boilerplate to eyeball lately, nothing signed yet, on advice of attorney.  The applied mathematics were intriguing, though not what I&#39;d be tasked with specifically.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Regarding Iran, the initiative to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/12/freeman-dyson-in-portland.html&quot;&gt;criminalize nuclear weapons around the world&lt;/a&gt; is of course &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/jihad.html&quot;&gt;a principled religious position&lt;/a&gt; that many take in all faiths.  I&#39;m pleased if that&#39;s an official position within the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/02/fear-mongering.html&quot;&gt;Islamic orthodoxy&lt;/a&gt;.  Whether this means &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/07/psy-war-whos-losing.html&quot;&gt;the IAEA has complete access&lt;/a&gt; to US, Chinese and Russian facilities remains a point of controversy I suppose, although not for me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This thing about calling &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/07/pr-for-pl.html&quot;&gt;the whole earth &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Israel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and using a Fuller Projection to talk about the &quot;no state solution&quot; sounds kind of radical, even for &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/back-at-laughing-horse.html&quot;&gt;the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Laughing Horse&lt;/span&gt; crowd&lt;/a&gt;, but of course many rabbis already take the position that Israel, like Nirvana (or Samsara for that matter), relates to something more existentially primordial than some nation-state, even so in ancient times.  That&#39;s esoterica however, in that most people only think in literal terms, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/more-from-97214.html&quot;&gt;about Persia&lt;/a&gt; etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When you &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/usaos2.html&quot;&gt;virtualize&lt;/a&gt;, you make the whole earth the game field for any responsible planning, meaning one is taking more consequences into account.  There&#39;s no contradiction in having &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/01/cyber-nations.html&quot;&gt;cyber-nations&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/07/2nd-life-2nd-world.html&quot;&gt;virtual nations&lt;/a&gt; assume responsibility for the whole earth, given &quot;responsibility&quot; doesn&#39;t mean dictating or behaving in some tyrannical fashion.  The &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/06/nightmare-alley-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;geek&lt;/a&gt; world&#39;s meme of &quot;world domination&quot; is related, and may be translated as &quot;self mastery&quot;.  So-called &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/grunch.html&quot;&gt;desovereignization&lt;/a&gt;&quot; may result in more responsible governance simply because the thinking is more realistic, less side-tracked by yesteryear&#39;s legal fictions.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/917305626771851581'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/917305626771851581'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/more-negotiations.html' title='More Negotiations'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8548988585315423844</id><published>2010-03-05T20:13:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-03-06T14:22:23.487-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Back at Laughing Horse</title><content type='html'>A lot goes on around here I don&#39;t know about, duh.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Just tonight I learned that one reason Lindsey was able to join the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Laughing Horse Collective&lt;/span&gt;, was that some holocaust deniers had managed to jump on board and stage an event here, then departed, creating vacancies.  There have been some lasting repercussions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This news seemed kind of freakish, as the collection is packed with holocaust videos, many of which have come through HQS for review.  I bought a copy of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Hilter&#39;s Willing Executioners&lt;/span&gt; here (to the best of my recollection), &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/04/back-at-zoo.html&quot;&gt;mom a book on Hitler youth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/crisis-line.html&quot;&gt;I&#39;m doing door again&lt;/a&gt; tonight, a no-alcohol event.  This benefit is for &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Laughing Horse&lt;/span&gt; itself.  Julia is here too, advising potential customers.  She also paid back some of her IOU ($15), made a note in the book.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Regarding the Fuller syllabus, I&#39;ve had our state-free world projection on display here (briefly, like at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Circadia&lt;/span&gt;), but won&#39;t claim the political left has made him an avatar, any more than the political right has (&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Laughing Horse&lt;/span&gt; leans left, in case you were wondering, calls itself radical).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Around Portland, Fuller (a subversive and a radical) has gotten more attention through OSCONs (not only through me), &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Esozone&lt;/span&gt; (through Trevor especially), and of course through &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/57830&quot;&gt;Portland Center Stage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I would certainly like OMSI to get in on the action, perhaps with some tetrahedral mensuration sculpture and/or some &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/01/location-scouting.html&quot;&gt;cool dwelling machine exhibits&lt;/a&gt;.  Something both futuristic and humanitarian, consistent with our Portland spirit (which Portlandia personifies (she&#39;s a radical too)).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Getting more synergetics-informed geometry on that Omnimax screen would remind us to keep thinking outside the box.  Some of us have been dying to see something along those lines.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lindsey&#39;s friend is helping with the door, so I&#39;m able to focus on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freelists.org/post/wittrsamr/Family-resemblance-and-Mathematics&quot;&gt;the Wittgenstein thread&lt;/a&gt; I was following earlier today.  Wittgenstein was a contemporary of Hitler&#39;s; not saying I believe they were acquainted, although &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/10/triangulating.html&quot;&gt;some say they were&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/back-at-dukes.html&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mike D. of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Duke&#39;s Landing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is here next to me (he&#39;s a member of the Collective).  He&#39;s been upgrading the company XO, got us a developer key.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8548988585315423844'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8548988585315423844'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/back-at-laughing-horse.html' title='Back at Laughing Horse'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-9018938767004400589</id><published>2010-03-03T11:43:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-03-04T09:35:46.215-08:00</updated><title type='text'>For Credit Curriculum Games</title><content type='html'>Geocaching was invented &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/12/we-win.html&quot;&gt;by Dave Ulmer&lt;/a&gt;, early bizmo engineer and pioneer.  His on-board GIS systems led him to many a frontier find.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;However, in thinking of physically strenuous mathematical exercises, a genre, we need to accommodate lots of urban teens, may not simply assume &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/08/escaping-light-pollution.html&quot;&gt;easy access to rural areas&lt;/a&gt; with the wave of a magic wand.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Introducing bus and subway maps from around the world as topologically correct, yet highly simplified (schematic) is a standard data visualization segment.  The next step, of actually riding the bus and train systems, in search of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/05/legally-free.html&quot;&gt;some treasure&lt;/a&gt;, is where this becomes a sport.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Student-friendly urban establishments such as coffee shops, subsidized to operate this program, might provide welcoming environments.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The video game aspects of the course would have this familiar indoor ambiance (already &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/03/serving-buzz.html&quot;&gt;associated with scholarship&lt;/a&gt;), as students swiped their ID cards for points, went through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/middle-school-geography.html&quot;&gt;cartography and geography quizzes&lt;/a&gt;, touched base with on-line referees and/or judges, perhaps sitting in booths with branded swag (sponsor regalia).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then its on to the next puzzle (some algebra required?).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This would be another meaning of &quot;busing&quot; (or &quot;training&quot;), as you would get small groups going between zip codes, creating more shared awareness of a city.  This isn&#39;t a race or game of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Survivor&lt;/span&gt; in which there&#39;s only one prize or winning team, although perks for being faster or first might pertain, depending on the game&#39;s design.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The point is to actually explore one&#39;s environment and not settle for a &quot;virtual world&quot; on one&#39;s desktop.  The incentives need to be far more reliable and real than winning the lottery.  You might not get cash, but you might get a 25 pound bag of organic brown rice, as one of your computerized options.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The reward system will focus a lot of human ingenuity, with participating schools getting much of the credit at an institutional level.  If your school fields some teams, that may be your school&#39;s ticket to some interesting benefits.  Your school will get noticed, its reputation boosted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The more interesting versions of these games feature convergence points deliberately designed for group learning activities.  Having coffee shops participate is a piece of the puzzle but not the whole story.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many high schools already have some of the right stuff, so it might be a matter of organizing across schools, optimizing more.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the other hand, here&#39;s an opportunity to do some basic rethinking and updating.  A claymation studio need not be in the same building as a music recording studio, but better synergy might develop if they were.  Include faculty from art and/or design schools among your advisers, would be my advice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Designing these for-credit games is one thing, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/01/recruiting-for-xrls.html&quot;&gt;recruiting players&lt;/a&gt; another.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/03/wanderers-20100302.html&quot;&gt;The advertising&lt;/a&gt; needs to set realistic expectations.  Some of the exercises shown will require mastery of prerequisite skills, meaning you might not get access to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/06/immersion-experience.html&quot;&gt;all that gear&lt;/a&gt; up front.  That&#39;s what the reward system is about:  equipping those ready for a specific work/study challenge (a role) with the requisite props (as in theater).  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flextegrity.com/galleries/artificial-reef78.php&quot;&gt;The scuba diver&lt;/a&gt; needs scuba equipment and so on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Doing some metal work for high school geometry credit is not as off topic as it sounds, if you imagine building &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/10/nclb-polyhedron-memo.html&quot;&gt;a rhombic triacontahedron&lt;/a&gt; from scratch, or a geodesic sphere.  But where might you go to acquire these skills in a safe environment?  These are the kinds of questions our game designers need to be asking themselves and their communities.  The answers will vary depending on town-gown dynamics, other factors.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Related reading:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=2049288&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&quot;Off Your Duff&quot; Mathematics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (math-teach, Math Forum, March 3, 2010)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhlZPk5ylAXhlB_2-6wrWGdwn0Kj3NIIFLAMAGewAEAqn8Zqx_f-bmFp7kNRx9pEKMzF2cVBeE_lqL4Id8sEuJF81LQ2diHpmEVd9IibIBlbBXBVLJaI95YSv0of8GWuUSY_hKL/s1600-h/ngnm.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 221px; height: 320px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhlZPk5ylAXhlB_2-6wrWGdwn0Kj3NIIFLAMAGewAEAqn8Zqx_f-bmFp7kNRx9pEKMzF2cVBeE_lqL4Id8sEuJF81LQ2diHpmEVd9IibIBlbBXBVLJaI95YSv0of8GWuUSY_hKL/s320/ngnm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5444515979340311618&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9018938767004400589'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9018938767004400589'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/for-credit-curriculum-games.html' title='For Credit Curriculum Games'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhlZPk5ylAXhlB_2-6wrWGdwn0Kj3NIIFLAMAGewAEAqn8Zqx_f-bmFp7kNRx9pEKMzF2cVBeE_lqL4Id8sEuJF81LQ2diHpmEVd9IibIBlbBXBVLJaI95YSv0of8GWuUSY_hKL/s72-c/ngnm.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6495310379285000610</id><published>2010-03-01T21:23:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-03-01T21:41:35.779-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Journal Jot</title><content type='html'>Math teachers in North America would appear to have &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/06/literary-investigation.html&quot;&gt;first dibs&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=2047973&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;this heritage&lt;/a&gt;, but seem to have shrugged it off (can&#39;t be bothered).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Is this &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=2045815&amp;amp;tstart=15&quot;&gt;another chapter&lt;/a&gt; where the wisdom of the ages is kept in hibernation through another dark age, by Arabic speaking cultures?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I met with a teacher of that language this evening at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Bagdad&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=2047973&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;sent a link&lt;/a&gt;, just in case.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lindsey is downtown attending a study group on legalized zombiehood (&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/07/corporation-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;corporate personhood&lt;/a&gt;).  There&#39;s a reason they called it Voodoo Economics.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6495310379285000610'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6495310379285000610'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/journal-jot.html' title='Journal Jot'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3410812805623269818</id><published>2010-02-24T16:38:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2011-05-29T15:54:03.723-07:00</updated><title type='text'>New Essays</title><content type='html'>I have two major new essays in circulation, regarding:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;(a) analytic philosophy and its potentially catalyzing role post linguistic turn (Nietzsche - Wittgenstein):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/WittrsEX/message/2052&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Re: Rorty&#39;s Sins&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  (some autobio, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;WittrsAMR&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/blockquote&gt;and&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;(b) the relevance of an executable logic with types, when it comes to learning concepts like multiplication really well:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=6992862&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Multiplication and the Importance of Types&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (math-teach at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Math Forum&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/WittrsAMR/message/2052&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;By &quot;logic with types&quot; I simply mean a computer language mirroring mathematical objects already in the pantheon:  types of number, polynomials, vectors, matrices... things that add and maybe multiply.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I&#39;m suggesting in (a) is that we encourage more philosophers to look over the hedge into &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2010-February/009824.html&quot;&gt;the computer science neighborhood&lt;/a&gt;, where we suffer from logjams and &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/crisis-line.html&quot;&gt;stalled stories&lt;/a&gt;, at a cost to Global U students everywhere.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our curriculum is in a shambles.  Here we are in 2010, with stronger than ever 3D projection techniques, and yet spatial geometry is still in the dumpster.  Thanks to &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/10/duck-typing.html&quot;&gt;duck typing&lt;/a&gt;&quot; I&#39;m prone to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/08/lightning-talk-re-mites.html&quot;&gt;blame quacks&lt;/a&gt;, but that&#39;s a pretty generic response to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/12/dire-straits.html&quot;&gt;a dire situation&lt;/a&gt;.  We should get more focused.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reviewing my own essay (b) on &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Math Forum&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergeo&lt;/span&gt;, I wrote:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;About as clear as it gets, when it comes to encapsulating an approach, spelling out the whys and wherefores... Note the last section is a not-so-veiled allusion to &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/main-menu.html&quot;&gt;the synergetics concentric hierarchy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/kite-sighting.html&quot;&gt;No kite this time&lt;/a&gt;, but you might imagine one as two sytes, somewhere on the menu.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;We&#39;re enjoying a steely gray day in Portland, with lots of cold rain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A neighborhood representative came by with the Richmond newsletter and we discussed gardening strategies.  The truth about Portland is it&#39;s hard to go wrong, and people try many things, most of which work, in one way or another.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Alexia zipped through to use wifi between appointments.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Glenn and I are on tap through Free School, as teachers of &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Digital_Math&quot;&gt;Neolithic and Martian math &lt;/a&gt;respectively.  The control room collective acts as a dispatcher, books venues, like on SE Belmont or wherever.  Our next gig is in March.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4383572749/&quot; title=&quot;Twinning (POV-Ray) by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2691/4383572749_38cfc18714_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Twinning (POV-Ray)&quot; height=&quot;233&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;python + povray&lt;br /&gt;(feb 23, 2010)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3410812805623269818'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3410812805623269818'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/02/new-essays.html' title='New Essays'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2691/4383572749_38cfc18714_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2004320714309715455</id><published>2010-02-23T11:35:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-02-23T11:44:13.186-08:00</updated><title type='text'>A Parable</title><content type='html'>Sometimes Italian hill towns, tired of internal feuding, would outsource the mayor position to someone with a recognized track record.  The crack team would come in, set up housekeeping, and maybe show the locals how it&#39;s done.  Before long, the town would be running smoothly again, simmering issues resolved, hard questions confronted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If the temporary managers saw themselves in that light, as temporary, not looking for permanent work, then the workflow would go smoothly.  However, some might see themselves as wanting to become entrenched, to go for that pension.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In exceptional cases, this might be a welcome development, to have an outsider join the community in some responsible capacity, but for the most part, your outsourced team should move on, as the locals will eventually wish to reassert their steering functions, now that they&#39;ve learned how to drive in a new way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This same issue arises with mercenaries, ostensibly hired to protect against foes in neighboring hill towns.  A corrupt force, taking money from all sides, selling services to all sides, will simply run it as a protection racket.  In a monopolistic economy, that spells trouble for all concerned.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2004320714309715455'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2004320714309715455'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/02/parable.html' title='A Parable'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1008101023042585368</id><published>2010-02-22T15:07:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-02-22T15:12:31.595-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Teacher Trainings</title><content type='html'>I characterize teacher trainings as B2B, versus B2C, in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=2045815&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; to the Math Forum:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;in business, we speak of B2C vs. B2B.  That&#39;s business to consumer and business to business.  I think of teacher trainings as B2B.  Imagine Intel a sponsor, and teachers getting paid to be there (on the clock, serving the public).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;In the balance of this post, I&#39;m giving examples of the kind of lore each teacher might adapt, translate, recast in terms relevant to those placed in her or his care.  The teacher manages the classroom, and the curriculum deliberately encourages a place based approach:  embed this material in local circumstances in ways that will help your students gain mastery over their own environment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That being said, the stories are from all over the map, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;National Geographic&lt;/span&gt; style, and come from many parts of the time line:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;factoring polynomials on the Italian peninsula, thanks to the new technology coming in through Pisa from Baghdad and places east;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bishop Berkeley&#39;s vicious attacks against Calculus, when first unveiled by Newton and Leibniz (and the naming of UC Berkeley in his honor);&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the rise of perspective in European painting and the evolution of XYZ coordinates in that milieu;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the impact of the spread of &quot;cyphers&quot; on the Italian Renaissance;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the emergence of 60-degree coordination (in contrast to XYZ) in connection with the discovery of the hexane ring, newly popular drawings of naturally occuring shapes.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;Would a child in Borneo have any interest in such stories?  She or he might well.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;UN agencies, many school districts, some curriculum providers, prefer this &quot;place based&quot; approach.  The geographic component gets a boost. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Math becomes more of an outdoor activity as navigating the subway and bus system becomes an exercise in topology or graph theory. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Counting calories in an energy conserving context is not off topic either, as foods and food values have their own calculus, worth learning.  Calories connect to kilowatt-hours, other measures of energy.  Conversion constants apply.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In some parts of Oregon, there&#39;s a trend towards schools having their own gardens, even in urban settings.  This is par for the course in many parts of the world.  Having &quot;the field&quot; be a gridiron and practice space for mostly physically dominant boys is likewise commonplace.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ve seen many schools with ample room for both a field and a garden.  In some of these same schools girls share access to sports facilities as equal partners, with varying degrees of segregation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Entirely segregated schools may be publicly chartered in your zip code area.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Language immersion schools may also be provided, with or without segregation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Once you start getting into permutations, no one district may be expected to cover every possibility.  An active exchange program will give your family access to other options, including overseas.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1008101023042585368'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1008101023042585368'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/02/teacher-trainings.html' title='Teacher Trainings'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4775277563304127027</id><published>2010-02-20T18:28:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-02-21T03:15:34.672-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Doing the Math</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4374854038/&quot; title=&quot;Computational Math by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4053/4374854038_e511d47fc6_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Computational Math&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; width=&quot;180&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The math problem at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Peoples&#39; Food Co-op&lt;/span&gt; was to figure out which eco-friendly dish washing powder soap had the most bang for the buck.  The bulk offering said 3x concentrated, only a table spoon per load if your unit had but the one soap holder.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The two boxed offerings gave weights, but only one gave loads per box.  The other had temporarily removed the word &quot;natural&quot; from its literature and wanted readers to know why.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My challenge was to use my cell phone as a calculator.  This isn&#39;t one of those Droids or anything, not R2D2.  I flubbed getting a decimal point, plus still needed to ask how much of the bulk item gets one those 64 loads.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lindsey, much better at this game, volunteered to obtain this information next time, was just too busy buying to feed her army, at the time of my flailing.  We were at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Peoples&#39;&lt;/span&gt; in service of another  &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Vegans not Pigs&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Duke&#39;s Landing&lt;/span&gt; (with chicken an option for carnivores).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These have become ritualized no-alcohol events, where we learn how to buy and cook effectively and tastefully, amidst live music provided by local bands.  A more wholesome event would be hard to distill.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I brought a whole paper bag of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flextegrity.com/&quot;&gt;Flextegrity icosahedra&lt;/a&gt;, cast-offs with paint on &#39;em, fresh from the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Pauling Campus&lt;/span&gt; studio.  I feel like one of Santa&#39;s elves.  I piled some around an old XO for another photogenic tableau.  Maybe this one &#39;ll end up as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/01/pacific-rim-economics.html&quot;&gt;polyethylene billboard&lt;/a&gt; in Tokyo somewhere (just kidding)?  G1G1 meets Radical Math (polyhedra are considered somewhat radical in 2010, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/11/world-game-museum.html&quot;&gt;check standard textbooks&lt;/a&gt; to gauge the level of our poverty).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One imagines these innovative subcultures, working towards a better tomorrow.  In Portland, we have them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;However it&#39;s probably a good thing &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/02/more-musings-about-television.html&quot;&gt;the Japanese TV crew&lt;/a&gt; didn&#39;t come all the way from Narita for this one.  Troy has to DJ somewhere else tonight.  There&#39;s not been much publicity to speak of.  You won&#39;t find any mention of these experiments in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Oregonian&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Willamette Week&lt;/span&gt;.  We&#39;ll make do with the amateur film crew (me).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4104819987/in/photostream/&quot;&gt;Evelyn&lt;/a&gt; just showed up, is joining Lindsey in the kitchen upstairs. Now here&#39;s one of the bands. My daughter is off at her debating tournament all day, is welcome to join us (too exhausted: &quot;extem&quot; with 30 minutes to prepare on any subject, no Internet, is a rough row to hoe).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now that Pycon is gathered in Atlanta, we&#39;re getting some themes coming through on the PSF members list.  If you scrounge around in the blogosphere, you&#39;ll likely glean more.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I spent another long day with the math teachers, yakking about &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/02/remembering-new-york.html&quot;&gt;my days at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;McGraw-Hill&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Hugh Kenner important, wrote a column for BYTE).  We should be seeing those recruiting commercials around now, for our new kind of math course.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fighting about what programming language to use is somewhat beside the point, as that&#39;s for teachers on the ground to decide.  One goes with the army one&#39;s got, as someone once said.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mike D has installed &lt;a href=&quot;http://webpath.net/index.php&quot;&gt;Xtra Ordinary&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://aspn.activestate.com/ASPN/Mail/Message/edu-sig/3789265&quot;&gt;his XO&lt;/a&gt;, an operating system geared  more for adults.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yes, there&#39;s a counter-culture aspect to these operations, in that we&#39;re documenting how Portland&#39;s underground was &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2010/01/coffee-shop-schools.html&quot;&gt;carrying the torch forward&lt;/a&gt;.  When it comes to tetrahedral mensuration, world game, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/02/octet-truss.html&quot;&gt;octet truss&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/02/celebrating-soho.html&quot;&gt;tensegrity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/08/flextegrity_18.html&quot;&gt;flextegrity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/12/global-grid-info.html&quot;&gt;global grid&lt;/a&gt; etc., the avant-garde was on SE Belmont, with &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Laughing Horse&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Pauling Campus&lt;/span&gt; among the back office collectives.  Lets keep this in mind as other institutions crowd in to cash in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh9moFK8alORv0wh5M_Ex4xNF-arycAr7HVuIGkR4TOEu8OietRNlZzWewcWeyTzDp9cUfvTWy_Pm-KR5_m5RQMeccNS0KQQ-YQ3GIWmUU6iSZcz5UtmpmjN_IDimnwawmMXE6s/s1600-h/next_dukes.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 130px; height: 200px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh9moFK8alORv0wh5M_Ex4xNF-arycAr7HVuIGkR4TOEu8OietRNlZzWewcWeyTzDp9cUfvTWy_Pm-KR5_m5RQMeccNS0KQQ-YQ3GIWmUU6iSZcz5UtmpmjN_IDimnwawmMXE6s/s200/next_dukes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5440603690803016242&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: next week ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4775277563304127027'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4775277563304127027'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/02/doing-math.html' title='Doing the Math'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4053/4374854038_e511d47fc6_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6132870365171419332</id><published>2010-02-18T18:08:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2014-08-20T13:10:57.095-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Fear Mongering</title><content type='html'>I&#39;m seeing all those worries about Iran, but then I&#39;m thinking the diplomatic corps has been amply endowed with all the raw materials necessary to implement confidence building measures.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We don&#39;t just want better nuclear medicine in Iran, we want a stronger power grid feeding the Middle East, including states with no right to exist (all of them).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Don&#39;t blame the religions for not getting along, as I think those problems have been mostly resolved.  You&#39;ve got a bunch of weak kneed politicians running around drumming up fears, but that&#39;s hardly to work for one&#39;s pay.  If fear mongering is all you&#39;ve got, why not just admit to incompetence and gracefully announce retirement?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
OK, harsh words from the peanut gallery, I admit it.  However, the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/10/us-versus-john-lennon-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;give peace a chance&lt;/a&gt;&quot; meme didn&#39;t start with me.  Lots of great ideas for &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2014/08/pilgrimmage.html&quot;&gt;geodesic mosques&lt;/a&gt;, worth trying, Allah would like it I bet.  Many interesting civilizational innovations ahead.  To ramp up towards war is definitely anti-Christian, as well as anti-Muslim etc.  I wouldn&#39;t go running to the corner guru for an excuse.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Wallowing in &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/08/archived-political-cartoon-may-1998.html&quot;&gt;the nuclear weapons world&lt;/a&gt; is just poorly thought out.  We need to stop proliferating, obviously, but we also need to keep cutting back, decommissioning.  It&#39;s a long slow process and requires ongoing verification.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Iran is neither the first nor the last player at this table, just one more among many.  So let&#39;s get on with the real work of disarmament, starting with the big powers as usual.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6132870365171419332'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6132870365171419332'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/02/fear-mongering.html' title='Fear Mongering'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7512125504992276152</id><published>2010-02-17T21:37:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-02-18T16:50:39.570-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Necklace Theory</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjJCMzyVOpbe-yvxUXDrKTyp_-owFQH_KZMO-l54P0vP01jrXegLHeYvy8v1-1NrDsCjy-r5lrBudVT4UzZ2hUBcyL_TOYffE3vfTJCpp8WqWFADHENKxU3McevcZkq7ysJx6ql/s1600-h/fungus.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 228px; height: 320px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjJCMzyVOpbe-yvxUXDrKTyp_-owFQH_KZMO-l54P0vP01jrXegLHeYvy8v1-1NrDsCjy-r5lrBudVT4UzZ2hUBcyL_TOYffE3vfTJCpp8WqWFADHENKxU3McevcZkq7ysJx6ql/s320/fungus.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5439726111685775826&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;People glance in my cage and wonder what makes me so fanatical about &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/05/show-me-polyhedra.html&quot;&gt;Polyhedra&lt;/a&gt; and such.  What&#39;s this guy&#39;s problem.  Writing today:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Regarding 60-degree coordination, we have this focus on the tetrahedron instead of the cube. In this case you find many published books, some coffee table arty, some on the web, magazine articles, web pages, Youtubes, other scholarship, and *still* it&#39;s almost impossible to get the time of day from busy (too busy) people.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;I&#39;d say it&#39;s the Necklace Effect that I&#39;m after, in that the 60-degree aesthetic forms a glue language, a rubric, like a string, with concentric hierarchy, octet truss, Fuller Projection, world game, geodesic domes, high tech eco-villages, healthier lifestyles... mom and apple pie, all beads on that string.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yes, I note the family resemblance to &quot;domino effect&quot;, well exploited in &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/04/robots-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;the movie &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Robots&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/12/another-rant.html&quot;&gt;The concentric hierarchy&lt;/a&gt; is the best bead to keep nudging, because it&#39;s so mathematically correct.  Those defending the bastions of rationality tend to close loopholes with hard logic, if any might be found.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Or will they try to fake it?  Using some flavor of CS BS perhaps?  Is this about Computer Science versus &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.geneseo.edu/pipermail/math-thinking-l/2010-February/000621.html&quot;&gt;Neo-Platonism&lt;/a&gt;?  Ghosts of Bourbaki?  What do the artists say?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You&#39;d think the intelligentsia might at least appreciate the marketing challenge.  Here&#39;s a fun puzzle for &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/01/random-walking-in-ivm-fm.html&quot;&gt;you Madison Avenue types&lt;/a&gt;.  Is this a &quot;too bitter a pill&quot; scenario?  What sugar might we coat it with?  The eye candy is already tops.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Once in, we find the concentric hierarchy is a bastion of rationality in its own right, and worth defending.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then it&#39;s on to the adjacent bead, and so on down the line, like firecrackers going off.  Some kind of celebration?</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7512125504992276152'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7512125504992276152'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/02/necklace-theory.html' title='Necklace Theory'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjJCMzyVOpbe-yvxUXDrKTyp_-owFQH_KZMO-l54P0vP01jrXegLHeYvy8v1-1NrDsCjy-r5lrBudVT4UzZ2hUBcyL_TOYffE3vfTJCpp8WqWFADHENKxU3McevcZkq7ysJx6ql/s72-c/fungus.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6816857165442504834</id><published>2010-02-16T00:14:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-02-23T02:39:22.244-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Getting Phi in the Game</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgsKs474ABxsa88rMMOEyRB4gl4LOuExEevUutIHhK9fwEJmeGqAUOcW4Ctx05aFFKsPSkcIVBmpRD85sjlr4SJCY_35fVhdbVTAsgji2dzyZ3q1J_tsGmFYurjV_IqBjqR-WRL/s1600-h/rtwithcube.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 320px; height: 303px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgsKs474ABxsa88rMMOEyRB4gl4LOuExEevUutIHhK9fwEJmeGqAUOcW4Ctx05aFFKsPSkcIVBmpRD85sjlr4SJCY_35fVhdbVTAsgji2dzyZ3q1J_tsGmFYurjV_IqBjqR-WRL/s320/rtwithcube.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5438753047391208866&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: vZome by Koski ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Kirby Urner&lt;/span&gt;:  in the calcs below, the assumption is always tetravolumes, meaning we&#39;ve calibrated to the concentric hierarchy with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/main-menu.html&quot;&gt;the volume 20 cuboctahedron&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The icosahedron with that same edge, of volume ~18.51 is the icosahedron of volume 5 Φ&lt;sup&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;2 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;√2 mentioned below.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The pentagonal dodecahedron is its partner in the rhombic triacontahedron, inside of which one finds these unit-edge cubes (but not of unit volume in this schema).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;David Koski&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Icosahedron edge = 1 in tetra volumes (blue)&lt;br /&gt;= ~18.51229587&lt;br /&gt;= 5 Φ&lt;sup&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;2 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;√2&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pentagonal dodecahedron edge Φ&lt;sup&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;-1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; or .618034 (orange)&lt;br /&gt;= ~15.35001821&lt;br /&gt;= (Φ&lt;sup&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; + 1) 3√2&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rhombic triacontahedron diagonals 1 and Φ&lt;sup&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;-1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (red)&lt;br /&gt;= ~21.21320244&lt;br /&gt;= 15√2&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cube edge = 1 (purple)&lt;br /&gt;= ~8.485281374&lt;br /&gt;= 6√2&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6816857165442504834'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6816857165442504834'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/02/getting-phi-in-game.html' title='Getting Phi in the Game'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgsKs474ABxsa88rMMOEyRB4gl4LOuExEevUutIHhK9fwEJmeGqAUOcW4Ctx05aFFKsPSkcIVBmpRD85sjlr4SJCY_35fVhdbVTAsgji2dzyZ3q1J_tsGmFYurjV_IqBjqR-WRL/s72-c/rtwithcube.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7473705478965265920</id><published>2010-02-11T22:24:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-02-11T22:26:32.419-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Crazy Busy</title><content type='html'>I was wigging out on Facebook, between praying for Pat and Aunt Betty, Aunt Evelyn, dear friends. Because of this looming ski trip.  Who were the adults?  Tara was organizing skillfully, but teens deserve role models.  I greatly appreciate those stepping up to the plate.  I&#39;m less stressed in that dimension.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;LW is loading the company car for another fundraiser.  I&#39;m likely out the door in a different direction, but that&#39;s for the future to bring.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I checked in with Dr. Tag earlier, walking to and from.  She was expecting to overlap with some Mercy Corps staffer, with news from Haiti, insider perspective.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I at least conveyed the good news about our green light for the math teachers (talking about those kites at the NCTM website):  you&#39;re officially free to teach our Renaissance shoptalk, in tandem with standard fare.  Be generous with those polyhedra, why not?  Think geodesic.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Spice it up, share the lore, build bridges to other ethnicities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Math is about reaching out, not just introspecting. Philosophy that much more so.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Midnight gardening anyone?  Sounds kinda kooky I realize, but the front side pile, the result of a welcome thwacking, was just calling out for attention -- of a kind I don&#39;t need.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So I filled a thistle bin, hauled some twigs (giant ones), moved stuff around.  It&#39;s not like we&#39;re over-staffed or anything.  I do what I&#39;m able, as a man of modest skills, still trainable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thank you to well wishers, co-conspirators, hangers on.  Blessed be.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7473705478965265920'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7473705478965265920'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/02/crazy-busy.html' title='Crazy Busy'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2949933266234852458</id><published>2010-02-10T20:32:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-02-11T00:38:17.593-08:00</updated><title type='text'>What is a Textbook?</title><content type='html'>[ reposted from &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=2036899&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;math-teach @ Math Forum&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;              I think what&#39;s probably obvious to all of us is that the word &quot;textbook&quot; is becoming decoupled from the medium, or was never that coupled in the first place.  A textbook has a specific format and purpose.  In a math teaching context, a textbook usually comes with exercises, perhaps a teacher&#39;s edition and so on (many criteria pertain).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Is it a PDF?  In wood pulp?  On a Kindle?  An XO-3?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We don&#39;t know, just from the word &quot;textbook&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the case of books through Google, the author may have already chosen a public license, so free copying is not an issue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/freecomputerbooks/web/think-python-an-introduction-to-software-design-2008-2009-allen-b-downey&quot;&gt;Good example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When I teach a &quot;Pythonic math&quot; course (math using Python), I&#39;m free to point students to free textbooks on the web, other writings, and not dictate whether they order printed copy or not.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some may have valid and necessary requirements for hardcopy. I have that myself, in part because some people don&#39;t believe a book exists until it weighs something.  Sometimes you just want that airplane seat copy, with no need to haul out a fat laptop.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2949933266234852458'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2949933266234852458'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/02/what-is-textbook.html' title='What is a Textbook?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-53395302715728799</id><published>2010-02-09T14:18:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-02-09T19:39:54.414-08:00</updated><title type='text'>News We Could Use</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjtO8O_PYmwadqtQRpcwPbxlBUnwFygTiaoQZJ6K56-0y_0kJn5XtsIHrSZfwOpjPpd9QHCQPnjwTVy9vU8Q00L7Kf-268gYKHbrzQm1dWvTvkvKSvLJTacQ5TCJWSkULdwvkfu/s1600-h/omruncovered.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 320px; height: 221px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjtO8O_PYmwadqtQRpcwPbxlBUnwFygTiaoQZJ6K56-0y_0kJn5XtsIHrSZfwOpjPpd9QHCQPnjwTVy9vU8Q00L7Kf-268gYKHbrzQm1dWvTvkvKSvLJTacQ5TCJWSkULdwvkfu/s320/omruncovered.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5436381012486721986&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Stories we&#39;d like to see&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The Obama Administration today signaled its interest in &lt;a href=&quot;http://solutions.synearth.net/a-community-dwelling-machine/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Old Man River City&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as a possible public works project.  Community leaders familiar with the design have been invited to the White House to discuss its prospects.  Clearing the construction site could begin as early as next year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sarah Palin acknowledged today that as former Governor of Alaska, she was quite familiar with the Bering Strait &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/02/connecting-with-friends.html&quot;&gt;high voltage linkup proposal&lt;/a&gt;, but thought it needed more study.  CNN will be running a series of special features focusing on the global electrical grid, its history and prospects.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Google Earth has created a new data overlay showing electrical grid information.  The recently implemented fold-out options show the entire Earth in one view.  The Fuller Projection is one of several available.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The NCTM has officially endorsed &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=2036171&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;tetrahedral mensuration&lt;/a&gt;&quot; as a worthy topic for inclusion in K-12 mathematics curricula, based on results from several pilot studies, and expert advice from key professors.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Students in Flint, Michigan will be among the first to test drive the XO3 tablet, the next iteration of the One Laptop per Child line.  Company sponsors include a long list of familiar brands, including Kellogg and General Mills.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiNpNsIbpjD0Z1HpXHoea0_nsM9Xm6k4-sHrZB8e3_Zkko22ghes6CextJYbRLBW9ujB1oMp0N2b5dVuKnQY9HqIK2YiJV5j3P0pV80yP_fFIZo0N8GpYEC_wayzubst-jNKR0o/s1600-h/olpc_xo3_1-540x386.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 200px; height: 143px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiNpNsIbpjD0Z1HpXHoea0_nsM9Xm6k4-sHrZB8e3_Zkko22ghes6CextJYbRLBW9ujB1oMp0N2b5dVuKnQY9HqIK2YiJV5j3P0pV80yP_fFIZo0N8GpYEC_wayzubst-jNKR0o/s200/olpc_xo3_1-540x386.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5436396375264986066&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Reality checks&lt;/span&gt;:  OMR is currently shelved and rarely if ever mentioned; Governor Palin and CNN never mention the Bering Strait electrical hookup (not the same as the Bridge to Nowhere); ESRI ArcGIS 9 includes a Fuller Projection but Google Earth does not; NCTM does do some &quot;non-traditional&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;http://illuminations.nctm.org/LessonDetail.aspx?ID=L639&quot;&gt;tetrahedral mensuration&lt;/a&gt; on an obscure web page; it&#39;s unclear if the XO3, with more skeptics than sponsors, will be available by 2012 (or produced at all).&lt;/span&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/53395302715728799'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/53395302715728799'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/02/news-we-could-use.html' title='News We Could Use'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjtO8O_PYmwadqtQRpcwPbxlBUnwFygTiaoQZJ6K56-0y_0kJn5XtsIHrSZfwOpjPpd9QHCQPnjwTVy9vU8Q00L7Kf-268gYKHbrzQm1dWvTvkvKSvLJTacQ5TCJWSkULdwvkfu/s72-c/omruncovered.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry></feed>