<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=626'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=601&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=651&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>626</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2608135158534468990</id><published>2015-12-08T22:41:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2015-12-14T19:06:53.882-08:00</updated><title type='text'>The Power of Community (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/23508390592/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF2143&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF2143&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/697/23508390592_217fe7a0d9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
This documentary is uplifting, as it tells a story we all want to hear, of humans surviving an energy crunch by cooperating, rather than turning on one another, every man for himself.  The backdrop is local politics, less than peak oil.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Peak Oil is real, and should be welcomed as our saving grace vs. global warming, as the fossil fuels are simply running out, at least half empty already mas o meno.  I always thought the Peak Oil talkers were more into &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/11/end-of-suburbia-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;taking the bull by the horns&lt;/a&gt; than the Oceans and Temperature Rising talkers, not that these are mutually exclusive talks.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Cuba was caught in the middle of Cold War politics and could not afford the lifestyle to which it had become accustomed, not in the wake of perestroika (&lt;span lang=&quot;ru&quot;&gt;перестро́йка&lt;/span&gt;). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Cubans were actually using more pesticide and fertilizer per hectare than many, and were exporting cash crops in exchange for basic foodstuffs, just like every other tropical paradise.&amp;nbsp; But for the US embargo, they had a mirror image thing going in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/07/2nd-life-2nd-world.html&quot;&gt;the Second World&lt;/a&gt;, which was a lot like the First.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But then the Soviet Union morphed into something else and left Cuba to face everything short of invasion, in terms of economic sanctions.&amp;nbsp; Any ship putting in to a Cuban port was blacklisted in the US for at least six months, a heavy penalty.&amp;nbsp; Cuba went from being Second World to Third World overnight almost.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
With the sudden shut off of former sources of income, Cubans had to completely reorganize their agricultural and transportation systems.&amp;nbsp; In so doing, they made some important discoveries, such that the way soil is compacted by heavy equipment requires heavy equipment to undo, and the pesticides and fertilizers were killing the natural topsoil, necessitating more artificial ingredients.&amp;nbsp; The spiral was unsustainable.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They went back to organic farming, and to oxen, with diverse crops, less mono-culture. This was done not out of idealism but out of necessity.&amp;nbsp; Cuba suddenly needed to be more food independent.&amp;nbsp; This takes big changes at the grass roots, but then in the face of severe shortages, the status quo was not acceptable either.&amp;nbsp; The changes were highly motivated.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tractors were still important of course, but someone taking a plow to his or her field, behind two oxen, was once against lionized as an agrarian superstar.&amp;nbsp; The &quot;peasant&quot; (aka organic farmer) had status again.&amp;nbsp; Agricultural engineering is about as basic as it gets, just ask the Australians (they help out with their permaculture knowledge).&amp;nbsp; Once the concept of &quot;working with Nature&quot; is ingrained, a lot of the work just happens.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The upshot of all this morphing is Cuba is now enjoying higher living standards, in terms of people having amicable relationships (i.e. social skills).&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re not mowing each other down as much as in some countries, nor living the life of sputtering gas-aholics or &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/11/smart-art.html&quot;&gt;shop-aholics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Better food, more savvy, a closer connection with the Earth.&amp;nbsp; Our back to the Earthers here in the US already believe in this lifestyle, and some even practice it.&amp;nbsp; Portland, Oregon is much infused with the same values.&amp;nbsp; We admire our agricultural sector quite a bit (a source for hops, grapes and wine, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/12/touring-home.html&quot;&gt;cannabis products&lt;/a&gt;, pears and apples, berries and Christmas trees, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/tillamook.html&quot;&gt;also cheeses&lt;/a&gt;), not just &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/11/onami-tour.html&quot;&gt;our nanotechnology&lt;/a&gt; (not that these are entirely separate).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s interesting is to mix the older more established methods of agriculture with new discoveries and inventions.&amp;nbsp; Going back to oxen and horses does not mean giving up Google Earth or smartphone apps, which draw little wattage on the demand side.&amp;nbsp; No one says you can&#39;t use Linux to help manage the farm, whether locally or in some cloud is up to the local proprietor.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This version of &quot;the agrarian lifestyle&quot; is not about self deprivation so much as learning how to master a definite puzzle, and learning to live lightly upon the Earth.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Living longer and prospering does not have to mean replicating a suburban American lifestyle, high on synthetic foods, low on developing the skills our pioneer progenitors took for granted.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Coming to grips with &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/10/oil-water-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Peak Oil&lt;/a&gt; is what Cubans have done in miniature.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re proud of what they&#39;ve done and know the world needs hopeful examples.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/12/global-data-global-matrix.html&quot;&gt;Bucky Fuller&lt;/a&gt; always called it &quot;starter fluid&quot; those oil reserves.&amp;nbsp; We have this convenient store of carbon energy to boost us into a next age, with different lifestyle solutions.&amp;nbsp; We took off like a rocket and cratered our own nest.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In this next chapter, one of weaning, if we just squander the asset away without planning, instead choosing to fight for the right to stay stuck in the mud, then we&#39;ll get to look back and wonder: just what was so important about all those &quot;jobs&quot; we were doing?&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I mean, how can we even call it &quot;work&quot; if its primary goal is to distract us from what really needs doing?&amp;nbsp; What if, unlike Cuba, the rest of us just decide to goof off?&amp;nbsp; We sure burn a lot of oil just dinking around with our war toys.&amp;nbsp; You&#39;d think as a species we might get more serious.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2608135158534468990'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2608135158534468990'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/12/the-power-of-community-movie-review.html' title='The Power of Community (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7319291423869445851</id><published>2015-12-07T14:57:00.005-08:00</published><updated>2015-12-15T05:28:20.807-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Timelines Welcome</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/18107831193/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF9128&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF9128&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8872/18107831193_35d80d8a5d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/01/thirsters-gather.html&quot;&gt;At &lt;i&gt;Thirsters&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a room on East Broadway where cognoscenti gather, we&#39;re blessed with some interesting room decor, including a framed timeline of world history, based on a Biblical version of events.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m guessing it was published in the early 1900s, maybe late 1800s?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve been talking &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/about-factory.html&quot;&gt;to Glenn&lt;/a&gt; about his &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/12/global-data-global-matrix.html&quot;&gt;Global Matrix&lt;/a&gt; system and the timelines it purveys, unfortunately not in such a concrete form as a website, yet.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiki2.org/wiki/Last_glacial_period&quot;&gt;Maybe 11K BC&lt;/a&gt; is when we find some evidence of humanity emerging from the prior ice age.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Missoula floods (about thirty of them) have to do with great glaciers melting.&amp;nbsp; Lakes would pool in the ice way back when, then one warm day, break through some rim and drench the land to the sea.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Black Sea got filled in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nationalgeographic.com/blacksea/ax/frame.html&quot;&gt;around the same time&lt;/a&gt; right?&amp;nbsp; Noah wasn&#39;t lying about what was to come.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That wasn&#39;t the only flood though.&amp;nbsp; Plus there&#39;ve been other ice ages.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The coasts keep changing.&amp;nbsp; Looking at the globe today does not tell us the scene even a few thousand years ago.&amp;nbsp; Dilmun is mostly under water.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Deep time timelines must be out there, I&#39;m just in the mood to find them.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s my attitude.&amp;nbsp; They must be out there.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, it&#39;s true, scholars do not all agree about deep history or what happened when.&amp;nbsp; Timelines are based on specific schools of thought.&amp;nbsp; Lets just get them on the table at least.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The precession of the planet on its axis is important to relate to climate phenomena.&amp;nbsp; Our north axis points at Polaris these days, but that was not always the case.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Before we got into this age of Ursa, the north axis was pointed more at a star in Draco.&amp;nbsp; Old myths talk about the bear triumphing over the dragon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It takes about 26K years to do a precessional cycle.&amp;nbsp; &quot;In approximately 3200 years, the star Gamma Cephei in the Cepheus constellation will succeed Polaris for this position.&quot; [&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Axial_precession&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhzBEok8f7BcN6SSCUCi3tK4wIFq8D7PqK7iKB_lpnHbiaLdwl0ggMUGEUDX2YQHi-6UjzbViZHlknKBpPliaMQV-SkrbPR7mhFQ05TJVO6ESxoF5Ab_9ydIExjoudW9N7M9A0Q/s1600/800px-Precession_N.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhzBEok8f7BcN6SSCUCi3tK4wIFq8D7PqK7iKB_lpnHbiaLdwl0ggMUGEUDX2YQHi-6UjzbViZHlknKBpPliaMQV-SkrbPR7mhFQ05TJVO6ESxoF5Ab_9ydIExjoudW9N7M9A0Q/s320/800px-Precession_N.gif&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Precession_N.gif#/media/File:Precession_N.gif&quot;&gt;Precession N&lt;/a&gt;&quot; by Tauʻolunga - self, 4 bit GIF.&lt;br /&gt;
Licensed under &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5&quot; title=&quot;Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 2.5&quot;&gt;CC BY-SA 2.5&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/&quot;&gt;Commons&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7319291423869445851'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7319291423869445851'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/12/timelines-welcome.html' title='Timelines Welcome'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhzBEok8f7BcN6SSCUCi3tK4wIFq8D7PqK7iKB_lpnHbiaLdwl0ggMUGEUDX2YQHi-6UjzbViZHlknKBpPliaMQV-SkrbPR7mhFQ05TJVO6ESxoF5Ab_9ydIExjoudW9N7M9A0Q/s72-c/800px-Precession_N.gif" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2714764131111086906</id><published>2015-12-07T14:57:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2015-12-07T18:19:45.557-08:00</updated><title type='text'>The Social Network (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Let me say right off the bat that I&#39;m highly skeptical of docu-drama as a genre, but then what else is there?&amp;nbsp; Every war movie ever made is a docu-drama, almost, unless you count the few documentaries, spliced together from footage from the actual battlefield.&amp;nbsp; Usually those get caught up in somebody&#39;s &quot;history&quot; and from there acquire spin.&amp;nbsp; Fictional bits creep in.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, having attended Princeton, I can attest to some realism in the importance of rowing as a lifestyle, to those lucky enough to grow up around rivers or otherwise break in.&amp;nbsp; However I think Zuckerberg&#39;s character is less interested in banking on Harvard&#39;s name than on achieving redemption through smarts.&amp;nbsp; The movie is about meritocracy versus patriarchy in many dimensions, with software engineering giving rise to that &lt;i&gt;nouveau riche&lt;/i&gt; we call Silicon Valley, self-booting.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Deeper than that though, the opening scene sets off a battle of the sexes, with the Zuckerberg character honestly insecure about what he brings to the table and trying to negotiate from perceived weakness.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s not one of those &quot;crew cut&quot; Harvard guys but he figures he still has the appeal of knowing some inner circle and so addresses his love interest in terms of a rags to riches story, as in &quot;I can help make you known to the people who matter&quot;.&amp;nbsp; Isn&#39;t that a core game at Harvard?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
His girlfriend breaks up with him over that as she&#39;s interested in a relationship more based in equality and neither having the leverage of social advantage.&amp;nbsp; Had Zuckerberg not felt he was coming from weakness, he might have avoided a lot of soul searching but then we might not have Facebook or this movie, so lets give him the space do the math in his own time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
His exoneration comes late in the film when a lawyer of that same ineffable species, who has heard the whole story, tells him to his face he&#39;s not what the other girl said he was.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s worth a lot, coming from her, as she&#39;s in a position to have insight.&amp;nbsp; From that standpoint alone I could see why this movie would not prove too damaging to any of those involved.&amp;nbsp; Each walks away with something, just like in real life.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2714764131111086906'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2714764131111086906'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/12/the-social-network-movie-review.html' title='The Social Network (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8576720852871277213</id><published>2015-12-01T11:44:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2016-01-16T14:07:34.766-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Mathy Memes</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/d/msg/mathfuture/2mCCtmdePbA/BUjBkyTQBgAJ&quot;&gt;a first draft&lt;/a&gt; published to MathFuture, a Google Group ]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My talks at PyCons 
(Python conventions) and OSCONs (Open Source conventions) going back 
show me mounting the stage to decry &quot;calculus mountain&quot;, by which I 
meant the obstacle course and sometimes source of disappointment occasioned by the &quot;forced march&quot; through &quot;delta calculus&quot; if 
wanting to get into a four year college, and by extension into a STEM 
field (or &quot;work for NASA&quot; as some put it).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My contention, in those years, was those like me who&#39;d made it over calculus mountain 
-- I got into honors calc at Princeton, skipping the regular, had 
Thurston the topologist for a prof; we used Spivak&#39;s, &lt;i&gt;Calculus on 
Manifolds&lt;/i&gt; -- found on the other side some &quot;cool pools&quot; i.e. an oasis of 
other mathy topics that &lt;i&gt;could have been&lt;/i&gt; just as well taught in high 
school, providing alternatives to those not turned on by calculus.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
An example of such a &quot;cool pool&quot;, no delta calc required, is Group 
Theory.&amp;nbsp; Permutations at play.&amp;nbsp; More generally, what we today call 
&quot;discrete mathematics&quot; was screamingly relevant, in terms of the doors 
it opens, compared with &quot;integration by parts&quot;, or so I believed.&amp;nbsp; I 
found other voices sang with mine.&amp;nbsp; I was part of a choir.&amp;nbsp; I also 
joined forces with those wanting to teach &quot;how to code&quot; (computer 
program) for core credit.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fast forward and I&#39;m in Oregon, 
joining a small lobby group to say to the legislature:&amp;nbsp; &quot;You know those 
three years of math you require for a high school diploma?&amp;nbsp; We want to 
bring in discrete math topics and open up more space in STEM than just 
pre-calculus / calculus, whaddya say?&quot;&amp;nbsp; As far as I can tell, pretty 
much all the states said &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://edhesive.com/blog/2016/iowa-may-require-cs-to-graduate-by-2018&quot;&gt;OK&lt;/a&gt;&quot; in unison i.e. they had no concrete 
objections to math-credit computer science.&amp;nbsp; So ruled without objection,
 right?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When it comes to marketing the possibility in 
practice however, that&#39;s another matter and big publishing gets 
involved.&amp;nbsp; I like to float mnemonics, easy to use -- but we hope not 
misleading -- memes.&amp;nbsp; Calling the conventional pre-calc / calc track 
&quot;delta calculus&quot;, as I do above, is not how most people write.&amp;nbsp; The 
letter &quot;delta&quot;, though used in differential / integral calculus, has not
 been made to &quot;brand&quot; it in that way.&amp;nbsp; High school calculus, as 
typically taught, does not go by any Greek letter.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2014/09/lambda-versus-delta.html&quot;&gt;My innovation, then&lt;/a&gt;, was to cast &quot;delta calc&quot; versus &quot;lambda calc&quot; as two flavors of 
&quot;calc&quot; (computation), like chocolate and vanilla.&amp;nbsp; No one said a given 
student can&#39;t do &quot;swirl&quot; (both flavors mixed together).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets
 be clear:&amp;nbsp; lambda calc already exists, one might point to the Princeton
 Institute for Advanced Study, a couple generations back:&amp;nbsp; Alonso Church
 and company.&amp;nbsp; So where do we want to take it next?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets remember
 that so-called &quot;delta calculus&quot; was at one time esoteric and not 
introduced pre-college.&amp;nbsp; In formalizing the work of Newton and Leibniz, 
as filtered through generations of refinement, thank the French, we got 
it into the form of pre-college deliverables, a spiral, a ladder, 
featuring Riemann sums and Leibniz notation for derivatives, first, 
second, third and so on.&amp;nbsp; Different school systems have different 
histories.&amp;nbsp; Many narratives criss-cross (inter-weave).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In 
canning calculus (&quot;canning&quot; as in &quot;canning tuna&quot; not as in &quot;firing from a
 job&quot;) for the pre-college crowd, we sliced out most of the history.&amp;nbsp; We
 take for granted that mathematics, being a &quot;universal language&quot; is 
somehow too eternal to be subjected to a merely tempo-real -- as in 
historical -- treatment.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s considered aftermarket trade book 
reading.&amp;nbsp; Textbooks must peek at history only in sidebar, or in footnotes 
maybe.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Whatever the rationale for so sanitizing the subject, we
 neglect a most important bridge to the humanities i.e. here is where 
C.P. Snow&#39;s chasm, betwixt the humanities and sciences begins to yawn.&amp;nbsp; 
History provides at least a rope bridge across, whereas many find 
themselves trapped, on one side or the other (reading maths or reading 
history, but never the twain together thanks to illiteracy barriers).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Were
 we to restore more of the history, we would discover more of the all 
too human drama of contention.&amp;nbsp; But is debate a bad thing?&amp;nbsp; Isn&#39;t moving
 forward a matter of dialog, or &quot;dialectic&quot; as the educated say?&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mathematics
 has not evolved quietly, without argument.&amp;nbsp; Newton and Leibniz argued 
with each other (a priority dispute) while Bishop Berkeley attacked the 
whole idea of infinitesimal quantities and proofs based on them (a 
conceptual integrity dispute).&amp;nbsp; Cantor and Kronecker took different 
sides in some arguments.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s ferment, disagreement, or at least 
alternative ways to go.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But that&#39;s precisely what gets white washed in going over this material:&amp;nbsp; schools find it expedient to agree 
there&#39;s at least one subject on which everyone agrees.&amp;nbsp; Or, if they 
don&#39;t, at least none of the boiling-over arguments should touch the kids.&amp;nbsp; That math is contentious gets &quot;dirty secret&quot; or &quot;in the closet&quot; treatment.&amp;nbsp; 
But Thomas Kuhn in his talk of &quot;paradigms&quot; at least made it OK / safe to
 question the caricature of a &quot;steady advance&quot; did he not?&amp;nbsp; So why be so
 timid?&amp;nbsp; Why all the shielding?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, in rolling up &quot;lambda 
calculus&quot; into a more popular form, like was done already with the 
Newton - Leibniz stuff, I&#39;ve focused on &quot;composition of functions&quot; as 
the primitive notion, with the multiplication operator very soon 
introduced as a &quot;composer operator&quot;, so that we further develop that 
sense of polymorphism around operators, the ground of Abstract Algebra.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/11/permutations.html&quot;&gt;A permutation&lt;/a&gt;, a mapping of objects to themselves in another or same 
order, is a primitive function, a set of ordered pairs.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s 
one-to-one, bijective.&amp;nbsp; And permutations may be &quot;chained&quot; (composed).&amp;nbsp; 
As a topic, they thicken the soup of whatever computer language, giving a
 gym to work out in.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Why use the multiplication operator at 
all?&quot;&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s where the &quot;cool pool&quot; of Group Theory comes in.&amp;nbsp; This is 
material we currently try to get into around Algebra 1 and 2, just a 
little, but we&#39;re in a hurry to dive into delta calc.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We have no time 
for passing functions as arguments to other functions, as we do in 
Python and other languages (that&#39;s a good introduction to delta calc 
too, through the gate of functions with function-arguments).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But now we
 &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; have that time, because we have a fork in the road and the freedom 
to follow the lambda calc road instead, or in addition, to the delta 
calc road.&amp;nbsp; The lambda calc road is certified legal and open to traffic,
 we just need more teachers to help out as guides.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m 
under no illusions that with the snap of some fingers, even more than 
just mine, these &quot;reforms&quot; might be injected in short order.&amp;nbsp; Rather I&#39;m
 providing a road map for like-minded to reference, when explaining to 
the general public or intelligent layman what the strategy is.&amp;nbsp; &quot;All the
 computer stuff we don&#39;t currently manage to squeeze in? -- we&#39;ve got a 
way now, and I can explain it in terms of two Greek letters, lambda and 
delta&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve &quot;rehabilitated&quot; obscure disciplines before, 
too early to assess with what success.&amp;nbsp; General Systems Theory (GST) is 
all over the place (somewhat like Tensegrity), as a management 
philosophy, as a kind of ecology, who knows?&amp;nbsp; It has a high caliber 
pedigree but where does it go from here?&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I noticed how 
Economists and Economics tend to have monopoly status when it comes to 
advising the financial markets regarding guns vs. butter, and suggested 
GST muscle in under the banner that &quot;monopoly breeds inefficiency&quot; owing
 to lack of serious competition.&amp;nbsp; GST was about giving Economics a run 
for its money.&amp;nbsp; Still is.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s easy to understand, no?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Courses in 
GST could just as well provide rungs of that &quot;climbing some business 
world ladder&quot; as more science-oriented than Econ in some dimensions, 
including around issues of climate change we might hope.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Finally, another axis or spectrum I&#39;ve contemplated, as have many, is what oft 
goes by &quot;left brain&quot; versus &quot;right brain&quot; as a dichotomy.&amp;nbsp; My track 
record is riddled with slides talking about &quot;lexical versus graphical&quot; 
by which I somewhat mean the same thing as the brain hemisphere people 
do.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re talking about bridges again.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In STEM a goal is to have 
noodling-with-symbols (call it &quot;algebra&quot; or &quot;being lexical&quot;) match up 
with visualizations and other experiential presentations or summaries.&amp;nbsp; 
We want to understand what we&#39;re looking at when interpreting all that 
data.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Control panels, dashboards, instruments, sensors...&amp;nbsp; we 
have a kind of model, view, controller architecture to consider, where 
what we reason about and codify using semi-numerical algorithms is the 
model, the business logic, and what we view and measure is feedback 
regarding our direction, as a company or enterprise or whatever.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We 
hope for some kind of decision-making or steering capacity, where 
choosing a more promising direction, over a less promising one, remains a
 possibility.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re hoping to be more like pilots, not just witnesses 
to the inevitable, spectator-fatalists with no active role.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Activism&quot; 
is not a negative, but informed and effective activism is better yet.&amp;nbsp; 
&quot;Passivism&quot; is not an English word, but needs to be, as many are 
militantly passivist in their anti-activism.&amp;nbsp; I think &quot;reactionary&quot; is 
getting tired and needs a rest.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One of the best 
left-right i.e. lexical-graphical connectors I&#39;ve found is using string 
substitution in lexical computer code to build a script that, when 
rendered, provides a ray tracing and / or perhaps a 3D printable 
object.&amp;nbsp; VRML and POV-Ray scene description language were often my two 
top choices, with similar choices in Elastic Interval Geometry land (a 
branch I was following).&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The 2D fractal, the Mandelbrot Set in 
particular, coupled with some historical timeline information, is a 
perfect topic, a sweet spot.&amp;nbsp; A strong lambda calculus course could set 
its sights in that direction:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; doing the vector math lexically, with 
overloaded operators (like + and *), yet driving graphics on the 
screen.&amp;nbsp; Gerald de Jong&#39;s &quot;creatures&quot; provide a great example, of &quot;math 
puppets&quot; turning logic into animations.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Another 
approach to bridging model-lexical with viewable-graphical is to simply 
build up the skills to create a dynamic web page, where things happening
 graphically are driven by things happening lexically in the code.&amp;nbsp; In 
my Digital Mathematics outline, I cover that in &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Supermarket_Math&quot;&gt;Supermarket Math&lt;/a&gt;&quot; which
 would cover &quot;e-commerce&quot; (but regular commerce as well, as brick and 
mortar stores use SQL just as much).&amp;nbsp; Mine is but one more sandcastle on
 this pretty big beach -- just take a few ideas, flatter me by copying.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The goal is to forge these left-right connections, even as we bridge the C.P. Snow chasm by remembering to share more history.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8576720852871277213'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8576720852871277213'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/12/mathy-memes.html' title='Mathy Memes'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2630919243046318343</id><published>2015-11-28T13:41:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2015-12-15T05:29:22.734-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Athena&#39;s Sail Makers</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2B1XXV2Eoh8&quot; width=&quot;420&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A subculture that saw a lot of importance in triangles might have two well known means to multiply. Imagine saying &quot;three by two&quot; and meaning not a ninety degree rectangle with opposite edges three and two, but a sixty degree triangle with edges three and two, the third side closing off said area, of six triangular units. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Either way, with ninety or sixty degrees, we have a model. &amp;nbsp;Both operations may be quite familiar within a culture, the triangular way having more to do with textiles and sail making, or weaving covers for domes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What models of multiplication have we now? &amp;nbsp;Remember how complex numbers do it, on the Argand Plane. &amp;nbsp;Their real and imaginary parts project to XY, giving length, and these quantities multiply to give another length, and yet it&#39;s their angles (say alpha and theta) that add. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So we already have multiple models for multiplication. &amp;nbsp;Adding our sixty degree based operation just reinforces the same freedom: &amp;nbsp;to have &quot;multiplication&quot; mean various recipes. &amp;nbsp;Matrices &quot;multiply&quot;. &amp;nbsp;So do we.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I like associating the sixty degree based model with matters maritime, as sailing the high seas has always involved triangles, as well as economizing (&quot;more with less&quot;). &amp;nbsp;The maritime tradition takes off into aerospace in later decades, incorporating &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/07/apollo-chronicles.html&quot;&gt;NASA&#39;s Apollo Project&lt;/a&gt; with its mythical associations, of rationality, lucidity, intelligence and so on. &amp;nbsp;People spontaneously accept geodesic domes as normal, when NASA does them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The advantage of our triangular picture of two by three, if you don&#39;t know, is that two by three by three (nine by two) becomes an eighteen-volume tetrahedron, two thirds of the three by three by three tetrahedron of volume twenty seven, all facets equiangular. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A third number joining the multiplication takes us from surface to volume, just as in the rectilinear case, but by this route we come to a unit volume that&#39;s tetrahedral instead of a cube. &amp;nbsp;Our subculture works with that too. &amp;nbsp;They don&#39;t suffer from either / or thinking the way a dogmatist might.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Might we / they want such a unit volume tetrahedron for some reason? &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synergetics_(Fuller)&quot;&gt;In Synergetics&lt;/a&gt;, we certainly do, and that&#39;s why we boot up with a triangle in the first place: &amp;nbsp;as a first step towards a rational and/or whole number volumes &quot;concentric hierarchy&quot; of nested concentric polyhedrons. &amp;nbsp;One twenty fourth will prove another important rational number, the volume of A, B and T modules for starters.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not that in adding all these whole numbers we thereby banish incommensurability (irrationality) or the surds. &amp;nbsp;We still have convergent series and the algebra of Phi is as strong as ever. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You know the drill (maybe): the Icosahedron of edges PV (prime vector) which is two PVR (two times unit ball radius) has a volume of&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #333333; font-family: &amp;quot;georgia&amp;quot; , serif; font-size: 13px; line-height: 20.8px;&quot;&gt;5 Φ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;sup style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #333333; font-family: Georgia, serif; line-height: 20.8px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 9.20833px;&quot;&gt;2&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #333333; font-family: &amp;quot;georgia&amp;quot; , serif; font-size: 13px; line-height: 20.8px;&quot;&gt;√2.&lt;/span&gt;  The unit volume sphere still has Pi in it too (easily memorable): &amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #333333; font-family: &amp;quot;georgia&amp;quot; , serif; font-size: 13px; line-height: 20.8px;&quot;&gt;π √2.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Philosophically speaking, we may not want to suggest that &quot;nature is using Pi&quot; (to how many digits?) even if Greek letters provide a convenient notation. &amp;nbsp;Numbers are approximations of realities, not the other way around.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sails and sailing might be associated with a female goddess religion. &amp;nbsp;The conspiracy literature has already done a lot of work for us, in gathering the similarities between the Eve and Athena myths.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Athena is a goddess of war, like Mars in some ways, but preferring strategy to brute force, and wisdom to hormonal imbalance. &amp;nbsp;Her victories tend to be &quot;at sea&quot; i.e. over the horizon from visible land, meaning invisible to the landlubbers. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The ocean, these days, has become cyber-space (a space of steering, triangulation, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/12/global-data-global-matrix.html&quot;&gt;whole systems thinking&lt;/a&gt;). &amp;nbsp;We could say that Athena wins with better music, if at all possible. &amp;nbsp;She prefers to solve with psychology. &amp;nbsp;Military leaders &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2015/11/delphian-interlude.html&quot;&gt;came to Delphi&lt;/a&gt; for the advice, however enigmatic, not outward weapons.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Telling the story of this subculture, this ethnicity, should not pose too great a threat to existing STEM courses, given Anthropology is well able to merge narratives. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/02/thirsters-2015226.html&quot;&gt;Let STEM become STEAM&lt;/a&gt; for the purposes of enlivening our sense of history. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Deliberately forgetting our metaphysical heritage would be the greater danger. &amp;nbsp;We should aim to remember, and in a context that&#39;s more than a jumble of semi-meaningless and unmemorable factoids.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2630919243046318343'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2630919243046318343'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/11/athenas-sail-makers.html' title='Athena&#39;s Sail Makers'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/2B1XXV2Eoh8/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3257186547791784018</id><published>2015-11-24T23:12:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2015-11-26T21:42:49.732-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Cider House</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/23235498531/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Quadrays&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Quadrays&quot; height=&quot;359&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/650/23235498531_849e865084.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
One might logically surmise I&#39;d been here before, a new establishment just blocks from my house.&amp;nbsp; But other times I&#39;ve tried, I&#39;ve found it really crowded, as in no seating.&amp;nbsp; At least they&#39;re doing a good business.&amp;nbsp; Given my no beer diet, this was an appropriate place to meet up with Trevor.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Trevor&#39;s experience doing archive work began in earnest with his tackling the writings of one George Walford and his peers regarding their newly invented subject of Systematic Ideology.&amp;nbsp; When I first met Trevor, decades back, he was already steeped in that project.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He has continued to grow in that role, more recently sifting and compacting the Buckminster Fuller Virtual Institute collection by Joe Moore.&amp;nbsp; Next to Applewhite, Joe was one of the key archivists of Fuller-related &quot;collateral&quot; as Ed referred to such materials.&amp;nbsp; Ed had worked with Bonnie on other aspects of the same challenge.&amp;nbsp; Joe chose Trevor as an heir for his collection.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This time, when we met at &lt;i&gt;Cider House&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/arts-and-crafts.html&quot;&gt;Trevor&lt;/a&gt; had taken on at least two more projects, one for the City of Portland, involving a special collection within the library, with some very rare and great books (even an ancient stone tablet) and another involving papers donated to an academic institution by a famous columnist alum.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;d flown back east in connection with the latter project.&amp;nbsp; He loves his new Apple watch.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I kept it to one dry cider &amp;lt; 7% alcohol as my Internet radio show was soon to begin.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s not really what it is, it&#39;s a class that I&#39;m teaching by sharing audio and my screen, in real time.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Tonight we looked at Python generators, using triangular, tetrahedral and icosahedral numbers, Pascal&#39;s Triangle, then Fibonacci numbers for a lab.&amp;nbsp; The time went by quickly.&amp;nbsp; I somewhat lost track of it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One of Trevor&#39;s older websites had become so popular that it fit Google&#39;s profile of a spam site.&amp;nbsp; How could one person be that prolific?&amp;nbsp; Rather than fight the shunning that occurred, being listed as a spam site, he took that as a cue to drastically reshape the content.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s life on the Web:&amp;nbsp; rolling with the punches and morphing if need be.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I meant to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/03/field-trip-to-seattle.html&quot;&gt;work in Lucy&lt;/a&gt; today, in my talk on classes having ancestor classes.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/23267848896/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;STEM Class 2015&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;STEM Class 2015&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/582/23267848896_f22040b181.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3257186547791784018'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3257186547791784018'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/11/cider-house.html' title='Cider House'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4689842412788582651</id><published>2015-11-16T15:43:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2015-11-16T15:50:11.197-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Steve Jobs The Lost Interview (movie review)</title><content type='html'>Let me immediately disentangle this interview from the docudrama running in theaters now, which features a Steve Jobs character, interpreted by an actor. &amp;nbsp;I haven&#39;t seen that one yet, but expect to at some point.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
No, I was milling about at Quakers, chauffeuring mom (packing for Whittier), and ducked into &lt;i&gt;Movie Madness&lt;/i&gt;, per longstanding habit. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;ve been looking for &lt;i&gt;Going Clear&lt;/i&gt; by Alex Gibney, which I&#39;ll watch and review next. &amp;nbsp;Gibney has done &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt4425064/?ref_=nm_flmg_prd_7&quot;&gt;a documentary on Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;also, which I hope to see soon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Jobs is still with NeXT in this interview, having suffered the painful break with Apple. &amp;nbsp;He&#39;s anticipating Apple&#39;s demise, with the next big thing clearly not happening there. &amp;nbsp;Apple would bring him back as their chief after this interview, as interviewer Paul Sen reminds us. &amp;nbsp;The rest is history (I&#39;m writing this on a Mac Air, great machine).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Jobs is very succinct in his telling. &amp;nbsp;He fell in love with computers early, giving a story not unlike Neal Stephenson&#39;s in &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cryptonomicon.com/beginning.html&quot;&gt;In the Beginning...,&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; then talks about the Three Things they showed him during his now legendary visit to Xerox-Parc, the Seat of Genius in this story. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He only saw and understood the first of the three things, at first: &amp;nbsp;the GUI. &amp;nbsp;Anyone seeing a graphical user interface for the first time knew that would be the future. &amp;nbsp;The Terminal would become one of the windows.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The two other things they showed him, which he didn&#39;t get at first: &amp;nbsp;object oriented programming, and networking. &amp;nbsp;He would grow into those visions later. &amp;nbsp;NeXT was all about developing and extending the former. &amp;nbsp;He&#39;s quite right about what we should expect from the Web, a decade ago. &amp;nbsp;A lot of us were.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He certainly seemed to me to have his ego under control or is that calling the kettle black? &amp;nbsp;He&#39;s quite happy to stand up for high quality and does the hip-hop thing of dissing his rivals, upholding his side in a rivalrous tale. &amp;nbsp;That&#39;s par for the course and translates to athletics. &amp;nbsp;But hey, this is just the one interview -- lots of jabber about Jobs in the background in November, 2015.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Windows was maybe more plebian, but somewhat paved the way for Free and Open Source by prepping a generation to be unafraid of hardware guts in open cases. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Macs were intentionally a lot harder to break into and mess with. &amp;nbsp;The IBM side of the business, with its PC clones, did a lot to make Linux happen, and Linux is still happening. &amp;nbsp;IBM was happy to provide source code as well (the case of SCO).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I sometimes forget I&#39;m not using Linux when in my Terminal window on the Mac Air. &amp;nbsp;How did it go again? Was Darwin a port of FreeBSD? &amp;nbsp;Time to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darwin_(operating_system)&quot;&gt;check Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;I think of Windows versus POSIX as backward versus forward slash cultures (\ versus / e.g. C:\ vs. /bin). &amp;nbsp;We call that os.sep (separator) in Python and let the host operating system supply the value.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4689842412788582651'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4689842412788582651'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/11/steve-jobs-lost-interview-movie-review.html' title='Steve Jobs The Lost Interview (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7282255519624438413</id><published>2015-11-11T19:20:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2015-11-28T21:16:07.795-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2015.11.11</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I made it to Wanderers this morning. &amp;nbsp;This group has met in the Linus Pauling House for many years, settling on a Tuesday night, Wednesday morning weekly format, often just a wandering conversation, whoever&#39;s there spinning it one way or another.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I remember as a little kid looking up at &quot;grownups&quot; (much taller) and listening to them talk. &amp;nbsp;I noticed this form called &quot;conversation&quot; could twist and turn quite a bit, depending on whom were the talkers. Other times there&#39;d be &quot;an agenda&quot; and the talk might be less free form.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol took off on the bus for Pioneer Place, where Veterans for Peace were holding their annual vigil &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/11/armistice-day-2012.html&quot;&gt;for Armistice Day&lt;/a&gt;, a name that recalls the war is against outward war; we haven&#39;t given up by accepting Endless War as our &quot;evermore&quot; end fate (to quote the raven). &amp;nbsp;The goal all along has been to get beyond outward war, even if we still fight about stuff.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A few people really groove on outward war though. &amp;nbsp;The simulations have been getting better and better. &amp;nbsp;Perhaps with the next version the few holdouts will give in and go out and buy a console.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Today the conversation wandered through the geography of Oregon, where some of us (not me) were well traveled. &amp;nbsp;Yes, I&#39;ve seen the Canyonville Museum, been to Fossil, but these were once in a lifetime experiences for me, whereas for many long time Oregonians, this is all more of a familiar stomping ground. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;m lucky if I make it either to the coast or over the mountain to the high desert, like to Mount Scott in Terrabonne.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
OSCON is earlier this year. &amp;nbsp;I don&#39;t know if I&#39;ll make it to Austin, but I&#39;m checked in as a proposals reader again. &amp;nbsp;Open Source is not to be taken for granted, oxymoronic though that sounds (doesn&#39;t Open Source mean &lt;i&gt;Free&lt;/i&gt; -- so why not take it for granted?). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Free as in freedom (vs. &quot;free&quot; as in beer) requires protection, and I understand Veterans who say freedom is worth fighting to preserve, even when that means engaging in outward wars. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;m not the backseat general who sees how it all could have all worked out better with me calling all the shots. &amp;nbsp;I keep calling shots though, some of them. &amp;nbsp;I have a front row seat on some &quot;operations&quot; (doctors call them that too).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The local news tonight talked about the Blob, which may be starting to dissipate. &amp;nbsp;We haven&#39;t been hearing much about the Blob on televised media, or at least I haven&#39;t, so I&#39;m glad to see more of that information getting out, KOIN the one breaking the news. &amp;nbsp;Charlie Rose anchored the CBS News that followed. &amp;nbsp;I left the radio on downstairs, along with the space heater, for the dog, and retreated up to my direct broadcast TV. &amp;nbsp;I also pay for some of the same stations through CenturyLink.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7282255519624438413'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7282255519624438413'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/11/wanderers-20151111.html' title='Wanderers 2015.11.11'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2394012255406480581</id><published>2015-11-07T18:50:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2015-11-07T22:13:25.938-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Winning Ways</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5nwNfmkaV_I?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9QS0q3mGPGg?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2394012255406480581'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2394012255406480581'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/11/winning-ways.html' title='Winning Ways'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/5nwNfmkaV_I/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1687226682123049940</id><published>2015-11-06T22:41:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2015-11-12T08:05:32.181-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Spectre (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/22853625641/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;old_neighborhood&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;old_neighborhood&quot; height=&quot;411&quot; src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5644/22853625641_7ecb3078cc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I started watching Bond movies in middle school at the &lt;i&gt;Teatro Archimede&lt;/i&gt; (no longer in business) in a high density suburb of downtown Rome, near &lt;i&gt;Piazza Euclide&lt;/i&gt; (red balloon on image), our family apartment being near &lt;i&gt;Piazza Ungeria&lt;/i&gt;, Viale Parioli Twenty-Five (closer to right edge, across from that roof-top swimming pool).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You may imagine I was nostalgic for Rome, a great city for a car chase.&amp;nbsp; Bond stuck behind that Cinque Cento... hilarious.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I think we were all afraid the cars would blast into St. Peter&#39;s basilica itself, which would have been in poor taste most likely, and the franchise wisely steered clear, though does allude to the priesthood in passing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I remember taking my daughter to her first Bond film &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/12/action-figure.html&quot;&gt;in Santa Fe&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Dawn was on oxygen and &lt;i&gt;Apria&lt;/i&gt; helped us orchestrate some high tech logistics.&amp;nbsp; Santa Fe under snow is something else.&amp;nbsp; This new Bond guy was just getting going with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/12/casino-royale-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Casino Royale&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I had a lurking suspicion I might have missed one and I did, &lt;i&gt;Quantum of Solace&lt;/i&gt;, but this episode maintains continuity with the last, not breaking the storyline, and keeping with Daniel Craig.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A lot of the &quot;intelligence lore&quot; is converging to the same plot lines anyway:&amp;nbsp; automation is putting even these pros out of business.&amp;nbsp; They plan to phase out all the &quot;double ohs&quot; with their too human judgements.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/ATxKtQ&quot;&gt;Computers are taking over&lt;/a&gt;, along with &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/02/despicable-me-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;minions&lt;/a&gt; and drones.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets cut to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-34644273&quot;&gt;the BBC radio interview&lt;/a&gt; (replayed in the US) of two disguised-voice MI6 types, having more fun around this movie, assuring the public that the real spies of the British intelligence apparatus are quite the opposite of Bond in so many ways, but especially in brashness.&amp;nbsp; Whatever happened to self-effacing?&amp;nbsp; Bond keeps making a spectacular spectacle of himself (luckily for movie-goers).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, this &quot;we&#39;re just goody-two-shoes government servants&quot; line plays into the poking and prodding these spy thrillers get away with.&amp;nbsp; The &lt;i&gt;Marvel Comic&lt;/i&gt; style projection, with moments for uncomplicated self reflection by almost robotic characters (that&#39;s a compliment) is a good fit for the big screen and its hoodwinks and hi-jinx.&amp;nbsp; The more serious-minded derive their thrills in other ways, through &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2014/01/more-espying.html&quot;&gt;John le Carré&lt;/a&gt; (a pen name) perhaps.&amp;nbsp; Different strokes for different folks.&amp;nbsp; Some read Tom Clancy (not me).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The suggestion that all this trashing of real estate and pouring through expensive merchandise, in addition to loss of life, has to do with sibling rivalry, family feuding, is a great statement on history.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m reminded of another spy novel of sorts, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.yahoo.com/neo/groups/Wittrs/conversations/topics/7089&quot;&gt;The Jew of Linz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, which makes all of WWII a closet brawl between two school boys (young Adolf and Ludwig, Hitler vs. Wittgenstein) who presumably couldn&#39;t stand each other (the record is open to interpretation) -- and the rest is history as they say.&amp;nbsp; Makes a good story, as many spy stories do.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our Portland audience at &lt;i&gt;Cine Magic Theater&lt;/i&gt; was entertained, with a burst of laughter when the violence turns to sex per an abrupt and well worn formula.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s the Bond brand, meant as light fare with some gorgeous photography and lots of beautiful people.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Back to movie magic, the seemingly seamless blending of reality and imagination is pushed to the state of the art in Bond films.&amp;nbsp; The London landscape is as plastic as Narnia&#39;s, it sometimes seems.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/22424349617/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Viale Parioli, 25&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Viale Parioli, 25&quot; height=&quot;411&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/754/22424349617_7e8f40ab2e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: former family digs, top floor right, with terraces ::
&lt;/i&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1687226682123049940'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1687226682123049940'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/11/spectre-movie-review.html' title='Spectre (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7276937397573087137</id><published>2015-10-28T16:46:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-11-07T09:23:30.725-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Martian Math Storyboards</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/22374736740/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Going viral...&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Going viral...&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5816/22374736740_a675428754.jpg&quot; width=&quot;476&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/21933099824/in/album-72157624750749042/&quot; title=&quot;Masthead&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Masthead&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5650/21933099824_1038037149.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/22567056371/in/album-72157624750749042/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF1690&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF1690&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/668/22567056371_1ba175852b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1n9MFI-Xy34?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;For Further Reading&lt;/i&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/10/so-you-wanna-be-martian-math-teacher.html&quot;&gt;Orientation Video&lt;/a&gt; (Youtube)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/d/msg/mathfuture/VvkHG3-RtVM/WLx79AsYAQAJ&quot;&gt;Thread on MathFuture&lt;/a&gt; (Google Group)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/aOajXg2_x_c&quot;&gt;Introduction to Quadrays&lt;/a&gt; (Youtube) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157624750749042&quot;&gt;Storyboards Album&lt;/a&gt; (Flickr)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157622961425831&quot;&gt;More Stills&lt;/a&gt; (Flickr)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Digital_Math&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Digital Mathematics:&amp;nbsp; Heuristics for Teachers&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (WikiEducator)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7276937397573087137'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7276937397573087137'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/martian-math-storyboards.html' title='Martian Math Storyboards'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/1n9MFI-Xy34/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-568326292604707841</id><published>2015-10-25T06:45:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-25T08:56:51.110-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Computer Lore</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-rPPqm44xLs?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Wi326Leuemg?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/568326292604707841'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/568326292604707841'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/computer-lore.html' title='Computer Lore'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/-rPPqm44xLs/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1693350388857140482</id><published>2015-10-22T00:17:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-25T20:01:41.569-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Black Panthers: Vanguard... (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I finally got to this, having naively shown up on opening night thinking I could just waltz in and buy a ticket.&amp;nbsp; That was a gala event, for which I had not planned in advance.&amp;nbsp; No matter, &lt;i&gt;Hollywood Theater&lt;/i&gt;, a nonprofit with members, let this important new documentary run for quite a few days.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I found it helpful to tightly focus on the Panthers through this period, but was always aware, since I was alive through some of this, of how much else was going on in parallel.&amp;nbsp; How Black Panthers related to Black Muslims and Malcolm X is discussed even less than their relationship with Black Christians and Martin Luther King.&amp;nbsp; The Panthers were more secular, less likely to invoke God in their speeches.&amp;nbsp; They simply wanted higher living standards and freedom from oppression.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
With mass movements like this, mob psychologies, the so-called leaders act as tone and trend setters, but then the real inertia comes from the rank and file, people looking to be a part of something bigger than themselves. Not much vetting goes on sometimes as players are thrown together by circumstance.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This out-of-control snowballing effect was evident in the case of the Panthers but also in the case of law enforcement.&amp;nbsp; J. Edgar Hoover helped set the tone with Cointelpro, but it was up to individual police departments to &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/11/murder-of-fred-hampton-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;get creative&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.&amp;nbsp; Effectively micromanaging from the top, with this much going on concurrently, is somewhat impossible.&amp;nbsp; Would be public figures ride the wave, and use the media to help them do so, as another category of celebrity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The former Panthers, police, journalists and historians, interviewed for this film have the benefit of a lot of hindsight.&amp;nbsp; If people had only had the luxury of being this reflective at the time... if only. Quakers intersperse a lot of silence for a purpose.&amp;nbsp; People need that time to reflect and to hear one another&#39;s voices in a safe environment.&amp;nbsp; They also need ways to debate and challenge one another without resorting to physical violence.&amp;nbsp; William F. Buckley, to his credit, worked at providing such a forum, an &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/02/avp-again.html&quot;&gt;alternative to violence&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of Buckley, the segment on the park in Chicago segues smoothly to the famous &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/09/best-of-enemies-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Buckley-Vidal altercation&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Eldridge Cleaver delivered the speech in that park, and had left the scene before violence erupted, however he was charged with inciting said violence.&amp;nbsp; He decided he&#39;d be better off in Algeria, where he started an international chapter of the Black Panther movement.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The commitment to Free Huey (Newton) from prison was a big part of Panther psychology and when he was finally let free, he was an icon.&amp;nbsp; However all that prison time had shaped him in ways that distanced him from his fans.&amp;nbsp; The party tried to consolidate &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bobbyseale.com/&quot;&gt;around Bobby Seale&lt;/a&gt;, who ran for mayor of Oakland, and when that didn&#39;t work, things fell apart.&amp;nbsp; Huey had become abusive and tyrannical.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One could say the Panthers lost in their bid for a revolution, however big wheels turn slowly.&amp;nbsp; Nixon, the law and order president, turned out to be a crook (in addition to the usual war criminal, what most warlords are) and to this day the right to openly carry guns on public property (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/10/more-on-gun-control.html&quot;&gt;not private necessarily&lt;/a&gt;) owes a lot to the Black Panthers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Their work in Chicago to build bridges with poor whites, so-called hillbillies from Appalachia, has paid off in some dimensions.&amp;nbsp; And backwater Oregon, where being black is &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/03/arresting-violence-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;no longer illegal&lt;/a&gt;, now has &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/OregonGovBrown/status/656402607708090369/photo/1&quot;&gt;peaceful ties with Hanoi&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Today we have the Internet, and infiltration was always a two way street.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Watching this documentary in tandem with a few others, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/02/neverland-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;such as &lt;i&gt;Neverland&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the one about Patty Hearst and the Symbionese Liberation Army, would help open more windows on a complex timeline.&amp;nbsp; Historians are still putting together these vistas.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/10/us-versus-john-lennon-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The US Versus John Lennon&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; would be another good one to watch in close proximity.&amp;nbsp; No one documentary gets the whole picture of course.&amp;nbsp; History is non-simultaneously conceptual, meaning there&#39;s no single snapshot synopsis (obviously).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Today was much higher in pain and stress than anyone had planned, mostly for Carol, my mom (age 86).&amp;nbsp; She managed to gouge her leg quite deeply getting out of the car, fortunately at a hospital.&amp;nbsp; What was supposed to be a routine thirty minute checkup turned into a visit to the ER for sutures and a tetanus shot (as well as for the blood test she&#39;d originally come in for).&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m required to report this event to my car insurance company or risk Medicare not covering any of the costs, according to the hospital.&amp;nbsp; Mom is OK.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re still planning that trip to Corvallis tomorrow.&amp;nbsp; Followup from Corvallis:&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Farmers&lt;/i&gt; says they&#39;ll cover it. &lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1693350388857140482'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1693350388857140482'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/black-panthers-vanguard-movie-review.html' title='Black Panthers: Vanguard... (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2763668311279583335</id><published>2015-10-19T23:19:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-20T17:13:36.885-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Religious Teachings</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dXGGOz_DkGg?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;420&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
The talking animals in this namespace (&quot;Noah&#39;s Park&quot;) seem remarkably incurious as to the origin of a buried treasure that comes to light.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The hypothesis it was placed there deliberately to inspire future experiments is one definitely worth exploring, but what else might it mean?&amp;nbsp; Is it a relic of a past civilization?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That the wings could have metaphorical significance is not proposed, nor does anyone care to speculate as to how this statue actually did come to be in the pond.&amp;nbsp; Is it some kind of trick, like a faux fossil in the mud?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Clearly none of the animals present have the skills to manufacture such trophies.&amp;nbsp; If this really is the complete namespace, then divine origins are as good an explanation as any.&amp;nbsp; We may accept &quot;God-given&quot; as axiomatic. Honk is right to seek its meaning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At least the mysophobic camel takes this sign from God seriously, as some form of communication, and attempts to do God&#39;s will, by trial and error.&amp;nbsp; As the dutiful empiricist, seeking his true niche (a cleaner place) he does his homework, practices science.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, Honk the camel is the most faithful, the most loyal to God in the face of skeptics who have never felt the tug of the divine.&amp;nbsp; Honk is perhaps the Moor, the Arab alchemist, the Kabbalah scholar who seeks to know God&#39;s secrets first hand.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The authority figure or imam, a frog-faced individual named Ponder, does not dispute the sign&#39;s divine origin, nor really offer much of an alternative interpretation.&amp;nbsp; Yet he tut tuts the camel&#39;s empiricism, smug in his all-knowing attitude.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The frog recommends the camel keep the statue once the wings have symbolically broken off (a reminder of the dead-end nature of ego pride), but then seems uncertain as to whether he, a mere frog, has comprehended God&#39;s will himself.&amp;nbsp; Any show of humility is more than welcome at this point.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Children exposed to this material will have an easier time ignoring loose ends, such as &quot;what did the sign from God really signify?&quot;&amp;nbsp; Did it foretell that birds, another species, would one day collaborate to form an airline, creating friendly skies for this camel?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This would seem far fetched but in retrospect apparently it did.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A hidden teaching was in due course revealed:&amp;nbsp; go ahead and give up on dreams of greater powers obtained through your own efforts and loyalty to God, and instead let your friends help you compensate for your obvious weaknesses.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Your approach to God will be indirect, mediated by others (the birds) whom God made to ply the sky.&amp;nbsp; Be satisfied with your base nature (as a camel).&amp;nbsp; Don&#39;t aspire to be in some way above your station or &quot;beyond your light&quot; (as Quakers might put it).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Depend on your community to prop you up, in exchange for learning your lesson and in future adopting their same incurious / unquestioning attitude, and lack of aspiration.&amp;nbsp; Learn to restate the obvious (&quot;camels don&#39;t fly&quot;) over and over, as a kind of mantra, while avoiding all manner of speculative experimentation as empty vanity.&amp;nbsp; Be a dolt.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2763668311279583335'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2763668311279583335'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/religious-teachings.html' title='Religious Teachings'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/dXGGOz_DkGg/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1014945094853569641</id><published>2015-10-17T17:57:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-25T20:24:08.895-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Diplomatic Gaffs</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
There&#39;s some loudmouth general on the Official Washington press release circuit who is probably making life harder for diplomats, in saying he expects to have permanent bases in Afghanistan, just like in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.g2mil.com/okinawa-solution.htm&quot;&gt;Okinawa&lt;/a&gt;, Korea and Germany.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Generals may be too busy administering &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/drone-papers&quot;&gt;bureaucratically intensive&lt;/a&gt; Iron Mountain activities to bone up on recent history.&amp;nbsp; The granting of bases to the US was always with a veneer of sovereignty to paper over any sense of perpetual empire and hegemony as officially the New World Order (as purveyed by one District of Columbia).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That face-saving rhetoric was thin, as in hollow, but now that it&#39;s nakedly controverted, there&#39;s no way to restore the mask.&amp;nbsp; The sugar coating has now dissolved away, leaving only the bitterness of strong medicine -- or was it really a toxic poison?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The nightmare has by now become official policy.&amp;nbsp; &quot;We&#39;re not trying to solve these problems, we&#39;re making them pillars of our institutions, our way of life&quot; is the new line.&amp;nbsp; The War on Terror, as many predicted, is to be hard-coded, with AQ, IS and the Taliban the now eternal justification for ongoing combat (with a fallback to China and North Korea).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The US military is now frankly admitting it has no plans to scale back, meaning what were once called &quot;zones of insecurity&quot; are actually its source of security, with many &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/06/25/us-afghanistan-nato-idUSKBN0P52I820150625&quot;&gt;fighting seasons&lt;/a&gt;&quot; ahead (just like &quot;football season&quot;!).&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s a meal ticket right there.&amp;nbsp; War is indeed a racket, feeding on deliberately induced fears, inflamed to hatred by war-monger PR.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Keeping Okinawa a theme park and playground for US forces is tantamount to job security complete with R&amp;amp;R and that&#39;s what &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/12/iron-mountain-revisted.html&quot;&gt;Iron Mountain&lt;/a&gt; is all about (i.e. military socialism).&amp;nbsp; The military is the US jobs corps, with the least bang for the buck (in terms of dollars per livable lifestyle -- especially when lives lost or taken is factored in).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We have an Islamic bank in Whittier, part of Greater LA.&amp;nbsp; If some people want a Sharia Court satellite channel where they voluntarily put their cases and relationships under the care of Judge Imam and his code, so what?&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not like there&#39;s a shortage of bandwidth.&amp;nbsp; We have orthodox everything in New York City already.&amp;nbsp; Lawyers are trained to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/08/liberal-islam.html&quot;&gt;merge management systems&lt;/a&gt;, like what &lt;i&gt;US Airways&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;American&lt;/i&gt; are doing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some women really would prefer &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; to go to school, given learning from home is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/a-breakdown-in-self-discipline.html&quot;&gt;viable option&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; More of the men might want to stay home as well.&amp;nbsp; Lifestyles abound and the freedom to choose one is the freedom to practice and believe.&amp;nbsp; Weren&#39;t those the rights the US military was pledged to protect in the first place?&amp;nbsp; How was denying Taliban their religious freedom in any way a Constitutional value?&amp;nbsp; What is the end goal with respect to that orthodoxy?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Culture wars should be fought (&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/MTohDQl1kJY&quot;&gt;debated&lt;/a&gt;) through one&#39;s culture, whereas wanton dismemberment and execution ala Vietnam is the antithesis of really having one.&amp;nbsp; Arguments around the dinner table are what&#39;s civilized (&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/fcFbVAKX0LY&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;All in the Family&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), and tensions between generations over how best to adapt.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/03/wanderers-2015310.html&quot;&gt;Civilian life&lt;/a&gt; is hard work and trying to find short cuts through violence only postpones that work getting done.&amp;nbsp; We end up back where we started, just with more haunting memories and yet deeper regrets.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Official Washington cannot be trusted to not say stupid things, is the (new?) global perception, heightened by the risks taken by political campaigners, on the Republican ticket especially.&amp;nbsp; The Russians, in contrast, have their new network of intelligence centers, one in &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/serving-from-algebra-city.html&quot;&gt;Algebra City&lt;/a&gt;, where supposedly they&#39;re sharing IT skills with their new-found friends.&amp;nbsp; Iraqis have found a new way to fight back maybe? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Once the superpower mentality was allowed to reveal its &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/02/philosophy-101.html&quot;&gt;innate slowness and complacency&lt;/a&gt; so directly, it became a farcical embarrassment.&amp;nbsp; Public opinion has intuitively recoiled, at least in some hard currency markets.&amp;nbsp; Is it good PR to fund scary clowns?&amp;nbsp; Matters of taste are at stake as always, but then having standards for quality was never trivial.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In stating the Pentagon position is so weak in Afghanistan that it must be extended indefinitely, like in Korea, like in Germany, the general is projecting &lt;a href=&quot;http://fpif.org/americas-global-military-bases-actually-undermine-national-security-heres-how/&quot;&gt;weakness on a global scale&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The US clings to its supremacy more out of self-deception than reality.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s why it&#39;s called a complex.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s why the air is leaving the balloon.&amp;nbsp; The executive branch especially, is way over-extended.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The US is less truly capitalist than a mixture of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/05/cowardly-capitalism.html&quot;&gt;cowardly capitalist&lt;/a&gt; and military socialist.&amp;nbsp; The military provides the &quot;safety net&quot; (full of holes) and a measure of social mobility, while the cowardly capitalist fears any government competition in the civilian sector (NGOs especially, but really anything well-managed and more multi-dimensional in its wealth-creating than &quot;money driven&quot; is perceived as a potential threat, Open Source included).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Bernie Sanders could probably create more space for his brand of &quot;socialism&quot; were his public attuned to the fact that they &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/10/advice-to-sanders-campaign.html&quot;&gt;already live&lt;/a&gt; in the midst of a socialized wealth distribution system, called the US military.&amp;nbsp; As long as one signs up to fight for cowardly capitalists, one has one&#39;s meal ticket punched indefinitely.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/19812362065/in/album-72157655634700169/&quot; title=&quot;More Summer Reading&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;More Summer Reading&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3702/19812362065_e23219dd77.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1014945094853569641'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1014945094853569641'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/diplomatic-gaffs.html' title='Diplomatic Gaffs'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6494362467751351053</id><published>2015-10-14T19:16:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-14T22:04:06.702-07:00</updated><title type='text'>A STEM Exercise</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ufK2XRGUjuc?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Use biological organic chemistry language to translate the language of some ET asked to report on the chemical structure and function of:&amp;nbsp; a traffic intersection in a human city.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&quot;The sapien exoskeleton conveyances alternate arterial traction (rubber-street friction) in response to controlling red and green frequencies emitted from the electro-signaling neurons.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
In other words:&amp;nbsp; &quot;Cars stop and go in response to traffic signals&quot; (or &quot;to robots&quot; as we say in South Africa, where traffic lights are robots).&amp;nbsp; I may presume the ETs understand the sapiens have a molecular-mechanical interface (&quot;steering wheel, gas pedal...&quot;) whereby said signalling gets implemented by motor action.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They&#39;d have to catch examples, if only on slides, of &quot;car crashes&quot; resulting from some disconnect twixt the &quot;red light&quot; and the &quot;brake&quot; (an enzyme, embedded in the membrane twixt &quot;passenger compartment&quot; and &quot;engine compartment&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Clearly quantum mechanical randomness was at work.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[ They (the ETs) would probably not have the science to figure out that the sapien going &quot;against traffic&quot; was talking on its &quot;cell phone&quot; (yet another neuronal network for meme delivery). ]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Now draw the diagram, then do the animation.&amp;nbsp; Of course the human translators are highly intuitive and their interpretations, though often quite similar, will have unique elements.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our capacity to communicate with these ETs continues to improve.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XQfLgA6TyUk?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;420&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6494362467751351053'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6494362467751351053'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/a-stem-exercise.html' title='A STEM Exercise'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/ufK2XRGUjuc/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1411059988528272019</id><published>2015-10-12T12:28:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-16T00:32:27.034-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Synergetic Shoptalk</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Synergetics sometimes takes flak for Fuller&#39;s including a model of DNA as &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/05/brilliant-blunders.html&quot;&gt;a triple helix&lt;/a&gt;, whereas of course it&#39;s only a double helix.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The triple helix does occur in nature, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=collagen+VII+triple+helix&amp;amp;safe=off&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;tbo=u&amp;amp;source=univ&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0CDAQsARqFQoTCKb1o_3PvcgCFU76YwodroEJvA&amp;amp;biw=1157&amp;amp;bih=795#safe=off&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;q=collagen+triple+helix&quot;&gt;in collagen&lt;/a&gt; for example, used to weave fabric in the skin for example.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These are not replicatory fibers, lets be clear i.e. not every helical structure implies direct involvement &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/10/more-tales-of-cell.html&quot;&gt;in mitosis&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Collagens get manufactured within cells.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Given the importance of &quot;colloids&quot; in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/10/substance-control.html&quot;&gt;Korzybski&#39;s &lt;i&gt;General Sementics&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I think we could use the &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; triple helix as a bridge to / from that title / namespace.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fuller&#39;s uses &quot;tactile&quot; in the sense of &quot;feel&quot; i.e. visceral &quot;gut level&quot; intuitions versus having &quot;visions&quot; or &quot;seeing&quot; a truth.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Seeing&quot; versus &quot;Feeling&quot; is contrasted within &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; shoptalk as Eulerian (topological) versus Gibbsian (tactile).&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; remains psychological in its meanings, which is why it continued to hold Applewhite&#39;s interest.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Explorations in the geometry &lt;i&gt;of thinking&lt;/i&gt;&quot; was the subtitle (emphasis added).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We both feel and see our networks (texts, tissues) and sense their level of &quot;bondedness&quot; as liquid, solid, gas -- with fluid the home base / happy medium for life.&amp;nbsp; One of the Synergetics animations symbolizes gas, fluid, solid using vertex, hinge and face bondings of the tetrahedron respectively.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&lt;b&gt;1054.50&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp; Polyhedral Bonding: Willard Gibbs&#39; phase rule treats with the states of the environment you can sense with your eyes closed: crystallines, liquids, gases, and vapors. Euler&#39;s points, lines, and areas are visually described, but they too could be tactilely detected (with or without fingers). &amp;nbsp;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&lt;b&gt;1054.51&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp; The mathematicians get along synergetically using Euler&#39;s topology alone. It is the chemists and physicists who cannot predict synergetically without using Gibbs&#39; phase rule. &lt;/blockquote&gt;
Is this meaning merely mnemonic?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In a tactile sense, these different bonding modes emulate (simulate) the degrees of freedom characteristic of these three phases of matter, and even of thought.&amp;nbsp; We speak of logical foundations under-girding more fluid prose, which supports yet more gaseous / cloudy styles of thinking, more uninhibited and speed-of-light.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But then logic may be too brittle, as in less flexible, so &quot;foundations&quot; may not be quite the right metaphor when dealing with crystal cores.&amp;nbsp; Fuller was not a fundamentalist.&amp;nbsp; The fluid phase was the least eccentric in his book, the zero, with solid and gas a -1 and +1 degree of freedom respectively.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
An Eulerian (topological) cartoon is applied to a Gibbsian (tactile) intuition, by Bucky.&amp;nbsp; I think he&#39;d say the move is synergetic (yielding of new insights), and not just mnemonic (aiding memory).&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1411059988528272019'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1411059988528272019'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/synergetic-shoptalk.html' title='Synergetic Shoptalk'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7755560200476607572</id><published>2015-10-11T09:49:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-11T09:50:08.276-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Python&#39;s __ribs__ (Special Names)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lwDfvdUxuQc?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;420&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nOzMG-cPWnc?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;420&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9pxshtSJI8E?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;420&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7755560200476607572'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7755560200476607572'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/pythons-ribs-special-names.html' title='Python&#39;s __ribs__ (Special Names)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/lwDfvdUxuQc/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7557354211078146355</id><published>2015-10-10T08:12:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-10T10:50:26.105-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Integrated Learning</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/21885178318/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Fluent Python&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fluent Python&quot; height=&quot;442&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/745/21885178318_55bbb7ba2e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve got my nose back in Luciano Ramalho&#39;s &lt;i&gt;Fluent Python&lt;/i&gt; this morning, in &lt;i&gt;Safari On-line&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; I caught two of Luciano&#39;s talks at OSCON this year, and have downloaded their recorded versions.&amp;nbsp; The book itself has been a bestseller in its category on Amazon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve always want to see a concise Pythonic narrative that ties back to underlying C code and &lt;a href=&quot;https://hg.python.org/cpython/file/tip/Objects/dictobject.c&quot;&gt;here I&#39;m finding that&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; For example Luciano does a great job describing the hash table algorithm behind dicts and sets, and then links directly to source code, where we find these comments:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;sourcelines stripes4 wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;l418&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cm&quot;&gt;The basic lookup function used by all operations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;l419&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cm&quot;&gt;This is based on Algorithm D from Knuth Vol. 3, Sec. 6.4.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;l420&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cm&quot;&gt;Open addressing is preferred over chaining since the link overhead for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;l421&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cm&quot;&gt;chaining would be substantial (100% with typical malloc overhead).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span id=&quot;l423&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cm&quot;&gt;The initial probe index is computed as hash mod the table size. Subsequent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;l424&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cm&quot;&gt;probe indices are computed as explained earlier.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span id=&quot;l426&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cm&quot;&gt;All arithmetic on hash should ignore overflow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span id=&quot;l428&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cm&quot;&gt;The details in this version are due to Tim Peters, building on many past&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;l429&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cm&quot;&gt;contributions by Reimer Behrends, Jyrki Alakuijala, Vladimir Marangozov and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;l430&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cm&quot;&gt;Christian Tismer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;l430&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cm&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Having a link directly to Knuth&#39;s &lt;i&gt;The Art of Computer Programming&lt;/i&gt; in the comments for the Python dict object grounds a specific source code implementation in the computer science behind it.&amp;nbsp; Great for digital mathematics teachers in need of heuristics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I have that Knuth volume upstairs.  What a great way to learn.  Plus I have the Python REPL (pronounced &quot;reh-pull&quot;) open in another window.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In going over the set data structure and its operations, I was thinking back to New Math and elementary school, when set notation was making its early entry into kid consciousness.&amp;nbsp; This was unfamiliar material to most teachers and much of it was junked in the ensuing backlash.&amp;nbsp; But we had no REPL back then (a few lucky college kids &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SETL&quot;&gt;had ISETL&lt;/a&gt; maybe?), what if we&#39;d had one?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/22085060961/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;set_ops&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;set_ops&quot; height=&quot;206&quot; src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5657/22085060961_28e1919c4b_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: a duck is not a mammal! ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But in 2015, why not boot a Python interpreter at some point when typing has been mastered?&amp;nbsp; Learn about union, complement, difference, intersection all over again.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s just like New Math, but with more machinery to back it up.&amp;nbsp; I call it &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/search?q=gnu+math&quot;&gt;Gnu Math&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of typing, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/about-factory.html&quot;&gt;my friend Glenn&lt;/a&gt; reminded me why he can&#39;t type effectively, even after a lifetime as a typist:&amp;nbsp; most keyboards don&#39;t allow resting fingers on keys whereas in his time with NSA he had to pound through ten-ply fan-fold.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; When he tries to type on a keyboard, he floods his own text with errors.&amp;nbsp; So frustrating!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Maybe there&#39;s some steampunk solution where an old mechanical Royal typewrite type keyboard is wired up as a USB peripheral?&amp;nbsp; My retired college &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/09/some-family-history.html&quot;&gt;professor friend Chuck Bolton&lt;/a&gt; never seemed to master the new keyboard either.&amp;nbsp; The Royal sits proudly in the living room.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In sharing Python with art history students or journalists, what&#39;s more important than exhaustive practice or keyboarding is an appreciation for the layers of culture, the ecosystem.&amp;nbsp; How does C source code relate to Python and what&#39;s a hash table?&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s enough of a story for one article.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Why I&#39;m addressing art historians these days has to do with the &#39;4D meme&#39; in the art world since the late 1800s, the core topic of another book I sometimes &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/art-history.html&quot;&gt;reread and review&lt;/a&gt;:&amp;nbsp; Linda Dalrymple Henderson&#39;s &lt;i&gt;The Fourth Dimension and Non-Euclidean Geometry in Modern Art&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Through Python, I introduce art history students to the topic of Quadrays or Q-rays, needing no more than some high school XYZ mathematics, thereby helping to anchor the &#39;4D&#39; meme as Fuller used it. I also introduce &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/satacad/martianmath/mm17.html&quot;&gt;Q-rays&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/10/so-you-wanna-be-martian-math-teacher.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Martian Math&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a curriculum field tested with high and middle school students at the Reed College and &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/08/adventures-in-teaching-and-driving.html&quot;&gt;Portland University&lt;/a&gt; campuses.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/21738915279/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF0953&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF0953&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/635/21738915279_44d3ca8256.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7557354211078146355'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7557354211078146355'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/integrated-learning.html' title='Integrated Learning'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3491747844430971920</id><published>2015-10-07T16:27:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-16T00:51:05.234-07:00</updated><title type='text'>A Breakdown in Self Discipline</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/22027468855/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF1054&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF1054&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/694/22027468855_ddfd4ba4f9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Carol and I drove to &lt;i&gt;Tom&#39;s&lt;/i&gt; this morning, which isn&#39;t far.&amp;nbsp; Walking is good for her, but today it was raining and this time three years ago she came down with pneumonia, after insisting on giving a speech on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/10/mixing-it-up.html&quot;&gt;bright October 2012 day&lt;/a&gt; in the park.&amp;nbsp; She had to be hospitalized and was on oxygen for months after that.&amp;nbsp; So we take care and not push it.&amp;nbsp; This year she went to Des Moines.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, at &lt;i&gt;Tom&#39;s&lt;/i&gt;, an eatery, we had our breakfasts.&amp;nbsp; Per usual, I wolfed mine, being part wolf, at least in spirit (but also in eating behavior), so had time to spare.&amp;nbsp; Rather thank yak away, letting hers get cold, I went out for a &lt;i&gt;Willamette Week&lt;/i&gt;, new on Wednesdays.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The cover article was really interesting.&amp;nbsp; Portland knows it&#39;s &quot;too white&quot; in some dimensions but is still trying to figure out in what way.&amp;nbsp; Lots of feedback circuits have been set up, and I think it&#39;s sinking in day by day, but to accelerate the process, PPS (&lt;a href=&quot;https://mail.python.org/pipermail/portland/2015-October/001728.html&quot;&gt;Portland Public Schools&lt;/a&gt;) has put its shoulder to the wheel and tried to get some real Diversity going.&amp;nbsp; Some active recruiting has occurred.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The article is a first person account by one of the main guinea pigs in this experiment, Erica Jones, from Georgia.&amp;nbsp; Although the experiment may sound like a failure the way she tells it, I think it tells of a talented and brave person making a difference and filing her report.&amp;nbsp; Mission accomplished.&amp;nbsp; PPS and &lt;i&gt;WW&lt;/i&gt; readers learn a lot, the whole point from the start (to learn).&amp;nbsp; The protagonist gets to retire to an easier lifestyle free from PPS pathologies (they&#39;d made her sick), so a happy ending.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I recall on a jumbo jet, international in flavor, wherein we were all taking our seats, preparing for take-off.&amp;nbsp; Then some loud-mouth all-American white kid came on board, running his mouth incessantly in some fantasy world about terrorists and bombs, complete with sound effects -- unpleasant chatter to say the least.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What was most amazing though, was his parents seemed to see no reason to have erased this behavior before bringing him on an international flight, subjecting fellow travelers to nerve-grating spew.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not like this was an infant.&amp;nbsp; And that in a nutshell is what astounded this teacher:&amp;nbsp; the schools had no effective means of working with a lack of discipline and disrespect (there&#39;s a difference between &quot;respect&quot; and &quot;obsequious&quot; which any English teacher might go into).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But then to speak up on behalf of the kids, I&#39;d say the school they&#39;re placed in really is more like a penitentiary in that the brainwashing forced through those text books is really quite obsolete and not matched to the needs of current generations.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The curriculum is way behind and kids have that intuitive resentment that stems from feeling warehoused, like refugees anxious to get somewhere better, to some Promised Land, and feeling delayed by fences and border guards.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The teachers take on the sheen of prison guards.&amp;nbsp; But that&#39;s hard to articulate when you&#39;re a kid and when kids before you all went to school and a lot of &#39;em thought the same thing.&amp;nbsp; Only &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/05/cry-baby-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;juvenile delinquents&lt;/a&gt; hate school right?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, we can give objective shape to their deprivation.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Do they teach you to cook (yes in some cases)?&amp;nbsp; Including for big numbers?&amp;nbsp; What history do you get and what civics?&amp;nbsp; How many voting machines does your school have and how often do they get used?&amp;nbsp; Do you ever get away &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/08/escaping-light-pollution.html&quot;&gt;from light pollution&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m not saying I know the outcome in all cases.&amp;nbsp; How about tetra-volumes, do your math books cover that?&amp;nbsp; They do?&amp;nbsp; Excellent.&amp;nbsp; I bet in some private Quaker schools they&#39;re already introducing at least a sidebar &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/09/compare-and-contrast.html&quot;&gt;on Quadray Coordinates&lt;/a&gt;, designed to keep those philosophical debates alive (to be revisited in later years). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve recently connected with another &quot;hacktavist&quot; youth group willing to take on more parallel / alternative schooling.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s not a new pattern I realize.&amp;nbsp; Black Panthers did the same.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When some mainstream system or curriculum breaks down, others grow up around it, sometimes to become mainstream themselves.&amp;nbsp; This has happened often in history.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not necessarily a crisis, or calamity, not an apocalypse (except maybe in some technical religious sense with positive connotations -- check with your local religious authorities).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When change needs to happen, it tends to happen in some way, even if not the ways planned, and change often needs to happen.&amp;nbsp; Rule of thumb:&amp;nbsp; improving one&#39;s powers of anticipation and responsiveness is usually a likely possibility compared to the relative likelihood of stopping change cold in its tracks.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
With all our new abilities &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/09/flipped-classroom.html&quot;&gt;to flip classrooms&lt;/a&gt; and provide professional development, more teachers could be like me, not responsible for a student&#39;s everyday behavior, which I don&#39;t monitor.&amp;nbsp; The teachers and students are not in the same room.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Studying for real also means time alone, as in a study carrel, not just in collaboration.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s what you learn in college if not before.&amp;nbsp; Packed into rows and columns, in a classroom, with all present supposed to be connecting the same dots at the same time... why force that?&amp;nbsp; Why is such enforced regimentation even a selling point?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Having &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/07/pws-personal-workspace.html&quot;&gt;a safe personal workspace&lt;/a&gt; is what&#39;s paramount, if learning is really the priority.&amp;nbsp; If warehousing is the priority, why not just say so and drop the pretense?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Just having a locker is not sufficient.&amp;nbsp; When does this student just get to sit and read, undisturbed, or just meditate, free of distraction?&amp;nbsp; Do motion studies &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/05/elephant-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;like in &lt;i&gt;Elephant&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (cameras follow each student).&amp;nbsp; Develop stats.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Homework is great in theory, if you really have a home that fosters study.&amp;nbsp; Many homes do not.&amp;nbsp; Losing all interest in reading is a sign of serious brain rot.&amp;nbsp; Measure &quot;time reading&quot; as seriously as you measure &quot;calories eaten&quot; at least (over eating is more of a real danger, though over reading at the cost of degrading physical health is also a real condition).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The word &quot;gymnasium&quot; is right:&amp;nbsp; reading and reflecting are a form of working out.&amp;nbsp; Keeping fit is not just about swimming laps.&amp;nbsp; Watching TV is informative.&amp;nbsp; This is not an anti-TV rant.&amp;nbsp; However &lt;i&gt;making&lt;/i&gt; TV (video / audio) is even more informative.&amp;nbsp; Does your school help you learn to do that?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As when writing or jamming, you may be lifting from other sources, making links.&amp;nbsp; Sharing camera shots, including segments, is not a crime when the licensing is deliberately liberal.&amp;nbsp; Citing sources is much appreciated and lends credibility but in some forms of journalism, sources get concealed, for their protection.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Does your school cover these basics then?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3491747844430971920'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3491747844430971920'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/a-breakdown-in-self-discipline.html' title='A Breakdown in Self Discipline'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7761419861277979543</id><published>2015-10-06T01:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-19T14:29:53.894-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Men Without Honor</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Official Washington got disgraced by its military again today, a bunch of unprofessional uber-cowards.&amp;nbsp; No one in the Pentagon resigned.&amp;nbsp; The Secretary of Defense still gets a paycheck.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/afghan-official-hospital-in-airstrike-was-a-taliban-base/2015/10/04/8638af58-6a47-11e5-bdb6-6861f4521205_story.html&quot;&gt;Disgusting&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
An inveterate glutton for war toys, way beyond reason, and with zero self control, Washington has made the mass killing of civilians a somewhat routine event.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This most recent massacre was much worse &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/10/more-on-gun-control.html&quot;&gt;than in Roseburg&lt;/a&gt; obviously (do the numbers), but with the same cause:&amp;nbsp; mental illness, an inability to face reality, unrestricted access to weapons by those who shouldn&#39;t have them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The perps in this case used a monster death machine against defenseless Doctors Without Borders and their hospital.&amp;nbsp; The logistics were so bad that phone calls from the hospital made no difference to &quot;central command&quot; (a &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/02/memorandom-fs-4702.html&quot;&gt;headless chicken&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
President Obama said &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/10/truisms.html&quot;&gt;nothing public&lt;/a&gt; about it.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s going to Roseburg, Oregon, apparently because only American lives matter, whereas his own sickly mercenary forces murder children routinely.&amp;nbsp; The hypocrisy is palpable.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/34461462&quot;&gt;Some slob&lt;/a&gt; with stupid medals all over his chest tried to make it all better with his lame excuses, but of course WDC lost this &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/11/a-khan-at-thirsters.html&quot;&gt;stupid war&lt;/a&gt; long ago in the hearts and minds sense.&amp;nbsp; Who needs an enemy when you have &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/07/comments-on-news.html&quot;&gt;goons like these&lt;/a&gt; running the show?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets see if anyone takes any responsibility whatsoever for this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-34462538&quot;&gt;obvious war crime&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d reckon the loss to WDC in the billions over this, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/08/city-of-morons.html&quot;&gt;that city&lt;/a&gt; has negative money anyway and will never repay, bankrupt as it is, morally as well as financially.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Flags at half mast?&amp;nbsp; Why have them on the pole at all?&amp;nbsp; Definitely the Pentagon should take theirs down, at least for a few symbolic minutes.&amp;nbsp; Show some public remorse maybe?&amp;nbsp; Just &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-34471182&quot;&gt;a tiny bit&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In any case, stop claiming to represent &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/03/why-we-fight-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;the American people&lt;/a&gt; already!&amp;nbsp; Your services are neither required nor admired.&amp;nbsp; Your cowardice will echo through the annals of history.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/09/citizen-diplomacy.html&quot;&gt;Citizen diplomats&lt;/a&gt; disavow this war and the perps behind it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Just because one wears a military costume doesn&#39;t make one a respectable human being.&amp;nbsp; More is required.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I somewhat expect the story to morph such that the &quot;Afghani forces&quot; who supposedly requested the strike were actually &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2011/06/28/world/asia/28infiltrate.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;Taliban infiltrators&lt;/a&gt; looking for ways to embarrass central command and make it appear like a headless chicken -- a way to deflect criticism and make the Taliban share the opprobrium.&amp;nbsp; The story has already morphed away from &lt;a href=&quot;http://humanrightsinvestigations.org/2011/07/27/great-man-made-river-nato-bombs/&quot;&gt;NATO itself&lt;/a&gt; making the request.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Everyone knows &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nationalreview.com/feed/253774/nato-us-and-afghan-leaders-tricked-negotiating-taliban-impostor-greg-pollowitz&quot;&gt;NATO can be tricked&lt;/a&gt; into doing just about anything, if one just acts and sounds like a warlord.&amp;nbsp; Finding a way to blame &quot;the terrorists&quot; would be the typical response here.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/34461462&quot;&gt;Lets see&lt;/a&gt; if that&#39;s how it plays out.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Why an organization so easily duped should be allowed access to war planes would be the next question but that&#39;s easy to explain:&amp;nbsp; no background checks required, just a credit card and the signatures of a few paid-for well-paid elected officials.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/09/investigating-how-things-work.html&quot;&gt;Talk about corruption&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7761419861277979543'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7761419861277979543'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/men-without-honor.html' title='Men Without Honor'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2189290596315946629</id><published>2015-10-04T14:31:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-18T12:07:21.423-07:00</updated><title type='text'>My Comment on QuakerQuaker</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;xg_user_generated&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;xg_user_generated&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;xg_user_generated&quot;&gt;
Yeah,
 it&#39;s hard to not get cynical about religion once one sees how it&#39;s 
harnessed by the temporal powers to their own ends.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/12/twelve-years-of-slavery-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Emperor Constantine&lt;/a&gt;
 learned his lesson:&amp;nbsp; if you can&#39;t beat &#39;em, join &#39;em, i.e make the 
Roman Empire officially Christian and you&#39;ll have the tools to keep 
growing.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mass produce Christian baubles for the gift shops, and
 the faithful will follow you blindly, as their &quot;blind faith&quot; (so very 
similar to blind loyalty to one&#39;s King) is built right in as a virtue, 
at least in the more decadent brands of pyramid scheme hierarchy.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Obedience, not defiance, is what to cultivate in the masses.&amp;nbsp; Any religion able to do that is worth more than gold.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Religion
 is used to create that state of reverence and solemnity, gravitas.&amp;nbsp; The
 Cross gets planted on some South American beachhead, and voila, miracle
 of miracles, this is now Papal Property.&amp;nbsp; Amazing.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s downright 
Biblical!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Unfortunately for emperors and dictators, crime bosses 
of all kinds, Christianity is not quite tame enough to support a Borg 
Cube forever.&amp;nbsp; Whereas most humans seem eager to the point of desperate 
to surrender their free will to experts, professionals, pundits of all 
stripes, a tiny minority seems hell bent on doing its own thinking.&amp;nbsp; 
Irreverent Quakers pop up, questioning authority, refusing oaths of 
loyalty.&amp;nbsp; WTF!?&amp;nbsp; Where does the operator&#39;s manual say how to deal with 
Quakers?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As a result of such obstreperousness, micro-fractures 
emerge, and every so often, we get a meltdown, like the 100 years war 
twixt Catholics and Protestants [exemplary of a &quot;meltdown&quot; not saying Quaker caused -- &lt;i&gt;KTU&lt;/i&gt; ].&amp;nbsp; Or the Civil War in the US.&amp;nbsp; Or maybe 
even something good happens.&amp;nbsp; A shakeup in world religions might be just
 what the doctor ordered.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For whatever reason our species refuses
 to settle into any one Kingdom or Reich.&amp;nbsp; I consider this hopeful and 
positive.&amp;nbsp; The Tower of Babel is maybe my favorite Bible story.&amp;nbsp; Silly 
humans, thinking they could create One System to Rule Them All.&amp;nbsp; Ain&#39;t 
gonna happen.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks to some divine spark within common humanity,
 the peasants, handed a gun and a picture of their God, sometimes 
disobey their &quot;superiors&quot; and refuse to kill the enemy, seeing through 
the manipulation.&amp;nbsp; They see The Man behind the curtain, and, like 
Smedley &quot;Fighting Quaker&quot; Butler say out loud that &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/10/esozone-talk.html&quot;&gt;War is a Racket&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However,
 to see religion as a tool of social control is not to see the falsity 
of all religion.&amp;nbsp; Cynicism of that variety is simply too easy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Rather,
 the many religions and psychologies, not to mention philosophies, do 
indeed give us insights into something both collective and transcendent 
about the individual human mind.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One could simply say &quot;religion is the power of God&#39;s mind &lt;i&gt;combined with&lt;/i&gt;
 the human being&#39;s endless ability to distort it&quot;.&amp;nbsp; The idea that 
humanity is simply a distorted image of what true angels must be like is an
 old one and I think I&#39;ll land it there for now -- a friendly / familiar
 airport.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[original context:&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quakerquaker.org/profiles/blog/show?id=2360685%3ABlogPost%3A137344&amp;amp;commentId=2360685%3AComment%3A137639&quot;&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; re &lt;i&gt;So What&#39;s So Terrifying About Christianity?&lt;/i&gt; ] &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2189290596315946629'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2189290596315946629'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/my-comment-on-quakerquaker.html' title='My Comment on QuakerQuaker'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-9215466134601099320</id><published>2015-10-03T17:38:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-04T17:13:36.593-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Art History</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/21738915279/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF0953&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF0953&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/635/21738915279_44d3ca8256.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Glenn Stockton has purchased the latest edition of Linda Dalrymple Henderson&#39;s book, &lt;i&gt;The Fourth Dimension and Non-Euclidean Geometry in Modern Art&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; I have an earlier edition (depicted above).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
She&#39;s expanded her introduction considerably for the new edition, looking at published works at least up through 2009.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Linda is correct in lumping Bucky with those claiming to work in a fourth &lt;i&gt;spatial&lt;/i&gt; dimension, versus time, and quotes him regarding the tetrahedron providing his own justification for such terminology.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt;, simply turning a right angle number of degrees (90), going around a street corner, is not escaping into &quot;another dimension&quot;.&amp;nbsp; A turn of 89 or 91 degrees would be no less significant, were true dimensions at stake.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Rather, we start with Kant and an admission of volume or space as &lt;i&gt;a priori&lt;/i&gt;, with the passage of time thrown in to give the grammar of change.&amp;nbsp; Things take up room and persist in doing so -- that&#39;s our experience in a nutshell.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How many spatial dimensions is volume?&amp;nbsp; The conventional answer is three, building up by right angles, through height, width and depth.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fuller&#39;s answer is to throw a tetrahedron into the picture as a whole &lt;i&gt;ab initio&lt;/i&gt;, and to argue its faces and vertexes bespeak a primitive fourness.&amp;nbsp; &quot;A tetrahedron shouts &lt;i&gt;four&lt;/i&gt;!&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s about all he&#39;s saying -- almost too simple to make it into the history books.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you want the 3ness of 3D, look at each of the two complementary zig-zags or &quot;cobras&quot; that make any Tetrahedron, a Z of three connected vectors.&amp;nbsp; But the four points so connected define the alternative &quot;other&quot; Z, so 3 + 3 = 6 is more like it, but sure, a Z might be used for addressing purposes, giving 3-tuples. Space is &quot;Z-D&quot; (but what number is that?).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The conventional description of volume as &quot;3D&quot; relies on a &quot;jack&quot; of X, Y and Z axes, each one a next dimension.&amp;nbsp; From this &quot;jack&quot; (vs. a &quot;caltrop&quot;) we get 3-tuple addresses.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A fourth orthogonal is problematic (in the sense of oxymoronic), however 4-tuples are not, and these n-tuple data structures may be &quot;projected&quot; to something visual in ordinary space.&amp;nbsp; nD phase spaces have their Z-D analogs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A ball of n spokes from the center, whether orthogonal or not, may be declared &quot;independent&quot; with sliders set each to a specific level.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s a &quot;point&quot; in an nD phase space.&amp;nbsp; Tighten the rules a bit, and you get a manifold or metric.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fuller&#39;s math is not investing in having any &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/hypercross.html&quot;&gt;&quot;hypercross&quot; of four orthogonals&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The tetrahedron pure and simple anchors our talk of 4D in this logical model, not in some sleight of hand or science fiction. One may use &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/09/compare-and-contrast.html&quot;&gt;4-tuple quadrays&lt;/a&gt; isomorphically with 3-tuple XYZ rays.&amp;nbsp; The caltrop spans Z-space (Z + N = Tetrahedron).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Developing an alternative 4D namespace is not to find fault with, nor invalidate, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/11/matrix.html&quot;&gt;anything by Coxeter&lt;/a&gt;, the grand master of multi-dimensional polytopes to whom &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; is admiringly dedicated (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/09/quick-account.html&quot;&gt;with permission&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Frequency (time/size involvement), added to angle (pure shape), gets us to five dimensions if we wish to avail of such tools, i.e. a tetrahedron persisting in time-size, the stuff of scenarios in &quot;Scenario Universe&quot; -- make sense?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Energy added to pure Platonic form (4D) is more the Synergetics template.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When we have room for multiple namespaces, including exotic remote ones, such alternative beginnings get more room to breathe and show off their advantages, if any.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; itself, once booted, helps us keep our minds open, to multiple namespaces.&amp;nbsp; Systems, fully omni-triangulated, may be plentiful, like bubbles, produced quickly and in great numbers.&amp;nbsp; Stay tuned.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9215466134601099320'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/9215466134601099320'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/art-history.html' title='Art History'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4392790259245238070</id><published>2015-10-01T08:26:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-04T13:45:44.155-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Journalistic Shorthand</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/21819709436/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF0838&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF0838&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5658/21819709436_bf33e01c10.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
In journalistic shorthand, adapted from diplomacy, they say &quot;Assad must go&quot; or &quot;Saddam must go&quot; (Saddam, Qaddafi and Assad were all on the short list they tell us), but of course in reality that&#39;s code for a whole administration, extended families, neighborhoods, sections of town.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Were we to decree that so-and-so could no longer be Mayor of Portland, Bud Clark for example, that might affect the people of &lt;i&gt;Goose Hollow&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So when we hear talk about trying to remove &quot;Assad&quot;, lets remember we&#39;re talking about institutions and organizations, a complicated motherboard, circuitry.&amp;nbsp; One doesn&#39;t swap out a leader like a light bulb or other simple component, it&#39;s not like that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The diplomats all say the goal is to broker a deal with various parties at the table but it sounds like WDC doesn&#39;t want Assad at the table even to begin with.&amp;nbsp; Given that NATO / EU / US has already taken out Saddam and Qaddafi, the question is when will it stop?&amp;nbsp; What was the window?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Of course there&#39;s a ton of history to go over, if TV viewers ever have the patience for it.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s no way to learn anatomy in thirty seconds.&amp;nbsp; Wasn&#39;t it Walter Cronkite who said his biggest fear was that so many people just got their news through him?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
All we&#39;re in a position to do in Portland is welcome new refugees.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s what &lt;i&gt;Willamette Week&lt;/i&gt; is about this issue, introducing some new families.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
No one asked &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/08/city-of-morons.html&quot;&gt;Cascadia&lt;/a&gt; if / when to commence bombing; that decision was made by quite a few self-appointed authorities and a smattering of elected ones.&amp;nbsp; Their comic book language (&quot;Assad must go&quot;) says nothing reassuring about their grasp of the situation.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Shorthand is too short sometimes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets talk about what&#39;s going on in Iraq a lot more maybe?&amp;nbsp; What&#39;s the view from Baghdad?&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll dig into that some, but for the most part I know they&#39;d prefer we stay out of it and just deal with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news24.com/World/News/Afghan-bombing-Patients-burned-to-death-in-their-beds-says-MSF-20151004&quot;&gt;collateral damage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4392790259245238070'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4392790259245238070'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/journalistic-shorthand.html' title='Journalistic Shorthand'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7782158734446607531</id><published>2015-09-26T19:07:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2021-03-17T09:03:22.776-07:00</updated><title type='text'>WILPF Festivities</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157659076799646&quot; title=&quot;WILPF Turns One Hundred&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/597/21553845198_70d704c1ff_w.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;WILPF Turns One Hundred&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
The gala events were in The Hague, NL, and Carol (my mom) got to go, as an official delegate this April, when the Women&#39;s International League for Peace and Freedom celebrated a hundred years of existence.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One hundred years ago, Grace De Graff -- who&#39;d moved to Oregon from Illinois, to become a school teacher, administrator, and education planner -- was at the league&#39;s founding in The Hague, invited by Jane Addams herself.&amp;nbsp; Jane was on the lookout for strong manager women, still struggling to gain basic parity, in terms of rights, with men of privilege.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Today&#39;s events were the Portland, Oregon WILPF chapter&#39;s version of a Centennial, and I was invited to be one of the photographers (I believe technically I&#39;m also a member of WILPF).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol Urner wrote a letter to the &lt;i&gt;Oregon Reporter&lt;/i&gt; in the early 1960s, when I was pre-school aged, expressing fear and disappointment that this was all she had to look forward to:&amp;nbsp; a lifetime of fear under the threat of thermonuclear war.&amp;nbsp; That was no kind of world in which to bring up children, surely Russian moms agreed.&amp;nbsp; She&#39;d wished so long for a family life, and having it end up a twisted science fiction nightmare in the wake of WWII was just heartbreaking and she wrote that to the newspaper.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Adult readers, other mothers especially, from all over town responded by telephone the next day, really wanting Carol to cheer up as &quot;we can do something&quot;, and so a Portland women&#39;s movement was formed, to create some outcry about the standard assumption that we should all be buying and installing bomb shelters, with kids learning to duck and cover.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This movement later fed into WILPF, already active, and discovered by my mother and her friends as a perfect fit for their concerns.&amp;nbsp; Another famous WILPF member: Ava Helen Pauling, wife of the two time Nobel Prize winner, Linus Pauling.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol has been at it ever since, though in Rome and the Philippines, Cairo and Bhutan, she back-burnered her focus on abolishing nuclear weapons.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m glad she did, as that way she did get a family life mostly free of obsessing about The Bomb, and the end of civilization as a place of playgrounds and carefree kids.&amp;nbsp; She got to study history a lot more (one of her passions) and work with women&#39;s self help projects, handicraft-based, and teach grade school, and write text books.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One of the women who took the torch from De Graff, not directly but in a reconstitution of Portland&#39;s WILPF, was Eleanor Davis, age 92.&amp;nbsp; She grew into WILPF through her mother, whom she recalls being active in the 1950s.&amp;nbsp; Iona Tanner, whom I remember from childhood, has chronicled some of the history, as did &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/09/some-family-history.html&quot;&gt;Mary Bolton&lt;/a&gt; later, in the form of scrap books and clippings.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s a lot of organizational memory here, worth curating I should think.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My job, as chauffeur plus photographer was to take Carol, Eleanor and their equipment and literature, to the staging site, named &lt;i&gt;Walk of the Heroines&lt;/i&gt; on the Portland State campus. This monument was designed specifically to memorialize women, and a great many names appear thereon, sometimes grouped by organization.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The WILPF section is two or three stones of names towards one end.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not sure how the monument is managed as to whether more names might be added.&amp;nbsp; Either way, I&#39;m glad for this monument, though I&#39;m biased given mom&#39;s name is inscribed thereon, next to that of Mary Bolton.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sonya Pinney, not named (she&#39;s self effacing) was at the event, as observant as ever, seems to me.&amp;nbsp; She&#39;d been digging through the recent issue of &lt;i&gt;Western Friend&lt;/i&gt; and seeing letters replying to my article (two long ones).&amp;nbsp; That had led her back to the article itself in the previous issue, so we had quite a bit to talk about, comparing notes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then I had to attend to my car, moving it and the wheel chair to a next terminus, where the march would end.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, the women marched with their WILPF banners quite a few blocks.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For some of that time, I was talking with Joel, a Food Not Bomber connected with Unitarians, and grabbing a quick salad at &lt;i&gt;Safeway&lt;/i&gt;, catching up with the women at the Eliot Center.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For those into digging, the slides embedded in the show above are but a sampling, with more in the Photostream.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I won&#39;t try narrating the entire program in Eliot Center, save to say I took Eleanor home a little early, as she&#39;d had all the fun she could bear, as &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/09/autobiographical-interlude.html&quot;&gt;my wife Dawn&lt;/a&gt; was wont to say.&amp;nbsp; Also, I caught up with Elizabeth, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wweek.com/portland/article-6828-remembering_ben.html&quot;&gt;Ben Linder&#39;s mom&lt;/a&gt;, just a little.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol, who made at least three speeches over the span of the 
program, was pretty exuberant the whole time, on not much sleep, and 
crashed upon our arrival home.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Given all the logistics involved, and how much time had 
gone into the planning, I&#39;d say stress levels were somewhat high, but 
that we all worked together on pulling it off.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Part of my job was staying peripheral, an unobtrusive observer, similar to my role &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/08/disarm-day-2015.html&quot;&gt;at Disarm Day&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; My camera and I wandered off into the surrounding context, capturing a slice of Portland in the Fall of 2015.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Making Sarah-the-dog hold it for so long was an oversight on my part and I phoned Deke rather late in the game to please check up on her if in the neighborhood.&amp;nbsp; I didn&#39;t have a clear grasp of the script we were following and imagined getting home earlier.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Congratulations to WILPF on a hundred years of focused work.&amp;nbsp; May the next hundred be likewise invested in having the world become a more humane place.&amp;nbsp; Lets hope we get to look back on continued progress, with thanks to our heroines for showing a way forward.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7782158734446607531'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7782158734446607531'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/09/wilpf-festivities.html' title='WILPF Festivities'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>