<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=501'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=476&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=526&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>501</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-125187317252711837</id><published>2017-01-25T22:04:00.003-08:00</published><updated>2023-09-02T08:02:22.290-07:00</updated><title type='text'>School Teaching</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I&#39;ve been deeply involved in work-study, about 50% work, 50% study, which was my goal. The work that I do is teaching. I&#39;m an andragogue (teach adults) by night, and a pedagogue (teach kids) by day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s the latter work I&#39;m just starting, meaning I&#39;ve still got a ways to go when it comes to mastering MIT Scratch and Codesters, even though I&#39;m pretty well versed in pure Python (above average anyway).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The studying part is more eclectic and harder to describe. I think of myself as an anthropologist quite a bit. I&#39;m an avid consumer of culture.&amp;nbsp; Remember Bucky Fuller (whom I write about often in these journals) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/quotable-quotes.html&quot;&gt;Marshall McLuhan&lt;/a&gt; were &lt;a href=&quot;https://mcluhangalaxy.wordpress.com/2014/05/12/an-evening-of-marshall-mcluhan-bucky-fuller-in-rotterdam/&quot;&gt;good buddies&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s a Fuller title that&#39;s very like a McLuhan book, what is it again? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Seem-Be-Verb-Environment-Future/dp/B0006CZBHO&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;I Seem to be a Verb&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/125187317252711837'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/125187317252711837'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/01/school-teaching.html' title='School Teaching'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8511227003090612337</id><published>2017-01-22T21:30:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2024-03-19T18:06:07.889-07:00</updated><title type='text'>I, Robot</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I reconnected with Russian mysticism, as some call it, thanks to a pile of books for sale at Multnomah Meeting. I&#39;ve since traced prior ownership, of these four volumes, from a set of six, by Maurice Nicoll, to&amp;nbsp; Friend Marson (&quot;the Marsonite&quot; I sometimes call him, a Peace Corps vet).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m referring to Psychological Commentaries by the Scottish Jungian, also a disciple of one &quot;Dr. O&quot; i.e. P. D. Ouspensky. Where did Dr. O enter our story before? In &lt;a href=&quot;https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/fourth-dimension-and-non-euclidean-geometry-modern-art&quot;&gt;Linda Dalrymple Henderson&#39;s book&lt;/a&gt;, about non-Euclidean geometry and modern art. Ouspensky was branding around 4D, an icon which the young Bucky Fuller took on as well. Einstein was flying this banner. The 20th Century was looking propitious.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As I&#39;ve been clear about in other blog posts, we have multiple meanings of &#39;4D&#39; in play here, but let me avoid that whole thread and get back to the Russian mystics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Nicoll suggests we get back to developing our essence in later life, after maturing through the earlier stages. We have a fully formed personality by then. We&#39;ve worked out with the reality principle. Put another way, our egos are fully developed and now we&#39;re ready to go the next step as it were, to reach for wisdom.&amp;nbsp; How is that done?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Russians want us to confront our robotic nature, our mechanical side. That&#39;s not always easy for US Americans because &quot;robotic behavior&quot; is usually demonized as somehow totalitarian (which it may be). Using &quot;robotic&quot; without a negative spin, with reference to human behavior, is akin to making &quot;porn&quot; somewhat meaningless, as when we talk of &quot;train porn&quot; (admiring trains, thinking of a Barcamp talk by &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/10/at-wherecamppdx.html&quot;&gt;the late Igal&lt;/a&gt;, PDX geek, worked with Patrick a little).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Let me take a well run (smoothly clerked) Quaker business meeting as my model.&amp;nbsp; The people in attendance all have considerable experience, personalities fully formed.&amp;nbsp; Kids would usually be off elsewhere, in a program of some kind. Business meeting is all adult stuff, pretty much, awfully dry for little kids especially. Nursing mothers are certainly welcome.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In saying the meeting went like clockwork, I&#39;m not making a negative characterization. However if I say that Friends were robotic in their practice, that sounds insulting, like I&#39;m saying &quot;unimaginative&quot; or &quot;dull&quot; (without the spark of life etc.). That&#39;s the cultural divide I&#39;m facing, in translating these Psychological Commentaries into the language of my locale. &quot;Robotic&quot; is a term of admiration.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The resolution of my puzzle is perhaps through the example of Muhammad Ali, a man of schooled reflexes who could hold his own both inside and outside of the ring.&amp;nbsp; He professed the discipline of Islam in later life, however he came to that religion already self-disciplined.&amp;nbsp; In Afro-American subcultures, &quot;machine dancing&quot; is a recognized art form, influenced and enhanced by some of Michael Jackson&#39;s maneuvers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Through &quot;machine dancing&quot; we move to the martial arts and all those routines people go through when working for that next colored belt, the next level.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
True, Dr O. and Maurice want us to see, in our robotic nature, those features we may at first project on others, when we fail to &quot;remember ourselves&quot; as they say in their jargon.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not suggesting that Friends all convert to such thinking.&amp;nbsp; However I do think it worthwhile to remember our deeper culture and apply that in our daily lives. Teachers like Maurice did not do all that writing out of sheer boredom. They were working towards a less violent world, less indulgent in negative states, from which great misery arises.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For those not familiar with Ouspensky, one of his famous maxims is &quot;man cannot do&quot; which is on the face of it meaningless. I&#39;d say the program is meant to apply what Nicoll calls &quot;the shock of consciousness&quot; which is an experience of extreme determinism and epiphenomenalism wherein all humanity appears to be on autopilot. Walt Whitman&#39;s &lt;i&gt;The Sleepers&lt;/i&gt; is a soliloquy of great compassion, by someone with a body electric, another robot in other words. &lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8511227003090612337'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8511227003090612337'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/01/i-robot.html' title='I, Robot'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1435665481580711916</id><published>2017-01-20T22:41:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2017-01-21T01:46:20.142-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Amortizing</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I was watching one of those reviews of Uber, where they try to talk a would-be driver out of the deal, based on various starting assumptions.&amp;nbsp; One thing people forget to do is continue discounting the value of what to them is valuable equipment.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In my case, for example, I have this creaky-old 2011ish Mac Air that&#39;s been my workhorse through thick and thin.&amp;nbsp; It has no health insurance.&amp;nbsp; I could send it in for refurbishing at some expense, but in the accounting world I&#39;d have been creating a savings account based on the obvious need for a next computer someday.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
OK, so I&#39;m thinking in that direction. All I need to do is slip in the ice one more time, as they say.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll be starting another class soon though and as long as she&#39;s still running (the Mac Air), I&#39;m going to keep her on my desk. She&#39;s wheezing though. Her fan is off kilter. The severity of the wheeze comes and goes. I know it could get so much worse.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of loss, did I mention the fish that are going or have gone?&amp;nbsp; We decided the horse faced loach was a goner quite awhile ago, when he failed to appear even at the usual low frequency. More recently, my top-feeder has died. Lower temperatures may have been to some extent to blame. Fish don&#39;t last forever though. Turnover is built in to their design.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Alexia is studying bookkeeping at the college level, having gained some practical experience working with her mother, Dawn, my wife and business partner.&amp;nbsp; She was good at accounting and really understood the clients she worked for.&amp;nbsp; She had already taken on another partner and split off the bookkeeping in a way that could continue, after DWA was reduced to a checking account.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One of the DWA aliases, registered with the bank so people could write checks to it, still can, was 4D Solutions, which I map to 4dsolutions.net on the web.&amp;nbsp; Behind my logo lives the Oregon Curriculum Network (OCN), which I consider my not-for-profit way of helping Oregon in particular.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not that anyone in particular has adopted &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/xtals101.html&quot;&gt;this material&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;m more just joining the throng of earnest scholars who took to the web, like fish to water.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Probably my most ambitious project, considered as a business plan, is Coffee Shops Network (CSN). Under that heading comes a &quot;charitable gambling&quot; operation that converts winnings at games into charitable donations to the coffee shop&#39;s list of charities it supports. A donut company might give you the token, with purchase, to try your skill in some way, and then back up your performance with charitable giving on your behalf. You&#39;ve won the right to commit the donut company&#39;s dollar to the cause you&#39;ve championed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
GST used to be about &quot;fundraising thermometers&quot; a lot, on the web. That certainly happened, in the form of Kickstarter, GoFundMe and all the rest. I&#39;ve been pretty strong at predicting things, but that&#39;s what hindsight is good at seeing.&amp;nbsp; We get to be right about stuff.&amp;nbsp; We get to be wrong about stuff.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Talking with Alexia about bookkeeping a little has reminded me of amortization as a concept. Lots is coming back to me. I also used to write about Global Data the corporation a lot.&amp;nbsp; Going back in time in my blogs gives some examples of that. The goal was and is to provide a lot of global data to the world, however in practice it&#39;s Google we usually think about.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My style of thinking is somewhat informed by those years looking at the Hunger Project and looking at some of the Fernando Flores stuff around that same time. His thinking was centrally featured at the 2016 Pycon here in Portland, when one of his students delivered a keynote. I&#39;ll insert my recent tweet about that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LorenaABarba&quot;&gt;@LorenaABarba&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/deg511&quot;&gt;@deg511&lt;/a&gt; your keynote at Pycon2016 was excellent and I think back to it often. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/d0AXtx4noA&quot;&gt;https://t.co/d0AXtx4noA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@thekirbster) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thekirbster/status/822267530005790725&quot;&gt;January 20, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Hey, right on cue, as I write about things breaking or falling apart, my kitchen sink just stopped draining. After wrenching apart some pipe, I&#39;ve discovered wherever the blockage is, it&#39;s below the standard trap. Not good. Especially with guests coming.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1435665481580711916'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1435665481580711916'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/01/amortizing.html' title='Amortizing'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4629604280940027547</id><published>2017-01-18T20:00:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2017-01-19T00:58:32.745-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Blockchain Voting</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I was bringing up blockchain voting in a Quaker forum, as an example of a promising technology. Farm house Friends still put more faith in old fashioned paper balloting with visible counting, and in a one room school house, this can work.&amp;nbsp; Perhaps paper ballot counting scales much further, without limit, for the sake of discussion.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Blockchain has excited people for different reasons. What a financial playing field requires is a set of rules that are self-enforcing, in the sense that cheating should be next to impossible, even in theory. With strong encryption, such schemes became feasible.&amp;nbsp; Gambling casinos are a first good example, as they depend on the mathematics of probability to stay profitable, not on sleight of hand, even if stage performing magicians are among the attractions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The example most cited up to now is Bitcoin, which came with clever terminology and a self funding model of a self booting currency.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Bit miners&quot; around the world would learn of the different transactions at different times, more how Facebook works. Not every Friend sees updates to your profile at the same time, but after awhile, everyone knows about them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The question then becomes, which sequence of events, which chronology, is real?&amp;nbsp; Instead of making the players prove their case, each one hiring an army of lawyers (good for middle men), a contest is held (about every ten minutes), of a brute force nature, meaning if your computer is capable of monster computations, you win the contest often enough to make transaction-tracking worth your while.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If your bitcoin miner computer wins the contest, it&#39;s paid some bitcoin, and its version of events (of transactions, their sequence) gets added to the globally shared blockchain, the one true narrative account. The point of doing it this way is precisely to rely on some shake of the dice that no one controls. Agreement gets created. Trust builds that the transactions are secure.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Micro-payments between individual parties becomes possible, without the usual and more expensive amount of overhead. Sending remittances home, from family members working abroad, is one of the most used applications of this technology.&amp;nbsp; The currency converts into bitcoin at the source, and out into perhaps some other currency at the intended destination.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How does all this apply to voting though?&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s an excellent question.&amp;nbsp; Lots of talented social engineers have been exploring the ramifications of blockchain technology on electronic voting.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Before Measure 97 went down to defeat, on the State of Oregon ballot (November, 2016), I was having fantasies of showcase facilities where rotating groups of students, with faculty (more advanced students) could come to learn about &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/05/the-blockchain-and-global-u.html&quot;&gt;the new tech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However I hadn&#39;t thought through who goes where exactly. The mostly unused Sunnyside Methodist Church (or &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/06/ghost-church.html&quot;&gt;ghost church&lt;/a&gt;&quot;) had given me some ideas. I was thinking in terms of teacher training, having watched over my dad&#39;s shoulder (he was an education system planner) and having some sense of the workflow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In other words, say you&#39;re at Cleveland High School and learning about how polling and voting works, or doesn&#39;t. The school has some voting machines and equipment for counting ballots, with the school routinely bringing questions to a vote. &quot;Who believes in UFOs?&quot;&amp;nbsp; Yes, that&#39;s a poorly designed question, however if the goal is to work out with equipment, the point of the question may not be the point of the exercise.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We go through a lot of effort to authenticate here and there.&amp;nbsp; To our banks.&amp;nbsp; To our medical service providers.&amp;nbsp; One would think a citizen of a nation is by definition entitled to specific on-line services, including the right to vote in various elections by means of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/07/the-last-colony-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;a smartphone application&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The fact that the USG gives us no means to authenticate as citizens to perform our civic duties, is evidence that USA OS is still more on paper than a socially engineered reality. Lets hope better days are ahead.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some readers may have been inwardly objecting, from the top, that Quaker practice is not about voting, so why would blockchain voting be pertinent in a Quaker forum in the first place.&amp;nbsp; To clarify, I&#39;m accepting that Quakerism does not define the public sphere and that my civic duties as a voter do not fall outside the scope of my duties in general. &lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4629604280940027547'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4629604280940027547'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/01/blockchain-voting.html' title='Blockchain Voting'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1977322431912609912</id><published>2017-01-16T11:22:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2017-01-20T21:38:32.314-08:00</updated><title type='text'>War Studies</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/32311318036/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF2938&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF2938&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/579/32311318036_8856af0a34.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
That famous folk song that goes &quot;ain&#39;t gonna study war no more&quot; seems clearly in the back of the mind of our writer, Friend Wolf Mendl, as he opens with a defense: &quot;Why would a Quaker, a subclass of Pacifist, study and/or play war games?&quot;&amp;nbsp; Obviously, in order to end it (outward war), in favor of world game instead, he says in translation to 2017-speak.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets remember George Fox was looked up to as a leader of the type you&#39;d want to follow in battle. England found it frustrating that some of its bravest had a strong penchant for non-violence, but as the pamphlet points out, that&#39;s more the Chinese way, of Sun Tzu. Overt force is just gross, compared to the subtle thrusts of his martial art.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Friend Mendl, then quotes Clausewitz (more often cited than read) in saying the political has to guide the military is a truism, as &quot;the political&quot; is simply what thoughts go through our minds as we set about with our planning. What&#39;s the ideological glue that coheres this massive attempt at cooperation? What follows is almost robotic, and gets faster and more precise with practice, which is what drilling is all about.&amp;nbsp; Martial artists are always looping through their moves in various hypertoon scenarios.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We get to Kissinger and ample citations to a dogma that military might makes for influence on the world stage. That truism, combined with a lot of zero sum game misassumptions endemic to English speakers, but not only English speakers, has led us to the threshold of mutually assured destruction, a cliffhanger for sure.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Back to my point about George Fox as cut from cloth similar to that of a military leader, I think Quakers around Oliver Cromwell&#39;s time, on through William Penn, got some appreciation from the war rooms for at least having done some homework. They didn&#39;t walk in and immediately start kneeling or handing out pamphlets or other inappropriate behaviors (pouring lamb&#39;s blood on everything). They speak knowingly of the chessboard (if not a go board) and have constructive things to say.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This Pendle Hill Pamphlet (#247) contributes in that tradition. Having come out several decades ago, there&#39;s no hint of our curriculum changes in the lower grades around geometry, bringing the context of world game to &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kirbyurner/american-literature-101-224489c26f19&quot;&gt;American literature&lt;/a&gt;, as &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/02/ayatollah-of-tetrahedron.html&quot;&gt;E. J. Applewhite&lt;/a&gt; predicted and helped make happen. I&#39;m not saying every public or private school shares anything about all of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/09/focal-points.html&quot;&gt;focal points&lt;/a&gt; my own students all know about. Not in early 2017.&amp;nbsp; However the garden had been planted, the memes released, much earlier in the 1900s. Osmosis takes time. At least Quakers were doing their homework.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1977322431912609912'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1977322431912609912'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/01/war-studies.html' title='War Studies'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2141302550487322605</id><published>2017-01-11T16:49:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2017-01-28T01:16:08.224-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2017.1.10</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/32093641162/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Honored Guest&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Honored Guest&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://c3.staticflickr.com/1/383/32093641162_cb4b67b9d9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Our honored guest at Wanderers last night is an extremely intelligent and diplomatically skilled dude.  I&#39;ve met a few of these Afghani-Americans with a foot firmly planted &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/11/a-khan-at-thirsters.html&quot;&gt;in both worlds&lt;/a&gt;, that of the US, and that of contemporary Afghanistan.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dr. Monammad Khan Kharoti is a medical doctor, a surgeon, with a strong understanding of the cultures he&#39;s dealing with.&amp;nbsp; His focus, since well before 9-11, has been &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greenvillageschools.com/&quot;&gt;providing schooling&lt;/a&gt; for Afghans, for girls as much as for boys.&amp;nbsp; The Taliban have never objected to that agenda.&amp;nbsp; The facilities are internally gender-segregated and religious texts are not eschewed, as has been the Western standard until quite recently.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Khoroti sees two scourges in Afghanistan: illiteracy (which leads to incapacitating ignorance) and the misfortune to have been associated with Osama bin Laden, which turned the US from friendly to definitely hostile.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Offering free tours of the US to small groups of Taliban, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/03/chauffeur-duty.html&quot;&gt;through the State Department&lt;/a&gt;, just to learn about the differences first hand, would go much further towards establishing a peace than misguided attempts at &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/02/report-from-afghanistan.html&quot;&gt;military takeover&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Ideologies spread by osmosis, not bullets, which only harden the hearts of those shot at.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We reminisced about the good old days when the world was less in turmoil.&amp;nbsp; I took a commercial bus for ordinary folks from Peshawar to Kabul that time, through the Khyber pass, with my mom and dad. We had no reason to be fearful in the 1970s.&amp;nbsp; From Kabul we flew to Tashkent on Aeroflot, then on to Moscow and St. Petersberg, then Helsinki no problemo.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Those were the golden years maybe? Any way back to that?&amp;nbsp; The trucking industry needs the routes from Istanbul to Kabul to work without obstruction.&amp;nbsp; Kabul isn&#39;t far from Islamabad after that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Kharoti is well respected by &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/05/bait-and-switch.html&quot;&gt;the Taliban&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s clearly acting in the best interests of the people he serves. His integrity goes unquestioned. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/l6GEpxUCdzI&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cqL1JlhSbUw&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2141302550487322605'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2141302550487322605'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/01/wanderers-2017110.html' title='Wanderers 2017.1.10'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/l6GEpxUCdzI/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8244446091171990070</id><published>2017-01-09T22:01:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T07:49:09.306-07:00</updated><title type='text'>More About Martians</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4_oGLN0p3Gc&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;presentation at NIST &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I&#39;ve been on a CC or two with Istvan as I recall, as I was in communication with &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2016/08/necker-cube-guy.html&quot;&gt;Ed Applewhite&lt;/a&gt; about the time he wrote &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/synergetica/eja1.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Naming of Buckminsterfullerene&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;i&gt;Chemical Intelligencer&lt;/i&gt;, which Dr. Hargittai edited.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m still taking this one in, about the Martians of Science, Istvan&#39;s name for his fellow Hungarians advising the Manhattan Project.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Me on Facebook: &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&lt;span data-ft=&quot;{&amp;quot;tn&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;K&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;UFICommentBody&quot;&gt;I
 remember when Edward Teller spoke at Princeton. Students hissed a lot. 
They do that at Princeton, like a viper pit or something, could be 
unsettling. They did the same thing with James Schlesinger as I recall, 
another GST guy. No hissing at Isaac Asimov&#39;s packed talk as I recall, 
nor at Nader&#39;s (an alum).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;_3-8y _2lhm&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;_6m2 _1zpr clearfix _5cwb _4y_8 _pb2&quot; data-ft=&quot;{&amp;quot;tn&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;H&amp;quot;}&quot; id=&quot;u_jsonp_2_1i&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;clearfix _2r3x&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;_42ef&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_3ekx _29_4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_6m3 _--6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mbs _6m6 _2cnj _5s6c&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;_3c21&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/05/general-systems-theory.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;General Systems Theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_6m7 _3bt9&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;_3c21&quot;&gt;Certainly economists compete with one another to become stars in their own field, but the discipline as a whole still…&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_59tj _2iau&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_6lz _6mb ellipsis&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;_3c21&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;_3c21&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Given my interest in &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/more-core.html&quot;&gt;Martian Math&lt;/a&gt;, with input from Applewhite, it makes sense that I&#39;d be doing this homework.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of NIST, I&#39;ve enjoyed a recent exchange with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/09/revisiting-911.html&quot;&gt;Friend David Chandler&lt;/a&gt; on the awaited results of a next study (not by NIST, a peer review thing). NIST has findings of consequence for future building designers, given WTC7&#39;s structural failure from fires.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m following from a distance.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8244446091171990070'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8244446091171990070'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/01/more-about-martians.html' title='More About Martians'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/4_oGLN0p3Gc/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7904063858085837901</id><published>2017-01-01T17:39:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2021-03-05T15:18:28.417-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Andy Warhol Exhibit</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157678519165665&quot; title=&quot;Andy Warhol Exhibit&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/277/31184748843_9a69196853_w.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Andy Warhol Exhibit&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I&#39;ve been speculating on Facebook that a combination of &quot;cosplay&quot; (costume play), rebellion against arbitrary dress codes (&quot;no head covering&quot;) and the emergence of more fairy-tale job titles (&quot;security princess&quot;) is going to make the business world quite a bit less boring, in terms of people making fashion statements.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not that the &quot;business world&quot; even today is a monolith.&amp;nbsp; In high tech we dress down whereas those &quot;motivated by money&quot; tend to &quot;dress for success&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My own outfit has drifted towards Urban Cowboy with Magnetic Mittens. I&#39;ve got a P-coat and a Stetson (a little discolored from the weather), and these nifty mittens that fold back to give me fingers, more precise than gloves especially when it comes to smartphones.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I don&#39;t have to take my mittens on and off as I ride the bus, at risk of losing them.&amp;nbsp; Out come the fingers and the smartphone.&amp;nbsp; I get on with my work.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The hat stays home a lot.&amp;nbsp; I have a Python logo sweater, gray or black, as an intermediate layer, given we&#39;re averaging around water&#39;s freezing point, with frequent thawing and melting.&amp;nbsp; Snow rarely piles up here for very long.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was heading towards the bus stop the other day, going to see the Andy Warhol exhibit before it leaves town, and letting ten quarters jingle in one of the magnetic mittens, my bus fare.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In a moment of absent-mindedness, I brought out the fingers, I think to wave at someone, and the ten quarters went flying, meaning I was on my hands and knees on the sidewalk picking them up.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When I got to the bus, I was short one quarter but then found a disk in the lining of the mitten I was mistaking for the tenth quarter.&amp;nbsp; I told the bus driver a just needed a minute to get it out.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But of course the disk was actually the mitten magnet. I must have lost one of the original ten.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fortunately, my associate had an extra quarter and I explained to the bus driver how I&#39;d made a mistake.&amp;nbsp; Kinda funny.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Now you might think I shouldn&#39;t be bothering a busy city bus driver with meaningless drivel about how what I thought was a quarter was actually a mitten magnet.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I will respond in my own defense that the bus was following another of the same number and was therefore approximately empty.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Just two of us and the driver sailed over the Hawthorne bridge (figuratively speaking) and into town.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The next thing that happened was the PDX Crow Choir (not paid, not human) did their 5 PM raucous caucusing.&amp;nbsp; The sky and trees were host to great numbers of crows.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In Italian cities it&#39;s maybe pigeons and Portland certainly has those, and a few seagulls.&amp;nbsp; But this time of year the crows own the south Park Blocks, where the Portland Art Museum is.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Again on Facebook, I was showing off my knowledge of arcane English and referring to this large gathering as a &quot;murder&quot; of crows, as that&#39;s the technical word for a collection of crows, much as we have a &quot;flock&quot; of sheep, a &quot;herd&quot; of cattle, and a &quot;grunch&quot; of giants.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At lunch today at &lt;i&gt;Dick&#39;s Kitchen&lt;/i&gt; on Belmont (with pictures of Dicks, such a Tracey and Nixon) my eating partner agreed that &quot;alchemist&quot; sounds less cynical than &quot;spin doctor&quot; for a business card, not that I have either card.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Job titles are getting weirder, that&#39;s for sure, and not just in the Capital of Weird (sorry Austin).&amp;nbsp; Both jobs involve PЯ (PR&amp;nbsp;&lt;complete id=&quot;goog_934220616&quot;&gt;+&lt;/complete&gt; propaganda) which is also storytelling.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7904063858085837901'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7904063858085837901'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/01/andy-warhol-exhibit.html' title='Andy Warhol Exhibit'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1441273408603305830</id><published>2016-12-29T19:27:00.004-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-29T22:14:16.090-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Countermeasures</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6-yOYxHpFLA&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;some USers remain skeptical...&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Obama White House did not need to wait until the requested analysis was completed, before showing it means business when it comes to punishing perpetrators. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Like when we first heard reports from Syria, of chemical weapons being used: the White House &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/08/city-of-morons.html&quot;&gt;knew immediately&lt;/a&gt; who was behind the attack, and barreled ahead big time, UN investigation be damned.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What Russian spies helped uncover, about the Democratic Party, apparently proved &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2016/11/election-postmortem.html&quot;&gt;so heinous and repulsive&lt;/a&gt;, that the public recoiled en masse and joined the Trump train to drain the swamp.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So the question now is whether the Russians did us a favor.&amp;nbsp; That remains to be seen.&amp;nbsp; USers have at least learned an important lesson:&amp;nbsp; we&#39;re a Banana Republic like everyone else, not immune from foreign meddling.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This historic revelation, that Russia forever changed the course of American history, using tricks well known to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/10/bed-time-stories.html&quot;&gt;Nigerian bankers&lt;/a&gt;, is going to have repercussions around the world.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some surveys suggest USers themselves remain skeptical of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/10/emerging-cyberia.html&quot;&gt;seventeen intelligence agency&lt;/a&gt; consensus, the same &quot;intelligence community&quot; that made both Colin Powell and George Tenet, and eventually the US president, seem &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/01/more-geopolitics.html&quot;&gt;so like idiots&lt;/a&gt; on the world stage.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I understand why &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2016/12/political-cartoon.html&quot;&gt;the president-elect&lt;/a&gt; is reluctant to sign his name to this narrative.&amp;nbsp; Anyone hoping to &quot;make America great again&quot; would think twice about surrendering to this tail of defeat.&amp;nbsp; Russia is more of a world power than we realized maybe.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Given what we now know about &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/12/library-science.html&quot;&gt;the DNC&lt;/a&gt;, might that be a good thing?&amp;nbsp; Time will tell. Obama himself, judging from a last press conference, seems to think a new grass roots movement will help rebuild its image, in the wake of the latest rout.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Trump has been saying all along the Obama administration was being outplayed by Putin.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s been hankering for a fresh start, without the baggage of so many botched opportunities.&amp;nbsp; With the US losing momentum with its &quot;regime change&quot; agenda, this might be a time to figure out a new strategy?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Me? I voted for Hillary because I supported the plan &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/12/radical-islam.html&quot;&gt;with Iran&lt;/a&gt; to create thousands of new American jobs in transportation.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quakerquaker.org/forum/topics/iran-is-officially-anti-nuke-wmd&quot;&gt;The Iran Deal&lt;/a&gt; is good for American workers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As we learned from &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/09/maintenance.html&quot;&gt;Susan Lindauer &lt;/a&gt;(a CIA asset in the lead-up to 9-11), Iraq was prepared to buy millions of Made in the USA automobiles before Colin Powell messed up and persuaded us to attack the wrong country. The weapons testers were not happy with that Iraqi offer and railroaded us into war without telling us about it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets not keep making the same mistake in thinking DC really has our best interests at heart.&amp;nbsp; If that were true, we wouldn&#39;t be where we are today. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
Starting a stupid war with Iran would kill American jobs waiting in the wings once long haul trucking routes are restored to former glory.&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@4DsolutionsPDX) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/4DsolutionsPDX/status/814639263199293440&quot;&gt;December 30, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
Transportation engineers in training have that Istanbul-to-Kabul route to camp along, the El Camino of long haul trucking. Khyber Pass extra&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@4DsolutionsPDX) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/4DsolutionsPDX/status/814631780158296064&quot;&gt;December 30, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1441273408603305830'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1441273408603305830'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/countermeasures.html' title='Countermeasures'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/6-yOYxHpFLA/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3493947947940453970</id><published>2016-12-27T16:59:00.003-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-27T17:27:14.667-08:00</updated><title type='text'>More Core</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/E4q6OCDw7Rg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Three cheers for MIT Scratch, a great learning environment for young coders.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://scratch.mit.edu/projects/138035016/&quot;&gt;This project&lt;/a&gt; provides a quick recap of some of our core concepts.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Remember, the canonical Martian tetrahedron has edges of a full diameter, whereas the Earthling cube has edges = radius, so only half the length.&amp;nbsp; Even so, the cube holds more concrete.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Most of this core content should be review by now, if you&#39;re in &lt;a href=&quot;http://4dsolutions.net/ocn/winterhaven/section3.html&quot;&gt;middle&lt;/a&gt; or high school.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3493947947940453970'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3493947947940453970'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/more-core.html' title='More Core'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/E4q6OCDw7Rg/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8622487129712991911</id><published>2016-12-22T15:26:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2017-03-08T17:08:46.395-08:00</updated><title type='text'>New Conspiracy Theories</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/migu4suXvV8&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As we all know, the network of shopping mall and department store Santas is primarily an intelligence gathering tool of the retailers, who pay top dollar to find out what&#39;s hot and what&#39;s not in the minds of children each year. &amp;nbsp;Is Minecraft still mentioned as often? &amp;nbsp;With what frequency does a kid somewhere on a Santa say &quot;Lego&quot; (Ogel wants to know).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not mentioned are the more specialized Santas, able to predict US foreign policy months in advance, simply by resonating with the parents, through their kids. &amp;nbsp;The tallies get fed to machine learning algorithms back in the homeland, code named Ogel, and out pops some highly refined anticipatory policy analysis. &amp;nbsp;As you might imagine, these more sensitive Santas sometimes make enough to live on the entire rest of the year!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The next new wrinkle, already under development at MIT, will be the AI Santas, marketed as OK for adults to sit on and confess to (picture &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.manifestation.com/neurotoys/eliza.php3&quot;&gt;Eliza&lt;/a&gt; on steroids). &amp;nbsp;An electronic brain the size of Watson&#39;s will dispense therapeutic advice while meanwhile telling Big Pharma where to hit a goldmine this year. &amp;nbsp;Is it uppers or downers that most adults crave? &amp;nbsp;And that&#39;s just the tip of the iceberg. &amp;nbsp;Ask your doctor!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On a related topic, count me a skeptic when it comes to Winnie-the-Pooh&#39;s secret identity as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/12/library-science.html&quot;&gt;KGB agent&lt;/a&gt;. That he would secretly blackmail Christopher Robin while keeping up the &quot;silly bear&quot; act as a front, seems beyond ridiculous. &amp;nbsp;The notion that Christopher had deep insecurities around gender that could be exploited by Pooh to turn him against the GCHQ (let alone MI6) is the projection of American FBI investigators, still mostly male, and as usual unable to see passed their own homophobia (their pet &quot;issue&quot; since Hoover).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, if requests for &quot;Pooh Bears&quot; sees some unexplained resurgence, i.e. even in the absence of a new Disney film, I&#39;m prepared to look again at the evidence. &amp;nbsp;Even if it turned out to be true (stranger things have happened) this intel would be on the stale side in any case, Christopher having long ago reached an age when he could overpower Pooh in any inevitable fight to the death. &amp;nbsp;Even Piglet (supposedly Pooh&#39;s handler) would have had a hard time intervening, once Robin decided to exact his revenge.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Coming full circle, and while we&#39;re naming names, I expect the Santas Network has already been tasked with keeping a lookout for any resurgence of interest in Eeyore. &amp;nbsp;Pooh may have supplied the muscle, but Eeyore was rumored to be the real brains of the operation, and second to none when it came to sapping morale. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/PuQt9N4Dsok&quot;&gt;The life insurance industry&lt;/a&gt; pays a premium for tracking such indicators, even if Langley is more interested in Barbies (that&#39;s their prerogative), or if the UK, the more mature culture, cares more about lamp posts and wardrobes. &amp;nbsp;There&#39;s no accounting for taste sometimes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I checked Snopes before sharing these rumors on Facebook, just to let my friends know that I&#39;m aware of the False News aspects to this story. &amp;nbsp;Like I said, I&#39;m a skeptic myself. &amp;nbsp;However, some of you out there may know more than I do, and when it comes to fighting to defend freedom, better safe than sorry, right?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/31440003210/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Checking for False News&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Checking for False News&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://c3.staticflickr.com/1/560/31440003210_e5a9764d81.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/32794322140/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;SIGINT&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;SIGINT&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/3/2897/32794322140_6364386189.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8622487129712991911'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8622487129712991911'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/new-conspiracy-theories.html' title='New Conspiracy Theories'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/migu4suXvV8/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7629919327669054328</id><published>2016-12-19T11:37:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-19T11:51:16.643-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Blue House Tour</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Lets focus on the office spaces in this one.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not showing the Raspberry Pi 3 workstation in the basement because it&#39;s accessed through the local network.&amp;nbsp; No one needs to go down there to see its screen, which I may just unplug and use elsewhere.&amp;nbsp; Or not.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s usable as a temporary office as is.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Winter Office might sound like it&#39;s for winter use, and that would make sense, but I&#39;m thinking it more as the cold office that has links to the outside world.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s under the upper deck we restored.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/30939261943/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Winter Altar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Winter Altar&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://c8.staticflickr.com/1/658/30939261943_61cbf36a7f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Because the Winter Office may run at freezing temperatures, I keep it behind a closed door, running a space heater to heat the Downstairs Office (there&#39;s a whole-house furnace but in this day and age I consider running that an unnecessary luxury).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A fish tank right outside has only a small heating device, so I abet that with warmer ambient air, though on a fluctuating schedule.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/30907265034/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Downstairs Office + Fish Tank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Downstairs Office + Fish Tank&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://c3.staticflickr.com/1/371/30907265034_254dce9da1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Finally, the Upstairs Office: also with a cold blooded creature, the pet snake.&amp;nbsp; This is where I do a lot of my work.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m able to sleep there on a futon if I need to, turning my bedroom into more of a guestroom if that&#39;s desirable.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve had a few guests, from Brazil and &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/08/basement-revolutionary.html&quot;&gt;Indonesia&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The upstairs has its own restroom.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/31711486906/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Snake Habitat&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Snake Habitat&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://c3.staticflickr.com/1/607/31711486906_ec0e407a23.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Under the guest room (the Downstairs Office also doubles as a guest room), I have a large workspace equipped to share media.&amp;nbsp; People come over to watch DVDs sometimes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When the temperature is suitable, I may quit my office and work there instead.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When others come over to work on projects, a question is whether they need a computer.&amp;nbsp; In that case, the Winter Office might be a best bet, as it has a guest account already set up.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mostly I&#39;m just supplying fast Wifi, including 5G in the Upstairs and Winter Offices.&amp;nbsp; We share a smaller bandwidth channel elsewhere.&amp;nbsp; People bring their own devices (BYOD), like at a coffee shop.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/31376209920/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Gotta Have Coffee&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Gotta Have Coffee&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/636/31376209920_7f82ab5c10.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7629919327669054328'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7629919327669054328'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/blue-house-tour.html' title='Blue House Tour'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5951222464077755425</id><published>2016-12-18T10:31:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-19T17:44:59.668-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Back on that Python Train</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/31590014101/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Pythonic Vista&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Pythonic Vista&quot; height=&quot;313&quot; src=&quot;https://c6.staticflickr.com/1/341/31590014101_985a7fc1ac.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
By &quot;Python Train&quot; I mean the succession of versions, fine to come in from the top i.e. no reason to go back and learn older ones, unless you inherit responsibility for older code.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve got quite a bit of 2.x on the web, &lt;a href=&quot;http://4dsolutions.net/ocn/&quot;&gt;at Oregon Curriculum Network&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However 3.6 is out, final release candidate, with the first official non-candidate set for release on the 23rd.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve learned about formatting strings from Chris, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/TKhgl38EPPg?t=28s&quot;&gt;CTO at PDX Code Guild&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But only recently, in coming late to &lt;a href=&quot;https://eev.ee/blog/2016/07/31/python-faq-why-should-i-use-python-3/&quot;&gt;various debates&lt;/a&gt;, did I get a longer run-down of new features, which inevitably include many other less new ones I&#39;d been overlooking.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Since I&#39;m in the teaching biz and like any professional have to keep doing homework, working on updating skills with latest new wrinkles, I&#39;m taking advantage of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/12/sampling-python-tutorials.html&quot;&gt;snow days&lt;/a&gt;, with power, to bone up and stay with it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s a sense of being on a moving train here.&amp;nbsp; Time to move along.&amp;nbsp; Inertia.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We always do a Hanukkah party this time of year, though we&#39;re Quakers and all that. Great traditions. good times, great peeps. My family is all spread out.&amp;nbsp; White Christmas in Portland (actually not yet, this is in the lead up to), snow and ice both.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Of course I&#39;m thinking of Lindsey&#39;s &quot;...get on that train&quot; lyrics (and melody).&amp;nbsp; She later moved it to Spanish.&amp;nbsp; I caught &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/h923W5h3-oM&quot;&gt;a version for Youtube&lt;/a&gt; some years ago.&amp;nbsp; Merry Christmas Lindsey wherever you are. I hope we cross paths sometime in 2017.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For those of you squinting at the code above (click picture for original, bigger), yes, all &quot;clerks&quot; (what I&#39;m calling them) named &quot;sentinel&quot; or &quot;nigel&quot; or whatever, will file to the same key.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Before you throw up your hands and yell &quot;bug!&quot; or &quot;security risk!&quot; or whatever, remember a use case where we have freeway cams all along the highway.&amp;nbsp; All cams file to &quot;see it!&quot; and all users of &quot;last_seen&quot; have it in them already, no need to &quot;subscribe&quot; (you did that by naming the clerk as the others did).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The version below assumes we need to keep each value stored with its specific instance, including across types (instances serve as unique keys regardless of type).&amp;nbsp; What you need from your clerk type varies with use case; Python gives you the &quot;hooks&quot; (the places to fill in the script).&amp;nbsp; For consenting adults (one of the tag lines).&amp;nbsp; Batteries included.&amp;nbsp; Fits your brain.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The takeaway is one does need a clear head, to keep track of what &quot;self&quot; means when several classes have instanced the clerk as a class-level name.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The clerk has a window orthogonal to the type structure, or &quot;the committees&quot; one might say, is privy to what goes on across instances.&amp;nbsp; Must it keep all those instances straight?&amp;nbsp; Or is the goal to share information?&amp;nbsp; Or both?&amp;nbsp; The language is more about allowing than dictating your designs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So just remember to document clearly and tell a compelling story to future maintainers, or they&#39;ll end up rewriting it just to keep track of what&#39;s going on.&amp;nbsp; Don&#39;t just assume the code &quot;will speak for itself&quot; — to you it might, but remember the other people in the room.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/31352623520/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Clerk Objects&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Clerk Objects&quot; height=&quot;313&quot; src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/527/31352623520_4aa3ba3b71.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5951222464077755425'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5951222464077755425'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/back-on-that-python-train.html' title='Back on that Python Train'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8576012571813908968</id><published>2016-12-15T19:33:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2018-04-16T21:48:17.599-07:00</updated><title type='text'>A Tale of Two Tunnels</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/3013259991/in/photolist-pNEb73-e7i8Db-bPvict-b89Pev-azUX29-8ZoRQn-8YLin9-8DhHcJ-7iN1QW-72iA4m-6YooRg-6V6uqW-6US1xd-6TzsJT-6xA7MG-5AgKdt/&quot; title=&quot;Max on the Move&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Max on the Move&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://c8.staticflickr.com/4/3241/3013259991_054091b834.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: Max line ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When boring from both ends under the Tualitin Hills, under&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/01/wanderers-2007123.html&quot;&gt;the cemetery&lt;/a&gt; (some bodies moved), &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2016/12/wanderers-omsi.html&quot;&gt;the zoo&lt;/a&gt;, and the Rose Garden, the engineers used a combination of explosives and a tunnel-digging machine, custom designed, &lt;a href=&quot;https://maxfaqs.wordpress.com/tag/robertson-tunnel/&quot;&gt;big and expensive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The tunnelers from east and west would need to meet somewhere in between, for the Robertson Tunnel to take track, then trains, and they did, not without some delays, three cheers for getting the math right.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Max trains (in Portland, Oregon) use those tubes (one each way) day in and day out.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I get a similar vibe, of two tunnels &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/new-conspiracy-theories.html&quot;&gt;needing to meet&lt;/a&gt;, when I read the papers (understood to be &quot;pixelated papers&quot; more often than not, with moving bits — ads mostly — like &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2016/11/fantastic-beasts-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;in &lt;i&gt;Fantastic Beasts&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The tunnel from the left is looking for &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/10/bed-time-stories.html&quot;&gt;Russian spies&lt;/a&gt;, the ones capable of steering the offended egos of proud hackers and libertarians.&amp;nbsp; The tunnel from the right is maybe looking for high rolling internationalist bankers in the long run, but in the short term is hot on the trail of a ring of pedophiles.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Where these stories meet is probably where Russian spies hack in to their victims&#39; computers and plant incriminating evidence.&amp;nbsp; Didn&#39;t we hear something like that on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/TDBFcWFurfc&quot;&gt;Alex Jones channel&lt;/a&gt;? He was blaming &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/john-podesta-something-is-deeply-broken-at-the-fbi/2016/12/15/51668ab4-c303-11e6-9a51-cd56ea1c2bb7_story.html&quot;&gt;John Podesta&lt;/a&gt; as I recall.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I think &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/2016/12/10/pizzagate-explained-everything-you-want-to-know-about-the-comet-ping-pong-pizzeria-conspiracy-theory-but-are-too-afraid-to-search-for-on-reddit/&quot;&gt;the PizzaGaters&lt;/a&gt; have a point though:&amp;nbsp; if this is the topic that really most interests &lt;i&gt;that many&lt;/i&gt; readers and viewers, then the so-called mainstream media needs to go &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.snopes.com/pizzagate-conspiracy/&quot;&gt;beyond Snopes&lt;/a&gt; and really show the PizzaGaters where they&#39;ll need to defend their worldview, even as they advance it. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Saying &quot;pedophilia is real&quot; is no defense, as we just went through over a decade, more like two, of talking about the reality of pedophilia among some professional Catholics. Those stories were and are the focus of any number of mainstream stories, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/zQu3KBAMLlI&quot;&gt;talk shows&lt;/a&gt;, documentaries, exposes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We can&#39;t say the &quot;corporate media&quot; (and/or NPR) turns a blind eye to the whole phenomenon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We grownups are expected to love children, just not in a twisted sexually exploitative way.&amp;nbsp; Freud revealed (made OK to talk about) child sexuality.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The so-called &quot;unconscious&quot; is having a harder time finding places to hide in the 21st Century, given all the open secrets.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets not forget so-called &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/09/forbidden-lies.html&quot;&gt;honor killings&lt;/a&gt;, genital mutilation, and forced sterilization as concomitant causes of outrage.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Is it that the mainstream media is hoping to keep its more genteel profile and appeal &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/05/more-thoughts-on-politics.html&quot;&gt;to tea-cuppy Victorians&lt;/a&gt; by remaining aloof from the tabloid world, more lurid and sensational?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Journalists are groomed to see such &quot;entertainment news&quot; as the opposite of professional.&amp;nbsp; Academics write in knowing tones about the post-truth world, but without themselves participating in the mudslinging, getting down and dirty debating &quot;what&#39;s a proved fact and what&#39;s mere hearsay&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
PizzaGaters want to know:&amp;nbsp; does Comet Ping Pong really have a basement or not, and if it does, are there tunnels? A tour on camera with owner&#39;s consent, might&#39;ve forestalled the lone gunman showing up to &quot;self investigate&quot; on his own.&amp;nbsp; Snopes claims it&#39;s hard to find claims concrete enough to debunk, though it does keep updating its page on the topic. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But then the hero lone gunman, there to rescue the kids, was reviled as &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/CjxJVkj_IBw&quot;&gt;a crisis actor&lt;/a&gt; (just look at IMDB right? — he&#39;d done some dabbling in acting, then must&#39;ve gotten really committed). The gunman was roundly dismissed as a paid actor, by the very mob he claimed to represent (that&#39;s irony for ya).  Crisis actor theories permeate the 9-11 literature as well. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In my view, if the US president is willing to dignify the Russian spy story with a full report, due in January, then we might as well dive in to the specific allegations and collect whatever debunkings more publicly and officially, while finding what truth is to be found.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s real and what&#39;s Photoshop?&amp;nbsp; We only get this in dribs and drabs.&amp;nbsp; Partly how conspiracies gain momentum is they fill with meme viruses of questionable factoids never flagged by the true believers&#39; immune systems. They have no antibodies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s just a picture out of the blue, with an incriminating caption?&amp;nbsp; What&#39;s innuendo?&amp;nbsp; A lot of noobs won&#39;t know what that means.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Don&#39;t we have a calling to educate the young?&amp;nbsp; For that reason I&#39;ve referred PizzaGate &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/pizzagate-debate.html&quot;&gt;to the forensic societies&lt;/a&gt;, as more grist for the mill.&amp;nbsp; What constitutes a compelling argument?&amp;nbsp; Constant repetition?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The sleights of hand used to fill the echo chamber with &quot;common knowledge&quot; need to come to the light of day. Yes the Nazis used such trickery, but so does just about everybody else with a knack for PR.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets not pretend only one fighter in this ring knows how to use psychological techniques.&amp;nbsp; Wrestlers trash talk and self-promote as a part of their job description.&amp;nbsp; So do chess masters, in more subtle ways (thinking of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Chess_Championship_1972&quot;&gt;Bobby Fischer versus Boris Spassky&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If the mainstream press doesn&#39;t role up its sleeves and tackle the allegations more directly, beyond saying they&#39;re False News, then we&#39;re going to have to credit Russian intelligence for doing all the heavy lifting for us, in bringing corruption to light. Accusing them of causing the leaks, without refuting what the leaks are used to purportedly prove, only gives them more power.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The PizzaGate people already look up to Wikileaks for all the emails, which they insist are Google-verified and so on.&amp;nbsp; The technology gets respect.&amp;nbsp; Should President Donald Trump pardon Julian Assange then?&amp;nbsp; Otherwise won&#39;t it look like he&#39;s afraid to help &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2016/11/election-postmortem.html&quot;&gt;a hero in battle&lt;/a&gt; (the presidential campaign) because he&#39;s hiding something about the Russians helping? &lt;a href=&quot;http://hotair.com/archives/2016/11/16/the-latest-hot-pardon-rumor-trump-pardons-julian-assange/&quot;&gt;The debate rages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Russians are coming out heroes in this chapter, in having apparently put pedophiles on the radar of a once unaware US public, now out for blood.&amp;nbsp; Stories about pedophile priests on NPR were not enough.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m not saying this is the outcome that&#39;s fated.&amp;nbsp; I am saying that going after Russian spies while failing to pander to the mostly younger generation of &quot;investigator and researcher&quot; is going to self-fulfill a lot of prophesies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Give PizzaGate the respect it deserves, as a phenomenon, for exercise.&amp;nbsp; Then maybe we&#39;ll be ready to &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/09/revisiting-911.html&quot;&gt;revisit 9-11&lt;/a&gt;, long overdue for a more public re-examining.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Me? I voted for Hillary, mostly as a favor to President Obama, who asked me to (me and everybody eligible).&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d asked him to not start a foolish, endless war with Iran.&amp;nbsp; He obliged, attacking Libya and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rt.com/news/332109-russian-jets-isis-warlords/&quot;&gt;then Syria&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But just about anyone running for president except maybe Bernie is seen as a warmonger out here in Cascadia.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s just DC&#39;s culture, going back a couple hundred years (through Taft, McKinley and Andrew Jackson to name a few Manifest Destiny heads).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
DC as a City (&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/08/city-of-morons.html&quot;&gt;of Morons&lt;/a&gt;, with a Beltway) is the province of arms dealers in the business of showcasing and selling WMDs, and not much else they do serves to compensate.&amp;nbsp; Make peace or go down to defeat.&amp;nbsp; Right now, DC is choosing defeat, as making peace is much harder. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I see Iran as sanely &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/11/fighting-nukehead-nations.html&quot;&gt;anti-nuke weapon&lt;/a&gt; (not power) while I see nuke-heads as drunk with a phony sense of their supposed &quot;superpowers&quot;.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m sure that makes me some kind of globalist, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2016/11/thinking-globally.html&quot;&gt;and it&#39;s true&lt;/a&gt;, I believe Planet Earth is a globe (spherical) and that we have only our science fiction (which includes science) &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/07/pr-for-pl.html&quot;&gt;and PR&lt;/a&gt; (tools of persuasion) to keep our various civilizations thriving thereon, God help us.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8576012571813908968'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8576012571813908968'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/a-tale-of-two-tunnels.html' title='A Tale of Two Tunnels'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-479164882047370664</id><published>2016-12-11T11:05:00.004-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-20T19:17:24.734-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Yesterday...</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/31526303496/&quot; title=&quot;Storm Consequence&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Storm Consequence&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/674/31526303496_e605a59612.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Yesterday was post snow storm, meaning frosty winds had turned the flurries to ice, over-burdening trees, many of which dropped their branches, to the street, to the ground.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Given I had no fixed plans for Saturday, and have a long-standing interest, through AFSC etc., in how Washington (District of Columbia) imposes European-style colonial powers in the territories, I wandered by public transit to the church, ate a bagel, took some pictures, apologized to Pedro on the way out for causing a stir.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One of the agreements was no photography, but I came late and no sign was posted so blithely broke the rule. Someone had the presence to interrupt proceedings and call me out on it, and I acknowledged up front I&#39;d come late and was clueless.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, I put the camera away and made my exit, using the same bus ticket.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Indigenous migration flows of humans, somewhat mediated by weather patterns, have mixed with the waves of immigration to create a migrant farm worker ecology, with many social ills, hardly a utopia.&amp;nbsp; Now a stronger sense of nationalism is encouraging all nations to wall themselves off.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some professors of nationalism may think going to wall systems is a return to normalcy, but they&#39;re thinking more of castle ramparts, Hadrian&#39;s wall at the most.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ve never really tried fences.&amp;nbsp; Human migration patterns have always been at odds with political storytellers, or at least often have been.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The commitment to wallify becomes a new test of humanity&#39;s patience for this latest invention of some 200 nation-states, many more if we count the virtual and not-UN recognized.&amp;nbsp; The nation-state memeplex has been swept up by marketing, creating Rogue Nation this (beer brand) and Cyber Nation that (Cyberia).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Twilight zone states, such as Palestine, Tibet, Kurdistan and maybe Cascadia, all cast long shadows in the quantum foam.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, that Louisiana Purchase was really a good deal.&amp;nbsp; President Jefferson was conflicted in how he might make the nation grow like magic, on paper.&amp;nbsp; Where does the rubber meet the road?&amp;nbsp; Creating more of the USA territory was akin to creating a national bank:&amp;nbsp; smoke and mirrors.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In this case, a war in Europe led to bookkeepers &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/11/storybook-nation.html&quot;&gt;sliding Louisiana Territories&lt;/a&gt; from Spain to France, and France being really hard up for cash, given Napoleonic Wars (right?).&amp;nbsp; Selling spoils of war with Spain to immediate cash advantage, in a war against the rest of Western Europe (including Russia), seemed a shrewd move at the time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Why not sell all that land to the Americans?&amp;nbsp; France would still get a piece of the action in New World business (as would Spain).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Humans had learned to think globally and were divvying it mentally into what was theirs and their king&#39;s, with not much long term agreement, lots of bookkeeping, narrative accounts.&amp;nbsp; The time zones had not been figured out yet, nor the grid of airports with three-letter codes.&amp;nbsp; Latitude-longitude was getting a stronger grip, with the hexa-pentagon tilings of today (in computer games mostly) still esoteric.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of narrative accounts, I&#39;m looking forward to &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/12/toontown-revisited.html&quot;&gt;a lecture on Homer Davenport&lt;/a&gt;, an influential political cartoonist of his day, and horse raiser.&amp;nbsp; His imported Arabians somehow account for Mr. Ed on television.&amp;nbsp; Maybe I&#39;ll get that story straight this time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How happy are humans about wallification and fencification?&amp;nbsp; Travel and migration has always been about more than tourism.&amp;nbsp; Getting away from weapons testers is another strong motivation.&amp;nbsp; Drug wars crash lives.&amp;nbsp; Slavers seem to capitalize on owning you in exchange for getting you through some gate.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The USA is caught in the middle of this questioning as West Region especially has been known for its wilderness and wildness.&amp;nbsp; Walling in the nations will feel more like one global government than ever, but then where will all the rebels go?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dictates of biology beget rebels, dissidents, divergents, geniuses and so on.&amp;nbsp; The nations, with the cushion of virtual nations, need to not be too brittle, which sometimes happens when the logic gets overly calcified (as in skeletal).&amp;nbsp; Credibility is strained.&amp;nbsp; Look what happened to the Soviet Union.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/479164882047370664'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/479164882047370664'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/yesterday.html' title='Yesterday...'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4043664753940315224</id><published>2016-12-07T09:19:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-14T17:12:43.724-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Okinawa:  The Afterburn (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/31371152211/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;From Movie Madness&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;From Movie Madness&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://c4.staticflickr.com/6/5502/31371152211_7c009bfcae.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Males especially, as future breadwinners, need training in being fathers and fixers, flyers and foes (for self defense). The military is their school or institution for providing these things, free of charge but at a price similar to the one exacted by prison: a loss of freedom, and possible death by legal means (the state has pre-authorized you to die defending said state, just as prison guards may use lethal force).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Okinawa was such a training ground.&amp;nbsp; Lots of Japanese proto-wives to have and to hold, lots of children to share candy with, lots of B-52s to fly around and maintain.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;d go home to Ohio and Alabama all the more ready to care for their families and communities in a civilian setting, having served, and therefore skilled and deserving of honor and respect, as veterans.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The reason one needs bases far away is to absorb the dominance culture and feel the might of one&#39;s homeland.&amp;nbsp; Soldiers impress other soldiers, by ordering locals, making them accept base after base, servant ranked jobs, and all the sex trafficking that entails.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Also, no one wants to be seen by one&#39;s friends and relatives, stumbling around in a drunken state, experimenting with sex and so on.&amp;nbsp; Best to go off and do that alone, with strangers, in a forgiving environment, then maybe straighten up and fly straight once home, grateful to not be dead yet.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Okinawans did not take on this role without resistance.&amp;nbsp; Whole cave-fulls committed suicide or mercy-killed one another, having been trained since birth to equate hostile takeover with a death sentence, an instruction to self destruct.&amp;nbsp; That programming worked in many cases.&amp;nbsp; Parents euthanized their own children.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Others stumbled around in the Battle of Okinawa getting shot at, losing their people.&amp;nbsp; Many of them get interviewed for this movie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
After World War 2, Okinawa became a US military base, the Japanese military having been pushed out.&amp;nbsp; The Americanization process had started with Commander Perry, who sailed his fleet into harbor in the late 1800s and started bossing people around right away.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Japan to the north understood Americans were planning on having bases (not so much schools or resort hotels) all over and pushed back, as we know, with bases and prison camps, and comfort stations, of their own.&amp;nbsp; Korea, China and the Philippines bore the brunt of their counter-empire.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The option to have bases &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/12/at-berkeley-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;more like schools&lt;/a&gt; and resorts is always just beneath the surface.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The same Iron Mountain command structure that enslaved Okinawa has &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/03/why-we-fight-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;enslaved North America&lt;/a&gt; for many years, is striving to hold the world hostage more generally, with its nuke weapons and all that.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re to obey, not question.&amp;nbsp; However some questioning still goes on, some reminding of the locals of our democratic values (similar to Okinawan values).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A lot of Okinawans misunderstood the Nixon Era and thought &quot;reversion&quot; i.e. &quot;returning Okinawa to Japan&quot; (like what the Brits did with Hong Kong) would mean an end to the US military bases.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;d come to think that was what &quot;reversion&quot; meant.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So when Okinawa reverted, yet the bases stayed, even grew, some belief systems imploded.&amp;nbsp; Okinawans came to see themselves more as an ethnic minority people take advantage of and feel superior to.&amp;nbsp; The push back there has been more identity politics and island nationalism, not unlike in Puerto Rico. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Given all the inertia and the needs of males for dominance in situations, as expressed in their pressing need for these military bases, I&#39;m not seeing any office in the USA that&#39;s powerful enough to command otherwise.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Figurehead presidents won&#39;t phase them out, whereas &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/diplomatic-gaffs.html&quot;&gt;the Pentagon&#39;s fantasies&lt;/a&gt; of the future all depend on this network of bases, all interconnected in their own underworld.&amp;nbsp; Civilians have been stripped of any real power to stop the global dictatorship of a controlling military.&amp;nbsp; They just don&#39;t have the weapons. The whole planet seems like Okinawa in a nutshell, the prisoner of an evil genius, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2016/12/wanderers-omsi.html&quot;&gt;the Y chromosome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4043664753940315224'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4043664753940315224'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/okinawa-afterburn-movie-review.html' title='Okinawa:  The Afterburn (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7979903427896056505</id><published>2016-12-05T09:29:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2024-01-12T21:33:26.401-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Pizzagate Debate</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/30621568523/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Mississippi Pizza Club&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Mississippi Pizza Club&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://c4.staticflickr.com/6/5596/30621568523_5f3f6bb5ef.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I&#39;ve been suggesting on Facebook that high school forensic (debate) teams pick up on Pizzagate as a topic to analyze for lessons in how to structure, or not structure, a case (argument).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For those unfamiliar, a conspiracy theory developed in social media, suggesting various politicos used a code language around setting up pizza parties to &quot;secretly&quot; plan for the molestation of the under-aged.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This code language had a double burden, as the double meanings apparently had to carry the full weight of both types of logistics, as actual pizza parties (of the innocent sort) did occur, wherein participants did eat pasta, in addition to pizza, and play dominoes while digesting lots of cheese.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So when were the orgies and other decadent practices planned?&amp;nbsp; Did the same emails serve to organize two vastly different types of event in parallel?&amp;nbsp; Exactly how did these parallel worlds arise from the same coded messages and wasn&#39;t there ever confusion about which type of &quot;party&quot; was meant?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Investigators into this conspiracy and/or those performing postmortem analysis have a splendid opportunity to dive into the underworld of pedophilia, sex trafficking, the sex industry, pornography and so on, with a noble purpose.&amp;nbsp; Lets sort out what our values are, our ethics.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s not a waste of time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For many new to the politics of Humans in Universe, this underworld is eye-opening, revelatory.&amp;nbsp; If you wish to fight some aspects of what you find, it pays to know the enemy&#39;s territory.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s what any serious education must include, right — at least the opportunities?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Going back to Roman times (cite Cicero), schooling has focused on Rhetoric and the notion of a logical argument.&amp;nbsp; Many Buddhist cultures have evolved in similar fashion (cite Nagarjuna et al).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the Wild West, when one runs out of arguments, one simply reaches for one&#39;s gun (e.g. the American War in Indochina): debate is over now, we win because of our weapons.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s called winning the battle, but losing the war for hearts and minds.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Romans were just as prone as their Anglo-Euro offspring, to use their battle-hardiness as an excuse to rape and plunder.&amp;nbsp; If one is strong, why not take advantage and seize the work of others?&amp;nbsp; Some find such logic hard to resist (they&#39;re strong in body, but short on brains maybe).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How else was an able-bodied man to earn a good enough salary, if not by serving a command structure that would absolve him from guilt while indulging in what civilians call &quot;crimes&quot;?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For purposes of building a sustainable empire however, Rome needed more reason, less brawn.&amp;nbsp; This is where Christianity came in, bringing with it a lot of the more mature Greek civilization.&amp;nbsp; Rape and pillage could now be justified as &quot;converting the heathen&quot; — that breathed new life into New World conquest (the Roman emperor had become Pope by then).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/01/looking-back.html&quot;&gt;
We don&#39;t let minors vote&lt;/a&gt; in 2016 in the USA.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re expected to slave away, unpaid, on whatever XYZ homework (IVM math is firmly censored). Abuse by adults is rampant.&amp;nbsp; Not a pretty picture.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So even if the Pizzagate conspiracy is a lot of thin ice, tough to defend in the full light of day, it&#39;s a hot topic of conversation among the abused and semi-defenseless.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So why squelch it?&amp;nbsp; Why bully the kids into silence about topics that obviously concern them (e.g. pizza)? Vector the energy in a positive direction why not?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/31403272246/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;pizzagate&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;pizzagate&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; src=&quot;https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5787/31403272246_43281a128a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7979903427896056505'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7979903427896056505'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/pizzagate-debate.html' title='Pizzagate Debate'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1216769365067118537</id><published>2016-12-02T17:58:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-02T18:11:52.277-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Funny Joke</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I got this &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/02/live-from-dorkbot.html&quot;&gt;from Brenda&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; A &lt;i&gt;New Yorker&lt;/i&gt; cartoon?&amp;nbsp; She might&#39;ve made it up (she&#39;s one smart cookie), and in any case tells it better than I do.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
ET viewing Earth through ship&#39;s window: &quot;Signs of intelligent life  captain.&quot; Captain: &quot;they must be well-defended then, we&#39;d better leave!&quot;&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@thekirbster) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thekirbster/status/804866502130176000&quot;&gt;December 3, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
ET:  scratch that captain, they&#39;ve got plenty of weapons, but they&#39;re all aimed at themselves.  Unintelligent.  No danger.&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@thekirbster) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thekirbster/status/804866394223316992&quot;&gt;December 3, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1216769365067118537'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1216769365067118537'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/funny-joke.html' title='Funny Joke'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7528945666903608931</id><published>2016-12-02T11:44:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-11T09:29:38.699-08:00</updated><title type='text'>German Philosophy</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/30568068225/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Spheres III&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Spheres III&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5562/30568068225_8b34d0f604.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I&#39;ve started with the third book in the trilogy, &lt;i&gt;Foams&lt;/i&gt;, which author Peter Sloterdijk says in the introduction is OK.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m fortunate to live near a true scholar, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/03/the-global-matrix.html&quot;&gt;Glenn Stockton&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; He now owns all three in their English translations: &lt;i&gt;Bubbles&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Globes&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Foams&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve been blessed with friends who were also serious scholars in my life, Alex another (we had Szechuan food the other day, at John&#39;s Landing), and of course &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/12/wanderers-20161229.html&quot;&gt;Lindsey&lt;/a&gt;, and my mom.&amp;nbsp; At Princeton, my contemporary &lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.ithaca.edu/karafin/&quot;&gt;Brian Karafin&lt;/a&gt; opened many doors for me.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Whereas Sloterjijk is generously inclusive of Bucky Fuller in his index, I&#39;m not yet sure how much he makes of &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; as providing a toolbox of spherical metaphors, right down to the dyadic relationship of self-other and the kinds of twoness one finds in generalized concepts.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The arc of Peter&#39;s work starts with the household and village as the archetypal human collective and therefore psychological seed bed for much of our thinking.&amp;nbsp; Here is the micro-sphere or &quot;bubble&quot; of micro-economics, the &quot;hearth&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Surrounding the village was its cosmos, the biggest containing sphere or context, a &quot;globe&quot; with mediation between micro and macro spheres perhaps through a castle (a residence for temporal powers) or a church and its priests (eternity based).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The cosmos was ontologically spherical and provided a celestial cast, of angels, demons, beings beyond human.&amp;nbsp; The microcosm was contained within the macrocosm.&amp;nbsp; Both architecture and alchemy sought to harmonize these relationships.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Any sense of shared consensus sustaining the aforementioned Old World Order, which Peter anchors in European history, has since broken down.&amp;nbsp; The old cosmologies have burst asunder and we experience ourselves in diaspora, more like a foam, with no parent globe to console or contextualize.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, in his recent writings about orbiting space stations as likewise consciousness-altering, not just for their denizens, the metaphor of Spaceship Earth seems not far beneath the surface.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s a globe, a promised land, we might still agree on.&amp;nbsp; He &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/quotable-quotes.html&quot;&gt;cites McLuhan&lt;/a&gt; a lot, tracing the latter&#39;s possible indebtedness to Toynbee for some of his ideas.&amp;nbsp; But does he fully appreciate Fuller?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/connecting-dots.html&quot;&gt;kinds of twoness&lt;/a&gt;&quot; to which I referred, as &quot;in pure concepts&quot;, would be: &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the inside-outside dichotomy, the state of being contained, which more negatively is one of being imprisoned, encaged, fenced in (the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/08/hp4e-continued.html&quot;&gt;buckyball&lt;/a&gt;&quot; of 60 carbon atoms is likewise a &quot;carbon cage&quot; analogous to the &quot;carbon- or nano-tubes&quot; of the same &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/07/of-kepler-and-aristotle.html&quot;&gt;graphene&lt;/a&gt; substrate).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the twoness of polarity and axial rotation: the globe spins, the record plays, great circles and hemispheres are formed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
With the sphere comes notions of convex/concave and of spin/polarity. Given the generic growth formula &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/synergetica/synergetica2.html#top&quot;&gt;2 * P*N*N + 2&lt;/a&gt;, where P are the shape-modulating primes, N a sequence of consecutive integers (linear growth vector), we associate the first term with radial exponential growth, and the +2 with the constant presence of any axial pair.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In &lt;i&gt;Foams&lt;/i&gt;, Sloterdijk devotes a lot of attention to gas warfare, and also psychological warfare (atmospherics) and manipulation through propaganda.&amp;nbsp; Warfare turned from attacking combatants to undermining their environments.&amp;nbsp; The modern awareness of &quot;climate change&quot; owes a lot to the science of killing and/or &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/funny-joke.html&quot;&gt;&quot;neutralizing&quot; ourselves&lt;/a&gt; in large numbers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/30499407584/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF1704&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF1704&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5806/30499407584_a5faf0c79d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7528945666903608931'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7528945666903608931'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/german-philosophy.html' title='German Philosophy'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8213519313895056230</id><published>2016-12-01T00:04:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-01T00:10:40.901-08:00</updated><title type='text'>American Transcendentalism 101</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
American Transcendentalism 101:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/eP21UwVuZC&quot;&gt;https://t.co/eP21UwVuZC&lt;/a&gt; (6 minute read on Medium, no login required)&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@4DsolutionsPDX) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/4DsolutionsPDX/status/804233972955742208&quot;&gt;December 1, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Some literati and cogniscenti want a simple linear tale, nothing too parallel, with forking.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/07/quaker-roots.html&quot;&gt;As a Quaker&lt;/a&gt; though, with &quot;Beanite&quot; a parent class, I&#39;m used to forking and have no problem with Pragmatism and Transcendentalism running parallel, even unto this day and age.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8213519313895056230'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8213519313895056230'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/american-transcendentalism-101.html' title='American Transcendentalism 101'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6514512829773411284</id><published>2016-11-30T14:12:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-30T14:22:25.985-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Fighting the Nukehead Nations</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
Iran is wise to continue pressuring Pakistan to dismantle its nuclear arsenal. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/lWnWldNELk&quot;&gt;https://t.co/lWnWldNELk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@thekirbster) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thekirbster/status/804079393819660289&quot;&gt;November 30, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
Non-Aligned States, Iran a leader, want to stay pure and nuclear free. Dim-wit &quot;Nukehead Nations&quot; get no respect. Escape that circle!&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@thekirbster) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thekirbster/status/804080189143584768&quot;&gt;November 30, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
Iran is anti-nuke, people forget, &amp;amp; calls for nuke free Middle East, electrical plants OK. The weapons are what&#39;s criminal, anti-humanity.&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@thekirbster) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thekirbster/status/804083749289738240&quot;&gt;November 30, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
Cite this next time a trolling bozo questions whether Iran is anti-nuke WMD. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/EhOjlvFfsz&quot;&gt;https://t.co/EhOjlvFfsz&lt;/a&gt;  Nuke weapons are for loser states duh.&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@thekirbster) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thekirbster/status/804084456013250564&quot;&gt;November 30, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6514512829773411284'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6514512829773411284'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/11/fighting-nukehead-nations.html' title='Fighting the Nukehead Nations'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8898492811276723498</id><published>2016-11-25T22:28:00.004-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-01T00:07:37.135-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Web Components</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zfQoleQEa4w&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/e6lrUZWUxos&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6t2JRKTCYbI&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Monica is way beyond me in her depth of knowledge regarding how we&#39;re now able to define custom HTML tags, meaning components, with their own encapsulated behaviors, state and styling.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve done lots of GUI programming in my day and so &quot;widgets&quot; are not new to me, but how they&#39;re embedded in HTML + JavaScript desktop and mobile apps, using the Polymer library, is something I&#39;m interested in learning more about.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the new HTML, which structures the document per the Document Object Model (DOM), we have what&#39;s called &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.tutsplus.com/tutorials/intro-to-shadow-dom--net-34966&quot;&gt;a &quot;Shadow-DOM&quot;&lt;/a&gt; tightly coupled to specific HTML tags.&amp;nbsp; Defining web components involves stuffing little shadow DOM pockets with hidden functionality, though with the right developer tools you&#39;re free to crack in and read it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If a website comes from a server it more than likely is talking to a server, that goes for phone apps as well. There&#39;s nothing open source about most websites other than the fact the tools to build them are open. Developers have made it easy to develop black boxes.&amp;nbsp; That was never going to go away.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However by training on a lot of the same tools, we learn to hop around among the boxes, contributing within each, bringing the lessons from one to another.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Monica is a fantastic teacher and speaker.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8898492811276723498'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8898492811276723498'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/11/web-components.html' title='Web Components'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/zfQoleQEa4w/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8710131274352362390</id><published>2016-11-23T19:25:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2020-07-21T08:42:22.813-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2016.11.23</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/31168770706&quot; title=&quot;On R-Pi 3 over VPN&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;On R-Pi 3 over VPN&quot; height=&quot;313&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/5826/31168770706_212bc8ed29.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
:: &lt;i&gt;working through JavaScript challenges&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;using a Nodeschool Workshopper script &lt;/i&gt;::&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Naming this group Wanderers owes much to a saying of Mandelbrot&#39;s, the fractal guy (I met him, gave an opening talk before an elite audience at PSU, before he came on as the main event).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Here&#39;s that quote we use for a tagline:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&quot;Science would be ruined if it were to withdraw entirely into narrowly&lt;br /&gt;
defined specialties. The rare scholars who are Wanderers-by-choice are&lt;br /&gt;
essential to the intellectual welfare of the settled disciplines.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
(Benoit Mandelbrot)&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I&#39;d say we&#39;re also name that because our conversation follows a pattern I first noticed from the backseat for a car of the floor of a living room:&amp;nbsp; none to speak of.&amp;nbsp; Or rather, themes may develop and cycled round to, but a lot of what goes on around a dinner table, say, is &quot;rambling&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I rambled in late, having overslept.&amp;nbsp; Several topics had already been broached, obviously.&amp;nbsp; While I was there the conversation turned to airport security dogs, species of rat used to sniff out land mines, bomb and drug sniffing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What occurred to me later is how we&#39;d ventured into a mainline theme around Thanksgiving in the US, a national holiday associated with traveling.&amp;nbsp; Chinese have those too.&amp;nbsp; The trains, not just the planes or the buses, feel the added weight and responsibility, given so many travelers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m fine with the hypothesis that group dynamics exhibit replicable phenomena. &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/05/twenty-one-guns.html&quot;&gt;Nick Consoletti&lt;/a&gt; did his doctoral dissertation on &quot;Bohmian dialog&quot; and had hoped to attend a class led by Dr. Bohm himself at Schumacher College in England.&amp;nbsp; Nick did his thesis work in Eugene, starting a Bohmian dialog group himself and making recordings (with permission of the participants).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Bohm&#39;s theory was conversational fields could be established that wandered within constraints and actually produced useful results when no individual nor even faction could for long control the flow.&amp;nbsp; Think of a focus group without a focus.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s what Wanderers sometimes achieves.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What I also hadn&#39;t realized, at least consciously, as Barbara had brought the dog she cares for sometimes, to the Linus Pauling House (our venue).&amp;nbsp; Our conversation centered on responsibly employed non-humans who serve us loyally, without our non-human guest saying a word.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Much of the rest of the day was code school business, talking with one about an offer, advising another taking a JavaScript-only (mostly) tack.&amp;nbsp; One needs to say &quot;mostly&quot; as all these languages negotiate within an ecosystem of other languages.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks to Nathaniel Bobbitt I was able to learn about Nodeschools and their &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodeschool.io/index.html#workshopper-list&quot;&gt;Workshopper technology&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m plowing through some of those.&amp;nbsp; Note how they&#39;ve been done in many human languages.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2014/07/i18n.html&quot;&gt; i18n&lt;/a&gt; is one of my themes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;CBS News&lt;/i&gt; tonight was very much about the nation&#39;s transportation arteries, especially around WDC, site of many a monument, including the one to Lincoln, the last story&#39;s focus.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m likely to join the throng, hoping for a lull on Black Friday, when a family branch has strategically staged their Thanksgiving dinner meetup.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve already made some pies, and dented one of them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m running the Node modules, downloading through NPM, on my Raspberry Pi 3 in the basement.&amp;nbsp; I used to visit the basement to use the R-Pi 3, but now I just VPN into it, and use the UI in a window from anywhere in the school (a home school hybrid, as allowed by law). &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/30836580880/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Installing javascripting: a Workshopper module&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Installing javascripting: a Workshopper module&quot; height=&quot;313&quot; src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5810/30836580880_bffb8e13ed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: R-Pi from Mac Air over school LAN ::
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8710131274352362390'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8710131274352362390'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/11/wanderers-20161123.html' title='Wanderers 2016.11.23'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2338601677190293427</id><published>2016-11-19T00:42:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2020-09-12T20:31:27.976-07:00</updated><title type='text'>ISEPP Lectures Kickoff (2016-2017)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157675484204600&quot; title=&quot;ISEPP: Moral Arc&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/5830/31068964776_70551d7fa6_w.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;ISEPP: Moral Arc&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
The formal name for this lecture series is the Linus Pauling Memorial Lectures, organized by Terry Bristol&#39;s ISEPP (I used to serve on his board, and before that my partner Dawn was his bookkeeper). Tonight was the first lecture this season.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s had &lt;a href=&quot;http://isepp.org/&quot;&gt;an historic lineup&lt;/a&gt; of MVP (most valuable player) speakers, tonight&#39;s speaker being no exception.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Michael Shermer has made a name for himself around &lt;a href=&quot;http://skeptic.com/&quot;&gt;Skeptic.com&lt;/a&gt; and as a columnist for &lt;i&gt;Scientific American&lt;/i&gt;. Other Wanderers besides me have had him on radar more than I, especially Glenn and Christine (and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2015/05/engineering-as-moral-enterprise.html&quot;&gt;of course Terry&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;nbsp; Dr. DiNucci was there as well, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/10/libyan-eclipse.html&quot;&gt;the Buxtons&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/10/psychiatry-today.html&quot;&gt;Joe Arnold&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; I learned a great deal about the &quot;Eclipse Economy&quot; that&#39;s sweeping a sometimes reluctant-to-care central Oregon.&amp;nbsp; August 21.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The lecture was perfect for the occasion, relaunching the lecture series, and right after a contentious US presidential election.&amp;nbsp; His message is similar to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Steven-Pinker/e/B000AQ3GGO/ref=dp_byline_cont_ebooks_1&quot;&gt;Steven Pinker&#39;s&lt;/a&gt;:&amp;nbsp; objectively, many global trends are positive, in terms of less slavery, torture, outright war, more animal rights, more rational problem solving.&amp;nbsp; The lecture hall was comfortably full, with many in the balcony pews.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Saying yesteryear&#39;s kings and queens had low living standards compared to those of us with air conditioning, central heating, refrigerators, was like a direct quote from Bucky (music to my ears in other words).&amp;nbsp; &quot;Accentuating the positive&quot; remains a high calling, whereas evolution seems to predispose us to focus on the negative.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Given my recent immersion in Jungianism as filtered through &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2016/10/mystics.html&quot;&gt;Russian mysticism&lt;/a&gt;, in the form of the four volumes I purchased by Maurice Nicoll, I was quite open to hearing about how negative emotions tend to drive the action.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re at the mercy of &quot;monkey mind&quot;.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s how science and rational design patterns help us grow and mature as a species: we overcome mere reflex-conditioning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He&#39;s not worried about overpopulation.&amp;nbsp; The only terrorists he&#39;s really worried about are the ones who want to be dead, and think taking us all to kingdom come would be a best course of action.&amp;nbsp; He sees more hope for those wanting to make course corrections as democracies are on the rise and he has charts and statistics to argue that&#39;s a good thing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Shermer was brave and bold with his content, mocking the ethics of ages past.&amp;nbsp; &quot;What were they thinking?&quot; is his implied caption to many a grim scene, from Medieval torture chambers to more recent lynchings.&amp;nbsp; Mom reminded me later, when I briefed her on the lecture, that Eleanor Roosevelt was dead set against lynchings but FDR was mindful of wanting to keep the southern Democrats in his camp, a balancing act.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Michael is not shy about reminding us that when it comes to committing atrocities, no one holds a candle to certain Christians. Lets remember the Hitler Holocaust for what it was, a culmination of long-running trends.&amp;nbsp; But then he shows that acts of genocide in general are going down.&amp;nbsp; Lets not pretend ISIS invented beheading.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of beheading, in keeping with his French Enlightenment spin, he advertised the guillotine as maybe the most humane of the capital punishment devices. At least it&#39;s fast and efficient. Certainly &quot;old sparky&quot; is not withstanding the test of time.&amp;nbsp; He thinks our ugliest practices are on the wane.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s what his new book is about, &lt;i&gt;The Moral Arc&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At the dinner afterward, to which I was cordially invited, Glenn and I had a whole table to ourselves.&amp;nbsp; I wandered around snapping pictures, discarding most of them (not the best light), and enjoying the catered repast, certainly world class.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The downstairs area of the First Congregationalist Church is perfect, as is the upstairs meeting space.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;How is this not a religion?&quot; would have been the pithier version of my question, but meant inclusively, as Shermer was certainly seeing the great religions as masterful in their ability to adapt.&amp;nbsp; He expects most of them will survive the Darwinian process, and as I often put it, the best religions are yet to come. Dr. DiNucci had just attended a church that meets weekly for singing and sermons, but with no talk of the supernatural encouraged.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
During dinner, a butter aficionado visited our table wondering if he could take some of the butter balls.&amp;nbsp; He returned for the rest of them later, saying his objective blood test data showed he could neutralize bad effects of carbs with plenty of butter.&amp;nbsp; He enjoyed fatty breakfasts based on similar reasoning.&amp;nbsp; We agreed this might be a personal quirk of his own biology.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re not all created equal when it comes to the details of our metabolism. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2338601677190293427'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2338601677190293427'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/11/isepp-lectures-kickoff-2016-2017.html' title='ISEPP Lectures Kickoff (2016-2017)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2525770363107092107</id><published>2016-11-16T13:33:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-16T14:06:30.945-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Downloaded (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/30967779765/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF1323&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF1323&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5754/30967779765_31bb7c72ea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Historians will appreciate this quality anthropology.&amp;nbsp; Two cultures clash:&amp;nbsp; hackers with Hollywood, with the Feds hauled in to mediate through their Congressional and Court system.&amp;nbsp; The executive branch was also involved, leading to FBI warnings next to all these copyrights.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As Bucky Fuller points out, making money means keeping supplies of something scarce. Sometimes the floodgates burst, as happened in the case of Napster.&amp;nbsp; The paywall broke down.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The hackers were young and assumed adults in charge would have an optimized response to their disruptive technology.&amp;nbsp; A positive synergy would be discovered in short order.&amp;nbsp; On the contrary, the generation aging out was defenseless and had no choice but to go on the offensive, to save its way of life.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fast forward to 2016 and the infinite copiability of digital assets is akin to the power of DNA to reproduce.&amp;nbsp; Any reproductively active adults are capable or creating new billion dollar humans (applying a government published statistic).&amp;nbsp; Imagine having to buy your factory-made children and all the hoops they&#39;d want to put you through.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some musicians were overjoyed to see that, along with pornography, the new telecommunications technology was quickly harnessed to channel them.&amp;nbsp; People wanted their music, more than anything.&amp;nbsp; Facebook would come later.&amp;nbsp; Other musicians understood their incomes were in the hands of an unprepared music industry and joined in the battle to shut Napster down.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d just hosted an after-Wanderers party, pumpkin pie served, and had at least one after-party viewer crashing on the couch.&amp;nbsp; I may have misunderstood that I was seeing a lot of the same people over time, mistaking the older versions of X and Y, for new talking heads.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, that mistake is in keeping with the moral of the tale, which is never mind how fast the technology is changing, humans are able to reprogram themselves at a relatively finite rate.&amp;nbsp; More than one generation is needed to implement the adaptations.&amp;nbsp; The pioneers get to hit the proverbial &quot;brick wall&quot; or whatever it is that cannot abide change.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The whole topic of file sharing is too big to handle except in the abstract, in principle, whereas in reality we have special cases, such as hackers versus Hollywood.&amp;nbsp; The makers of this documentary understand they&#39;re exploring some deeper issues with even wider ramifications than an overhaul of the Hollywood music industry.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I go back to Hillsboro Police Department, here in the Silicon Forest (this Hillsboro is a township west of Beaverton).&amp;nbsp; Chamber of Commerce types were prodding public schools into yoking police into coming into classrooms and scaring the kids about the anti-capitalist practice of &quot;pirating&quot; (you could go to jail, and bring disgrace to your family).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The police were not dummies though and understood a new Free and Open Source culture was inspiring hopeful hackers to share their talents freely, using GNU / GPL and other innovative legal licenses.&amp;nbsp; Instead of just scaring the kids and criminalizing their natural tendencies, why not show them a better way?&amp;nbsp; HPD actually started its own Linux Lab as an after school opportunity, myself one of the instructors.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/30922121531/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Rage Against the Machine&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Rage Against the Machine&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://c4.staticflickr.com/6/5824/30922121531_0f27fc652c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2525770363107092107'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2525770363107092107'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/11/downloaded-movie-review.html' title='Downloaded (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>