<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1051'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1026&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1076&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1051</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-430977595867449869</id><published>2010-07-04T18:29:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-07-04T18:32:34.900-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Indie Day</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4762537390/&quot; title=&quot;Indie Day by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4119/4762537390_e5cfcd8f91.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;449&quot; alt=&quot;Indie Day&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;306&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/fdKTHL0PMGw&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/fdKTHL0PMGw&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;306&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot; style=&quot;font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Americana&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/430977595867449869/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/430977595867449869' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/430977595867449869'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/430977595867449869'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/07/indie-day.html' title='Indie Day'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4119/4762537390_e5cfcd8f91_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4754674627703463675</id><published>2010-06-29T18:18:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-07-01T10:50:14.281-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Disaster Zone</title><content type='html'>At the time of the great flooding of New Orleans, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/tillamook.html&quot;&gt;I wrote about Tillamook&lt;/a&gt; in an idyllic Oregon setting.  This might have seemed far removed from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/levee-town.html&quot;&gt;devastation in the Gulf&lt;/a&gt;, soon to be followed by hurricane Rita, hitting Texas, and the BP hemorrhage.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;With all these past and looming natural disasters, plus BP&#39;s, you might wonder why humans also inflict disaster upon themselves.  Could any species be this dysfunctional and survive?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Oregon is facing its own day of reckoning.  A subduction earthquake, hitting about 9 on the Richter scale, is expected off the coast, based on previous patterns.  Some planning (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crew.org/PDFs/CREWSubductionZoneSmall.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;) has occurred (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/06/asian-scholar-visits.html&quot;&gt;Alan Potkin&lt;/a&gt; could advance the art). &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Were we to live more lightly on the Earth, per aerospace ecovillage scenarios (ala Project Earthala), we could get off with less loss. We wallow in a dark age though, postponing engineering maturity.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;My thanks to Glenn for updating me on some of the math future buzz.  He also brought by the right crimping tool and workspace light, and supervised while I replaced &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/06/conspiracies.html&quot;&gt;the heating element&lt;/a&gt; in my oven, pretty much in an apprentice role.  The part itself was hard to find.  I credit the hard worker at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wlmay.com/&quot;&gt;W.L. May&lt;/a&gt; for pinpointing something in stock.  She&#39;s a genius (seriously: it&#39;s an old Magic Chef in a retro style kitchen, hard to find parts).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4754674627703463675'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4754674627703463675'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/06/disaster-zone.html' title='Disaster Zone'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6501027333132315083</id><published>2010-06-28T20:33:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-11-28T07:16:56.172-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Mortality Again</title><content type='html'>Losing all of ones personal files off a laptop may be a serious psychological blow.  Retreating to the &lt;i&gt;est&lt;/i&gt; model of 1s, 2s and 3s, this definitely triggers a 1.  That model was ridiculously stark and austere by the way, like the training itself.  &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;m crying inside about some of what I&#39;ve lost.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I am grateful for my life and the people in it.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Loss is an occasion for suffering which is a manifestation of love.  Attachments are not bad, just potentially painful.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Losing my dad so suddenly on October 13, 2000, was very hard.  I flew to Lesotho to close out the estate.  Mom was in the hospital in Bloemfontaine and not expected to live.  She helped me manage from her hospital bed, so many bones broken. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I am proud of myself for holding it together under duress, could not have done so without my community.  Eugene Norcross-Renner offered to accompany me, an offer that touched me deeply even though I ended up going alone.  Gayle helped me get a plane ticket on short order.  Dawn kept things running for the month I was gone.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Annis and George Bleeke, who were planning to visit for Annual Session, which my parents were organizing, came to this tragic scene and helped me organize the estate sale and off-load a lot of stuff (I shipped other stuff back to here).  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I am proud of my sister for flying out to take over nursing mom back to where she could travel.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Losing my wife Dawn to breast cancer was also all about community, for both of us.  She prayed her death would be a healing.  She lived bravely and brought joy to many.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Someday I will need to surrender this body.  Like many who contemplate their own passing, I don&#39;t want to leave a lot of hassles and loose ends.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;d like my love to live on, my gratitude to my community.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Thinking also of Ed Applewhite, George Hammond, John Talmadge, and Elise Boulding.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6501027333132315083'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6501027333132315083'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/06/mortality-again.html' title='Mortality Again'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1204008354282385034</id><published>2010-06-23T21:28:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-07-14T11:15:18.003-07:00</updated><title type='text'>End the Qyooban Embargo!</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
For quite awhile now, I&#39;ve been using the word &quot;Qyoob&quot; to parody the word &quot;Cube&quot;. &quot;Qyoob&quot; has a kind of Persian or  Arabian Nights look and feel (Al Qyoob), which creates some  valuable artistic distance for some readers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Looking back at the  Euro cultures, we see &quot;four square&quot; and such inter-twining  attributes as &quot;upright&quot; &quot;normal&quot; &quot;orthodox&quot; and &quot;upstanding&quot; -- not  to mention &quot;regular guy&quot; and &quot;square deal&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sound  familiar?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Remember, the &quot;beatniks&quot; didn&#39;t want to be  &quot;squares&quot; in an age of hyper-dimensional &quot;cubism&quot; -- were perhaps prototypical of the &quot;buckaneers&quot; in that way.[0]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;So what?&quot;  you ask, &quot;what has any of this to do with &lt;i&gt; Philosophical  Investigations&lt;/i&gt;?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Well, when undertaking a philosophical  investigation, in the Wittgensteinian tradition, it pays to take in the lay of the land, to map out the surrounding grammar.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Connotations  matter, not just denotations.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The goal, to fight the  bewitchment of our intelligence by means of grammar, will be more  effectively reached if we&#39;ve actually done some homework.[1]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
To  get how these key vocabulary words weave their meanings, one  actually needs to study them in action, not just assume one  &quot;already knows&quot; as a kind of gedanken experiment.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
To  assume one &quot;already knows&quot; is to bleep over the whole point of  Wittgenstein&#39;s philosophy, which is to get you to actually investigate, not take &quot;it&quot; -- whatever meaning -- for granted.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Back to Al Qyoob: the prevailing caliphate starts drilling children early on to think of &quot;squaring&quot; and &quot;cubing&quot; as mathematical equivalents of &quot;2nd powering&quot; and &quot;3rd powering&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some rather subtle mathematics inheres in this difference twixt saying &quot;squared&quot; and &quot;to the second power&quot;, as the former presumes a shape, whereas the latter leaves the door open to different  shapes, such as a triangle -- or a tetrahedron in the case of 3rd  powering. [2]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My recent essay &lt;i&gt;Aristotle was Right!&lt;/i&gt; is an  opening salvo from the newest NeoPlatonists, one might say, as it challenges philosophers to revisit their ancient ties to the  Polyhedra (and their inter-relationships).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Geometrical thinking is a primitive form of logical reasoning.[3]  Before we  had modal logic or a theory of logical types (ala Russell), we had  the golden ratio, vesica pices, and the accepted methods of  construction and proof.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Architecture was accomplished by these processes. Real work got done.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The story going  forward, starting from Aristotle&#39;s claim that pyramids fill space  (dismissed as bogus in superficial treatments), wends its way to  recent times, to the geometrical explorations of a lone geometer named Sommerville.[4]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sommerville circles a certain tri-rectangular tetrahedron as the simplest candidate that follows  some specific rules in his mathematical language game, namely that:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
(a) to count as &quot;space filling&quot;, the tetrahedra must face bond (as is typical in such studies) and&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
(b) the  space-fillers in question must &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; rely on mirror images of one  another (i.e. sometimes a left and a right fill space, but not  something alone).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Said tri-rectangular tetrahedron is found  in &lt;i&gt;Regular Polytopes&lt;/i&gt; by Coxeter (Wittgenstein&#39;s student, contributor of a venue for the &lt;i&gt;Blue / Brown Book&lt;/i&gt; notes I think it  was), where it is referenced by page number from our NeoPlatonist work. [5]  There it is dubbed the Mite, or Minimum Tetrahedron, because of its space-filling role (no need of mirrors -- nor smoke  for that matter).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In this referring work (dedicated to  H.S.M. &quot;King of Infinite Space&quot; Coxeter), said Sommerville shape is in turn dissected, into the two As and 1 B particle, also described and depicted by Robert Williams in his groundbreaking  work &lt;i&gt;The Geometrical Foundation of Natural Structure&lt;/i&gt;. [6]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Qyoobans have been embargoing this information (hence the term  &quot;Qyooban Embargo&quot;), as evidenced by Math World, which on the page  about space-filling polyhedra pointedly eschews mentioning any of  the tetrahedra meeting Sommerville&#39;s rules.[7]  These would be the Mite and two Sytes in current parlance, a tetragonal disphenoid (Rite) and another one (Bite), all three illustrated in the chart by Guy Inchbald.[8]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Furthermore, the Qyoobans  censor and/or forbid sharing about the alternative model of 3rd  powering, whereby said Mite and Sytes have volume 1/8 and 1/4  respectively, vis-a-vis a cube of volume 3 (no longer unity).  Their public school systems deny their own citizens access to this heritage.  Write to Congress?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Having their beloved Qyoob (a hexahedron) booted from His Eternal Throne is tantamount to heresy for them, hence the Embargo or Boycott, easy to document for the history books.  The sense of entitlement among these Qyoobans (not to be confused with Cubans) is legendary.  Talk about road hogs!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Those philosophers paying any attention to this little tempest in a teapot (not!), are probably aware that the dike is breaking, and that Qyooban philosophers are soon to be held accountable for their intentional and insistent dumbing down of our common heritage (logic).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Their overly high price tags may be questioned, even as their bigoted and ethnocentric behaviors fall into disrepute.  All math is ethno-math.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m  thinking Wittgenstein&#39;s philo will come out smelling like roses though.  His investigatory style has proved a real asset.  Hooray for the linguistic turn.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
To summarize:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you want the benefit of a liberating gestalt or enlightenment (as the  fly escapes the fly bottle), then you&#39;ll need to find all those pesky little strings the Lilliputians have used, to tie down their  Gulliver (our hero), to trap him with their small-minded meanings.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Snip snip&quot; go the Philosopher&#39;s Scissors (similar to Occam&#39;s Razor).  Don&#39;t let those lab-coated Qyoobans nab you in their straitjacketed way of thinking.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Qyoobism tends to be overly-confining, awkwardly unimaginative, some say a symptom of its insecurity in its logico-authoritative role (arrogated).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Cubes are unstable unless triangulated, as any honest architect-engineer will tell ya.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets end the  Qyooban Embargo.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Notes:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[0]   Of beatniks vs. squares, also buckaneers:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=D&amp;amp;q=http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/07/mining-cartoons.html&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGitfxsx9ot7U0ehhHkX2WhOvqHpQ&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/07/mining-cartoons.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=D&amp;amp;q=http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/08/buckaneers.html&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGYW13XasyKhUciNuoCSMMqZCYIuA&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/08/buckaneers.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[1]  from a recent journal post:&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;&quot;&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
Lots of  comparing notes occurs among the spin doctors, with secondary sources echoing primary ones in disseminating the latest bewitchments (the great Austrian philosopher Ludwig Wittgenstein used this term &quot;bewitch&quot; in a technical sense, in the context of  investigating the hypnotic powers of &quot;language games&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;&quot;&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=D&amp;amp;q=http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/06/supporting-troops.html&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGP-lZ7n3jAJkxivrT5my5NPvb7ng&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/06/supporting-troops.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[2]  &quot;Triangling and Tetrahedroning&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=D&amp;amp;q=http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/synergetics/s09/figs/f9001.html&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEjHjofSBmXx1PFJcceYVg9maouOg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/synergetics/s09/figs/f9001.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[3] &lt;i&gt;Aristotle was Right!&lt;/i&gt; (remember the Mite)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=D&amp;amp;q=http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa%3FthreadID%3D2084375%26tstart%3D0&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHn0lBnFcFa36hgdMeZo-oziW673w&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=2084375&amp;amp;tstart=0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[4]   D. M. Y. Sommerville (1879-1934), see:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Which  Tetrahedra Fill Space?&lt;/i&gt; by Marjorie Senechal, Mathematics Magazine,  Vol. 54, No. 5 (Nov., 1981), pp. 227-243.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[5] One of several  portals to said Neoplatonist philo:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=D&amp;amp;q=http://grunch.net/&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGAC3f3OoP_QJdrvAR5W3BSlSFcLA&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://grunch.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[6]  He changes the meaning of B-particle from its original source, but is otherwise on target:&lt;br /&gt;
R. Williams, &lt;i&gt;The  Geometrical Foundation of Natural Structure&lt;/i&gt;, Dover, New York  (1976), see footnote 20 on pg. 136.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[7]  No mention of Mites  or Sytes (as of June 23, 2010):&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=D&amp;amp;q=http://mathworld.wolfram.com/Space-FillingPolyhedron.html&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGa-zonBXx5b9CS6pcKKsNBzf2hmQ&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/Space-FillingPolyhedron.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[8] &lt;i&gt;The Archimedean honeycomb duals&lt;/i&gt; by Guy Inchbald, The Mathematical Gazette 81, July 1997, p.p. 213-219.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=D&amp;amp;q=http://www.steelpillow.com/polyhedra/AHD/AHD.htm&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHnSkfxWOpvKnrJ2ary_M8cIRVw4g&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.steelpillow.com/polyhedra/AHD/AHD.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Kirby Urner is a RadMath teacher living in Portland,  Oregon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
==========================================&lt;br /&gt;
Need  Something? Check here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=D&amp;amp;q=http://ludwig.squarespace.com/wittrslinks/&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHGWaxJL2uoob0drpD20UrLDaiSmQ&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://ludwig.squarespace.com/wittrslinks/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/1204008354282385034/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/1204008354282385034' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1204008354282385034'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1204008354282385034'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/06/end-qyooban-embargo.html' title='End the Qyooban Embargo!'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8793587515501235491</id><published>2010-06-19T23:47:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2015-06-09T14:48:21.444-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers Summer Retreat</title><content type='html'>We&#39;re packed around the table again.  Lots of plastic.  Our Blue House ethics have shifted against plastic, which doesn&#39;t mean we don&#39;t have any.  I went to the supermarket, determined not to get anything with plastic in the packaging (I got glass, cardboard and metal).  I paid with plastic.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
This is potluck time, so some of the plastic contains food.  Tara joined us.  She&#39;s booted into the wifi with my old laptop.  She&#39;s at the table, I&#39;m on the steps.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
For those just joining us, this is the boyhood home of Linus Pauling, one of Oregon&#39;s favorite sons. He received two (unshared) Nobel Prizes, although the one for peace you could say goes to Ava Helen as well.  Their papers are collected at Oregon State University.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Our patron and sponsor, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/09/wanderers-200597.html&quot;&gt;Doug Strain&lt;/a&gt;, helped endow the reading room, as well as restore this magnificent old home.  Doug co-founded &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/planting-seeds-in-silicon-forest.html&quot;&gt;Electro-Scientific Industries&lt;/a&gt;, which also supplied a facility to Quakers in the late 1950s, where they practice their faith to this day, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/01/launching-mother-ship.html&quot;&gt;two remodels later&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Our group, called Wanderers, gets its name from (a) the ancient Greek word for &quot;planets&quot; (they wander the sky, especially in a geocentric coordinate system -- simpler spirals if you look from a heliocentric point of view) and (b) a quote by Mandelbrot that goes like this:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Science would be ruined if it were to withdraw entirely into narrowly defined specialties. The rare scholars who are wanderers-by-choice are essential to the intellectual welfare of the settled disciplines.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
-- Benoit Mandelbrot&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot; style=&quot;font-family: Georgia; font-size: 12px; line-height: 14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fractalwisdom.com/FractalWisdom/fractal.html&quot; style=&quot;color: #333333; font-family: Georgia, Times, serif; font-size: 12px; text-decoration: none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
We&#39;re looking at close up pictures of Mars on the Web, mostly gray scale.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/12/wanderers-20061212.html&quot;&gt;Gus Frederick of Silverton&lt;/a&gt; is a Mars nut, actually a good presenter on an interesting topic.  This isn&#39;t about Martian Math so much, which is something I write about.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Carol is home prepping for her next journey.  She lost some pills, I lost some money.  Our &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/03/campus-household.html&quot;&gt;exchange student&lt;/a&gt; (per Census interview) is out and about.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Some traffic on PSF channel today;  another Synergetics boot camp on &lt;i&gt;Synergeo &lt;/i&gt; (ongoing). &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Art Kohn and I spoke at some length in the alcove (near the food table), about family matters, about image processing and the Hubble space telescope.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
This latter topic led Art to recommend &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mcadams.posc.mu.edu/parnell/sl2.htm&quot;&gt;Case Closed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gerald_Posner&quot;&gt;Gerald Posner&lt;/a&gt;, laying to rest &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/05/cold-war-operations.html&quot;&gt;all those conspiracy theories&lt;/a&gt; around the assassination of JFK.  The computer-stabilized version of the Zapruder film helps clarify the single bullet theory.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Jon Bunce and Don Wardwell sang an old Woody Guthrie song &lt;i&gt;Pastures of Plenty&lt;/i&gt;.  Jon and I then yakked about Subgenius literature, the bleeding head of Arnold Palmer in particular.  We&#39;re an eclectic group, so pretty open to a wide range of topics.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Best wishes to Dr. Tag.  I mentioned our internationalization work on the PSF list again.  Not every Python-related chat room uses Latin-1 after all.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
I started screening the first of &lt;a href=&quot;http://dimensions-math.org/Dim_reg_AM.htm&quot;&gt;a series on spatial geometry&lt;/a&gt; that&#39;s been showing on Portland community access TV, after screening &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vzYu88jIDYs&quot;&gt;O Superman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vzYu88jIDYs&quot;&gt; by Laurie Anderson&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
After a just few minutes into the polyhedra, Don and I heard yelling and cheering so went outside to see what was happening.  A large number of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldnakedbikeride.org/&quot;&gt;naked and/or partially clad cyclists&lt;/a&gt; (skateboarders, roller skaters, unicyclists) were turning onto Hawthorne, protesting exposure to exhaust fumes, other machine world insults and indecencies.  The procession was over a mile long, maybe longer.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8793587515501235491'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8793587515501235491'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/06/wanderers-summer-retreat.html' title='Wanderers Summer Retreat'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8697844106699635661</id><published>2010-06-18T23:14:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-06-18T23:32:48.926-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Git Mo Stupid</title><content type='html'>&quot;Too stupid to close Gitmo&quot; was the verdict, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/lame-analysis.html&quot;&gt;last time we checked the score&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It&#39;s mighty hard to put any faith in those &quot;counter-terrorist&quot; twits after seeing their bogus blog posts in defense of that operation, an embarrassment for [what little remains of] &quot;intelligence&quot; in those circles.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;No career path to an elite inner circle by that route apparently.  Just cruft on the c.v., might as well say &quot;unemployable&quot;.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;m not blaming the White House though, even back to Bush, who wanted it closed too.   Few people know that, as they can&#39;t believe presidents get lied to (&lt;i&gt;especially&lt;/i&gt; presidents).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This defying of presidents is what &quot;the woodwork&quot; is good at (the so-called spineless bureaucracy -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/01/other-news-blips.html&quot;&gt;aka &quot;banana republic&quot;&lt;/a&gt; -- which hides behind anonymity, posing as patriotic).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;USAers don&#39;t seem to understand how &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/03/stress-tests.html&quot;&gt;their credit rating&lt;/a&gt; so much depended on what they might offer the future.  Overlooking the debt was easier when the policies made some sense.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/power-of-nightmares-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Endless &quot;war on terror&quot;&lt;/a&gt; is wearing thin, especially when there&#39;s so much positive futurism waiting in the wings, on hold while the world sits through this tortuous little stage number.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;At least we&#39;re making some headway &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/09/paved-over-past.html&quot;&gt;on the voting machines&lt;/a&gt; and attendant infrastructure.  If they&#39;re not NSA approved, then we know they&#39;re unworthy.  Or did I get that backwards?  Good to see &lt;i&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/i&gt; is on top of it, vigilant as ever.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Any truth in the rumor that the Pentagon wants to commandeer Gitmo as a HQS to monitor&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/oil-spill.html&quot;&gt; the oil bleed&lt;/a&gt;?  Certain BP executives might need to be watched, asked a few questions.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8697844106699635661'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8697844106699635661'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/06/git-mo-stupid.html' title='Git Mo Stupid'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6426112856541976440</id><published>2010-06-16T19:57:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-06-17T16:29:15.203-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Bruno (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/11/borat-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;As with &lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/11/borat-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Borat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, the comic index of this film depends a lot on the viewer&#39;s assumptions about how scripted it is, i.e. which characters know this is a spoof and which do not?&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The DVD version, which my daughter inherited from somewhere, has the movie with commentary, and that clears up some questions.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;However, given Sasha is good at fooling people, how much of the commentary are we to believe in turn? Was Harrison Ford really &quot;in on it&quot;?  Perhaps not.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;m reminded of Werner Herzog&#39;s commentary regarding &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/01/fitzcarraldo-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;the filming of &lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/01/fitzcarraldo-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Fitzcarraldo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.  I took that as a spoof as well, in cahoots with his cast, the film savvy, Mick Jagger, Jason Robard and friends.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I viewed &lt;i&gt;Bruno&lt;/i&gt; (twice, once with commentary) with a gay rights activist and community organizer, who thought, as I do, that Sasha is brilliantly brave, and knows how to do poignant social commentary.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;Borat&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Bruno&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/05/incompleteness.html&quot;&gt;Ali G&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; represent a new form of cultural anthropology, wherein the anthropologist learns enough about a culture to offend, enrage, excite and otherwise perturb it. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This is the opposite of trying to stay out of the limelight while taking notes.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I found myself reminiscing about &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/12/team-america-world-police-movie-review_04.html&quot;&gt;Team America:  World Police&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; after it was over, a likewise penetrating spelunking exercise within &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/60578&quot;&gt;the collective unconscious&lt;/a&gt;.  Talk about &quot;special operations&quot;!&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6426112856541976440'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6426112856541976440'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/06/bruno-movie-review.html' title='Bruno (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3241721778337497806</id><published>2010-06-13T18:44:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-03-26T08:19:18.898-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Supporting Troops</title><content type='html'>I&#39;m using &quot;troops&quot; rather loosely, to mean roving bands or remotely deployed teams of experts (&quot;away teams&quot;).   &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;When I was a young boy, a &quot;troop&quot; was a multiplicity of soldiers, only later reducing to a singular individual, i.e. a &quot;trooper&quot; became a &quot;troop&quot;.  Other linguists have remarked on this trend.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Later still came &quot;An Army of One&quot; (a marketing campaign).&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The idea of embedding journalists or chroniclers (log makers, bloggers) as a part of the away team was a post-Vietnam War development.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A perception had developed around the Pentagon that too many journalists were loose canons and were seeing and reporting on events they should not, such as atrocities, murders of innocents, the agony of the troops.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The hellish nature of war motivated an insistence that it stop.  Television played a big role. Young people (Global U students) especially resisted accepting their work / study assignments overseas.  Others rebelled once they arrived at the scene.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A system of self-censorship was set up such that the media today are much more self-controlled. Pictures of atrocities get passed around on memory sticks, often mixed with pornography, but the general public is mostly spared from vicariously experiencing the horror of war.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Reporters violating the new code of ethics lose privileged access, and are punished for betraying their roving band, with whom they should have bonded to form a seamless team.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In the meantime, the public has been trained to harden itself against disturbing imagery, to become more accepting of inhumane behavior (witness Gitmo etc.).  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Per C.G. Jung&#39;s posthumously published &lt;i&gt;Man and His Symbols&lt;/i&gt; (which I borrowed from the Quaker meetinghouse today, along with &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/03/uncovered-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Uncovered: the War in Iraq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;) people have the ability to &quot;lose their souls&quot; by means of various ego-dynamics.  There&#39;s a picture of a band of Australian aborigines suffering from soul loss, amidst psychological analysis.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A TV-watching public sinks into unconsciousness under the watchful management of its spin-doctor anesthetizers, who continually remix the memes to keep the war tolerable and securely remunerative for its sponsors.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Lots of comparing notes occurs among the spin doctors, with secondary sources echoing primary ones in disseminating the latest bewitchments (the great Austrian philosopher Ludwig Wittgenstein used this term &quot;bewitch&quot; in a technical sense, in the context of investigating the hypnotic powers of &quot;language games&quot;).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Some of the troops I&#39;m thinking about have been thankfully reassigned to perform humanitarian duties, such as during the tsunami in South Asia.  A lot of the same national guard type logistical skills pertain.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Coordination and planning, command centers and communications, all come into play.  Some of the same military bases play a role.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The overlap is such that it&#39;s not always obvious which troops are engaged in which operations, or whether these ops are &quot;special&quot; or &quot;covert&quot; in any way.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In these pro-human operations, the embedded chroniclers are often keen to get the images and words out to a public, not just to show the heroism of the troops, but to garner public support in the form of actual goods and services.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Once a need becomes clear, sponsors step forward, either as individuals, as private companies, or as government agencies.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;People at home or in coffee shops may wire funds directly, and take credit for doing so, on Facebook or whatever.  Perhaps they send other forms of support (such as I&#39;ve been doing, and chronicling on Facebook).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The chroniclers (bloggers, TV crews, filmmakers) are not under such pressure to keep the lid on their stories, as there&#39;s less fear of a negative backlash or reprisals.  I&#39;m not &quot;spilling the beans&quot; so much as &quot;sharing the beans&quot; (insider philosophy talk).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This image of civilians supporting humanitarian services from behind the front lines derives from many a war-time design pattern.  People spend their time and energy making uniforms, boots, meals, other equipment for these troops.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In today&#39;s high tech military, a single troop is a million dollar investment over time, in terms of training, transport and equipment.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This high level of investment towards humanitarian endeavors marks a big step towards the amelioration of specific problems in many areas of the world.  That same sense of good will flows towards the sponsors, for supporting the troops.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Yes, the military is a wealth redistribution and government jobs program.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/12/iron-mountain-revisted.html&quot;&gt;This is not news&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Having some of the programming serve humanitarian ends only means that the endeavor is somehow profitable to humanity.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Some characterize this difference as &quot;adding intelligence&quot; which might imply sponsorship by specific government agencies.  Let&#39;s see &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/06/more-documentaries.html&quot;&gt;which ones&lt;/a&gt; take credit.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3241721778337497806'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3241721778337497806'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/06/supporting-troops.html' title='Supporting Troops'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1815691977278024310</id><published>2010-06-12T21:53:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2024-02-05T07:58:36.907-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Aristotle Was Right!</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4680326861/&quot; title=&quot;Error in ConceptNet by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Error in ConceptNet&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4037/4680326861_e5a9de2287.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/mathfuture/msg/85da4f8aeafca685?hl=en&quot;&gt;oops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I put an &quot;oops&quot; here because a tetrahedron is not a polygon, nor need its faces be equal.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
On the other hand, its four faces &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; polygons, and they &lt;i&gt;might&lt;/i&gt; be equal.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The regular tetrahedron of four equilateral triangles is not a space-filler.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
The tetrahedral disphenoid, on the other hand, with four equal isosceles triangles, is a space-filler, meaning Aristotle was right:  tetrahedra &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; fill space.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Misinformation &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/04/suggesting-change.html&quot;&gt;from &lt;i&gt;Math World&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
A space-filling polyhedron, sometimes called a a plesiohedron (Grünbaum and Shephard 1980), is a &lt;a class=&quot;Hyperlink&quot; href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/Polyhedron.html&quot; style=&quot;color: #009999; text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;polyhedron&lt;/a&gt; which can be used to generate a &lt;a class=&quot;Hyperlink&quot; href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/Tessellation.html&quot; style=&quot;color: #009999; text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;tessellation&lt;/a&gt; of space. Although even Aristotle himself proclaimed in his work &lt;i&gt;On the Heavens&lt;/i&gt; that the &lt;a class=&quot;Hyperlink&quot; href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/Tetrahedron.html&quot; style=&quot;color: #009999; text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;tetrahedron&lt;/a&gt; fills space, it in fact does not.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
In fact the tetrahedron &lt;i&gt;does&lt;/i&gt; fill space, just not the regular one&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Per &lt;i&gt;Which Tetrahedra Fill Space? &lt;/i&gt;by Marjorie Senechal in &lt;i&gt;Mathematics Magazine&lt;/i&gt;, Vol. 54, No. 5 (Nov., 1981), pp. 227-243:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&quot;Aristotle did not state explicitly that he meant regular tetrahedra... some scholars continued to defend Aristotle on the grounds that he had not explicitly required regularity...&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
As well they might.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
What other tetrahedra fill space, all by themselves?  &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/02/mite-fight.html&quot;&gt;Which one is minimal&lt;/a&gt;, in the sense that it builds the others?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4585728237/&quot; title=&quot;OCN Branding by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;OCN Branding&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4036/4585728237_43710b92e2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We started Radical Math in Portland, Oregon, offering &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/03/radical-math.html&quot;&gt;a first course&lt;/a&gt; through Portland Free School on March 13, 2010.  Our venue:  SE Belmont around 30th, at &lt;i&gt;Flipside&lt;/i&gt; (since vanished).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
RadMath teaches what we call Verboten Math, which is considered somewhat on the subversive side, not suitable for textbooks.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Mathematicians tend to welcome our stirring the pot, as argument and debate &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/mathfuture/msg/df1bd13047a4ae93?hl=en&quot;&gt;stimulate interest&lt;/a&gt; in often dry topics. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
RadMath inherits from the Oregon Curriculum Network&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikieducator.org/Digital_Math&quot;&gt;&quot;digital mathematics&quot; curriculum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3261804560/&quot;&gt;Glenn Stockton&lt;/a&gt; focused on Neolithic Math whereas I was &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/11/martian-math.html&quot;&gt;more into Martian Math&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Would you like to help sponsor?  Help produce mathcasts?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Going down in history as a true radical, in conformist times when diversity was threatened, might be your reward. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Wanna win some brand loyalty from some of tomorrow&#39;s freest thinkers?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4680324919/&quot; title=&quot;ConceptNet in Python by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;ConceptNet in Python&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1265/4680324919_cb523eccb4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How might you build your own ConceptNet for a specific knowledge domain?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
What &quot;graphs&quot; would you create, what &quot;webs&quot;?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
In the case of a spatial geometry web, would you maybe have Mite, Syte and Kite as entries?:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
IsA(Syte, two Mite)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
IsA(Kite, two Syte) &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
IsA(Mite, A A B).  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Make any sense?  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
This math is somewhat esoteric &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/06/moratorium-proposal-synergeo.html&quot;&gt;by today&#39;s standards&lt;/a&gt;, but if you&#39;re &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2010/05/buzz-about-shops.html&quot;&gt;at MIT&lt;/a&gt;, maybe you know what I&#39;m talking about. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Or is &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/04/radical-math-and-python.html&quot;&gt;this stuff&lt;/a&gt; still verboten there too?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1815691977278024310'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1815691977278024310'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/06/aristotle-was-right.html' title='Aristotle Was Right!'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4037/4680326861_e5a9de2287_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8569130827263067189</id><published>2010-06-01T21:53:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-23T02:16:07.374-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Ruminations</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157624062450891&quot; title=&quot;Spring 2010&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Spring 2010&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/4072/4662083425_1eed99334b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: spring 2010 ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
World events backdrop:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/oil-spill.html&quot;&gt;oil continues to spew&lt;/a&gt;, repeating events of 25 years ago according to Glenn, when the same sequence of repairs was attempted to no avail.  Going through the motions.  And &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/12/thinking-globally.html&quot;&gt;the jigsaw puzzle of nations&lt;/a&gt; continues to defy solution, because nations are the product of lesser minds, were never God-given (human contrivances, an attempt at self-organization -- many valuable lessons learned).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
The neighbors actually did repaint &lt;i&gt;Sunnyside Piazza&lt;/i&gt;, looking good.  I wandered by there with my camera, between computer jobs.  We went looking for &lt;i&gt;Hebrew&lt;/i&gt; brand beer at &lt;i&gt;Zupan&#39;s&lt;/i&gt;, which we found in Pomegranate flavor, but it&#39;s the double IPA we were looking for.  &lt;i&gt;Dead Guy&lt;/i&gt; was on sale, along with another one.  Thai soup with sandwich.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/07/more-on-gothenberg_25.&quot;&gt;Shades of Gothenberg&lt;/a&gt;.  I miss &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/07/sunday-in-vilnius.html&quot;&gt;Vilnius&lt;/a&gt; as well, glad Aiste is a Facebook friend, though I can&#39;t decipher most of what she writes.  Greetings to Sir Laura, and to Steve Holden in Hong Kong (both PSF, Aiste should be if she&#39;s not).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Trey and Mike D. delivered some planters.  LinZ did her &lt;i&gt;Food Not Bombs&lt;/i&gt; run today.  I filled in last week so she could work on repairing her rib cage.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
The idea of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=7084546&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;a Beauty Pageant&lt;/a&gt; for Queen of the Space-fillers sounds kinda retro sexist, rather Rose Parade (there&#39;s a Rose Queen, high schools compete).  Part of the fun is no hexahedron even makes the first cut.  King Qyoob is thrown from his throne.  Then there&#39;s this business of not being even-handed, being biased.  Our Queen should be able to conceal her bias (orientation), is how the analogy works.  I&#39;m alluding to the B-module, which shows up as either left (+) or right (-), yet outwardly she has all the same shapely angles, either way.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
The logjam of nations, in some sense a failure, in some sense lasting karma, in some sense a projection of our obedience to eternal principles, is captured in the movie &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/10/terminal-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;The Terminal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; with Tom Hanks.  The airport shows lots of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/02/octet-truss.html&quot;&gt;octet-truss shots&lt;/a&gt;.  The limbo of &quot;nowhere / everywhere&quot; is what airports seem good at projecting, that &quot;space between nations&quot; (like where the duty free shops tend to be).  The Global University has roots in this limbo.  Many of our students have no passports, no travel documents, no citizenship in any country.  They fell through the cracks. World Game includes them, as more than statistics.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
I got some polyhedra in the mail today, Made in Korea.  My thanks to Gary of Pedagoguery Software of Canada. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Notice how I have no problem continuing to mention countries -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/train-reading.html&quot;&gt;a familiar calculus&lt;/a&gt;.  I like the stamps, money, flags and souvenirs.  I also recognize &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/07/2nd-life-2nd-world.html&quot;&gt;virtual nations&lt;/a&gt;, closer to states of mind in some ways. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Imagine a Buddhist state of Samsara, with Nirvana the state capital (like Olympia of Washington).  Or would Nirvana be more &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/03/storyboarding-tomorrow.html&quot;&gt;like Orlando&lt;/a&gt;?  Is Nirvana an &quot;after life&quot;?  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Many Xtians have questions about these &quot;exotic cults&quot; (as they might think of them, if not getting much tourism).  Even Quakers are exotic to most Xtians, especially those of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/08/quakers-101.html&quot;&gt;&quot;unprogrammed&quot; variety&lt;/a&gt; (how does one deprogram an unprogrammed Friend?).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/08/refugee-camps.html&quot;&gt;The folks in Louisiana&lt;/a&gt; have suffered plenty without this additional catastrophe of course.  New Orleans is like Baghdad, though in the latter case, the disaster was man made, self inflicted.  In both cases actually, counting the death-dealing oil plumes.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/09/more-global-data.html&quot;&gt;Poor engineering&lt;/a&gt; (e.g. FEMA trailers, decaying dikes) might be underlined as a cause of suffering in all of these scenarios.  Poverty of mind, of the imagination, results in self-fulfilling &quot;I told you so&quot; prophesies coming true.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
A more exultant engineering, clearly aimed at serving all humanity, would be easier to resonate with.  Sometimes I think the free software movement got that ball rolling.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&quot;World domination&quot; in that geek subculture meant an end to domineering &quot;owner enforced&quot; selfishness.  The workers co-owned the code, reaped the fruits of using their own heads -- what&#39;s under the &quot;thinking cap&quot; in &lt;i&gt;cap&lt;/i&gt;italism.  &quot;Brain in body, body in mind&quot; is what some say, projecting &quot;mind&quot; as like &quot;the Matrix&quot;.  That&#39;s pretty &lt;i&gt;est&lt;/i&gt;-like (branching off Zen?).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Having wars about nations seems dark ages and retro, given how they&#39;re on the ropes to begin with, with the flagship USA taking on debt like there&#39;s no tomorrow.  GST is switching the circuits, to where we speak more sensibly about energy inputs and workflows.  &quot;Not with a bang but a whimper&quot; is how it would be, to ignite a big row over that which was never God-given.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
The planet Earth on the other hand... now &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/02/wanderers-201022.html&quot;&gt;here&#39;s a Promised Land&lt;/a&gt; worth protecting.  We&#39;d need a Global University to do that.  Maybe MIT will show us how it&#39;s done.  Princeton?  Cal Tech? Standford?  We&#39;ll need a blend.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Speaking of Standford, we&#39;ve been hearing from Keith Devlin&#39;s corner, where &lt;a href=&quot;http://thirteencelebration.org/blog/edblog/edblog-wanted-an-apollo-program-for-math/1660/&quot;&gt;an Apollo Project&lt;/a&gt; for sharing precision thinking is planned, at least in a small corner thereof.  I&#39;ve not been able to trace the connections between Dr. Devlin and Dr. Benson, in case there&#39;s some overlap in the realm of Algebra.  From my angle, it&#39;s more &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/06/greek-mythology.html&quot;&gt;a Cult of Athena business&lt;/a&gt; (wisdom, defense, also music), with &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/serving-from-algebra-city.html&quot;&gt;Algebra City&lt;/a&gt; a source of algorithms.  We&#39;re &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/12/work-study.html&quot;&gt;feeding Pentagon Math&lt;/a&gt; with that NCLB Polyhedron and Polynomial:  sounds cryptic, I realize.  Other blog posts explain.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Trevor posted about &lt;a href=&quot;http://synchronofile.com/?p=344&quot;&gt;still-standing&lt;/a&gt; Dymaxion Deployment Units or DDUs.  Bucky was helping to get the idea of inexpensive, manufactured housing off to a good start.  Bulter continued to reap the benefits of vending commercialized living quarters.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8569130827263067189'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8569130827263067189'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/06/ruminations.html' title='Ruminations'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-114457464788320530</id><published>2010-05-26T13:14:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2013-08-20T15:29:27.567-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Another Chart</title><content type='html'>&lt;div&gt;
From the &lt;i&gt;Synergeo&lt;/i&gt; list (# 59600):&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
XYZ provides a &quot;treatment&quot; whereby all polyhedra will be smaller than their corresponding IVM values, per constant. Here&#39;s a chart, which includes [the] 2.8284... cube (XYZ treatment of Syn Cube of 3).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;2&quot; cellspacing=&quot;2&quot; style=&quot;font-size: inherit;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th style=&quot;font-weight: normal; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;shape&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th style=&quot;font-weight: normal; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;xyz volume in cubic units (cube diagonal is two units)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th style=&quot;font-weight: normal; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;ivm volume in tetrahedral units (tetrahedron edge is one unit)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;A,B&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;0.0393&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;0.04166666667&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;Mite&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;0.3536&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;0.125&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;Tet.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;0.9428&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;Cubo.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;2.357&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;2.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;Cube&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;2.8284&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;Oct.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;3.7712&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;Rt.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;4.714&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;Rd.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;5.6569&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;Rt.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;7.071&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;7.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;Pd.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;14.721&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;15.35&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;Ico.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;17.454&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;18.512&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;Cubo.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;18.856&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;Cube&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;22.627&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;24&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Cubo. = cuboctahedron; Rt. = rhombic triacontahedron; Pd. = pentagonal dodecahedron; Rd. = rhombic dodecahedron; Ico. = icosahedron; Oct. = octahedron; Tet. = tetrahedron; Mite = minimum tetrahedron&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In collaboration with Alan Michelson&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
X-ref:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/12/another-rant.html&quot;&gt;Another Mathematician&#39;s Lament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/05/past-glories.html&quot;&gt;Past Glories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114457464788320530'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/114457464788320530'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/another-chart.html' title='Another Chart'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2877156544842909062</id><published>2010-05-23T16:52:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-05-23T19:12:22.636-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Train Reading</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4633215915/&quot; title=&quot;Train Reading by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4070/4633215915_40f2220954_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;180&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; alt=&quot;Train Reading&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;I used much of the time to/from on the train (Amtrak Cascades) to study &lt;i&gt;The Long Emergency&lt;/i&gt; by James Howard Kunstler. The author uses the well-worn calculus of nation-states, unabashedly saying &quot;we&quot; for the Americans he considers his compatriots.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He expects a steady increase of entropy in human affairs, as oil reserves are depleted. It&#39;s the end of the world as we know it. Our chauffeur to the train used the word &quot;anomie&quot; for such identity-disrupting changes, a word I later found in the book.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Although Kunstler mentions &quot;Spaceship Earth&quot; in passing, he&#39;s not seeing desovereignization via Grunch as a potentially hopeful sign.  He intends his &quot;we&quot; to remain rather exclusively North American, projecting the potential for &quot;political psychosis&quot; on Chinese, even while admitting North America&#39;s sprawling commuter-based suburban lifestyles are kooky and squanderous.  Europeans are relatively sane by his yardstick, their commitment to agriculture and urban growth boundaries still well defined.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kunstler is pessimisstic about the global grid getting any nuclear juice from Persia, given high levels of paranoia all around.  WWIII will not &lt;i&gt;begin&lt;/i&gt; with an attack on these power plants in his estimation, but only because it is &lt;i&gt;already&lt;/i&gt; well under way.  In this sense, his lingo somewhat dovetails with that of the world gamers, who see WWIII beginning with &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/05/teacher-training.html&quot;&gt;the so-called Cold War&lt;/a&gt; (cite &lt;i&gt;Critical Path&lt;/i&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also on tap:  &lt;i&gt;The Corporation&lt;/i&gt;, a DVD borrowed from &lt;i&gt;Laughing Horse&lt;/i&gt; for Tara&#39;s benefit, and screened in a rural setting on an HDTV (at a private party).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At this same venue, I launched into my little rap on the Mite and the T-module, using &lt;i&gt;Mag-Blocks&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Ball of Whacks&lt;/i&gt;.  This mirrored my posts to &lt;i&gt;Math Forum&lt;/i&gt;, where&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=2078323&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt; I question the censorious attitude&lt;/a&gt; of comtemporaries.  My audience included one math savvy computer science person, steeped in Java, Ruby and Visual Basic (not Python).  She works in trucking, a sector I&#39;m also starting to tune in, a primary consumer of fossil fuels.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We didn&#39;t screen the whole of &lt;i&gt;The Corporation&lt;/i&gt; as the arguments against corporate personhood are already well known in this neck of the woods.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We took Amtrak&#39;s Cascades to/from.  The conductors over the PA were entertaining.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Going north, we had a Russian guy, thanking us for supporting this one international train in the region.  He suggested we keep our seating area clean and tidy, lest we be judged rude and crude by our fellow North Americans across the border.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Going south, our conductor suggested we refrain from smoking lest we be offloaded and transported to a secret prison in Eastern Europe, &quot;extraordinary rendition&quot; in action (he used those words).  So the CIA &lt;i&gt;does&lt;/i&gt; operate domestically after all (surprise surprise).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also on my reading list:  &lt;i&gt;Sum:  Forty Tales from the Afterlives&lt;/i&gt; by David Eagleman, a series of reveries encouraging self reflection.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The notion that communities might experiment with different lifestyles, versus kowtowing to one centrally dictated standard, is important to the idea of religious freedom.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Islamic forms need campus facilities, places to test themselves in relative security, just as do other religious forms, including Mormons in Texas.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This notion that lifestyles must be exterminated by force versus allowed to pursue a diverse set of options, goes against the idea of experimental prototype communities of tomorrow (some of which &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/05/bait-and-switch.html&quot;&gt;may be Taliban&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;World Game&#39;s focus on artifacts aims to lower barriers to entry for those wishing to create viable small (or large) scale communities.  Perhaps a blend of traditional ways and aerospace tech will assist in the terraforming.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the other hand, easy access to armaments and deliberately fostered feuding, an old divide-and-conquer technique, prevent a live-and-let-live ecosystem from occurring.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Scholarly forms of Islam have fostered such peaceful relations in the past, as have other religious lineages. Secular brands not religiously anti-religious likewise have a track record of fostering non-violent lifestyles.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A program of student exchange will provide the necessary diplomatic glue.  Those fearing a campus is secretly training militants in bomb making and torture techniques ala School of the Americas etc. will have ample opportunity to interview the exchange students.  We all spy on each other, by design and prearrangement.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The monitoring of nuclear facilities develops along similar lines: a global cast moves among them, both reporting and lending its expertise. Civilians monitor themselves.  The weaponization of nuclear materials is judged a crime against humanity, wherever and whenever, the hallmark of a corrupt Dr. Evil who must be stopped (like in the comic books).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A new media campaign:  Terraform Earth! This perhaps sounds ridiculous, as Earth is already terraformed.  However, in the Martian literature, &quot;to terraform Mars&quot; is &quot;to render Mars habitable&quot;. We need to use our best engineering and understanding of anthropology to keep Earth habitable over the long haul.  Terraforming is our ongoing responsibility, and if we&#39;re unable to do it here, then it&#39;s unlikely we&#39;ll ever be able to do it elsewhere.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This work may mean taking a somewhat alien point of view, not identifying with this or that nation too much.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/01/cyber-nations.html&quot;&gt;Cyber-nations&lt;/a&gt; (aka &quot;virtual nations&quot;) might help serve as an antidote to rampant nationalism, a mindset which keeps way too many humans trapped in some &quot;us against them&quot; mode of scenario planning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our only Promised Land is Spaceship Earth. Responsibility for the whole entails responsibility for the parts, but not vice versa.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Will world religions inspire us with positive and attainable visions of community, sacred spaces, or is religion inevitably invested in Apocalypse, with an afterlife situated in other worlds besides this one?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Those colonizing the so-called New World for religious reasons were looking for opportunities to practice unhampered, and to create relative utopias in so doing.  The motives behind the founding of Pennsylvania were not that different from those behind the founding of Israel or South Africa, with maltreatment of indigenous peoples a source of on-going karma.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nation-states are not synonymous with communities however.  We might have campus facilities in a Global U, with students free to move among them, independently of the claptrap of vast land tracts claiming sovereignty under God, lands often grabbed at gun point.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If we want our students to be intelligent, equal to the challenges at hand, then the jigsaw puzzle of nations need not appear on every map that they study.  Those learning to see Earth from Space need to see her as she really is:  a single ecosystem / economy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Refugees without established citizenship might be among the first to enroll, gaining new identity within these schools.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Corporations already incorporate many of the relevant memes, in being global without requiring vast contiguous land tracts in many cases.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Allegiance to all humanity is a curriculum goal, not as a matter of empty idealism, but of necessity.  We need at least some future thinkers, world leaders, to escape &quot;the calculus of nations&quot; as their only frame of reference.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2877156544842909062'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2877156544842909062'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/train-reading.html' title='Train Reading'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4070/4633215915_40f2220954_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-244286546195949234</id><published>2010-05-18T16:22:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-05-18T16:30:56.437-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Secret Garden</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4612848911/&quot; title=&quot;Bound Bamboo by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4006/4612848911_a7a162ddb5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Bound Bamboo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4613453618/&quot; title=&quot;Tetrahedra by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4056/4613453618_74fa1c1ac1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Tetrahedra&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4613457302/&quot; title=&quot;Joins by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3333/4613457302_0e4d60bddd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Joins&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/244286546195949234/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/244286546195949234' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/244286546195949234'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/244286546195949234'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/secret-garden.html' title='Secret Garden'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4006/4612848911_a7a162ddb5_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2187362602754372866</id><published>2010-05-16T22:02:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-05-16T23:18:06.391-07:00</updated><title type='text'>More Screenings</title><content type='html'>&lt;div&gt;Topic:  Niger Delta.  Venue:  PSU.  Lots of groups are studying the oil companies these days. They&#39;ve been getting away with murder (literally).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Happy Birthday to PB.  Mine tomorrow. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We celebrated outside, amidst &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4614151174/&quot;&gt;stacks of books&lt;/a&gt;.  Lots of peak oil talk, not all of it bleak.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;LW shared of her adventures in Tokyo.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I borrowed a bicycle to visit with Quakers, still haven&#39;t replaced TinkerBell.  Delivered &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4612830585/in/photostream/&quot;&gt;program materials&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;High schoolers came by to work on protest posters (an assigned PPS project).  I served on clean-up crew.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;  style=&quot;color:#000099;&quot;&gt;JB &#39;&lt;/span&gt;n &lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;  style=&quot;color:#660000;&quot;&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/59132&quot;&gt;on &lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/59132&quot;&gt;Synergeo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;  style=&quot;color:#330099;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;  style=&quot;color:#330099;&quot;&gt;Commercial potential of a product depends on how nifty people think it is, and on how much they all want one. So, what in the pantheon of Synergetic nifty objects has the potential of the HHoop, the Frisbee, or the Superball?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;  style=&quot;color:#660000;&quot;&gt;Aerospace sector dwelling machines (housing).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The fact that Lockheed-Martin hasn&#39;t unveiled anything cool in the last couple decades is discouraging. As an engineering culture, that sector is floundering, made fat and stupid by a cash cow Pentagon (after WW2 especially).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;  style=&quot;color:#660000;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;More computer science &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogger.com/ail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2010-May/date.html&quot;&gt;on edu-sig&lt;/a&gt;...</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2187362602754372866'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2187362602754372866'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/more-screenings.html' title='More Screenings'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6510664662098688764</id><published>2010-05-13T08:42:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-05-13T16:00:36.808-07:00</updated><title type='text'>More on Public Education</title><content type='html'>Reports are filtering back from the NCTM annual conference.  I&#39;m looking at &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/mathfuture/browse_thread/thread/9798ce0cc2eae9e0?hl=en&quot;&gt;Maria&#39;s recap of Ihor&#39;s talk&lt;/a&gt; in particular. Nothing too surprising.  &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/kite-sighting.html&quot;&gt;kite campaign&lt;/a&gt;&quot; was barely a blip on the radar, but then that was more for retrospective use.  When drawing attention to &quot;what&#39;s missing&quot; (e.g. Mites), one needs a frame with cross-hairs, a camera lens to look through.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;That sense of math education being under attack, with continued dismantling of tools, a rollback of advances, is felt around Portland as well.  Benson, our polytechnic, was ordered to dumb itself down by the school board awhile back, as its math-science standards were considered discriminatory.  The new proposal is to simply bus students there, i.e. to kill it as a school with a self-contained identity.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Obviously I&#39;ve been hearing from some seriously distraught math teachers.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;One could see where the economic incentive would be to prevent the local population from regaining its abilities to organize and staff industries.  Now that the Silicon Forest is well established, why not keep it a preserve for imported workers?  More generally, North America is being stripped of its human resources and dumbed down.  High school no longer teaches much of anything about machine world or how things work.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Turning this situation around &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/03/pps-has-friends-in-silicon-forest.html&quot;&gt;with free and open source software&lt;/a&gt; has been a theme in this doodle pad (not a diary really, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/01/diary-entry.html&quot;&gt;usually&lt;/a&gt;).  Another theme:  a place-based education that really gives a sense of local timelines.  Faculty have a responsibility to custom tailor curriculum imports.  There&#39;s no &quot;one size fits all&quot; approach that&#39;s going to work.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Cultivating regional identity, versus some tendency towards mono-culture, enforced from some imperial center: this an old pattern, one that doesn&#39;t just apply in &quot;the developing world&quot; (as people used to say).  In Biblical terms, one steers &lt;i&gt;around&lt;/i&gt; Rome (take the Annulare?).  Nor do we all get our news from the &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt; (at least not exclusively).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Xenophobia is not the way to go though.  We&#39;re lucky to have a diverse and cosmopolitan population.  Competence with tools and technologies should be encouraged everywhere, not just around Portland, Oregon (duh).  This Global U infrastructure to promote more student exchange will make it easier to keep schools like Benson in business.  Getting more households on stream and certified for visiting scholars is a part of the longer term plan.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In the meantime, our Radical Math and the Portland free school business are helping propagate mentors. Teachers are experimenting with new techniques, including more pair teaching.  I&#39;ve not been attending all of these classes (some in Spanish), but I do appreciate the efforts. Language and math &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; go together (and I&#39;m not just talking about computer languages).  We&#39;ve been recommending &lt;i&gt;Who Is Fourier?&lt;/i&gt; by the LEX Institute for some years on edu-sig (&lt;a href=&quot;http://markmail.org/message/tt5rq64ypulukcrj&quot;&gt;Jason Cunliffe&lt;/a&gt; and I especially).  The teaching techniques are prototypical of O&#39;Reilly&#39;s in the &lt;i&gt;Head First&lt;/i&gt; series.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;However, I&#39;m not claiming these efforts to keep math on life support will be sufficient in and of themselves.  As I was posting to &lt;i&gt;Synergeo&lt;/i&gt; yesterday, I don&#39;t have too exaggerated a sense of my own importance in these efforts.  The various networks have their own agendas and the synergetic result is more than the sum of its parts.  The Pythonic Math curriculum we&#39;ve been developing is just one effort among many.  Functional programmers have their own ideas.  &lt;i&gt;OS Bridge&lt;/i&gt; is shaping up to have more talks on Haskell than Python this year.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6510664662098688764'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6510664662098688764'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/more-on-public-education.html' title='More on Public Education'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-513178148462679519</id><published>2010-05-11T18:51:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-05-18T17:41:26.413-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2010.5.11</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4601043641/&quot; title=&quot;Rudi Nussbaum by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1353/4601043641_2f1d4c1af9_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; alt=&quot;Rudi Nussbaum&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This event was given considerable air time at the recent Raph Nader event, so we&#39;re expecting some extra guests (two more just walked in).  &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Rudi Nussbaum is here, with his wife Laureen, to talk about the Hanford down-winders, people adversely affected by the Manhatten Project&#39;s HQS in Washington State. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Purifying plutonium for atomic bombs has endangered the Columbia Gorge for the foreseeable future and attempts at cleanup is costing many times more than the Manhattan Project itself. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Daniel Ellsberg referred to this cleanup as &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/02/remembering-boston.html&quot;&gt;Manhattan Project 2&lt;/a&gt;.  Although people aren&#39;t much using that nomenclature, the reality is:  it&#39;s happening.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Lloyd Marbet has joined us, long time activist, opponent of Trojan (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/05/trojan-implosion.html&quot;&gt;since destroyed&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Rudi sincerely admired Linus Pauling, had the opportunity to speak with him at some length at Portland State that time.  He&#39;s feeling honored to join as at Linus Pauling&#39;s boyhood home, with his picture with Ava (a Quaker) over the mantelpiece.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Gofman&quot;&gt;John Gofman&lt;/a&gt;, an early whistle blower, helped expose the lies being promulgated by the Atomic Energy Commission regarding the safety and acceptability of using military personnel as guinea pigs around atmospheric testing.  His career and character were trashed in retaliation, though he didn&#39;t disappear.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alice_Stewart&quot;&gt;Alice Stewart&lt;/a&gt; was another of Rudi&#39;s mentors and personal friends.  Stewart was one of the first to alert the medical community to the deleterious effects of X-rays, on pregnant mothers etc.  Many were not ready for this finding, as X-rays were all the rage at the time.  Her career was definitely hurt by her professional integrity.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Rudi didn&#39;t originally plan on investigating the medical effects of nuclear fallout, fissionable materials in the environment.  He sought refuge from &quot;dirty politics,&quot; was not looking for a fight. For many years, he got away with mostly doing basic research. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Once he opened the can of worms that was the &quot;science&quot; around the health effects of radioactive material, he was blown away by &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/05/tomorrows-food.html&quot;&gt;the level of corruption&lt;/a&gt; he encountered.  Money buys scientists by the boatload.  Three Mile Island provided another example of corruption, with the government blue panel commission finding &quot;no health effects&quot; essentially by edict.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://iicph.org/high-tritium-in-ottawa-river-a-public-health-disaster&quot;&gt;Tritium alone&lt;/a&gt; is a leading cause of &lt;a href=&quot;http://iicph.org/childhood-leukemia-how-much-evidence-needed-for-action&quot;&gt;leukemia in children&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&quot;Inconclusive results&quot; is what PR firms are looking for, when fending off public resistance to whatever technology is paying their bills.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Official state-sponsored investigations of Hanford&#39;s health effects were often high handed, with members of the public advised they might be suffering from &quot;radiophobia&quot; -- an irrational fear of radiation.  Independent scientists got together to see whether they could produce some definitive findings.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Dr. Charles Grossman, another Linus Pauling fan, whom Jon Bunce and Rudi both know, was originally skeptical that &quot;down winders&quot; were victims of radiation poisoning.  After conducting some interviews, he had to change his mind.  Given releases of materials were initially into the atmosphere, the term &quot;down winders&quot; is meant fairly literally.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/08/flextegrity_18.html&quot;&gt;Sam Lanahan&lt;/a&gt; is here, and is eager to hear the scientific results of this counter-study.  What were these &quot;definitive findings&quot; he wants to know.  LaJean grew up in Walla Walla and would like to know some more details.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A finding of excess hypothyroidism associated with spontaneous abortions, excess cancers of thyroid, nervous system and reproductive system, by a factor of some 10x vis-a-vis background rates for Washington State, seems close to irrefutable. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Wind-borne iodine 131 and iodine 129 are the implicated isotopes.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The Hanford Thyroid Disease Study (CDC, National Cancer Institute, University of Washington), in contrast, found no ill effects.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Their technique was not to compare local incidence rates with background rates, but to look for a monotonic relationship between purported dose amounts and the number of cases reported, i.e. incidence rates in concentric circles around the release site needed to increase in a simple manner in the direction of Hanford, or there could be no evidence of correlation, regardless of absolute numbers.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Simple correlation of dose with distance is too simplistic in any case, given variations in topography, wind patterns and so forth.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Now that more data about Chernobyl is being released, the ability to cross-check the numbers is becoming easier.  A recent German study (&lt;a href=&quot;http://ehsehplp03.niehs.nih.gov/article/fetchArticle.action?articleURI=info:doi/10.1289/ehp.115-a313a&quot;&gt;plus an older one&lt;/a&gt;) applied some fairly rigorous protocols and showed children living within 10 km of nuclear plants are adversely affected.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Rudi asked not to be quoted in &lt;a href=&quot;http://ehsehplp03.niehs.nih.gov/article/fetchArticle.action?articleURI=info:doi/10.1289/ehp.117-a437&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; if he couldn&#39;t see a pre-publication draft, but Adrian Burton broke their agreement. Oh well.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Although the down-winders have been awarded some millions by some court, the government has unlimited resources to appeal and the current plan is to simply wait for these folks to die off.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Wanderers indulged their penchant for red wine during Rudi&#39;s talk and tended to embarrass themselves per usual.  Good thing we didn&#39;t have a lot of guests.  We need this semi-private venue to indulge our vices.  I hope those few visitors who did attend will forgive us our lack of social graces.  &quot;You oughta keep alcohol out of this event&quot; said Lloyd Marbet.  I tend to agree.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I had no idea that Phil&#39;s bookstore had burned down, a loss of some 100K rare volumes on the Pacific Northwest, a shocking loss.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/513178148462679519'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/513178148462679519'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/wanderers-2010511.html' title='Wanderers 2010.5.11'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1353/4601043641_2f1d4c1af9_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3933619386972050554</id><published>2010-05-08T19:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-05-10T16:00:48.214-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Civil Service</title><content type='html'>My daughters joined me for lunch at &lt;i&gt;The Bagdad&lt;/i&gt; today, a rare enough event.  I remembered when this had been a video rental store, pre &lt;i&gt;McMenamins&lt;/i&gt; buying the building.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We celebrated Carol&#39;s successful endeavors at the UN in NYC, welcomed the bright day, despite an abiding awareness of unfolding tragedies.  She found some atmospherics to be up beat about. The Russians and &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/america-reboots.html&quot;&gt;the Americans&lt;/a&gt; seem to indeed have rebooted their relationship.  Now if they could only act maturely around Iran... (that speech was pretty tame, nothing Canada couldn&#39;t have said).&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tara took the neg position regarding &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/10/mark-satin-at-powells-books.html&quot;&gt;a two year quasi-universal draft&lt;/a&gt;, whereas almost 100% of her peers are taking the aff (aff and neg:  shorthand from the Lincoln-Douglas debating subculture, Tara the district champion). &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A culture espousing freedom should not mandate mandatory service, was Tara&#39;s position.  Alexia saw relief from the pressure of student loans as a motivator.  I circled overseas service as a possibility for volunteers, but that&#39;s not how the proposal had been written (a domestic service only).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tara enterprisingly asked around and netted a cast-off PCIe card from a friend that solved her computer video needs.  This took me almost an entire day to install, between other projects.  Getting the dust blown out of her computer was definitely in need of doing.  This was no super high end vid card, but beats what came on the motherboard (there&#39;s a BIOS setting to switch it over).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Don&#39;t apply the same dust blowing techniques to a piano though, I learned in my visit to the warehouse, as you&#39;ll just blow off the delicate felt padding (not that I&#39;d done this, was learning from another&#39;s long ago mistakes).  I was working for food, got to drive a truck and trailer (still haven&#39;t tried &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4586359632/&quot;&gt;the forklift&lt;/a&gt; though).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;My student friend in Indonesia has moved on to XML, is studying elementree.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I need to show &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/01/wanderers-2007131.html&quot;&gt;Wanderer Bill Sheppard&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://effbot.org/zone/console-handbook.htm&quot;&gt;the Console module by Fredrik Lundh&lt;/a&gt;.  I just tested it on Win7 and it seems to run just fine.  Bill is always ribbing me about Python not being able to control a simple terminal window, sort of a basic test of basic smarts in his book (he writes in assembler).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In addition to upgrading the video card, I upgraded the Starling-1 netbook from Jaunty Jackalope to Karmic Koala, the next higher version of Ubuntu.  System76 technical support by email was most necessary in getting me through this.  I&#39;d lost wireless, needed to upgrade grub, the boot loader.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;m not some super Linux guru, believe you me, am in awe of some of those I encounter.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tara has been using the Starling-1 more than I have recently.  I mostly use it in meetings, to share pictures or quick takes from the Internet.  I find it difficult to use for production work and appear not to have &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/05/hypertoons-from-csn.html&quot;&gt;hypertoons&lt;/a&gt; installed, so it&#39;s hardly CSN-ready.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I wrote about &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2010-April/009979.html&quot;&gt;PyCuda on edu-sig&lt;/a&gt; when thinking about this new graphics card... not that I&#39;ve ever used it. PyCuda and its successor give Python coders a way to talk to the GPUs on nVidia cards.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I don&#39;t know what &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=7049061&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;the Security+ people&lt;/a&gt; have to say about rogue employees milking more cycles out of on-board hardware -- presumably, like skateboarding, that &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2010-May/009989.html&quot;&gt;shouldn&#39;t be a crime&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Speaking of which, the warehouse I was working in had an entire indoor skateboarding facility, which no one was using at the time.  I was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/1023018145/&quot;&gt;reminded of Vilnius&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The Wittgenstein list &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freelists.org/post/wittrsamr/popping-in-re-mathematics-foundations&quot;&gt;now has a record&lt;/a&gt; of some recent plowing and tilling in the Radical Math domain.  I&#39;m collecting recent links to my Math Forum posts &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/05/math-reform.html&quot;&gt;in &lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/05/math-reform.html&quot;&gt;MyBizmo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This may all seem more like idle banter than high stakes poker, I realize.  I live in my own &quot;private Idaho&quot; to some degree.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Nick (GU exchange) reminded me to check out the revamped BFI website.  Lets see if I&#39;m can find some old pages... &lt;a href=&quot;http://bfi.org/news-events/community-content/nctm-embraces-synergetics&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; (NCTM heart Synergetics), but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bfi.org/bfi_community/pythonic_mathematics_talk_by_kirby_urner&quot;&gt;not this one&lt;/a&gt; (my London Knowledge Lab lecture).  OK, cool -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lkl.ac.uk/video/urner0406.html&quot;&gt;the latter&lt;/a&gt; was out of date by now anyway.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;LinZ is a the UU church downtown at the Ralph Nader lecture, running a table for &lt;i&gt;Laughing Horse&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Alexia:  what about those disappearing bees, why don&#39;t we hear more news about that?  The only environmental cue we&#39;re getting is the steadily rising cost of honey.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3933619386972050554'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3933619386972050554'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/civil-service.html' title='Civil Service'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5228090102977522306</id><published>2010-05-05T17:53:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-05-07T08:27:19.400-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2010.5.5</title><content type='html'>The room was packed this morning.  I arrived a little late, having circled the company car via Cleveland/PPS, later to &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Jiffy Lube&lt;/span&gt; for a free tire top off.  Front right was down to 5 pounds i.e. technically flat.  Gotta keep a sharp eye on that one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What happened amounted to a series of lightning talks or fire crackers, a kind of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Ignite Portland&lt;/span&gt;.  Indeed, some of the same topics came up:  tensegrity, flextegrity... and a lot of other stuff.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My original plan had been to say something about my experience with STScI.  As it turned out, my large format glossy posters, provided by the STScI outreach office, were much appreciated.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Other than that, I expressed my sincere appreciation to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.holdenweb.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Holden Web&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for providing me with this short notice opportunity.  I&#39;ve continued to study numpy, although I realize the mainstream still considers Matlab the fish of the day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After the official meeting, I used the white board to diagram some of our Radical Math concepts.  This is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4585728237/&quot;&gt;a marketing moniker or brand&lt;/a&gt; promulgated by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/ocn/&quot;&gt;Oregon Curriculum Network&lt;/a&gt;.  Here&#39;s the logo I&#39;m using (click through for Photostream):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4583096472/&quot; title=&quot;P5050053 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4062/4583096472_46a79f70cc_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;P5050053&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/58589&quot;&gt;published &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Geodesic News&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergeo&lt;/span&gt;, synthesizing some recent findings.</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/5228090102977522306/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/5228090102977522306' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5228090102977522306'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5228090102977522306'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/wanderers-201055.html' title='Wanderers 2010.5.5'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4062/4583096472_46a79f70cc_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-8219947541928775424</id><published>2010-05-03T15:14:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-05-08T21:48:03.962-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Empirical Studies</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgAauffHCZsBk6L8jZ_vSosM2zX1jScyQRRXuF5OUtrQvx72JnmDLkE4BNr9jixYcyYnYEXeDbUABDp5kLz9EFjXvf5LJsYiQrFPrh0GGiCUCXZDO8rhsh2UbLskIu0evHLGn1j/s1600/oilspill2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;TEXT-ALIGN: center; MARGIN: 0px auto 10px; WIDTH: 320px; DISPLAY: block; HEIGHT: 240px; CURSOR: hand&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5467178360047413954&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgAauffHCZsBk6L8jZ_vSosM2zX1jScyQRRXuF5OUtrQvx72JnmDLkE4BNr9jixYcyYnYEXeDbUABDp5kLz9EFjXvf5LJsYiQrFPrh0GGiCUCXZDO8rhsh2UbLskIu0evHLGn1j/s320/oilspill2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Patrick threw himself into oil spill studies with a vengeance. &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Between well capping and surface skimming is the mile of intervening ocean where oil plumes. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;With only 10% of water&#39;s density, it forms a vertical flow that might be partially dammed by large, neutrally buoyant, inverted funnels. He calls them &quot;jellyfish&quot;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Patrick&#39;s quick survey of the existing literature, including various patents and proposals, showed that designs for under-sea collection infrastructure had never been implemented. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Relatively few had thought in terms of fielding ad hoc under-ocean oil snarfing devices. Their pumps would actuate in short bursts, in response a concentration of oil detected in their upper reaches. Oil might go into bags for pulling to shore, if not directly into ship tanks.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Patrick did some quick hydrological experiments. Then, as one of the few people who knows about Flextegrity, he wondered if Sam&#39;s way of tethering compressive members together could provide a quick skeleton for holding some membrane or skin in a collective position.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flextegrity.com/&quot;&gt;The Flextegrity web site&lt;/a&gt; shows breakwater and sea-bottom artificial reef applications, but neutral buoyancy applications have not been a feature. Patrick found a way to submit his idea on-line.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Like any good engineer, he&#39;s casting about for solutions, leveraging whatever knowledge base is available. BP no doubt has a vast army of such engineers studying the problem from all angles.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Patrick&#39;s proposal seems pretty radical, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/oil-spill.html&quot;&gt;radical thinking&lt;/a&gt;, even &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/03/radical-math.html&quot;&gt;radical mathematics&lt;/a&gt;, is what we need more of these days.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgXa3zajPgHb5x48wFoKvkQhqczOGyzt8PTsIKowEOlxNVvWU6yyLBfXM6m5k87jBQvrqEtRNyEAVh2xJxxVdmzRW0hHkbSr1IVJRMoNw7jvuG-7kd6eIFkOnKZ4gpHYrUhFaZ9/s1600/oilspill1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;TEXT-ALIGN: center; MARGIN: 0px auto 10px; WIDTH: 320px; DISPLAY: block; HEIGHT: 240px; CURSOR: hand&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5467178187319698098&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgXa3zajPgHb5x48wFoKvkQhqczOGyzt8PTsIKowEOlxNVvWU6yyLBfXM6m5k87jBQvrqEtRNyEAVh2xJxxVdmzRW0hHkbSr1IVJRMoNw7jvuG-7kd6eIFkOnKZ4gpHYrUhFaZ9/s320/oilspill1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Patrick joined us for morning coffee, just before my Python class in the piano room.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;From my email to Sam later that same afternoon (fixing one typo):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;I think a &quot;prose sketch&quot; of the rig, an inverted half octahedron, maybe 5-6 frequency with pretty gigantic icosahedra (ala coral reef), would be close to my interpretation of Patrick&#39;s concept: a giant inverted funnel designed to keep some sort of canvas or skin serving as a passive catcher&#39;s mitt. When an actuator measuring oil density gets triggered, because of collected oil in the top reaches of the cup, the pump sends it up the hose, as a burst, then shuts off, waits to be triggered again. He referred to them as &quot;jelly fish&quot;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;Sam, Patrick, Glenn and I met at a neighborhood meeting place to further discuss the proposal. In kicking these ideas around, they morphed somewhat. The shape isn&#39;t that important, so long as it&#39;s a concave capturing device. We talked a lot about buoyancy control.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Sam would be happy to hit the accelerator on all this. We&#39;d need to work with his engineers to move quickly.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Glenn&#39;s design wouldn&#39;t require Flexegrity at all. Stiffened dacron sails and PVC might provide the concave jellyfish. Sam actually thought this design made a lot of sense, given his knowledge of sailing and matters maritime. Sam: &quot;Cheap, simple, locally available, ready to go... See, I&#39;m prepared to subvert my own belief structure.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We have yet to see even the beginning of the end of this scenario. The ecological impact of our legacy radioactive materials is likewise measured in geological time. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We came up with the following abstract. Patrick got a call back from Senator Wyden&#39;s office while we worked on our draft. Patrick wrote most of this:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;We propose to deploy an array of sub-surface oil concentration/collection devices to interdict the oil plume between its source and the surface. The elements of our system include individual, submerged, inverted funnels that will consolidate the oil and deliver it, on demand, to surface-based tender vessels. These elements work independently but can be deployed as a coordinated, but redundent, network. Each element consists of a concave membrane for oil collection, a pump, and a demand-based activation mechanism. Each element is deployable using small watercraft such as shrimp boats, and each can be independently weighted/buoyed as requred to ensure collection occurs at an optimal depth. Elements can be procured and assembled using locally-available or off-the-shelf materials.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;i&gt;Follow-up&lt;/i&gt;:  more polish applied later, plus we presented it in assembly at the Pauling Campus the following Wednesday morning.  The name &quot;Medusa Array&quot; was proposed informally.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8219947541928775424'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/8219947541928775424'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/empirical-studies.html' title='Empirical Studies'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgAauffHCZsBk6L8jZ_vSosM2zX1jScyQRRXuF5OUtrQvx72JnmDLkE4BNr9jixYcyYnYEXeDbUABDp5kLz9EFjXvf5LJsYiQrFPrh0GGiCUCXZDO8rhsh2UbLskIu0evHLGn1j/s72-c/oilspill2.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3270676342960998351</id><published>2010-05-01T12:14:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-06-18T23:35:09.210-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Oil Spill</title><content type='html'>The eco-disaster unfolding in the ocean is eclipsing our conversations.  The irony was not lost on Tara or Autumn, if we were to all die by our chief civilizational juice after water.  Talk about peak oil.  &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Our standards of living, future prospects, have been changed overnight.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Last night I attended another benefit concert for &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2010/02/upcoming-event.html&quot;&gt;Portland Womens Crisis Line&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.  The event was held at &lt;i&gt;In Other Words&lt;/i&gt; on the corner of Williams and Killingsworth.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Both bands, &lt;i&gt;Lindsey Walker&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Mannequin Head&lt;/i&gt;, were enthusiastically received by a mostly youthful female audience.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;During a scouting expedition afterwards, seeking a bus stop for a girl and her guide dog, I got a callback from mom in New York.  She&#39;d had another long day with the airlines, had arrived at her destination.  Nuclear disarmament remains a WILPF priority, since Ava Helen Pauling days and before.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/09/wanderers-200892.html&quot;&gt;Linda Richards&lt;/a&gt; has also been in our conversations recently, amongst the Pauling House drifters (Wanderers).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I drank quite a bit of French press coffee during showtime, courtesy of a newly ensconced barista.  &lt;i&gt;Laughing Horse&lt;/i&gt; is aware of this wrinkle in the business model, is looking at hosting classes for example, in addition to concerts (has already done some of both).  No one said that radicals couldn&#39;t be enterprising.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Radical thinking is what we&#39;ll need more of to counter environmental degradation, public enemy number one.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3270676342960998351'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3270676342960998351'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/oil-spill.html' title='Oil Spill'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-150009359798569434</id><published>2010-04-28T10:05:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-04-28T10:06:19.687-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2010.4.27</title><content type='html'>Completely packed house tonight, with some of the rare birds.  I&#39;m ensconced in my blogging area, ready to poke my head in, take notes.  Something about psychokenisis (am I spelling that correctly?).  We have an out of town expert.  Already the coat hanger is buckling under the weight, given our double the usual number.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Earlier today: a good meeting with Dr. B. Fuller, University of Nebraska emeritus, busy with his grandchildren, studying Alexander Calder with one of them.  We met at &lt;i&gt;Lyrik&lt;/i&gt;, formerly &lt;i&gt;Fine Grind&lt;/i&gt;. I took these &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/04/first-person-physics.html&quot;&gt;cool pictures of Bob&lt;/a&gt; signing the book he edited, writings by one of his mentors, &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/02/about-constructivism.html&quot;&gt;Robert Karplus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Allen Taylor and I read each other&#39;s blogs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I spent the last few hours dumping FoxPro data through a converter program I found on the Internet, but needed to patch.  It uses AFIELDS to get data about table columns, and does a fairly good job of creating a MySQL table, then populating it with data.  &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;m doing the dumping on the Win7 host, then gmailing to myself on a Sun Virtualbox guesting Ubuntu (I should use a shared folder but haven&#39;t figured that out yet).  There I populate the ktraks database in the MySQL installation, point to it from settings.py in Django project /home/projects/ktraks/.  I&#39;m using virtualenv...  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjPgIUlAfQaMKcR0wLoT8kJTVQF2iHOUz5_72EMCCDCB3WP1KjFjFF-Ku1ncPo8XFTK1TWP-Of74EKgtelbfcEbFoi1PI2rTBAaw5a3IUgLua3ZorR1OWYJpjXOW2LACS-Nmf3c/s1600/ktraksconvert.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 320px; height: 242px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjPgIUlAfQaMKcR0wLoT8kJTVQF2iHOUz5_72EMCCDCB3WP1KjFjFF-Ku1ncPo8XFTK1TWP-Of74EKgtelbfcEbFoi1PI2rTBAaw5a3IUgLua3ZorR1OWYJpjXOW2LACS-Nmf3c/s320/ktraksconvert.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5465233395513557330&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;These were all just demo fragments, as I&#39;m hoping to gel a proposal.  The actual project would need more than one solo coder/developer.  In fact, I&#39;m already one of a dynamic duo, or trio if you count the author of the framework (based in Tampa).  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Actually, there&#39;s a vast army behind every project in IT world, it&#39;s just that we don&#39;t always know in advance for what purposes our tools will be used.  Consider TCP/IP.  Some use it to provide medical care while others use it to spread damaging misinformation calculated to inspire fear.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tele-kenesis, not psycho-kinesis.  Applause.  I should get a picture.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4559609876/&quot; title=&quot;033 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2258/4559609876_c7a12981a0_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;033&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;She speaks in Russian and this young guy follows in English, line by line.  She&#39;s talking about levels of consciousness.  This gets me thinking of those Jungian talks again.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Jon Bunce bailed early.  Apparently our guest requested no wine drinking in her presence. Probably a good idea to keep us sobered up. We weren&#39;t allowed to eat our cake either, nor interrupt much.  Seemed pretty telekinetic to me, in that respect -- knocked &#39;em off balance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Given I&#39;m sequestered in the blogging area, I&#39;m able to sip on the sly.  Is that why the disk didn&#39;t turn?  Later some said that it did, so I&#39;m confused about whether this was an experiment.  We got together and hit off each other, an exercise in re-vectoring with the &quot;tele&quot; part not that easy to see, though we have our models (great circle railroad tracks through points of inter-tangency etc.).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;m missing most of the content I must confess, &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/58376&quot;&gt;staying occupied&lt;/a&gt; talking to &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/04/my-first-critic.html&quot;&gt;my on-line critic&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=7049131&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;posting to Math Forum&lt;/a&gt; some more.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Good seeing Rhett Savage again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ll put some more polish on this tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/150009359798569434'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/150009359798569434'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/04/wanderers-2010427.html' title='Wanderers 2010.4.27'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjPgIUlAfQaMKcR0wLoT8kJTVQF2iHOUz5_72EMCCDCB3WP1KjFjFF-Ku1ncPo8XFTK1TWP-Of74EKgtelbfcEbFoi1PI2rTBAaw5a3IUgLua3ZorR1OWYJpjXOW2LACS-Nmf3c/s72-c/ktraksconvert.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7025624186624879407</id><published>2010-04-24T21:04:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-05-12T08:59:47.286-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Thinking About Bud</title><content type='html'>The Bud I mean is Dawn&#39;s step dad, father to Gail.  I had the great privilege of meeting the dear man on a couple of occasions.  He worked for Eastern Airlines, in operations, for many years.  &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;His gentle manner really helped restore Dawn and Sam to happier lives in Satellite Beach, Florida, after some blisteringly bleak years in Warren, Ohio and such places.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Bud married their mom and was looking forward to a cheery retirement, when she died suddenly, of complications from a standard PTCA or other angiogram (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/03/about-dawn-brief-bio.html&quot;&gt;I met Dawn afterwards&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;My heartfelt respect for this hero of many adventures I have not told of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/11/back-to-silicon-forest.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  His memorial service is tomorrow.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Sam phoned me from Florida as I was getting off my delayed United flight from Denver, left me voicemail.  I immediately texted Alexia, Dawn&#39;s first of two daughters, as I road public transport back to my home.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Mom and I talked by phone tonight.  She is with Julie my sister.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7025624186624879407'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7025624186624879407'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/04/thinking-about-bud.html' title='Thinking About Bud'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-427182406790223458</id><published>2010-04-22T14:24:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-07-31T18:01:48.615-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Immersive Python</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/04/hb2h-hb2m.html&quot;&gt;We blitzed through a lot of Python&lt;/a&gt; in three days. I knew STScI was deeply into NumPy but didn&#39;t really get it about Pyfits &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/04/python-gig.html&quot;&gt;until I got here&lt;/a&gt;. FITS is a file format used by astronomers around the world. &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;These files contain a lot of the imagery from Hubble, which dumps data to New Mexico, from whence it bounces off another satellite to the Goddard Space Center, thence it feeds into STScI here in Baltimore for archiving and analysis.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Various data processing pipelines then take the data through transformations to enhance the information and accommodate for idiosyncrasies, anomalies, other factors. The delicate instruments are in perpetual need of fine tuning and recalibration.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Clients will often get both the raw data heading into the pipeline, as well as the processed results coming out the far end.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The Hubble is always repointing this way and that as it circles Earth every 96 minutes. It uses gyroscopes to do this, not retro rockets. Astronomers compete for precious time on this always busy, tightly scheduled space telescope.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/427182406790223458'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/427182406790223458'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/04/immersive-python.html' title='Immersive Python'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2533024714715807789</id><published>2010-04-15T11:33:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-04-20T15:16:45.288-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Cramming and Cleaning</title><content type='html'>I&#39;ve been looking at &quot;cramming and cleaning&quot; as two of my principal activities of late.  &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;ve got &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/04/python-gig.html&quot;&gt;a teaching gig&lt;/a&gt; coming up, so feel a need to cram.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The other challenge is digging out from under a pile of stuff in a respectful manner.  I didn&#39;t throw away my old notebooks (yet), and other media are gradually aggregating:  books to the &quot;time capsule,&quot; photographs to a room upstairs.  I&#39;m under orders from a sponsor not to rent a dumpster (bad for PR to take the easy way out).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Speaking of sponsors, my thanks to one of them for a cell phone upgrade.  The previous one was providing &quot;half duplex&quot; some of the time (they could hear me, but I couldn&#39;t hear them).  This next one, an LG, used and still in good shape, is more both robust and includes the full keyboard I&#39;ve come to expect from the Samsung.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Given I lug a laptop or netbook, I&#39;m still not in the market for a busy &quot;apps phone&quot; with all the bling. Per &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2010/04/smart-bar-lcds.html&quot;&gt;my CSN writings&lt;/a&gt;, I tend to aim for bigger rather than smaller LCDs.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/05/hypertoons-from-csn.html&quot;&gt;Hypertoons on an iPhone&lt;/a&gt; might look cool though.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the nationalism thread (one of the subjects under study in this campus household), I&#39;ve been wondering about getting certain classes of student ID approved for trans-boarder traffic.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Some people, classified as refugees, have fallen through the cracks of the nation state system, find gaining citizenship (documentation) an almost impossible barrier.  A &quot;reboot city&quot; consisting of high turnover housing and skills training courses (like a college) might provide its graduates with student ID acceptable in at least some other locales.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Along these lines, I once &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/08/psf-posting.html&quot;&gt;made the suggestion&lt;/a&gt; on the PSF list, that &lt;i&gt;Python Nation&lt;/i&gt; (a 2nd world) issue passports.  These would be souvenir / gift shop items that one might get stamped at a Pycon or EuroPython or other venue.  The idea of actually using such a document to get through customs would actually be more prototypical of the &quot;virtual nations&quot; idea.  Yes, I see &quot;identity politics&quot; at work here; we&#39;re looking for ways to add freedoms, to improve the average global university experience.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;[ With all these gigabytes available, we should aim to start a thorough and helpful medical record for any new life, regardless of ethnicity or economic circumstances.  This would be an opportunity some might refuse, out of distrust or in obedience to some religious precept.  Better to refuse an opportunity than to not have it in the first place though.  Electronic medical records in some schemaless document management system (e.g Tokyo Cabinet) might make the most sense.]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As long as one&#39;s persistent veridical identity provides some kind of audit trail as borders get crossed, a lot of bureaucratic requirements will be satisfied.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A person with a valid passport and internationally certified student / faculty ID might use either. The Facebook-like chronology (perhaps of border crossings and nothing more), would show if both were linked to the same identity.  Scanning the ID retrieves the record within the custom agent&#39;s browser.  Iconic flags and decals would decorate the average tourist record.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Refugees with accepted documentation, yet still with no citizenship within any UN-recognized sovereignty, might nevertheless get opportunities to visit various campuses in the course of their work / study scenarios.  If Harvard had a satellite campus in Uganda, maybe Harvard students could go there using Harvard ID, just as Ugandans enrolling in Harvard through this satellite might thereby gain the credentials to visit Cambridge through a special gate at the airport.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A doctors without borders HQS in Siberia might offer valuable training opportunities, complete with airstrip.  You might not need a passport to go there through Russian airspace, by agreement with authorities.  Similar facilities and/or transit centers might dot the globe elsewhere.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Your chronofile might still show you&#39;d been there and elsewhere.  The average quality of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/10/on-tap.html&quot;&gt;the information on tap&lt;/a&gt; would actually be less sketchy than it is today. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We currently live in a dark time when the so-called &quot;undocumented&quot; (more Global U students) are provided with little to no practical recourse in the face of the same unrelenting pressures to move about the globe as those bringing the pilgrims to Plymouth Rock, others to destinations in the Middle East and so on.  People are not trees, are not &lt;i&gt;rooted&lt;/i&gt; so much as &lt;i&gt;routed&lt;/i&gt; by God&#39;s will (if you&#39;ll accept a religious moniker in this context -- how &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/04/globalization.html&quot;&gt;many pilgrims&lt;/a&gt; think of their leadings).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of &lt;i&gt;Doctors Without Borders&lt;/i&gt;, my congratulations to &lt;i&gt;Vino Vixens&lt;/i&gt; on Powell for hosting a fundraiser for this group the other night.&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4511219759/&quot; title=&quot;Lindsey Walker and Amy Bleu by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2302/4511219759_a5db4eac05_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; alt=&quot;Lindsey Walker and Amy Bleu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4511219759/&quot; title=&quot;Lindsey Walker and Amy Bleu by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;  style=&quot;font-size:small;&quot;&gt;:: musicians at work ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2533024714715807789'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2533024714715807789'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/04/cramming-and-cleaning.html' title='Cramming and Cleaning'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2302/4511219759_a5db4eac05_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5989229342104789785</id><published>2010-04-07T09:03:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-04-07T16:12:00.562-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2010.4.7</title><content type='html'>We learned about broadband under &quot;lawyer-capitalism&quot; (as our mentor and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/02/valentines-day-2006.html&quot;&gt;Medal of Freedom winner&lt;/a&gt; calls it).  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/03/why-we-fight-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;President Eisenhower called it the &quot;military-industrial complex&quot;&lt;/a&gt; and thought it might destroy the USA we had known.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The USA has some of the slowest Internet at the highest rates anywhere, thanks to the FCC, Supreme Court etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Other less backward parts of the world are creating their next generation of telecommunications with fiber instead of copper, leaving the USA in the dust.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The private companies controlling the cable franchises have not kept pace, have been turning the Internet into a one-way service for delivering movies to idiot boxes while clamping down hard on competing users and service providers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Google has been planning a few fiber-based test beds featuring a two-way gigabit service that would be open platform, shared with local companies kicked off the cable delivery system by the FCC.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The FCC lost its jurisdictional mandate yesterday in some dimension.  However, I had another meeting to attend so was unable to chronicle more details.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our speaker works for the City of Portland, which has been resisting this dying form of capitalism, hoping to open up the infrastructure to more players.  The concentration of media in a fewer hands goes against the grain of the Oregonian psyche.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5989229342104789785'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5989229342104789785'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/04/wanderers-201047.html' title='Wanderers 2010.4.7'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>