<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423</id><updated>2025-02-25T12:10:50.607-08:00</updated><category term="clojure"/><category term="FOSS"/><category term="http://www.blogger.com/img/blank.gif"/><title type='text'>Control Room</title><subtitle type='html'>Operation Spaceship Earth </subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=26'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=1&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default?start-index=51&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1777</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>26</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6524765066401234116</id><published>2024-11-19T22:39:00.007-08:00</published><updated>2024-11-20T08:19:41.310-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Draft Text</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/PhsvqbCIaAs?si=aJGNsACRM-K-I5LN&quot; style=&quot;background-image: url(https://i.ytimg.com/vi/PhsvqbCIaAs/hqdefault.jpg);&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Given I’m of the Quaker persuasion (there’s a more formal name) my angle on politics is who cheerleads wars? These are the ones I’m biased to disown, but I train myself to hear their arguments, partly so I understand what I’m up against. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Usually people who cheerlead for war are coming from a victim mindset, which typically involves wanting vengeance and redress, fantasizing about having someone get their comeuppance and so forth. That’s the pattern. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Does this mean Quakers don’t play victim? Of course we do. Speaking as a victim is like a tense in the language, akin to the subjunctive.&amp;nbsp;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Quakerism is more a monkey-bars / jungle gym of potentially beneficial workout practices, doing committee work, than it is a geopolitical ideology.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Hatched in the 1600s, it knows nothing of many 21st Century obsessions. Yet committee work in support of a Meeting (a kind of business) remains an important opportunity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Work out in a Quaker gym, so to speak, and you’ll probably become a more effective hotelier or restaurateur, because you were already not an avatar of violence, and therefore receptive to our teachings.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;However, if you’re an advocate for war, yet wish the attention of our Overseers (supervisors), don’t presume that your victimhood will go unchallenged, if indeed that’s what’s driving your despicable warmongering.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/6524765066401234116/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/6524765066401234116' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6524765066401234116'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6524765066401234116'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/11/draft-text.html' title='Draft Text'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/PhsvqbCIaAs/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4466716804216827453</id><published>2024-11-17T21:10:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2024-11-19T22:17:58.778-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Cultagory Theory (School of Tomorrow)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/Uh2HNlpmZdE?si=uYz0l7WPmVZDQlYd&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the minds of some fans, presuming fans, the above might seem a bold new direction, in terms of stepping onto the world stage. But for me it&#39;s more a tying off loose ends, as I&#39;ve got these long running themes I&#39;ve made some waves about, and now want to further contextualize, while I&#39;m around to do so.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;However, I&#39;m not denying there&#39;s new content. The &quot;USA OS&quot; meme has burgeoned and I&#39;ve been in meetings about it. My School of Tomorrow curriculum has come together more tightly.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;On the matter of where and how to introduce cryptography, I want to keep &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsa.gov/History/Cryptologic-History/Historical-Figures/Historical-Figures-View/Article/1623028/elizebeth-s-friedman/&quot;&gt;Elizebeth Friedman&lt;/a&gt; one of the portals and her crusade against &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohibition.themobmuseum.org/the-history/the-rise-of-organized-crime/rum-running/&quot;&gt;the rumrunners&lt;/a&gt;. Glenn Stockton educated me about this chapter. He&#39;d been a cryptanalyst (a code breaker) himself and during his stint with the NSA, Elizebeth&#39;s husband William&#39;s works, which she&#39;d help organize, were still classified.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The Roaring 20s, Prohibition, and Bucky Fuller&#39;s experiences with radio, including encryption, sets up a&amp;nbsp; prequel chapter to WW2, with Alan Turing and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Martians-Science-Physicists-Changed-Twentieth/dp/0195365569/ref=sr_1_1&quot;&gt;the Martians of Science&lt;/a&gt; (see Istvan Hargittai&#39;s book). The Vienna Circle features prominently as well, for its contributions to logic, music, and psychoanalysis. We pick up on Fuller&#39;s remarks about Freud and the importance of the invisible, relating to the metaphysical.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;From Freud we jump to Bernays and those Adam Curtis documentaries about the powers of persuasion and their importance in manufacturing consent. Now that Natural Language Processing has shown us ways to model word embeddings by means of a vectorized Hilbert Space, we&#39;re better able to appreciate &quot;tensegrity&quot; as Fuller meant it.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/4466716804216827453/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/4466716804216827453' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4466716804216827453'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4466716804216827453'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/11/cultagory-theory-school-of-tomorrow.html' title='Cultagory Theory (School of Tomorrow)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/Uh2HNlpmZdE/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-6895078514321569627</id><published>2024-11-14T11:16:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-08T18:32:38.031-08:00</updated><title type='text'>21st Century Data Science</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhtvKT11GArtGUJ2QA8SIJHq8TmvX6mP9f68oF-nwvb__5WK949TvEeLgcnV-pgoogg_23J1-4LqBLNhuz5mBIrI9e4FN_mTpExT79dT-8bk6MXJotEiz7usPdWtMfgL2ykWJYnHzui5kcDvmijK2RJMQg-tscrFkqhvgtlDgmDbJVmYbs4x6XO/s1144/tibet_3.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1144&quot; data-original-width=&quot;912&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhtvKT11GArtGUJ2QA8SIJHq8TmvX6mP9f68oF-nwvb__5WK949TvEeLgcnV-pgoogg_23J1-4LqBLNhuz5mBIrI9e4FN_mTpExT79dT-8bk6MXJotEiz7usPdWtMfgL2ykWJYnHzui5kcDvmijK2RJMQg-tscrFkqhvgtlDgmDbJVmYbs4x6XO/w319-h400/tibet_3.png&quot; width=&quot;319&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got to Princeton in 1976, graduating 1980, the stats department was already using APL to teach stats. I wasn&#39;t taking any stats but was looking over the shoulders of classmates, and for sure APL looked interesting, so I tackled that. APL = A Programming Language, by Kenneth Iverson, then at Harvard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays I&#39;m in that same realm, laying foundations in basic Python for ascending the data science mountain, a metaphor I&#39;ll use, and reminiscent of the &quot;Calculus Mountain&quot; I&#39;d often decry on Math Forum, ala Andrew Hacker&#39;s &lt;i&gt;The Math Myth&lt;/i&gt;. Calculus Mountain is abused by admin cullers to separate people from their dreams.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So couldn&#39;t Data Science Mountain be used just as abusively? Surely it could be. Depends on the school, the curriculum. My approach is to encourage many options, many pathways, posed to a consumer willing to self educate (that&#39;s idealistic, I realize).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a high schooler prefers a discrete math route, such as statistics, abet that with more number and group theory, some programming, and accredit these cohorts as college ready. If their discipline requires calculus, let the discipline teach it the way it needs its students to learn it, as it comes in many flavors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, tackling programming has become closer to taking up an instrument, a more broadly spread skill. In this case you&#39;re the music composer, with ways of making the music loop (repeat) or flow conditionally and interactively..&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The musician is in the composer role in other words, whereas the instrument plays itself (like a player piano), at superhuman speeds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And why should only electrical or electronics engineers learn the flute?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Obviously the question is rhetorical, the point being there&#39;s no reason stats can&#39;t be an entre into computer programming, and in fact stats have provided such a doorway since mainframes serving universities became available. The big corporations needed to keep churning out future staff. They would make their donations in the form of hardware. The PC revolution followed the same pattern, with many schools receiving tax deductible equipment donations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Princeton had APL terminals scattered all over, including in my dorm (Princeton Inn) and at the Firestone Library. I taught myself APL, and much later J, also with Dr. Iverson on the team. I was following from Portland, writing web pages on that language, some of which Iverson saw as he helped spot some typos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;APL and J are what we now call &quot;array based languages&quot;, such as R and BQN. Operations are performed on n-dimensional arrays, treating the latter as atomic, whereas in conventional computer languages, one has to write busy looping code to hit all the cells in the matrix, one by one.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;The Python community got busy a while back adding array-based packages, such as numpy (Travis Oliphant, 2005) and pandas (&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #111111;&quot;&gt;Wes McKinney, 2008)&lt;/span&gt;, which allowed it to stay competitive in the APL-friendly array-based arena.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Python might seem less pithy than say APL or BQN, as it sticks with the ascii-qwerty keyboard and prefers a more English wordy syntax, even though Guido himself (Python’s inventor) is a Dutchman.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My students come through Python to the tabular data structure of rows and columns we&#39;re so used to from ancient times. Ledgers of rows and columns are in no way a new invention. Computer code becomes a way of automating the job of ledger keepers tasked with keeping those ledgers accurate and up to date, once their composer-designer has orchestrated the perfect system (I’m being idealistic again)..&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Equipped with these tools, a data scientists learns to lay pipe (metaphoric pipe) from where the sluices open, allowing raw data to flow in, through successive shaping, cleaning, cutting and patching operations that transform said data into something pristine, polished and suitable for the gods.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The gods, in this case, are the model makers of Machine Learning, where the models are like golden egg, crystal ball, magic flutes that predict (with some likelihood) the future. Data science is about inferring and predicting, and also about sensing and measuring. How small a data sample might I get away with, and still reliably track the action? That question becomes a topic for deep analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where data science meets machine learning is where Artificial Intelligence gets much of its nutrition, in terms of achieving practical results, such as when performing text to voice, voice to text, text to graphics, text to video, and extruding synthetic suggestive strands from the LLMs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those famous deep learning neural network algorithms fit in here. Welcome to Hilbert Space. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data science is as much about data visualization (showing what’s so) &amp;nbsp;as about stochastic extrapolation (predicting what’s next). Data science is about providing dashboards, often updated in real time, meaning a set or combination of instruments sufficient to monitor and perhaps influence or control a situation (I’m bundling the car steering wheel and pedals in with the dashboard instruments).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh7RxxYOOlbDX66s42t3yyVQcyznpHaFzwwr0s1tWeAcXrglwnQnKReh1KI5cONw64spiSnEVu4jNQ3Zyta1Yo3isTA7D_LL7Qhkb_PIQ_tAgG1WHDjU9_1l_erU5rGOH03RoHohRZlpbchyApBh9nHyQNHMKSgeZwcIFWvrBnkOD9O91Y7mWGN/s618/Screen%20Shot%202024-11-07%20at%2011.03.39%20AM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;618&quot; data-original-width=&quot;477&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh7RxxYOOlbDX66s42t3yyVQcyznpHaFzwwr0s1tWeAcXrglwnQnKReh1KI5cONw64spiSnEVu4jNQ3Zyta1Yo3isTA7D_LL7Qhkb_PIQ_tAgG1WHDjU9_1l_erU5rGOH03RoHohRZlpbchyApBh9nHyQNHMKSgeZwcIFWvrBnkOD9O91Y7mWGN/w309-h400/Screen%20Shot%202024-11-07%20at%2011.03.39%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;309&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgvLhYw9QwgSSDL0UorJPdS5HanILEsffVnIPsETAdnizf2a0dqhEcJfmvSYopR9oyWZGPufg-n8NFWmj0kwmGGBoepZgg1kl6snGBrzR_bTgXF6g0bvUJXRIEVu_9O3uRM4wUJM61V-ZgvRNXc7LEXlDPkbBWh2bnbQuacHFuBdJ5WAPWX8K1a/s477/Screen%20Shot%202024-11-07%20at%2011.04.27%20AM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;219&quot; data-original-width=&quot;477&quot; height=&quot;147&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgvLhYw9QwgSSDL0UorJPdS5HanILEsffVnIPsETAdnizf2a0dqhEcJfmvSYopR9oyWZGPufg-n8NFWmj0kwmGGBoepZgg1kl6snGBrzR_bTgXF6g0bvUJXRIEVu_9O3uRM4wUJM61V-ZgvRNXc7LEXlDPkbBWh2bnbQuacHFuBdJ5WAPWX8K1a/s320/Screen%20Shot%202024-11-07%20at%2011.04.27%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data science is largely about anticipating the future based on the intelligent leveraging of what&#39;s known about the past.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikieducator.org/Digital_Math&quot;&gt;Heuristics for Teachers&lt;/a&gt; regarding my Silicon Forest Digital Math, the data science stuff mostly fits into my Casino Math, one of four realms.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Casino Math about risk, taking a gamble, rolling the dice, and developing winning strategies, designing games and simulations, imparting best practices and training chief risk officers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Silicon Forest is in the North American Pacific Northwest where casinos play an important role in the economy. Next to Casino Math we have Supermarket Math, Martian Math and Neolithic Math.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s true about learning basic programming is one cannot help but butt up against well-worn math topics such as: sets, set operations, number sequences (rule based), random numbers, primes, fibonacci numbers, cryptography, the web, history of the internet, and so on.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A data scientist is someone becoming fluent with a lot of lore, especially as the discipline becomes increasingly about representing data sets geospatially and considering Planet Earth the relevant display object.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Landlubber math gets augmented with lat/long and spherical trig. The data scientist is likewise a geographer, taking advantage of what GIS/GPS has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhLf56IqzDwXxbNotNB2DjdEDLEJp3WJ1kQ72CxWO76IG_6pF0wZZJJ8l2akbntlu1cEfbl4f3iXH_07lP2ZULH9ommxLiUmcMfnHcMvt8gHbyWwesoV8JEJsxEUVK5uNj5nyLMuUdqE0auVESuzWyA9ePrIZ6CVLdAsf5YYETWb1wwqQuzYD0_/s1920/Screen%20Shot%202024-11-07%20at%203.56.33%20PM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1080&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhLf56IqzDwXxbNotNB2DjdEDLEJp3WJ1kQ72CxWO76IG_6pF0wZZJJ8l2akbntlu1cEfbl4f3iXH_07lP2ZULH9ommxLiUmcMfnHcMvt8gHbyWwesoV8JEJsxEUVK5uNj5nyLMuUdqE0auVESuzWyA9ePrIZ6CVLdAsf5YYETWb1wwqQuzYD0_/s320/Screen%20Shot%202024-11-07%20at%203.56.33%20PM.png&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6895078514321569627'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/6895078514321569627'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/11/21st-century-data-science.html' title='21st Century Data Science'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhtvKT11GArtGUJ2QA8SIJHq8TmvX6mP9f68oF-nwvb__5WK949TvEeLgcnV-pgoogg_23J1-4LqBLNhuz5mBIrI9e4FN_mTpExT79dT-8bk6MXJotEiz7usPdWtMfgL2ykWJYnHzui5kcDvmijK2RJMQg-tscrFkqhvgtlDgmDbJVmYbs4x6XO/s72-w319-h400-c/tibet_3.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3742227234025220009</id><published>2024-11-11T07:56:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2024-11-11T07:56:45.894-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Dorkbots or Dorks for Short</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjzKyzbpoodFW3xYSzyzCoRTlt0F1qOjribtyX5Xrjpi68otaO9ZAg-R-N12vryC87u2Ko0DAmujWsv6DRcoXMsbycKTrnCb5tUyMMj8biA3dc6LhOYZidKZa8e3LcjM9BXuPrPnzEWAeQiFNpye0JaJshSq_7FecoelGQrrzsuvfp2TwnqEdzB/s685/Screen%20Shot%202024-11-11%20at%207.52.15%20AM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img a=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;672&quot; data-original-width=&quot;685&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjzKyzbpoodFW3xYSzyzCoRTlt0F1qOjribtyX5Xrjpi68otaO9ZAg-R-N12vryC87u2Ko0DAmujWsv6DRcoXMsbycKTrnCb5tUyMMj8biA3dc6LhOYZidKZa8e3LcjM9BXuPrPnzEWAeQiFNpye0JaJshSq_7FecoelGQrrzsuvfp2TwnqEdzB/w400-h393/Screen%20Shot%202024-11-11%20at%207.52.15%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgmau21CYPsSuEnZBRpkw2YQALARKU8q_Tx5J5n3udoO-JeXpKZAFg9zMEzMR6M2r8l_2fCQfzdxVFuoaDpVCHuDVFfp8EwPUoGCdsUr4d39hf6HRlalS8zoAKmtJed6oZ0A1DsmVI107GCLmrEO6jxAgQePMkmFICoshQTpWrz4z7ufOdUcQ2U/s685/Screen%20Shot%202024-11-11%20at%207.51.45%20AM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;342&quot; data-original-width=&quot;685&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgmau21CYPsSuEnZBRpkw2YQALARKU8q_Tx5J5n3udoO-JeXpKZAFg9zMEzMR6M2r8l_2fCQfzdxVFuoaDpVCHuDVFfp8EwPUoGCdsUr4d39hf6HRlalS8zoAKmtJed6oZ0A1DsmVI107GCLmrEO6jxAgQePMkmFICoshQTpWrz4z7ufOdUcQ2U/w400-h200/Screen%20Shot%202024-11-11%20at%207.51.45%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3742227234025220009'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3742227234025220009'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/11/dorkbots-or-dorks-for-short.html' title='Dorkbots or Dorks for Short'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjzKyzbpoodFW3xYSzyzCoRTlt0F1qOjribtyX5Xrjpi68otaO9ZAg-R-N12vryC87u2Ko0DAmujWsv6DRcoXMsbycKTrnCb5tUyMMj8biA3dc6LhOYZidKZa8e3LcjM9BXuPrPnzEWAeQiFNpye0JaJshSq_7FecoelGQrrzsuvfp2TwnqEdzB/s72-w400-h393-c/Screen%20Shot%202024-11-11%20at%207.52.15%20AM.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1935753664134385906</id><published>2024-11-08T19:26:00.004-08:00</published><updated>2024-11-08T19:30:12.895-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Isolationism</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEht7XJ29LLuTuu4nplN1JfYqBFZqCB9k2d0FxFMOggE09AXk7sgfXj9eaJjapmHEda1Y8vGVpYXG3k7P0ycqsgQUJqL3IgZwoGdmd4SqhY_v5zZ12hyP7Z6L5fM29-VjAv0lvZtdycrIq2gMEWRPLeuYM-Y2UKi9WpiA9a4sjHz8cA9X6-6rbUq/s1144/tibet_1.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1144&quot; data-original-width=&quot;912&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEht7XJ29LLuTuu4nplN1JfYqBFZqCB9k2d0FxFMOggE09AXk7sgfXj9eaJjapmHEda1Y8vGVpYXG3k7P0ycqsgQUJqL3IgZwoGdmd4SqhY_v5zZ12hyP7Z6L5fM29-VjAv0lvZtdycrIq2gMEWRPLeuYM-Y2UKi9WpiA9a4sjHz8cA9X6-6rbUq/w319-h400/tibet_1.png&quot; width=&quot;319&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hear a lot of talking head pundits expressing their frustration with &quot;isolationist&quot; tendencies within the American electorate, as if blundering on the world stage, pistols drawn, shooting at anything that moves, weren&#39;t a perfect recipe for self-isolating.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t think of a more isolationist regime than this outgoing one run by President Blinken (not a typo). Threatening the world with sanctions or worse is no way to make friends. To alienate everyone else is to isolate oneself: these are basic facts of English grammar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The real issue is the world needs &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/11/increasing-military-iq.html&quot;&gt;high IQ solutions&lt;/a&gt; whereas bombing and rubblizing is low IQ barbaric. We see a lot of throwback Planet of the Apes behavior, as outgoing boomers act out their tired old fantasies, juvenile and retro though they be. No one can stop them apparently. The endless cycle of revenge, punch and counterpunch, keeps the melodrama churning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whereas the males of the planet deserve better, the oldsters still see them as cannon fodder, expendable, unto &quot;the last Ukrainian&quot; as they say. The IDF is likewise full of males and females alike who never signed up to become expendable extras in someone else&#39;s grand plan. Hearts and minds are still relevant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As always, we need to draw the line between respect and fear. People may fear being carpet bombed by B52s, but I can&#39;t think of anyone I know who thinks carpet bombing is the answer, or has respect for those that do. My inner circle isn&#39;t that degenerate. Too bad if yours is. I&#39;m not an isolationist in that way, even if you are.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1935753664134385906'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1935753664134385906'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/11/isolationism.html' title='Isolationism'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEht7XJ29LLuTuu4nplN1JfYqBFZqCB9k2d0FxFMOggE09AXk7sgfXj9eaJjapmHEda1Y8vGVpYXG3k7P0ycqsgQUJqL3IgZwoGdmd4SqhY_v5zZ12hyP7Z6L5fM29-VjAv0lvZtdycrIq2gMEWRPLeuYM-Y2UKi9WpiA9a4sjHz8cA9X6-6rbUq/s72-w319-h400-c/tibet_1.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5093144187018269973</id><published>2024-11-04T09:58:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2024-11-04T09:58:45.169-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Yurt Village</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54117266279/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Biofirm&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Biofirm&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54117266279_4955e37dfb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;399&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54116073362/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Screen Shot 2024-11-03 at 8.33.58 AM&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54116073362_af291475d4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;418&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2024-11-03 at 8.33.58 AM&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5093144187018269973'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5093144187018269973'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/11/yurt-village.html' title='Yurt Village'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3360023372702170872</id><published>2024-11-01T08:34:00.005-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T08:34:52.069-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Hardball City</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54108616812/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Hardball City 2&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Hardball City 2&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54108616812_3a62c6dbbf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54109483781/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;hardball_city_3&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;hardball_city_3&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54109483781_52ea1b2295.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54109741328/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;hardball_city_1&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;hardball_city_1&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54109741328_4b126cc620.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3360023372702170872'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3360023372702170872'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/11/hardball-city.html' title='Hardball City'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7906700920437058437</id><published>2024-10-29T07:30:00.005-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T07:21:54.739-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Ant Works</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhSSPc5WIhP7MO2D6E3FSUIh7AMk9wte0Gp7Jgort3V2hSkYDS8OkaNtG_yNkhOq21XJFnu6pT5mB6JhuXSKhcdBupl58tk16IUR3wC7PwrPHBDqB79FkeFRjDyXWbwrvAx7dFVWwLfqLCrU6QfY2hASxeFsu35anFj9BfppHEDu9xqvebD9khk/s1144/flappers_1.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1144&quot; data-original-width=&quot;912&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhSSPc5WIhP7MO2D6E3FSUIh7AMk9wte0Gp7Jgort3V2hSkYDS8OkaNtG_yNkhOq21XJFnu6pT5mB6JhuXSKhcdBupl58tk16IUR3wC7PwrPHBDqB79FkeFRjDyXWbwrvAx7dFVWwLfqLCrU6QfY2hASxeFsu35anFj9BfppHEDu9xqvebD9khk/w319-h400/flappers_1.png&quot; width=&quot;319&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My School of Tomorrow, in terms of curriculum, is not trying to be all things to all people. On the spectrum, it’s further from For Everyman (mainstream) and closer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/10/keeping-it-quirky.html&quot;&gt;Quirky Kirby&lt;/a&gt; (one guy’s take).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, in the course of learning more about Zelda Fitzgerald from her grandson, as his guest, I was constructing a mental timeline of that time between the wars, WW1 and WW2. H.G. Wells came to New York City for a confab on how to prevent further warring, post-WW1.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He’s writing in the first person, as a journalist on the ground, at the scene. He mentions his giddiness, the effect of being in a booming city, quite different from the mood in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In looking for something to quote from those writings, I came across his &lt;i&gt;Empire of the Ants&lt;/i&gt;. That got me to reading and listening. He’d become friends with Joseph Conrad. Here we’re going up the Amazon to battle smart ants. Which takes me to ants more generally and the M4W “codacombs”. Ants, the many species thereof, is a core topic in that tunnel system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Zelda, what’s coming together is the graph connecting women’s suffrage, Dora Marsden, Prohibition, Art Deco, flappers, Great Gatsby, roaring 20s, H.G. Wells, feminism, Nick Consoletti’s mom, (a French woman who embodied independence — she comes later on the timeline).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orson Welles, Hearst, Homer Davenport, Silverton, New Thought, ETs, UAPs, science fiction, Martian Math… now add in all the Bucky stuff. We’re talking about a time period (the 1900s basically) consisting of partially overlapping world lines (time tunnels, scenarios).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgxLc-avt02DpwiGrK3otTX_h1CnW41JpWDORmgpmUyid0pVnbTqwmVH4BGLBGpjB_Tjk_DxhDd1LRffZnKkJObvWcIt50CT8h0PymwvOkgQAMSAyK2x-U5i6CttNibdfHSUbiqjPeokHlk5cfPMQMU4rAb42sqiv74usv-Yc7ssP4-2_Y1wZTI/s679/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-29%20at%208.29.29%20AM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;655&quot; data-original-width=&quot;679&quot; height=&quot;386&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgxLc-avt02DpwiGrK3otTX_h1CnW41JpWDORmgpmUyid0pVnbTqwmVH4BGLBGpjB_Tjk_DxhDd1LRffZnKkJObvWcIt50CT8h0PymwvOkgQAMSAyK2x-U5i6CttNibdfHSUbiqjPeokHlk5cfPMQMU4rAb42sqiv74usv-Yc7ssP4-2_Y1wZTI/w400-h386/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-29%20at%208.29.29%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7906700920437058437'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7906700920437058437'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/10/ant-works.html' title='Ant Works'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhSSPc5WIhP7MO2D6E3FSUIh7AMk9wte0Gp7Jgort3V2hSkYDS8OkaNtG_yNkhOq21XJFnu6pT5mB6JhuXSKhcdBupl58tk16IUR3wC7PwrPHBDqB79FkeFRjDyXWbwrvAx7dFVWwLfqLCrU6QfY2hASxeFsu35anFj9BfppHEDu9xqvebD9khk/s72-w319-h400-c/flappers_1.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3758942385027241401</id><published>2024-10-25T08:24:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-25T08:25:45.957-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Casino Math (USA OS)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgoNDV_ehCGHocDGuZk0BNkoY2s2rf-Mw-yo8RGul1gKYNgvFEH8xGOZazVD0Yp7NPZdjb9qOFyXO2uXq35Us0dKgSB9dXoBJwGAYxdCPbSVdWP_xTsr6wde4IAn48JrtnUDTA-uA0eDGzU7C4BSXUqn91jkEiVkmXthVoGVFTsgf5AdMqdas7b/s1024/usa_os_66.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgoNDV_ehCGHocDGuZk0BNkoY2s2rf-Mw-yo8RGul1gKYNgvFEH8xGOZazVD0Yp7NPZdjb9qOFyXO2uXq35Us0dKgSB9dXoBJwGAYxdCPbSVdWP_xTsr6wde4IAn48JrtnUDTA-uA0eDGzU7C4BSXUqn91jkEiVkmXthVoGVFTsgf5AdMqdas7b/w400-h400/usa_os_66.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgWo5M_rMv5WyxTA8esRXUAAoxkdq2KNKhVcvcLW4N5by7vlElHqc7h77nYJWpp-16TIK156tqztO1l655gtvOKAhmvnDHUaw929jO_HSZIGVziUVa88XhgsLiQmAuhOJAn-I21p497PMEuwGJxUDWKJnk4JuZ8nDaslbBLhyphenhyphen9fLicsQuf_OpTh/s1024/usa_os_67.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgWo5M_rMv5WyxTA8esRXUAAoxkdq2KNKhVcvcLW4N5by7vlElHqc7h77nYJWpp-16TIK156tqztO1l655gtvOKAhmvnDHUaw929jO_HSZIGVziUVa88XhgsLiQmAuhOJAn-I21p497PMEuwGJxUDWKJnk4JuZ8nDaslbBLhyphenhyphen9fLicsQuf_OpTh/w400-h400/usa_os_67.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3758942385027241401'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3758942385027241401'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/10/casino-math-usa-os.html' title='Casino Math (USA OS)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgoNDV_ehCGHocDGuZk0BNkoY2s2rf-Mw-yo8RGul1gKYNgvFEH8xGOZazVD0Yp7NPZdjb9qOFyXO2uXq35Us0dKgSB9dXoBJwGAYxdCPbSVdWP_xTsr6wde4IAn48JrtnUDTA-uA0eDGzU7C4BSXUqn91jkEiVkmXthVoGVFTsgf5AdMqdas7b/s72-w400-h400-c/usa_os_66.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-286407584433879648</id><published>2024-10-23T14:28:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-23T14:54:28.982-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Tractor Math</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54089196149/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;STEAM Powered BASKET Tractor&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;STEAM Powered BASKET Tractor&quot; height=&quot;306&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54089196149_789a231905.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Tractor Math&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

You may have seen our BASKET tractor before, in another context. We were saying BASKET meets STEAM, which we&#39;re saying here too, but we want to put the tractor to work, pulling a mower that plants Unicode seeds.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Lest you suppose Unicode is something proprietary or underground, on the contrary it&#39;s a public standard and your emoji are encoded therein. Meaning when we do tractor canvases, one could say fields as if seen from high up, from a drone&#39;s vantage point, we get to paint with a full palette, anything within the range of fonts used, which may be many.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/29832307687/in/album-72177720296706479&quot; title=&quot;Unicode on Windows&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Unicode on Windows&quot; height=&quot;345&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/1847/29832307687_0aee594ec5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

We&#39;ve used our Unicode and/or ASCII art output to show the Mandelbrot Set, to write simple messages, to write out patches of skulls for a Halloween greeting card. What I&#39;ve suggested to some Facebook friends they go to Youtube and look for my Lightning Talk on &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/iBvd5gU2sgY&quot;&gt;Pythonic Andragogy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. Quite a few of you have maybe already seen it, or were even there at the time, in Santa Clara, large meeting hall, at a Pycon.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Another Youtube I have out there, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/MH49zLTeQsE&quot;&gt;Leveraging Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, likewise gets into a lot of tractor imagery. And yet back then I had yet to drive one, a gap in my knowledge base since partially rectified.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54089091183/in/album-72177720296706479&quot; title=&quot;Looking Up an Emoji by Hex Code&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Looking Up an Emoji by Hex Code&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54089091183_57deb60b76.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

So what&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.io/g/synergeo/message/2763&quot;&gt;the BASKET stuff&lt;/a&gt;, even if my Just Use It! Mandelbrot tractor doesn&#39;t use it?&amp;nbsp;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;One of our main mentors around here was into dissecting polyhedrons in terms of his own vocabulary of particular tetrahedron shaped modules, irregular, relatively sized. A &amp;amp; B have the same volume, T &amp;amp; E have the same shape, while S seems an outlier, and there you have it: BEAST.&amp;nbsp;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;However a couple K-named guys, Koski especially, but also Kirby, ended up with a 7.5 volumed rhombic triacontahedron we wanted to emphasize and came to the conclusion that:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;(a) BEAST could be rendered less scary by adding a K and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;(b) the K was warranted, because the 7.5 RT, three halves times the 5.0 RT, holds hands the the 6.0 RD (rhombic dodecahedron).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The K therefore shares the shape of the ET (so KET or TEK is a family) in being 1/120th of an RT, 60 left handed, 60 right handed.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/286407584433879648'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/286407584433879648'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/10/tractor-math.html' title='Tractor Math'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-4529154432184366211</id><published>2024-10-21T10:48:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T11:01:35.091-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Walking a Plank</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEirh5_l1dXmXR3WpLZTDDE5TYXFZvwJU_To4UFdKs39XGQ3zqiAolKqtgy1DWJKg774xZmcJZSTnallkwvo6VrNPTWlJcEMGKFQx7c735qR2vTMbSUBAVyHk5AZElW9iXDJY4YwyzNc_3RMcy-zPb-UsJ0DSpYQtAZSLkHpYyLSNNWOwZbOzQ-r/s826/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-20%20at%206.20.24%20AM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;826&quot; data-original-width=&quot;769&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEirh5_l1dXmXR3WpLZTDDE5TYXFZvwJU_To4UFdKs39XGQ3zqiAolKqtgy1DWJKg774xZmcJZSTnallkwvo6VrNPTWlJcEMGKFQx7c735qR2vTMbSUBAVyHk5AZElW9iXDJY4YwyzNc_3RMcy-zPb-UsJ0DSpYQtAZSLkHpYyLSNNWOwZbOzQ-r/w373-h400/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-20%20at%206.20.24%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;373&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One of &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2020/08/pirate-party-planks.html&quot;&gt;our party planks&lt;/a&gt; is to not see Russia or China as adversaries in military terms but as competitors in how well they treat their civilians.&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When civilians have high living standards you get a military that&#39;s idealistic and not just in it for the job. The poorer the health of your middle class, the less the military seems to have standards (or honor). The privilege to not be in the military is what creates esprit de corps for those choosing this lineage of decorated service and rank.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So Nixon and Khrushchev were essentially agreeing to move their adversarial relationship to a different register: how well did their respective societies meet the needs of motherhood? A primal question. The so-called&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://english.elpais.com/culture/2023-01-25/the-day-when-an-ordinary-kitchen-became-a-stage-for-the-cold-war.html&quot;&gt;Kitchen Debate&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;was a welcome reprieve from the way more juvenile comparing of military dick size.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who had the better recipes and, as important, the appliances and ingredients to pull them off? &quot;What&#39;s the price of saffron in your commie supermarkets?&quot; the Nixonites could ask, sassily, suggesting that Americans had better prices on saffron.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So we of the Pirate Party might congratulate both Khrushchev and Nixon for &quot;walking the plank&quot; (hah hah) when it comes to being smart about relations with both Russians and Chinese. Who woulda thought, way back then, that we&#39;d have devolved to the sloping forehead neocon pre-human stage?&amp;nbsp; Of course that&#39;s propaganda. Pirates jeer and sneer a lot.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4529154432184366211'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/4529154432184366211'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/10/walking-plank.html' title='Walking a Plank'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEirh5_l1dXmXR3WpLZTDDE5TYXFZvwJU_To4UFdKs39XGQ3zqiAolKqtgy1DWJKg774xZmcJZSTnallkwvo6VrNPTWlJcEMGKFQx7c735qR2vTMbSUBAVyHk5AZElW9iXDJY4YwyzNc_3RMcy-zPb-UsJ0DSpYQtAZSLkHpYyLSNNWOwZbOzQ-r/s72-w373-h400-c/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-20%20at%206.20.24%20AM.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-173499294329186822</id><published>2024-10-19T19:58:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-19T20:29:09.521-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Applied Philosophy</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhIw1qtlI33qSqbISXt7DWzBT4wOhY8pFhg-m4EtmFSyW52fSHv1HBSEZsgMmwyjsTCdM8lBUvzg4TWdtiu57N69TvtZzGZOvPb6VfTZVXgBquV4GCfPqcsE3KogZFuUrhu-oN-jijMkK_rApozCoCYNJXHiHlocSQWGt2Eylo3ZPwwY7ydJXDb/s1630/IMG_0278.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1630&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1208&quot; height=&quot;492&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhIw1qtlI33qSqbISXt7DWzBT4wOhY8pFhg-m4EtmFSyW52fSHv1HBSEZsgMmwyjsTCdM8lBUvzg4TWdtiu57N69TvtZzGZOvPb6VfTZVXgBquV4GCfPqcsE3KogZFuUrhu-oN-jijMkK_rApozCoCYNJXHiHlocSQWGt2Eylo3ZPwwY7ydJXDb/w364-h492/IMG_0278.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;364&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;The Pragmatists had a healthy “when in Rome” attitude and unlike dogmatists, could hold more than one paradigm in mind when pursuing an agenda. The upshot was 4D in the Hilbert Space sense got entangled with 4D in the Martian (or ET) sense in ways that inspired humorous juxtapositions. In science fiction, the Earthlings and Martians cross-fertilized, if not genetically at first, then certainly memetically (i.e. epigenetically). Think of &amp;nbsp;Jesuits meeting Chinese in Marco Polo days, egghead to egghead. What a feast.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So a Rorty admirer (a Princeton pragmatist, Wittgenstein infused), fresh from reading &lt;i&gt;Achieving Our Country&lt;/i&gt;, could appreciate such Hilbert Space word2vec equations as Left - Marx = Hegel + Whitman. Stuff like that. From Hegel we get the synergy of the dialectic: two opposing camps giving rise to something neither had predicted.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;From Whitman we get a vision of peacefully slumbering souls aboard a westward heading passenger train, arriving at our left coast 21st century Transcendentalism by a different route than trying to exorcize Marx from postmodernism (a quasi-impossible task, just ask Jordan Peterson).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The dialectic arose in the wake of Darwinism, which devolved into Social Darwinism and a workers over owners propaganda, versus an owners over workers rationale. Both sides presumed a contextualizing Malthusian context. Data scientists extrapolated from various exponential and linear curves, predicting dire consequences. Given the immanent food shortages, the workers and owners would have to sort it out quickly, may the fittest class win.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;What the sleepers didn’t realize at first was their train was bound for greater glory, in that these rickety Malthusian underpinnings were giving way to a more robust systems science. Human initiative could still make a difference and redirect energy investments according to more likely-to-work strategies. Pragmatism meets Transcendentalism, our latest hybrid.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/173499294329186822'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/173499294329186822'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/10/applied-philosophy.html' title='Applied Philosophy'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhIw1qtlI33qSqbISXt7DWzBT4wOhY8pFhg-m4EtmFSyW52fSHv1HBSEZsgMmwyjsTCdM8lBUvzg4TWdtiu57N69TvtZzGZOvPb6VfTZVXgBquV4GCfPqcsE3KogZFuUrhu-oN-jijMkK_rApozCoCYNJXHiHlocSQWGt2Eylo3ZPwwY7ydJXDb/s72-w364-h492-c/IMG_0278.jpeg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7030867854486938783</id><published>2024-10-16T05:07:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-22T21:36:40.382-07:00</updated><title type='text'>From the UN to VNs</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54070154382/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Reunion Banner&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Reunion Banner&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54070154382_7363594926.jpg&quot; width=&quot;439&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not the first to remark that the hallmark of USA nationalism, at the peak of American confidence (we can say hubris), post WW2, was its internationalism. American Express. Pan Am. TWA. The United Nations even. Liberalism embraced the UN but then the UN was in New York and seemed plenty American. What had been American schools overseas (with that “A-word” in their name) became International schools (A became I). The American School of Manila (ASM) became the International School of Manila. That’s one that I attended (Class of 1976). We just held a reunion in Dallas, which I missed (I’ve been to one), but enjoyed vicariously through Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward and the whole nation-state system lacks much confidence, as when borders become too fluid, they simply snap, and then people don’t know if their citizenship means anything and they start to look for new roosts, perhaps within the bowels of an avuncular mega-corporation if such can be found. Become a salaryman first and a citizen a distant second; that’s one strategy I’ve seen. Survival being the goal of course. Many turn into refugees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Quaker sphere, we often speak of the refugees we’re always getting from other religions. Some megachurch will implode or explode, due to scandal or other loss of reputation, and families start looking for more ideological security. Unprogrammed Quakers pride themselves on how sparse a brainwashing one needs for Inner Light training. The ideological baggage is fairly lightweight and involves &lt;i&gt;doing&lt;/i&gt;, more than &lt;i&gt;believing&lt;/i&gt;. Join committees and run a business, the Meeting itself, with your peers, role modeling Good Order. See? Easy peasy. Take your inner light training out into the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However Quaker meetings are not all encompassing when it comes to one’s lifestyle. They don’t provide livelihoods directly, meaning committee positions are unpaid, up through and including the Clerk (like head pastor). All these roles rotate, if it’s your typical functional Meeting, with Nominating Committee recruiting a next cast, for Business Meeting to approve.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So Friends still need jobs, a source of income. We didn’t have UBI yet in 2024, although the old folks had their SSI (social security income) in many cases, in addition to whatever pension. Which is where citizenship comes in again. We’re back to nation-statehood, and ROI (return on investment).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What was eroding the UN were: fluid borders and the shaking loose of families from any security network called a nation. We’d lost nations before, such as Prussia. Plus they had often drastically changed in size (look at Lithuania).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But that kind of churning was a result of warring, and the whole point of the UN was to impose a freeze. Let’s give our states true self determination, post-colonial self respect, and focus on development instead of warring. That was the vision.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But in 2024 we’re &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/10/ghost-nations.html&quot;&gt;back to churning&lt;/a&gt;. The head of Israel is saying Israel’s neighbors are not real nations. Ukraine was unable to sustain its former unity. Yugoslavia had ominously disappeared in a rain of NATO bombing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To paraphrase the opening of &lt;i&gt;Grunch of Giants&lt;/i&gt;, the author wrote: “I could see from a young age that the nation-state system, as crafted, was not designed for a world that works, as the ethnicities would continue with their culture-clashing and refugees would be everywhere, as humans scrambled to survive aboard their little spaceship. So what I resolved to do, starting around 1927, is tell the world I was working for all humanity, messianic as that might have sounded, but I was thinking more through architecture than religious revival. Having put myself on the spot in that way, I would no doubt grow as a person.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fuller avoided cult leader status by joining the ranks of great writers, where one has fans more than followers. Here is where many will part company as they’ve checked out the writings in question and found &#39;em far from great. Here’s an engineer speaking in stilted terms, having never bothered to learn his mother tongue sufficiently, is often the reaction.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; is the kind of book an impatient reader slams shut, maybe because they’re not categorizing it correctly. Think of works by Joyce, Pound, David Foster Wallace… their writings were “experimental” in nature, a word Quakers also use. The difference is that Synergetics is consciously about focusing on generalized principles, meaning it’s designed to have pragmatic consequences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In response to a nation-state system likely headed for a train wreck, Fuller got to work in the early 1920s on a new mindset or framework, involving conceptual art informed by solid geometry. The UN building in New York could gaze upon a Geoscope in the East River, an illuminated global displaying global data. The whole of Manhattan might be domed over, saving on heating and cooling bills if you do the math, as it’s all about surface area to volume ratios. A city of skyscrapers is built like an old fashioned water heated radiator.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Would the Geoscope ever happen? No. Is New York domed over? No. So was Bucky a failure? No. This was conceptual art, working on the mind of the beholder. Instead of the Geoscope, we got Google Earth. And we do all live in domes: they’re called skulls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the crumbling of American self-confidence, typified by the shock and revulsion over the raging battlefields, killing fields, and slaughter zones, that sense of being rendered a powerless bystander, its version of globalism, its internationalism, crumbled as well.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UN had been a big part of that. The bright futurism it represented, a kind of globalism, was draining away, and with it went yesteryear’s brands of cosmopolitanism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The standard narrative of the time was a new “right wing” nationalism was springing up in an effort to save a crumbling system from complete collapse. This could only be accomplished by control over borders. The old timey boomer liberals, raised in the Age of Hubris, were vilified as holdover “leftists” which meant “globalist” in some distasteful way. Resentment of the younger, towards the older, was based on that sense of inheriting only failed, loser ideologies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a boomer myself, I saw Bucky as Boho, i.e. Bohemian, from a prior crop of Greenwich Village hipsters that he got to hang out with, Noguchi in particular (they were best friends). He had his cohort of eggheads and patrons, his Cold Warrior friends, both in and outside the Pentagon.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My generation came later, growing up through a time when Manifest Destiny was being challenged. The legacy of the colonial period, when Europe believed it owned the world (Doctrine of Discovery), had become burdensome on the United States. The conquest of the Philippines led to the General Lansdale era, of guerrilla warfare and counterinsurgency, mixed with narcotics trade as we called it. Capitalism’s Invisible Army.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having experienced American internationalism in its heyday as a youth, I could see the writing on the wall as well. As early as 8th grade, I was reading about the Club of Rome in dad’s &lt;i&gt;Futurist&lt;/i&gt;, and thinking about thinking globally while acting locally. I took it for granted that “thinking globally” was a thing. Didn’t Wendell Berry say it wasn’t a thing? He was more in the Schumacher &lt;i&gt;Small is Beautiful&lt;/i&gt; school. Bucky wasn’t so committed to a particular scale. Big could be beautiful too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The transitionary phase has been characterized by those Big Brother mega-corporations and the safety net those have provided their CEOs at least. Some might be worker owned. They have budgets the size of nations. They have a secular orientation that keeps them from competing for religious faithful. Keep to the religion you have, no one will insist you “convert” to anything. Skip ahead to a new religion if you wanna though, or resurrect an old one. Page forward. Page back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The upshot is today you find families in “&lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/01/cyber-nations.html&quot;&gt;virtual nations&lt;/a&gt;” (VNs) who think it’s OK for junior to be reading &lt;i&gt;Grunch of Giants&lt;/i&gt; and picking up some of that &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt;. The Bucky Boho stuff, reinterpreted through the boomers, and passing on to Gen X, Millennials and so on, comes with a world map and a habit of doing data science, in a format branded as World Game, which has continued to evolve. Whether Uncle Sam rejoins the living is a different question. In my iconography, that’s happening, via USA OS, a whole literature.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But it remains to be seen how we want to address those border questions. Citizenship is not a function of what country one happens to live in, in so many cases. Expats help us focus on creating the new rules in new games.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7030867854486938783'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7030867854486938783'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/10/from-un-to-vns.html' title='From the UN to VNs'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-5672139713217592214</id><published>2024-10-14T06:02:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-14T06:22:53.072-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Another 21st Century Curriculum</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiUfpVwaCATEPwjIN1t4nLiGWOQcYJTT67ToP_9UqRAo8OA6svRnXuFN0v5rv8XmmMCWAQcdiU0YqyfrpUvtN8GmHpFsuUZ8cPxOtqCEt6Bhni8i8u44S1-UJlCsSaAOGUrpF68quO5ffaO0dSI3AVf62vNL0Xi2UgTNUAKMYdv5K9e9Mm_2gG2/s800/iw_stack.gif&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiUfpVwaCATEPwjIN1t4nLiGWOQcYJTT67ToP_9UqRAo8OA6svRnXuFN0v5rv8XmmMCWAQcdiU0YqyfrpUvtN8GmHpFsuUZ8cPxOtqCEt6Bhni8i8u44S1-UJlCsSaAOGUrpF68quO5ffaO0dSI3AVf62vNL0Xi2UgTNUAKMYdv5K9e9Mm_2gG2/w400-h300/iw_stack.gif&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is it that I expect to accomplish through curriculum writing? For some decades, I&#39;ve been this working class dweeb who teaches online programming classes, on the basis of earlier decades developing computer applications, having majored in philosophy at Princeton, but always finding computers cool.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But then my online content isn&#39;t entirely about teaching programming. It&#39;s about thinking about geometry with a 3D computer graphics tool at one&#39;s elbow. A ray tracer in my case. To make the ray tracer do what I wanted, I had to feed it programs too tedious to write by hand, so I&#39;d have another program do that, and control that one at a high level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s take a look at some code I was writing yesterday:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiZ1g-CeJX2EbKtq6ZCV1QLVS5eIuJ-2Tq6FhE5P4UW7VBPZRIs0TSfu860vFbLgKulhGPGeWoo-Gq-t4EPBHe7qcgkWfFB0Tg88Y6tpQPGSO49hhr8sRFsdUS9onvw58zhUqlwHkCF9UJLUpW5lMzP25wuoNAJn47CnH6encSLdviX-WNPT_F8/s605/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-14%20at%205.44.46%20AM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;356&quot; data-original-width=&quot;605&quot; height=&quot;235&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiZ1g-CeJX2EbKtq6ZCV1QLVS5eIuJ-2Tq6FhE5P4UW7VBPZRIs0TSfu860vFbLgKulhGPGeWoo-Gq-t4EPBHe7qcgkWfFB0Tg88Y6tpQPGSO49hhr8sRFsdUS9onvw58zhUqlwHkCF9UJLUpW5lMzP25wuoNAJn47CnH6encSLdviX-WNPT_F8/w400-h235/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-14%20at%205.44.46%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The raytracer I use is called POV-Ray, a free open source tool that renders slowly compared to say Blender. I don&#39;t mind its slowness in the context of what I use it for, to generate animated GIFs such as the one above.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;POV-Ray expects to read and process files with extension .pov and in the code above we see I&#39;m opening a .pov file to receive a lot of stuff, through the arbitrarily so-named fileobject: out. I bring polyhedra into the foreground as objects: Icosahedron, PD, Octahedron. PD stands for &lt;i&gt;Pentagonal&lt;/i&gt; Dodecahedron. I also have an RD, a &lt;i&gt;Rhombic&lt;/i&gt; Dodecahedron. The code for those is in the same module, but once defined, I have a pretty succinct syntax for conjuring them, manipulating their properties, and writing them out in Scene Description Language for POV-Ray to process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Am I saying I expect other teachers to simply copy my code and use it verbatim? Sure, to start with, one may clone or fork my codebase, slides too. But then many teachers will be more into using their own methods, while picking up on more of the shoptalk, around BASKET modules, Quadrays, Synergetics in general. For them, this material may all be a gateway to 20th Century History and a telling that includes what the Boomers were doing (USA namespace) to propagate the &quot;4D&quot; memes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a boomer myself, one who propagates &quot;4D&quot; (e.g. 4dsolutions.net), I&#39;m a student of intellectual history and so my classes and lectures tend to have elements of that. My knowledge is quite limited. I&#39;m a fan of CJ&#39;s commitment to comprehensivity but accept, as he did, that omniscience is not necessarily the objective. Carve out a patch and cultivate that, and you&#39;ll receive news from afar in ways you might use, within your own garden (not walled exactly, but protected, perhaps even encrypted).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m also a political cartoonist, and my work with Holdenweb and Open Bastion was more along the lines of event producer. The logistics supervisor work in hotels in years prior set me up to be at home in such institutions. Not that I don&#39;t still have much to learn. At 66, I&#39;m still a noob. But a noob with some experience, I&#39;d be foolish to deny what little I&#39;ve got.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, I fancy myself a type of science fiction writer, but within the context of curriculum writing and general systems theory (GST) more generally. Science fiction becomes a stand in for what my dad did: regional planning. That field has its specific techniques, over which I am not a master, let alone doctor (he had a PhD), but the idea is similar: conjure a possible future by means of narratives, stories, blog posts, and other artwork.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5672139713217592214'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/5672139713217592214'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/10/another-21st-century-curriculum.html' title='Another 21st Century Curriculum'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiUfpVwaCATEPwjIN1t4nLiGWOQcYJTT67ToP_9UqRAo8OA6svRnXuFN0v5rv8XmmMCWAQcdiU0YqyfrpUvtN8GmHpFsuUZ8cPxOtqCEt6Bhni8i8u44S1-UJlCsSaAOGUrpF68quO5ffaO0dSI3AVf62vNL0Xi2UgTNUAKMYdv5K9e9Mm_2gG2/s72-w400-h300-c/iw_stack.gif" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-924715334823082753</id><published>2024-10-09T05:08:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-09T19:13:31.502-07:00</updated><title type='text'>More Political Rhetoric</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiQ0NP60NEyKizwB42ckjmkQUNitxwNGvM7ghTUfpf0CWUnVHFumWF3HCpgLeGxufpx6FgqORPbcsTm6i18plftPHAOETXzvBZaHAjgXO78UN9Wwblzi_CEfA2bVVdEuS3KU2nY3FRwbnYppsnat96Ibwh4qaf5pomOt-jYnGwIWJhfaNecFRUB/s806/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-09%20at%204.50.45%20AM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;806&quot; data-original-width=&quot;592&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiQ0NP60NEyKizwB42ckjmkQUNitxwNGvM7ghTUfpf0CWUnVHFumWF3HCpgLeGxufpx6FgqORPbcsTm6i18plftPHAOETXzvBZaHAjgXO78UN9Wwblzi_CEfA2bVVdEuS3KU2nY3FRwbnYppsnat96Ibwh4qaf5pomOt-jYnGwIWJhfaNecFRUB/w294-h400/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-09%20at%204.50.45%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;294&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;:: &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/N6W0TOpdqCE&quot;&gt;ranter&lt;/a&gt; ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been clear on Facebook that I&#39;m voting for Harris this time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I voted for Hillary in 2016 (she&#39;ll be speaking in Portland in a couple weeks -- I won&#39;t be there, not a fan). I&#39;m ready for a female president with an ordinary, average, representative background, more like Obama&#39;s, meaning complicated and multicultural, like America itself.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last thing we need is yet another golf clubby rich guy, another aristocrat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Per an email to a friend:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span face=&quot;verdana, sans-serif&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;BTW I&#39;m still voting for Kamala. She&#39;s proved herself highly malleable, flexible, not tied to specific positions. She&#39;s compliant and works&amp;nbsp;well with the oligarchy. Trump had his chance. I also like that she has female characteristics. Putin and I see eye to eye on this one. Doesn&#39;t mean she&#39;ll win, but it&#39;d be more instructive for people if she did.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;USers are such backsliders, endowing their scapegoats with superpowers before sacrificing them to the gods when all their hopes and dreams don&#39;t come true. As if it were all up to a president. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54038121072/sizes/l/&quot;&gt;Such monarchists&lt;/a&gt;. Why not just devolve into Brits then?&amp;nbsp; Forget we fought for freedom from such ill-begotten superstitions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To another friend I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span face=&quot;verdana, sans-serif&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span face=&quot;verdana, sans-serif&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Regarding the presidential contest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; face=&quot;verdana, sans-serif&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span face=&quot;verdana, sans-serif&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;I&#39;m ready for a first female president and anyone is gonna have their flaws. &quot;Laughing too much&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; face=&quot;verdana, sans-serif&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;and speaking in &quot;word salad&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span face=&quot;verdana, sans-serif&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;don&#39;t seem that objectionable.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; face=&quot;verdana, sans-serif&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Both may be assets.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span face=&quot;verdana, sans-serif&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Plus her background is certainly more average. Like Obama, she wouldn&#39;t have come from an aristocratic background, far from it, and to me, that&#39;s a plus. If her dad was a Marxist professor or whatever, so much the better. More proof the Muricans have an open mind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot; /&gt;&lt;span face=&quot;verdana, sans-serif&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Trump, with his celebrity billionaire background, encourages popular backsliding into thinking a president has to be from some financial elite, in this case New York mafia / slumlord / casino world (one of many subcultures our great nation has to offer). I think a president should be closer to average, and their role should include reporting back to the people what the insiders are up to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; face=&quot;verdana, sans-serif&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span face=&quot;verdana, sans-serif&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;a man or woman on the street elected to spy on the government. That&#39;d be how I&#39;d shape it, instead of going with an &quot;imperial presidency&quot; with a lot of pomp and circumstance ala Rome.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However I&#39;m never so tempted to vote for Trump as when the Dems truck out their vile Russophobia and spew it all over the media. Such a stinky vibe. I&#39;ll be holding my nose as usual.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Me on Facebook, the text the in above graphic:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Trump did give Putin some gift of a covid testing device, that would’ve been a nice gesture. A more constructive relationship between the Kremlin and White House would have been a good idea, and remains a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Likewise any calls made by Trump-the-private-citizen to Vlad would not be that upsetting to me. As a free American he or I should feel free to phone anyone in the world any time. Of course whomever we’re calling should be free to not take the call. Bibi, don’t call me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m skeptical though, as I think of Woodward as one of those journalists who believes what he’s told by various storytellers with the job of making up stories. These stories have the flavor of being unfalsifiable. But even if they’re true, I fail to experience any outrage, sorry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not a Trump supporter, but I do find Americans to be mentally ill when it comes to Russians. They’ve always been that way, since I was a kid. One of their least attractive qualities. I’m so glad I grew up outside the states in my formative years and never developed a lot of these crushing mental disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/924715334823082753'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/924715334823082753'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/10/more-political-rhetoric.html' title='More Political Rhetoric'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiQ0NP60NEyKizwB42ckjmkQUNitxwNGvM7ghTUfpf0CWUnVHFumWF3HCpgLeGxufpx6FgqORPbcsTm6i18plftPHAOETXzvBZaHAjgXO78UN9Wwblzi_CEfA2bVVdEuS3KU2nY3FRwbnYppsnat96Ibwh4qaf5pomOt-jYnGwIWJhfaNecFRUB/s72-w294-h400-c/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-09%20at%204.50.45%20AM.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3850039759360799827</id><published>2024-10-04T08:10:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-04T10:54:51.332-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Back to School</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgOckX76qOOwPytvQQCYhL6ccjSX2j8BH-3ms9NABKDL6-FUqIEQiYDf3pgtXipprTUZt8-WWl8vc2WCYW4rHRVZ9vwEzP4sW0A5XPNHAS9LzQEttjQYxcnGIOvanI5gojIfM8qWpez_gsctz7Sep9p5cdwCdV7pY8JWr_5xB5-1_1HhdK9mroD/s802/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-04%20at%206.29.52%20AM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;802&quot; data-original-width=&quot;591&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgOckX76qOOwPytvQQCYhL6ccjSX2j8BH-3ms9NABKDL6-FUqIEQiYDf3pgtXipprTUZt8-WWl8vc2WCYW4rHRVZ9vwEzP4sW0A5XPNHAS9LzQEttjQYxcnGIOvanI5gojIfM8qWpez_gsctz7Sep9p5cdwCdV7pY8JWr_5xB5-1_1HhdK9mroD/w295-h400/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-04%20at%206.29.52%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;295&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;:: pooh gets a bigger brain ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;For context, we were seeing a Planet of the Apes situation developing in western Asia, with various groups clinging to statehood amidst missiles flying in every direction.&amp;nbsp; The whole idea of &quot;sovereignty&quot; was going up in smoke.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More people escaped Gaza than I&#39;d realized (still not nearly enough), but there&#39;d been no cruise ship convoy nor other highly visible rescue effort. Most of the evacuation was under the radar and largely unreported&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A similar exodus from Lebanon is happening now, as the Netanyahu regime extends its carpet bombing campaign to more cities and towns. Not that Israelis are staying put either. When the missiles start flying, civilians leave in large numbers, if allowed to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My code school colleagues (Python, data science etc.) and I are these days gearing up for another cohort. I haven&#39;t been actively instructing a cohort in awhile, but the workflows are not unfamiliar. I&#39;ll have time to get ready. This is not my first rodeo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course the notion of statehood isn&#39;t about to fade overnight. The plot line axis hinges around &quot;globalism versus nationalism&quot; where there&#39;s some attempt to map these terms to &quot;left versus right&quot; respectively.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Radical lefty libs like Soros &amp;amp; Son versus righty tighties like Trump wanting non-porous borders, and the freedom to not be pawns within globalist agendas. That&#39;s a gross oversimplification of course. This much is sure: there&#39;s no way to avoid acting locally, whether or not one is able, or wishes, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/05/articulating-globalism.html&quot;&gt;think globally&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/10/let-us-debate.html&quot;&gt;Epistemology group member&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook, I recently questioned the whole idea of &quot;left vs right&quot; as &quot;too low dimensional&quot; invoking the notion of Principal Component Analysis. Even Myers-Briggs, akin to Cambridge Analytica&#39;s fave personality test, has more than one dimension. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why do people take it for granted that the terrain we&#39;re dealing with is a simple left vs right one-dimensional line? Data science is all about not imprisoning one&#39;s thinking inside decrepit obsolete models.&amp;nbsp; Are we so one-dimensional in our thinking?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My Princeton prof Walter Kaufmann did not think Marcuse (&lt;i&gt;One Dimensional Man)&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;was that great of a thinker, but then it doesn&#39;t take a genius to realize the English language is garbage, out of the box, when kept to factory defaults, but is potentially expressive once fine&amp;nbsp; tuned. Wrestle with your native language if your goal is to be a philosopher.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3850039759360799827'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3850039759360799827'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/10/back-to-school.html' title='Back to School'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgOckX76qOOwPytvQQCYhL6ccjSX2j8BH-3ms9NABKDL6-FUqIEQiYDf3pgtXipprTUZt8-WWl8vc2WCYW4rHRVZ9vwEzP4sW0A5XPNHAS9LzQEttjQYxcnGIOvanI5gojIfM8qWpez_gsctz7Sep9p5cdwCdV7pY8JWr_5xB5-1_1HhdK9mroD/s72-w295-h400-c/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-04%20at%206.29.52%20AM.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7502317041745480810</id><published>2024-09-28T09:24:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-28T09:24:31.242-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Western Metaphysics</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54028014910/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Omnidirectional Halo&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Omnidirectional Halo&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54028014910_a4b61eb0ea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;399&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/53850561500/in/album-72177720318719317&quot; title=&quot;Paradigm Shift&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Paradigm Shift&quot; height=&quot;386&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53850561500_a629aa7c05.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7502317041745480810'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7502317041745480810'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/09/western-metaphysics.html' title='Western Metaphysics'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-7054869789491362006</id><published>2024-09-27T18:33:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-27T18:42:08.808-07:00</updated><title type='text'>More Escapism</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiaa86HTvboAigstEGft8d1CbHkXgkKDlEPrMt2h2d6-5wWQPLOC0ZlaPP5KSKRBV6TQqYC9vL66dAPOWvDDxfI5HxmMS_omIC-LY2dETSi9-Zp-rcMDMXAMPNNQ5JJkhHHDxXBNPoMMvCB4divVAhQY9HWvgmrIcBtxBstK6PnuXW8OmZnJVto/s800/ball_in_rt_e.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiaa86HTvboAigstEGft8d1CbHkXgkKDlEPrMt2h2d6-5wWQPLOC0ZlaPP5KSKRBV6TQqYC9vL66dAPOWvDDxfI5HxmMS_omIC-LY2dETSi9-Zp-rcMDMXAMPNNQ5JJkhHHDxXBNPoMMvCB4divVAhQY9HWvgmrIcBtxBstK6PnuXW8OmZnJVto/w400-h300/ball_in_rt_e.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;RT_E&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh0MGNQdTkB3yrqOKXpEri5huZPsUvvpVL0SNH6c4qHDSE0BSu1C3SjxXhXa4mg4qqbWwJN9Y1DjMRzPSiyQyf4lsTmeQaN1B6_xKE5aPxv4zp5PjZAV41vt7XNEcnxHfRMsfemz1ojJX3DxX_xZd-gmFj28LB0v-XxGh1HeQY5yLp97Ynl1E-Z/s800/ball_in_rt_t.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh0MGNQdTkB3yrqOKXpEri5huZPsUvvpVL0SNH6c4qHDSE0BSu1C3SjxXhXa4mg4qqbWwJN9Y1DjMRzPSiyQyf4lsTmeQaN1B6_xKE5aPxv4zp5PjZAV41vt7XNEcnxHfRMsfemz1ojJX3DxX_xZd-gmFj28LB0v-XxGh1HeQY5yLp97Ynl1E-Z/w400-h300/ball_in_rt_t.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;RT_T&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Both RTs have a unit radius IVM ball inside, but only the RT_T is small enough to let it poke through. The RT_E enwraps the uni-ball completely, its body-center to face-center radius matching that of the ball&#39;s exactly.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The workflow or pipeline I&#39;m employing is an old one for me, in operation since the 1990s, using POV-Ray the whole time as my final rendering engine, and Python behind the scenes to write the scene description language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgNtLU_L8g1E1XYdkqWWX-QoFeLONhN3W03LRL5NFJAaBBczE6dO1csfmW7wXrfFJdk_Jdioe7xqPLlA-21IAeiD5_xpRxlxyo1rtFgcrFclIRKp1x9uVW19IfXvITtbB_rrdBX6EjZT3fw0o0PcSVgcek02ExbqcYLSX9RhdmixBBcmGCocI5B/s1520/Screen%20Shot%202024-09-27%20at%2011.27.44%20AM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;426&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1520&quot; height=&quot;113&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgNtLU_L8g1E1XYdkqWWX-QoFeLONhN3W03LRL5NFJAaBBczE6dO1csfmW7wXrfFJdk_Jdioe7xqPLlA-21IAeiD5_xpRxlxyo1rtFgcrFclIRKp1x9uVW19IfXvITtbB_rrdBX6EjZT3fw0o0PcSVgcek02ExbqcYLSX9RhdmixBBcmGCocI5B/w400-h113/Screen%20Shot%202024-09-27%20at%2011.27.44%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The above eight lines are sufficient to generate all of what&#39;s needed to get the above RT_T graphic. Note the 0.9994 which students of Synergetics also learn as an algebraic expression.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjmWc_3jTVUGKXLEPb53CwEmqqpyrtOhlgg9nkiW2d7twqsvkHEp2aCoPwPV-J1nykmrlCy0I9HOWQiDQWEPb8v8k9oiU1kIYq6e2e5vufaxj6eEhGb-PhZLSFJkrUQOGnKOvKxn7oOjwclObX2yHOA95DzjKKI3kfONm5yy5Z5LH_VDAoaqT_0/s741/Screen%20Shot%202024-09-27%20at%206.11.15%20PM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;416&quot; data-original-width=&quot;741&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjmWc_3jTVUGKXLEPb53CwEmqqpyrtOhlgg9nkiW2d7twqsvkHEp2aCoPwPV-J1nykmrlCy0I9HOWQiDQWEPb8v8k9oiU1kIYq6e2e5vufaxj6eEhGb-PhZLSFJkrUQOGnKOvKxn7oOjwclObX2yHOA95DzjKKI3kfONm5yy5Z5LH_VDAoaqT_0/w400-h225/Screen%20Shot%202024-09-27%20at%206.11.15%20PM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;A question I get is what does it all mean?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I usually say it means we have a ladder in spatial geometry for becoming more advanced at CAD (computer aided design).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Fluency in right-brained spatial imagery is an end in itself, or one could say a skill that comes in handy along many walks of life.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The ladder is accessible to middle and high school level students, with elementary school segments as well (e.g. &lt;i&gt;All Sixth Grade Assembly&lt;/i&gt;).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;At the college level, we&#39;re talking about America&#39;s leading positive futurist, getting smeared and then memory-holed by the Grunch, a monster he helped to foster.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The fight isn&#39;t over however. As Bucky spelled out in &lt;i&gt;Grunch of Giants&lt;/i&gt;, a mytho-poetic and prophetic work, the front lines run through our colleges and universities, with some presidents having the guts to allow deeper dives among faculty, in response to student demand. We want our positive future back.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The Global U is coming together, helping to fill the power vacuum left by a fading nation-state system, with the Middle East already in the blender.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Even as I write this, we&#39;re &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/08/posting-from-cyberia.html&quot;&gt;seeing Bibi&lt;/a&gt; quit the UN after lecturing legacy diplomats about how he&#39;s surrounded by non-nations he doesn&#39;t believe in (Jordan, Lebanon...), mere lines in the sand, against a backdrop of targeted explosions and terrorism among the well-armed paramilitary gangs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The political data layer is in turmoil, as people try to wrap their heads around the new post nation-state status quo that pertains therein. These gangs help themselves to factory-fresh inventory, amassed and allocated under the cover of nation-state decals, as politicians on the take grease the skids. That inventory proliferates and propagates in a free market, as economists predicted it would.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;That means &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2023/09/the-refugee-biz.html&quot;&gt;Refugee Planet&lt;/a&gt; is here, and is going to need more asylums, places for people to go who aren&#39;t wanting to participate in all the outward violence.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Even soldiers, most of them economic refugees themselves, stuck far from home thanks to low living standards, are not always on board with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2023/03/beltway-mafia.html&quot;&gt;oligarchic mafiosi&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Getting bossed around by privatized criminal syndicates takes some getting used to. One must overcome any sense of patriotism or honor.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhQg3ll5kpplfjzoEED4b4URPdlboRnJkG9NxwJKX2OY7T-0gUtqA27ELueRhxPatuZLqVKR9LwXCr9r_kSG1Fif4Vu9Z177EEg3JXmtMjAuPZ88FUDuIYRHxg88n8aE3wsLIAdroxPqFD2FiN4ioDOk7OkNGtn196Cb9BXsRRHOjOO5tbBZ6zS/s2012/Screen%20Shot%202024-09-27%20at%208.59.17%20AM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1208&quot; data-original-width=&quot;2012&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhQg3ll5kpplfjzoEED4b4URPdlboRnJkG9NxwJKX2OY7T-0gUtqA27ELueRhxPatuZLqVKR9LwXCr9r_kSG1Fif4Vu9Z177EEg3JXmtMjAuPZ88FUDuIYRHxg88n8aE3wsLIAdroxPqFD2FiN4ioDOk7OkNGtn196Cb9BXsRRHOjOO5tbBZ6zS/w400-h240/Screen%20Shot%202024-09-27%20at%208.59.17%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Prompt&lt;/i&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Uniformed soldiers and other economic refugees from many countries gather in a playful Epcot-like village featuring high tech yurts and electric ATV vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7054869789491362006'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/7054869789491362006'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/09/more-escapism.html' title='More Escapism'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiaa86HTvboAigstEGft8d1CbHkXgkKDlEPrMt2h2d6-5wWQPLOC0ZlaPP5KSKRBV6TQqYC9vL66dAPOWvDDxfI5HxmMS_omIC-LY2dETSi9-Zp-rcMDMXAMPNNQ5JJkhHHDxXBNPoMMvCB4divVAhQY9HWvgmrIcBtxBstK6PnuXW8OmZnJVto/s72-w400-h300-c/ball_in_rt_e.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3575826987193797016</id><published>2024-09-24T11:01:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-24T11:01:19.894-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Oval Office</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54019253894/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Explaining the Symbolism&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Explaining the Symbolism&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54019253894_a07e67ffd2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;399&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;i&gt;

Prompt&lt;/i&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The White House tour guide explains to tourists, by pointing to a diagram, how the Oval Office is meant to resemble the human skull in cross section, a secret teaching about the inner president within each one of us, a secular picture of a high position with lots of overview and supervisory powers.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3575826987193797016'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3575826987193797016'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/09/oval-office.html' title='Oval Office'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3999982752295665587</id><published>2024-09-17T11:58:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-17T12:04:16.475-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Safety Nets</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi38Zo8nxMHTjhu0GA2OV_2TiZJ7JF96bVYYUFfz92GlDlFNgpsZx6cNBeM1wwhIJTYTQ9CtdQuVRhaZMMGjOOAnwIzaFEZceqjuNhO_Yahv9Ms4JDI-vCk5swu9FwcK9pCitpKNzmMs-jmeObFFcRgdNW_-QkZYHtrTOiE-12K9JuXxcR_ZAQV/s1469/IMG_0193.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1469&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1208&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi38Zo8nxMHTjhu0GA2OV_2TiZJ7JF96bVYYUFfz92GlDlFNgpsZx6cNBeM1wwhIJTYTQ9CtdQuVRhaZMMGjOOAnwIzaFEZceqjuNhO_Yahv9Ms4JDI-vCk5swu9FwcK9pCitpKNzmMs-jmeObFFcRgdNW_-QkZYHtrTOiE-12K9JuXxcR_ZAQV/w329-h400/IMG_0193.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;329&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgGO2Fc_2AXywkbUtkHuFXq0CyhYQKq9NezpeBMmPvdhgB66LGvdCZWug1zDfD9_2phRDLRw_Si7l-WralKbjwVVIjy1Bj6dvgUaD2cM5Ow0MykyH9K7kJWff6j637vvjv42MRBryDMeOkSm_GQyZ4VBb9QieGaJ0MKv0oCzRY5oQznL92X_B5D/s1303/IMG_0194.jpeg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1303&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1208&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgGO2Fc_2AXywkbUtkHuFXq0CyhYQKq9NezpeBMmPvdhgB66LGvdCZWug1zDfD9_2phRDLRw_Si7l-WralKbjwVVIjy1Bj6dvgUaD2cM5Ow0MykyH9K7kJWff6j637vvjv42MRBryDMeOkSm_GQyZ4VBb9QieGaJ0MKv0oCzRY5oQznL92X_B5D/w371-h400/IMG_0194.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;371&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3999982752295665587'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3999982752295665587'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/09/safety-nets.html' title='Safety Nets'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi38Zo8nxMHTjhu0GA2OV_2TiZJ7JF96bVYYUFfz92GlDlFNgpsZx6cNBeM1wwhIJTYTQ9CtdQuVRhaZMMGjOOAnwIzaFEZceqjuNhO_Yahv9Ms4JDI-vCk5swu9FwcK9pCitpKNzmMs-jmeObFFcRgdNW_-QkZYHtrTOiE-12K9JuXxcR_ZAQV/s72-w329-h400-c/IMG_0193.jpeg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3196134948843485258</id><published>2024-09-13T09:31:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-13T21:15:08.406-07:00</updated><title type='text'>AFSC Stuff</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/53992445922/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Martin Gonzalez and Grandson&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Martin Gonzalez and Grandson&quot; height=&quot;658&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53992445922_462534f667.jpg&quot; width=&quot;417&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I worked with Martin for many years via AFSC here in Portland. Mostly I was a program clerk meaning the token titular Friend meant to help with the curriculum, which in our case was youth oriented and started out as a way to address tensions between two demographic groups in the high schools: Latinos and Asians. They had other names for one another. Our program was named LAAP (Latin American Asian Pacific program) or something like that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another role I played was as apprentice contributing editor for &lt;i&gt;Asian Pacific Issues News&lt;/i&gt; published out of our Portland office. Towards the end, I was briefly editor in chief. This newsletter is today very hard to find, a collectors’ item. We used it as currency to exchange for similar newsletters from around the Pacific Rim. We’d all read each other’s stuff, synthesize and summarize, and recycle. Such is a media ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why was I doing all this stuff? I had my skill set as a curriculum developer and had been sent to Boston to learn from an AFSC youth program there, as well as to attend Daniel Ellsberg’s Manhattan Project 2.0, about cleaning up post the original Manhattan Project (at Hanford et al).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later, I tried to adapt my AFSC ideas, successfully implemented in the form of LAAP, staffed by two directors, one Asian, one Latino, to a different clientele piggy-backing on Glenn Stockton’s dream of an Institute of Integral Design. Glenn had enough skills to impart and inventory to share to fill a “maker space” (a term he despised — “maker” sounded too crude maybe, for craftsman). I would encourage learning moviemaking (skills I’d also like for myself)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a short time, Portland AFSC itself was casting about for new digs, and we brainstormed this next chapter together (we had a committee). But the days of our youth program were over, at least here in Portland, and people moved on. Martin and I went our own ways but stay in touch over Facebook. I’m considered an AFSC Alumni Network guy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I did have another AFSC role I should mention: as representative of our Yearly Meeting (NPYM), I was tasked with flying back to Philadelphia for annual corporation meetings. I’ve written a lot about those corporation meetings elsewhere, including when chronicling &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.grunch.net/synergetics/kiyoshi.html&quot;&gt;My Dinner with Kiyoshi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (see comments).&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3196134948843485258'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3196134948843485258'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/09/afsc-stuff.html' title='AFSC Stuff'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-2651547502528019719</id><published>2024-09-07T16:37:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-11T21:22:52.492-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Invective</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjUI1AsfEn5j0ZLJYxfJlwNOc7th2xpLxu0LJ0PoG4Bnv1pUFaT1WvAqU8LqsSzPRPRS2lqb1p84LxTALNnx-KVk0qrICeboLly78tB6e1Honk3BIYBNXXC2CfXohLx3HTo8xlrFvmV-4qA101_l9rNITtfTm-HhBhRnxeb8z6fOlXitRt91oC4/s1024/july4_uncle_sam.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjUI1AsfEn5j0ZLJYxfJlwNOc7th2xpLxu0LJ0PoG4Bnv1pUFaT1WvAqU8LqsSzPRPRS2lqb1p84LxTALNnx-KVk0qrICeboLly78tB6e1Honk3BIYBNXXC2CfXohLx3HTo8xlrFvmV-4qA101_l9rNITtfTm-HhBhRnxeb8z6fOlXitRt91oC4/w400-h400/july4_uncle_sam.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Partly why &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2020/08/pirate-party-planks.html&quot;&gt;my Pirate Party&lt;/a&gt; wants the USG to take more responsibility for schooling its own future officials, is leaving it to prep schools has been a bad idea by many measures.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You get too many of these Elon Musk types who seem to assume their high status in life is God-given and well deserved, and that&#39;s why it&#39;s their burden to take the rest of us over some cliff or other.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Victoria Nuland comes to mind, or Condoleezza Rice, or Madeleine Albright. I don&#39;t look up to these peeps as intellectually suited to their roles. But they managed to pull strings and get plumb positions, too bad for world history, looking back. Not to only pick on women: Jake Sullivan, Antony Blinken... total disasters, from a USG point of view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think if the USG had boarding school opportunities starting for kids of a young age, not dependent on personal means or family finances, that we might groom (not a bad word) a cadre (not a bad word either) a cohort of future diplomats who were actually good at their jobs for a change, because of their well-conceived educations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One obvious symptom of our weak privatized system is that big publishing can&#39;t turn on a dime, or even take off from a runway a mile long. The inertia is just too much to overcome.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So whereas we should have been talking about America&#39;s greatest futurist subversive, Bucky Fuller, in the same pantheon as Martin Luther King, the only TV we got was either maudlin mourning or poking fun. Cry or laugh, neither serious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NPR did a really terrible job with the Bucky narrative, botching the story completely. Given the high &quot;spoiled brat&quot; index of the people working there, that&#39;s not surprising.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They didn&#39;t get any &quot;Bucky math&quot; in prep school and so assume there&#39;s no there there. That&#39;s the arrogance that comes with thinking your teachers really knew their stuff. Question authority more?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&#39;m glad at least a few schools are showing promise this fall season (you know who you are) and we have some talent in the pipeline.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, we&#39;ll put up with Imposter Syndrome and pretend the USG exists, even though it doesn&#39;t for the time being. Uncle Sam is quite dead. In his place: the corporate version: shallow, vapid, devoid of real brains. A zombie.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patriots underground work on a next version of USA OS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just saw &lt;i&gt;Beetlejuice Beetlejuice&lt;/i&gt; at the Bagdad last night (crowded!), which might explain why I&#39;m seeing Ghost House tropes in real life. The focus of that movie is phoniness versus what&#39;s really real. The difference may get pretty thin.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you&#39;ve lost integrity as a being, a lot of automaticity kicks in and you find your life filling up with involuntary unfree responses. You start lip synching the party line and marching to the groupthink drummer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2651547502528019719'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/2651547502528019719'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/09/invective.html' title='Invective'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjUI1AsfEn5j0ZLJYxfJlwNOc7th2xpLxu0LJ0PoG4Bnv1pUFaT1WvAqU8LqsSzPRPRS2lqb1p84LxTALNnx-KVk0qrICeboLly78tB6e1Honk3BIYBNXXC2CfXohLx3HTo8xlrFvmV-4qA101_l9rNITtfTm-HhBhRnxeb8z6fOlXitRt91oC4/s72-w400-h400-c/july4_uncle_sam.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-1623342255568404643</id><published>2024-09-05T09:22:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-05T09:35:36.910-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Martian Math (update)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/53973447428/in/album-72157624750749042&quot; title=&quot;King Hilbert (or N-dim-eus)&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;King Hilbert (or N-dim-eus)&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53973447428_2db042582f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martian Math has been heating up on the back burner. Now that it&#39;s &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kirbyurner.medium.com/back-to-school-c9b3d6f3778a&quot;&gt;back to school&lt;/a&gt;&quot; season, I&#39;m pumping out the educational materials that any Silicon Forest teacher might need, to tell our history.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who was Doug Strain? How did his scenario overlap the AFSC&#39;s here in Portland (AFSC = American Friends Service Committee)?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Answer: although Doug was a pacifist during WW2, a conscientious objector, he was not a Quaker, and yet he admired the work of the AFSC especially and so when Quakers needed a new meetinghouse, he helped arrange for that to happen, with AFSC gaining some office space in the process (from which it later moved).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s Doug Strain of Electro-Scientific Instruments (&lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/planting-seeds-in-silicon-forest.html&quot;&gt;ESI&lt;/a&gt;), one of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/05/silicon-forest-origins.html&quot;&gt;Silicon Forest&lt;/a&gt; parent companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doug also funded the preservation and renovation of the boyhood home of Linus Pauling, thereby establishing a beloved landmark along Asylum Avenue (renamed Hawthorne Boulevard after said Asylum&#39;s head doctor), in the Asylum District where I live.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What I did today was add the above picture of AI King Hilbert (named for Hilbert Spaces) to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/s/aHsjrM3Fho&quot;&gt;Storyboard: Martian Math&lt;/a&gt; album. I don&#39;t want my invisible army of Martian Math teachers (they might not call it that) to feel like I&#39;m only catering to high schoolers and not taking it up to the college level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the Jesuits wanted to impress Chinese intellectuals with &quot;best of the west&quot; inventions, what came to mind was perspective painting, as perfected during the Renaissance. These canvases went hand-in-hand with another Jesuit-favored topic: the mnemonic arts. Memorize the floorplan of a public building, such as might be shown in a perspective painting, and create a VR experience wherein treasured memories could be represented as icons, and thereby organized on a &quot;virtual desktop&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My understanding is the Chinese were skeptical that time-energy invested into realism was well spent, as paintings do not share the burden, later shared with photographs, of providing literal depictions of exactly what&#39;s present.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without falling into a rift and debating these issues, I simply want to draw the analogy and say n-dimensional linear algebra is a technology around which humans are justly proud. They&#39;ve made a lot of headway with their matrix-driven apparatus, including in the realm of metallurgy, where graphical processing units (GPUs) do matrix ops with blinding speed, allowing 30 frames a second and higher frame rates, computed in real time, within our computer games and simulations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This pride will feed our willingness to devote considerable attention to conventional Hilbert Space presentations, in tandem with delving into the Martian stuff, with its four basis vectors at a mutual 109.47 degrees, ala the methane caltrop (molecular structure). CH4.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead of XYZ and 3D space, we have the IVM and 4D space, but moving between the two has become smooth, owing to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/4dsolutions/m4w/blob/main/QraysDev.ipynb&quot;&gt;Qvector &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; Vector&lt;/a&gt; conversion algorithms. Qvectors are the 4-tuple &quot;quadrays&quot; used to map out the IVM, assigning unique whole number addresses to every CCP ball in the bunch.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1623342255568404643'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/1623342255568404643'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/09/martian-math-update.html' title='Martian Math (update)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-3018988360270782320</id><published>2024-08-31T14:39:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-31T14:48:04.202-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Food Services (Global U)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/32052969416/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;DSCF2662&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCF2662&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/328/32052969416_2a5b1859b4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I want to model a minimal food setup, including for myself, I&#39;m likely to think in terms of water (that&#39;s obvious) and Soylent, the white powder jokingly named, but also made of soy, so apropos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a place under siege, such as Gaza, it&#39;s not sufficient to have stockpiles of the powder, once the water goes bad. Brands like &lt;i&gt;Nestles&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Denali&lt;/i&gt; may come in too many small bottles, whereas the recipe at scale calls for tanker trucks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What we hope and pray for, of course, are non-emergency situations. Two teams of scouts have agreed to a meetup, involving game equipment, say paintball, and for the duration of their engagement, canteens and or camelbacks of Soylent are all you get, in terms of nutrients. The point is to stay focused on the game and not get sidetracked into the intricacies of outdoor BBQ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One may object to the cruelty of using humans as guinea pigs and I&#39;d agree, assuming the collaboration of the humans in question is involuntary. In my own case, I&#39;d go for days of only Soylent out of curiosity. Would my body die of boredom or send of signal flares in the form of cravings? I did not experience myself as self-hating. I was doing science.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What about pregnant women? Am I completely heartless?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, I&#39;m more suggesting an approximation or simulation when it comes to Soylent, given the total calories per bag are easy to measure.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We set up our Sims game &quot;as if&quot; they only eat Soylent, because we&#39;re in need of only so much realism, and no more. We keep the dry powder in sealed bags and add potable water as needed, at the point of service.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Soylent users have been known to introduce alcohols at this point, to keep things lively and or to aid with sleep. If that&#39;s something we want to model, or experience for ourselves, that&#39;s an option. Again, coercion need play no part in this. I&#39;m free to opt out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/feeds/3018988360270782320/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment/fullpage/post/10436423/3018988360270782320' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3018988360270782320'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/3018988360270782320'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/08/food-services-global-u.html' title='Food Services (Global U)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10436423.post-11868859318581774</id><published>2024-08-24T10:02:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-24T10:07:05.429-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Colluding on Confinement</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgBEEHoAobTgv0POMyHE35xoWvefeZuGjvucxZ_wjfDUKG4JFIMBztQwhfD-crHOv1YX1YnS2XbbWK9EW1-VCoe8_0ni8js8wKvmQ7wgv6rB8_EcNkT2qO9iwOak59uIjt-gB7SkXT3Ya-wGsEXR6oDu4WXWiuVMMhoYEGRVtRI2Ve7Ta2arxND/s1536/doomsday.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1536&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1536&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgBEEHoAobTgv0POMyHE35xoWvefeZuGjvucxZ_wjfDUKG4JFIMBztQwhfD-crHOv1YX1YnS2XbbWK9EW1-VCoe8_0ni8js8wKvmQ7wgv6rB8_EcNkT2qO9iwOak59uIjt-gB7SkXT3Ya-wGsEXR6oDu4WXWiuVMMhoYEGRVtRI2Ve7Ta2arxND/w400-h400/doomsday.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When it comes to writing the historical accounts, I think we&#39;ll find it interesting that the Americans were calling for &quot;a cease fire&quot; but not for &quot;an evacuation&quot; even though Gaza was rubble by then, unlivable, outbreaks of polio.&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;Sure, it&#39;s an &quot;open air prison&quot; but you&#39;ve gotta stay put, because we, the hand-wringers, the pearl clutchers, say so. Talk about collusion on genocide!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;Obviously the denazification program was never completed in the American mindset. Ukrainians and Bosnians, even Syrians, got to leave the war zone. Palestinians though: they&#39;re supposed to love bygone olive groves so much that they&#39;ll put up with any amount of carnage. Stay in the cage with the rabid dog kids! They&#39;re nostalgic at gunpoint.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If I were a Palestinian, I&#39;d use my sovereignty to get the hell out of there and never return. I&#39;d have the right of return, but I wouldn&#39;t use it. Who wants to go back to a hellhole Americans worship as &quot;a holy land&quot;? Not me. I&#39;ll take New Jersey over Gaza any day of the week. But wait, I have no sovereignty, that&#39;s the whole problem. I&#39;m supposed to just stay here and get bombed while the Americans fret and act stupid (what they&#39;re best at).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;XREF:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2023/10/gazans-to-guantanamo.html&quot;&gt;Gazans to Guantanamo?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/08/city-of-morons.html&quot;&gt;City of Morons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/03/why-we-fight-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Why We Fight (movie review)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/11868859318581774'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10436423/posts/default/11868859318581774'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/08/colluding-on-confinement.html' title='Colluding on Confinement'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgBEEHoAobTgv0POMyHE35xoWvefeZuGjvucxZ_wjfDUKG4JFIMBztQwhfD-crHOv1YX1YnS2XbbWK9EW1-VCoe8_0ni8js8wKvmQ7wgv6rB8_EcNkT2qO9iwOak59uIjt-gB7SkXT3Ya-wGsEXR6oDu4WXWiuVMMhoYEGRVtRI2Ve7Ta2arxND/s72-w400-h400-c/doomsday.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry></feed>