<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211</id><updated>2025-02-27T06:25:58.543-08:00</updated><category term="clojure python REPL ide"/><title type='text'>BizMo Diaries</title><subtitle type='html'>On the road with Global Data</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=1901'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=1876&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1905</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1901</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-110755476068370395</id><published>2005-02-04T14:23:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:42.271-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Power Skating with a CEO</title><content type='html'>So the CEO in this case is &quot;Power Boat Don,&quot; behind-the-scenes benefactor of The Wanderers, a Portland-based think tank to which I belong. He earned that nickname by taking us out, as individuals or in small groups, on the Columbia River, aboard his restored, mint condition, vintage power boat.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many CEOs don&#39;t use their boats. They buy one for status, as something to mention in cocktail parties, to prove their prowess. But actually putting out to sea is a big hassle, and not so much fun as golf, and so many a power boat just sits in the marina, under-used and under-loved (boats like to go boating). Anyway, Don loves his boat, and puts up with his cell phone, and uses the Columbia as his scenic headquarters for brainstorming about the future.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Don is pretty smooth on roller skates (he can go backwards for example). He found me last night, lacing up my rented pair (size 14), at this rink in Oaks Park, not far from Humphrey Bogart&#39;s wife&#39;s ashes (or so Trevor informs me). This time slot was set aside for mature adults, and indeed most of them were more mature than I, and better at skating.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Graying couples floated effortlessly, arm in arm. Khaki panted gentlemen (Intel engineers?) zipped past, leaving me figuratively in the dust (the rink&#39;s wooden floor is actually quite shiny and particle-free). A full scale wurlitzer was pumping out the tunes. This one guy circled the floor in an arms-out position, a soaring eagle (he even &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;looked&lt;/span&gt; a little like John Ashcroft).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One lady coasted up beside me and said she was glad to see she was not the only newbie in the rink. I nodded with a wry smile, and that little gesture almost tipped me over. But I kept my balance throughout the ordeal, not wanting to appear a disaster on wheels in the eyes of these seniors.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Don and I repaired to a sports bar afterwards, to MacTarnahan&#39;s and a shared burger (they&#39;re really big at Stanich&#39;s, so one is definitely enough for two). We went over some of his notes about Wanderers, agreeing about our group&#39;s enormous potential, not to mention the many dreams already realized.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One of my hopes was he&#39;d be available to offer out-of-towners a spell on his power boat. Given Don supports Terry with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/01/beyond-gene.html&quot;&gt;ISEPP lectures&lt;/a&gt;, this invitation might be extended to our big name speakers (many are on a tight schedule but still find time for fun -- Don shared about Stephen Hawking enjoying a ride in a sea plane over Seattle that time).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;However, I can imagine other lower profile guests, affiliated with Wanderers but without their names in lights on the marquee of the Schnitzer, yet nevertheless appreciating the view from our CEO&#39;s Columbia River vantage point. Don sounded quite open to this proposal. He&#39;s very generous with his time, an asset way more valuable than money.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/110755476068370395'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/110755476068370395'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/02/power-skating-with-ceo.html' title='Power Skating with a CEO'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-110740760138830434</id><published>2005-02-03T08:42:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2016-08-10T19:37:58.850-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Ayatollah of the Tetrahedron</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/img/254/1836/640/edapple2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/img/254/1836/320/edapple2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;border: 1px solid rgb(0, 0, 0); margin: 2px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;E.J. Applewhite&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some big name &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/synergetica/synergetica4.html&quot;&gt;crystallographer&lt;/a&gt; in the UK (A.L. Mackay right?) bestowed upon Ed this &quot;Ayatollah of the Tetrahedron&quot; moniker.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I took this picture about a year ago, at a Bucky Symposium at George Washington University, where I appeared with Ed and others on a panel. He was our guest of honor, the paradigm scholar and collaborator.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In his keynote presentation, we learned of Edgar Allan Poe&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://xroads.virginia.edu/~HYPER/poe/eureka.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Eureka&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a metaphysical prose poem which connects to &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; on many levels. Ergo, said &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/articles/A24912-2005Feb14.html&quot;&gt;Ed&lt;/a&gt;, lets keep alive this great American literature of ours and pass it on to future generations. And that we shall do.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the foreground is his four volume &lt;i&gt;Synergetics Dictionary&lt;/i&gt;, a painstakingly and meticulously undertaken enterprise aimed at documenting Fuller&#39;s use of key terms. &lt;i&gt;Teleology&lt;/i&gt;, for example -- Bucky had his own way of using it, in connection with the idea of &lt;i&gt;voltage pressure &lt;/i&gt;(humans &lt;i&gt;push&lt;/i&gt; to realize their destiny in Universe). When I first met Ed in Washington DC many years earlier, he gifted me with a copy. Matt and I drove it across country. I&#39;ve &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/01/national-treasure-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;treasured&lt;/a&gt; it (used it) ever since.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We have lots of opportunities to synergize with cultures in those parts of the world where bona fide Ayatollahs grace the hallways. Islamic art is sometimes about tiling a surface with polygons, and in space, with polyhedra. Engineering and architecture are similarly about shapes, as is sacred geometry, which dates back to the pyramids and before.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
High level cultural exchanges, including of open source software (like &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/11/canadian-tech-springdance.html&quot;&gt;SpringDance&lt;/a&gt; for example), and hardware (like big plasma screens), would show the world that &lt;a href=&quot;http://vw.indiana.edu/envision05/&quot;&gt;geekdom&lt;/a&gt;, at least, is gaining a brain in the new Iran. Let the politicos rattle their sabers and say menacing things. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/mycartoons/cartoon2.html&quot;&gt;We technogeeks&lt;/a&gt; already know the score, and want to get on with living our lives.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I think Iraq&#39;s neighbors might want to help a friend by furnishing some of the props, skills and backing, as well as the subsequent television coverage. I&#39;d love to see our geek counterparts, getting up to speed on these tools and infrastructure. If the &lt;a href=&quot;http://dosfan.lib.uic.edu/usia/&quot;&gt;USIA&lt;/a&gt; makes overtures, sensing a pro-democracy angle, well fine. But if it doesn&#39;t (because it&#39;s clueless -- or defunct), that&#39;s fine too.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s no reason to wait for a green light. This is about being free and independent. Want to map &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geni.org/globalenergy/library/buckminster_fuller/index.shtml&quot;&gt;electrical grids&lt;/a&gt; on a Fuller Projection, and show it off in control rooms on TV? Go for it, why not? No one is stopping you (or me).&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/110740760138830434'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/110740760138830434'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/02/ayatollah-of-tetrahedron.html' title='Ayatollah of the Tetrahedron'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-110706555617655536</id><published>2005-01-29T22:12:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:42.152-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Going Down?</title><content type='html'>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/img/254/1836/640/macromolecule.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;border: 1px solid rgb(0, 0, 0); margin: 2px;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/img/254/1836/320/macromolecule.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Julian with Macromolecule and Elevator Lady&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;January 28, 2005&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;FujiFilm FinePix 2600Zoom digicam&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;(click picture for larger view)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;&lt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.julianvossandreae.com/&quot;&gt;link to the artist&#39;s web site&lt;/a&gt; &gt;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/110706555617655536'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/110706555617655536'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/01/going-down.html' title='Going Down?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-110694206835222091</id><published>2005-01-28T15:00:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2012-01-30T08:36:25.405-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Motorcycle Diaries (movie review)</title><content type='html'>So, after helping Julian wrestle his steel macromolecule sculpture into an elevator (the gallery was on the top floor), and then into the back of his car (tight squeeze) -- the piece is on its way to a chemist in Australia -- and after attending the Jared Diamond lecture, reviewed in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/01/why-civilizations-fail.html&quot;&gt;parallel blog&lt;/a&gt;, I headed over to Fox Tower for the late night showing of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Motorcycle Diaries&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This soft focus chronicle documents Che Guevara&#39;s gradual sensitization to the economic injustices being visited upon Latin Americans, especially its long suffering indigenous peoples. He donates precious hard currency, earmarked to buy a swimsuit for his girlfriend, to a forlorn couple recently driven from their land and forced to compete for slave wages in the mines.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
His companion, Alberto, who gets flak for being fat (his weight problem was hardly noticable by US standards), discovers the cash is gone when the ship&#39;s prostitute comes on to him. Ever resourceful, he wins the needed funds in the ship&#39;s casino instead. Meanwhile, in his partially overlapping scenario as Bucky would say, Ernesto (&quot;Che&quot; was his middle name) was suffering the aftermath of a severe asthma attack (the guy had shitty lungs).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The contrasting characters of Ernesto and Alberto provide the foreground depth in this film, with scenic backdrops and an ever-puttering motorcycle (until it dies) setting the stage. They&#39;re both quite interested in women, with Alberto the older, bolder and more gregarious of the two. But Ernesto&#39;s looks, shyness, and quiet intensity make him quite the chick magnet -- not forgetting his integrity and sometimes brutal honesty (his withering criticism of that amateur writer&#39;s first novel wasn&#39;t very constructive, even if sincere).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Those disciples who know the rest of Che&#39;s story in detail (not me) should find this movie a satisfying prelude to his later canonization (he&#39;s right up there with Elvis and &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/10/us-versus-john-lennon-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;John Lennon&lt;/a&gt;). This is both biography and hagiography, and what&#39;s so bad about that? We can all learn from the lives of the saints, the boddhisatvas.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/12/judging-day.html&quot;&gt;the CIA&lt;/a&gt; gets blamed for Che&#39;s murder rightly continues to inspire outrage and mistrust of North American foreign policy architects, who have a long track record of messing up in this hemisphere (Chile, Argentina...). Consider Che&#39;s comrade Fidel, who escaped murder many times -- there&#39;s an entire museum devoted to the plots against him -- and who now suffers the effects of old age (including a recent fall): even to this day the US embargo continues. True, human rights are not unlimited &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/01/fidel-untold-story-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;in Castro&#39;s Cuba&lt;/a&gt;, but relative to what standard? &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/lame-analysis.html&quot;&gt;Guantanamo&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Old timers at the federal level, like many Florida voters, never forgave Castro for ending the control of well-connected crime bosses over Havana&#39;s lucrative casino economy. Castro became a hot button issue at many a candidate fundraising dinner in Las Vegas, and punishing his defiance was a top priority of the Kennedy administration.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of Las Vegas, I&#39;ll be interested to see how &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/05/aviator-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Aviator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; handles the final chapter of the Howard Hughes story. I&#39;ve always imagined him a sort of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.answers.com/ringwraith&amp;amp;r=67&quot;&gt;ringwraith&lt;/a&gt;, pulling political strings from his private hospital/penthouse, somewhat effectively.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/110694206835222091'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/110694206835222091'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/01/motorcycle-diaries-movie-review.html' title='Motorcycle Diaries (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-110675919836372916</id><published>2005-01-27T06:51:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2012-01-30T08:26:17.573-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Blog Launch</title><content type='html'>The title is an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/1023791886/in/set-72157601248882665/&quot;&gt;allusion to &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Motorcycle Diaries&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; -- which I haven&#39;t even seen yet, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/01/motorcycle-diaries-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;so I&#39;d better huh&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Plus I don&#39;t have the bizmo yet (other than this bipedal one, a 1958 model that needs to lose some weight) -- so for now this is sort of a placeholder (a &quot;stub blog&quot;). But there&#39;s prep work that needs doing, so I expect it&#39;ll stay active.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s a bizmo you ask?  Well, I go into that in more detail in my earlier blog:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Grain of Sand&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  Check it out.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Note: I tried out a more &quot;parchment scroll&quot; template but I&#39;ve gotten used to Minima by Douglas Bowman. This black and orange theme also reminds me of Princeton and its tiger totem, which I also like (hello William Blake).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The plan here is to give my crew members joint ownership of this blog -- it won&#39;t just be me doing all the posting.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/110675919836372916'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/110675919836372916'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/01/blog-launch.html' title='Blog Launch'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>