<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211</id><updated>2025-02-27T06:25:58.543-08:00</updated><category term="clojure python REPL ide"/><title type='text'>BizMo Diaries</title><subtitle type='html'>On the road with Global Data</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=426'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=401&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=451&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1905</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>426</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5382204960002268208</id><published>2018-09-10T12:41:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-10T12:58:01.957-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Who Gets to Be a Mathematician?</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Responding to &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kirbyurner/given-trends-in-ai-machine-learning-humans-are-coming-to-appreciate-that-in-constructing-and-bdd9fd4c7087&quot;&gt;an essay on Medium&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graf graf--p graf--leading&quot; id=&quot;8121&quot; name=&quot;8121&quot;&gt;
Given
 trends in AI (machine learning), humans are coming to appreciate that 
in constructing and internalizing any Reality Model (the process starts 
before birth) one is performing intensely mathematical operations, 
updating new “priors” (synthetic &lt;i class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;a priori&lt;/i&gt; judgements) in some Bayesian feedback loop, complete with cybernetic back propagation though many layers of perceptron.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot; id=&quot;75c0&quot; name=&quot;75c0&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot; id=&quot;75c0&quot; name=&quot;75c0&quot;&gt;
As &lt;i&gt;Kraftwerk&lt;/i&gt; so eloquently put it: “&lt;i class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;we&lt;/i&gt; are the [mathematicians]”.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot; id=&quot;75c0&quot; name=&quot;75c0&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot; id=&quot;66f3&quot; name=&quot;66f3&quot;&gt;
Dr.
 Keith Devlin showed biological life is at bottom a form of mathematical
 computation. Humans claim to do it consciously, as a brain activity, on
 top of a 99% automated metabolism.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot; id=&quot;66f3&quot; name=&quot;66f3&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot; id=&quot;2614&quot; name=&quot;2614&quot;&gt;
Sure,
 universities want their name on the bottle, when the math smells and 
tastes like the real deal. They’re like wine merchants. However I’m 
always willing to accredit the mathematical abilities, properties and 
practices I encounter in so many walks of life. Fine wines come with 
many labels.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot; id=&quot;aeaf&quot; name=&quot;aeaf&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot; id=&quot;aeaf&quot; name=&quot;aeaf&quot;&gt;
English
 majors studying New England Transcendentalism come up against a lot of 
architecture and geometry these days. Their PhD may be in American 
Literature of the 1900s, but that means knowing what the “isotropic 
vector matrix” is all about (1970s metaphysics), and of course 
“tetravolumes”. No, this isn’t mathematics necessarily, but when it 
comes to Reality Modeling, such concepts have utility.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/30187479138/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;4fold&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;4fold&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1799/30187479138_a1317ebf3a_o.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5382204960002268208'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5382204960002268208'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/09/who-gets-to-be-mathematician.html' title='Who Gets to Be a Mathematician?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-794718857537102575</id><published>2018-09-07T12:02:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-08T00:12:34.313-07:00</updated><title type='text'>On Saying More with Less</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/43634729695/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;P1060794&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;P1060794&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1879/43634729695_986e06e864.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I hiked up Mt. Tabor this morning, which sounds impressive, however I might have used the word &quot;stroll&quot;.&amp;nbsp; Some steep parts.&amp;nbsp; I almost turned around at the Narnia Lamp Post, but then decided to press on.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Coming down, I came across some interesting construction site activities involving a crane lifting heavy objects onto a flatbed truck.&amp;nbsp; I paused to take pictures.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What was going through my mind a lot was how I could write some new essay on &lt;i&gt;Medium&lt;/i&gt; about Wittgenstein&#39;s philosophy of mathematics and quadrays, a coordinate system apparatus I&#39;ve been yakking about since the 1990s.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, around noon, before beginning said essay, I did a quick search and found these two postings, both with hyperlinks of their own:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/lw.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;On Ludwig Wittgenstein&#39;s Contribution to a Pragmatic Philosophy&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (April 3, 1997)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/quadphil.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Investigations into the Linear Algebra Concepts used in the XYZ and Quadray Language Games&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (November 20, 1997 Last updated: October 1, 2005)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Wow, that&#39;s a lot of what I&#39;d planned to write today.&amp;nbsp; Do I really need to write it all again?&amp;nbsp; Probably not.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A better use of my time might be to hack in to those ancient web pages and add some new hyperlinks to them, to more recent writings.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I found my materials using Google, just searching on &lt;i&gt;Synergetics Wittgenstein&lt;/i&gt; as my two keywords.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/09/close-encounters.html&quot;&gt;Ravasio&lt;/a&gt; writes in her autobiography about finding out these high tuition schools for which loans are needed, not bothering to share &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kirbyurner/american-literature-101-224489c26f19&quot;&gt;New England Transcendentalism&lt;/a&gt; in the form of the Fuller corpus.&amp;nbsp; The math goes there too.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Academia will learn to &quot;get off it&quot; with the Bucky stuff, or it won&#39;t.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m thinking I won&#39;t lift a finger, as I want to see wheels turn without my input.&amp;nbsp; My goal is to publish less, not more.&amp;nbsp; Time to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/08/archiving-stuff.html&quot;&gt;wrap it up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sure, I&#39;d help as a consultant on the 3D movies about the Concentric Hierarchy etc., but for those to happen, the Global U would need to strengthen its curriculum.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s a chicken and egg vicious circle here, or maybe a &quot;down the drain&quot; vortex? Time will tell.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/794718857537102575'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/794718857537102575'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/09/on-saying-more-with-less.html' title='On Saying More with Less'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8974136383450512067</id><published>2018-08-27T00:26:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-27T14:06:00.843-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Discussing a Documentary</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
In case you don&#39;t have time to watch the movie, or can&#39;t get your hands on a copy, the National Geographic documentary about the Gospel of Judas is pretty interesting.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, National Geographic was a sponsor of the project, as if it turned out this was an authentic document, then kudos would accrue to the documentary makers.&amp;nbsp; For sure this whole operation would need to be memorialized using state of the art film techniques.&amp;nbsp; One doesn&#39;t mess with such heritage without making highly detailed records of the enterprise or project.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The two main puzzles were:&amp;nbsp; to decipher the badly decayed content of the recovered papyrus book, written in Coptic; to figure out where it came from exactly and how old it was.&amp;nbsp; Carbon dating was applied and an expedition to Egypt ended in caves with many traces of Coptic culture.&amp;nbsp; The dating put it &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gospel_of_Judas&quot;&gt;around 280 A.D.&lt;/a&gt; with some decades plus or minus, suggesting it be treated much as the other so-called &quot;Gnostic Gospels&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The film explains that &quot;gnostic&quot; was a put-down, a lot like &quot;truther&quot; and not a label self-applied, and that it was already a term of opprobrium by around 200 AD by which time Christianity had started to solidify, after taking many turns.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Bishop Irenaeus had railed against some Gospel of Judas way back then, but no one since had been able to snag a copy.&amp;nbsp; Leave it to some treasure hunter to get it on the black market, where it languished and almost turned to dust.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Judas was thoroughly demonized, yes, but more generally the Bible was being whittled down to Four Gospels with the others best forgotten.&amp;nbsp; But most especially oxymoronic would be any twisted &quot;Gospel of Judas&quot;.&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Revelation&lt;/i&gt; would be less confusing, in terms of making the Bible cohere.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Two often made points were echoed in this film.&amp;nbsp; (A) Jesus and his disciples were of course Jews and weren&#39;t really into questioning that and likewise (B) the Romans administered &quot;justice&quot; in that region so the irony of Rome&#39;s Christians later demonizing Jews for being Jesus killers seemed somewhat like a pot calling the kettle black (an English idiom meaning &quot;who are &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; to call &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt; that?&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d say &quot;Mahayana Christianity&quot; sees that humanity as a whole killed its own God when He came among them, a display of poor judgment which well explains why God, on previous occasions, took some pretty severe actions towards His creation. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Gnostics were to be disrespected for teaching the local God had indeed messed up, but that Jesus was pointing back to a greater God away from these unworthy humans, or something along those lines (considered heresy even today).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The narrower form of Christianity has taken on the mantle of &quot;Chosen People&quot; (us versus them) characteristic of those not thinking in terms of &quot;humans on Planet Earth&quot; (an Astrological conception).&amp;nbsp; Jewish shepherds were not schooled in esoterica with its cosmic vocabulary.&amp;nbsp; The older forms of Christianity also have less Greek metaphysics, or so I&#39;ve been told.&amp;nbsp; The Coptic people I&#39;ve hung out with were in Cairo.&amp;nbsp; But then Alexandria had the works of Euclid.&amp;nbsp; I guess my point is it took Christians a few centuries to get super educated, especially in light of their early persecution, by the Romans especially.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These last two paragraphs were me rambling.&amp;nbsp; The movie itself doesn&#39;t self indulge having bitten off a huge chunk. In addition to piecing the document together and determining its history, the film gets some character actors to tackle some really challenging plot lines that will be heavily scrutinized.&amp;nbsp; Agreeing to star in these sequences took some courage in case the film attracted the ire of some offended orthodoxy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fortunately, the seminaries have already done a good job of disseminating the historical and archeological approach.&amp;nbsp; The Gnostic Gospels had already carved out a space in consciousness, thanks in part to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/3dRiEgfjNrQ&quot;&gt;Carl Jung&lt;/a&gt;, who worked on saving this literary heritage.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not a super expert on all the details but have done enough homework to feel some gratitude to all involved in salvaging such remnants from our human past.&amp;nbsp; So much ransacking goes on, or sometimes deliberate defacing on ideological grounds.&amp;nbsp; We want to respect new findings and update our narratives as creation continues to reveal itself, a process some might call God while others would prefer not to.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The two points I mentioned above were to counter the anti-Jew sentiments that were cultivated by those casting themselves as victims of Jewish globalism and/or loyalty to only themselves.&amp;nbsp; These patterns of thought already had Judas epitomizing Judaism, but in a bad way.&amp;nbsp; According to this rediscovered gospel, Jesus relied on Judas to turn him in and maybe save the others.&amp;nbsp; One may debate whether we&#39;re talking actual history, but it seems well established that the story of Jesus was taught with this plot twist at least in that one lineage.&amp;nbsp; Several other gospels were floating about, including those of Timothy, Phillip, Mary Magdalen and so on.&amp;nbsp; Again, the existence and intelligibility of said texts does not constitute a proof of facts.&amp;nbsp; These stories don&#39;t actually require fact checking to go global, we know that from many other storytelling traditions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, I assume a lot of this stuff is old news to the Bible hounds among us, and to the archeologists, some anthropologists.&amp;nbsp; The literature since this movie must have grown considerably in the meantime.&amp;nbsp; We have also enjoyed many breakthroughs in getting to know the ancient Mayans.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8974136383450512067'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8974136383450512067'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/08/discussing-documentary.html' title='Discussing a Documentary'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-9115317433992325938</id><published>2018-08-21T23:09:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-21T23:29:29.505-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2018.8.21</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I haven&#39;t been chronicling Wanderers meetups at all frequently, in contrast to ages past. They&#39;re always datelined in that same titular format, so feel free to search, should you find intact infrastructure.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our practice as Wanderers is to practice &quot;open session&quot; wherein the conversation wanders and no one is obligated to stick to the topic, as there&#39;s no topic per se.&amp;nbsp; We sometimes take a vacation and turn the evening over to a leader, a presenter, thinking of ourselves as good guinea pigs, but then we go back to earning our name and reputation, as those with no fixed agenda, just a coffee fund.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The more formal story of our beginning is Terry Bristol, President of ISEPP, needed a stable of trusted conversationalists should a big wig come to town, meaning a top science &amp;amp; engineering practitioner and/or writer-journalist on the book selling circuit.&amp;nbsp; The cast was eclectic to say the least, with the guest often staying at the Heathman, then lecturing in one of Portland&#39;s swankest venues, either at the Schnitzer (old school theater palace) or the Christian church one door down (pews, gallery, organ), on the Park Blocks.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So say Jane Goodall shows up.&amp;nbsp; Everyone would like to meet her, but rather than mob the poor creature (actually quite self possessed), Terry could have a party, serve refreshments, and the Wanderers could instantly create the suave / sophisticated surroundings such a celebrity would have come to expect.&amp;nbsp; We were the proverbial intelligent laypeople, not peers perhaps, but from neighboring walks of life.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tonight we practiced yammering about (a) the big bang (did it have a center) (b) whether any good could come of our grave circumstances (c) near death experiences, such as almost-drownings (d) paranormal phenomena (e) the non-existence, or existence, of extraterrestrials and why we haven&#39;t detected them yet (no one present argued that we had, but each meeting is a random function of who happens to show up).&amp;nbsp; We had some jokes and puns.&amp;nbsp; We were a sampling of genders and generations, I won&#39;t claim random.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I want to mention in particular that Peter Sloterdijk came up and we debated the pronunciation of his name.&amp;nbsp; Francher has been delving into his most recent writings whereas I&#39;m still stuck in the trilogy, &lt;i&gt;Bubbles&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Globes&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Foams&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; We are not of any special religious denomination and I would say we&#39;re mostly a haven for those who don&#39;t espouse any mainstream religion, or religion at all, but with numerous exceptions of course (we&#39;re riddled with true believers of one kind or another).&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Francher and I are especially fans of Buckminster Fuller, whom Sloterdijk writes about quite a bit.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m also into the Wittgenstein stuff.&amp;nbsp; Larry knew the Trimtab meme. Later I posted to Facebook, in the spirit of what I&#39;d said then:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fsm&quot;&gt;
When
 I look back in history it&#39;s like Alexander Bell (telephone, &quot;kites&quot;), 
container shipping, the internet (more than just Al Gore)... i.e. I 
don&#39;t place my hopes &amp;amp; dreams [tm] in the hands of prima donna 
actor-lawyers who claim DC as their Hollywood-like universal studios 
(many well-known backdrops).  They&#39;re entertainment, at best a 
simulation, but these days sing off key.  My focus is on the artifacts, 
like the cars and trucks.  Highways.  Bridges.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_6a _29ee _5xec _43_1&quot; data-hover=&quot;tooltip&quot; data-tooltip-content=&quot;Amigos de BJ&quot; role=&quot;img&quot;&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9115317433992325938'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9115317433992325938'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/08/wanderers-2018821.html' title='Wanderers 2018.8.21'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2319168498838924730</id><published>2018-08-19T11:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-19T11:01:33.994-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Bizmos in 2018</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WRLmm3Ij8g0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
By this time in our narrative, the &quot;bizmo&quot; (business mobile) is a well-established genre of van or bus, mostly peddled as a luxury item.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m not saying I&#39;m yet able to head for the garage and download my favorite dashboards and stuff, but we&#39;re getting there.
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2319168498838924730'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2319168498838924730'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/08/bizmos-in-2018.html' title='Bizmos in 2018'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/WRLmm3Ij8g0/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4912193872993074055</id><published>2018-08-18T15:17:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-19T02:06:28.743-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Red Books</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/l6oh14vfhlI&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve gone from Alan Watts (influential in my early reading career) to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/l6oh14vfhlI&quot;&gt;James Hillman&lt;/a&gt; (likewise influential), talking about Youtube.  Great to get audio trax from these guys.  I&#39;d been doing silent reading.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Hillman kick got me to this lecture by Becca S. Tarnas, Ph.D. (a self-confessed &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/01/at-work.html&quot;&gt;Elvynchyk&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;nbsp; She&#39;s talking &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2016/10/science-fiction-future.html&quot;&gt;about similarities&lt;/a&gt; between &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/09/toontalk.html&quot;&gt;J.R.R. Tolkien&#39;s imagery&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2014/10/red-book-not-maos.html&quot;&gt;that of Carl Jung&lt;/a&gt;, in their respective books with red covers. &lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4912193872993074055'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4912193872993074055'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/08/red-books.html' title='Red Books'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/l6oh14vfhlI/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-332497421095602620</id><published>2018-08-12T08:37:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-12T08:47:52.791-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Delta versus Lambda Calc: Weighing Options</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/15152020989/&quot; title=&quot;What&#39;s Next?&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;What&#39;s Next?&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3881/15152020989_7918d3268e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I stumbled on this old fragment of storyboard this morning and decided to explain it again, adding a link to a related Youtube (8 mins). The picture corresponds to a high school student looking at the math tracks branching out ahead of her or him, and wondering whether to slant to the delta side, or to the lambda side.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The delta side stands for Calculus and is the only pre-college track as far as many are concerned.  You may have some stubs, like statistics and business math, that point in some other direction, but the college admin folks are pre-geared to like calculus.  Professors don&#39;t want to do all the heavy lifting and you need calculus to prove yourself educated, further up the line.  I have another calculus book on order from Amazon as we speak. I used to teach it myself, at the high school level.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The lambda side stands for Functional Programming (Scheme, Clojure...) but underneath that, for Lambda Calc in particular, as distinct from Delta Calc i.e. delta calculus (the one we learn in high school).&amp;nbsp; Lambda Calc, one might say, is the basis of computer science. We have instructions, or functions, and inputs, or arguments.&amp;nbsp; We think a lot about getting our syntax fine-tuned to actually &quot;run&quot; (execute operationally).&amp;nbsp; Lambda Calc is pretty much synonymous with Computer Science.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What happened in the late 1900s, after the rise of computing and computer power, kicked off by Alan Turing and others, was a greater need for Lambda Calculus and a requirement that Delta Calculus share the road more.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s why high schoolers would later have more choices, as to how to proceed with their math education.&amp;nbsp; They could choose to emphasize computer science over delta calc, and still get a lot of delta calc in the process.&amp;nbsp; Operational mathematics is not devoid of Newton&#39;s Method for example.&amp;nbsp; Computers do calculus all the time, even as discrete math devices.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In some ways, the whole dichotomy is an illusion, much like wave versus particle.&amp;nbsp; You have different tools for different needs.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not either / or.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/eTDH7m4vEiM&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/332497421095602620'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/332497421095602620'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/08/delta-versus-lambda-calc-weighing.html' title='Delta versus Lambda Calc: Weighing Options'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/eTDH7m4vEiM/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4993594879539370533</id><published>2018-08-08T11:16:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-08T12:25:42.403-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Green Screen</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
The &quot;green screen&quot; bizmo is one that drives around doing interviews, podcasts, other reconnoissance. Sometimes it&#39;s more convenient to actually go to a place and visit interlocutors close to home -- their home -- versus flying them to Burbank or whatever.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A green screener may do solo-casting from the mobile studio as well.&amp;nbsp; The bus or van is well stocked with video editing equipment.&amp;nbsp; The nearest truck stop may provide the uplink station.&amp;nbsp; Not every such van is like a TV news van with live satellite back to headquarters.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The connotation around bizmos is they&#39;re not passive observer speculator journalist mobiles, who &quot;get the story&quot; and then move on.&amp;nbsp; Some bizmos may be of that type, but their tendency is to network and followup.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not that any specific community is obligated to host any given caravan.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s where the dispatchers come in, and the control rooms (see other blogs).&amp;nbsp; Today we see a lot of interventionist control rooms thinking they know how to &quot;cure&quot; various global ailments.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re way ahead of the science, acting on pure superstition a lot of the time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My recent trip through the Warm Springs reservation and to the Madras area (Cascadia), to one of the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kirbyurner/spy-camp-499da1c87428&quot;&gt;spy camp&lt;/a&gt;&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/08/international-school.html&quot;&gt;XRL spots&lt;/a&gt;, was by Torture Taxi (the Nissan), and was not a green screen adventure.&amp;nbsp; Smith Rock was really behind me, and I really did feed the alpacas.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you&#39;re going fully for the illusion, then you don&#39;t really need a bizmo at all, do everything in studio.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The caravans plus innocent bystanders with cell cameras, create more points to omni-triangulate, meaning the believability of the operation will get a boost.&amp;nbsp; Spoofers won&#39;t be as good at authentication, most of the time.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4993594879539370533'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4993594879539370533'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/08/green-screen.html' title='Green Screen'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6778399913887123114</id><published>2018-08-03T22:09:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-08T11:06:01.586-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Central Oregon</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/29984025608/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Metolius Headwaters&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Metolius Headwaters&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/860/29984025608_a360077866.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks to my having family in this neck of the woods, I get one of those inside track experiences where I don&#39;t have to spend a lot to enjoy a wealth of experiences.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Eagle Crossing on the Warms Springs reservation is a great intersection of cultures.&amp;nbsp; The TV is tuned to news and the CBS morning show, with the N8V cook owner the main audience. His wife took our order and their daughter cashed us out.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Today we visited the place where the Metolius river emerges from underground.&amp;nbsp; No one really knows its route under the Cascades.&amp;nbsp; Once it emerges, it runs for about twelve miles to a lake, through forest populated by camp grounds and &quot;summer cabins&quot; (many have been turned into more than just cabins).&amp;nbsp; We picnicked along the shore, then drove into Sisters for music by Tony Lompa, who remembered me from last time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tomorrow we&#39;ll be listening to Steve&#39;s radio show on KPOV, and probably talking to Steve himself.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I drove the girls to the alpaca farm just a mile down the road on highway 97.&amp;nbsp; Then we visited Smith Rock.&amp;nbsp; These are ritual stops for us.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ll be adding pictures when home in Portland.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m meditating on how people seem to want it both ways:&amp;nbsp; we acknowledge a deeply non-rational side the motivates human affairs, and then try to give a role to rationality.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Clearly engineering based on awareness of generalized principles gives us more ways to act out our collective craziness, for better and/or for worse.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the media, crazy meets crazy and tries to sort itself out.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s called history or culture or something along those lines. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/42949796155/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Tony Lompa&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tony Lompa&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1796/42949796155_fdcb90bc34.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6778399913887123114'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6778399913887123114'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/08/central-oregon.html' title='Central Oregon'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2680148258669557113</id><published>2018-08-02T09:58:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-02T09:58:22.716-07:00</updated><title type='text'>World Game</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Carol and I are thankful to have granddaughter / daughter Tara in Portland for a week&#39;s visit.&amp;nbsp; I picked her up at PDX last night.&amp;nbsp; We met at the baggage carousel.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m taking a breather after an arduous week teaching class.&amp;nbsp; Tomorrow we have plans to leave town for a bit (some of us do).&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2680148258669557113'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2680148258669557113'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/08/world-game.html' title='World Game'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5215222350619343571</id><published>2018-07-29T13:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-21T10:38:11.519-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Speed of C</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/41911269920/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;povray_on_pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;povray_on_pi&quot; height=&quot;339&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/859/41911269920_2a853cf239.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was noting in class the other day that it&#39;s somewhat fortuitous, from a mnemonic standpoint (helps us remember), that C as in &quot;the C language&quot; (runs fast when optimized) shares its letter with lowercase &#39;c&#39;, typically used for &quot;the speed of light&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The concept of &quot;frequency&quot; is well-developed with regard to CPUs and GPUs.&amp;nbsp; Those with faster clocks crunch through more computations per time interval, accomplishing some &quot;least action&quot; (say a bit flip, taking us into teraflops) more often (right, more frequently).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That means more energy spent in a given time interval (E/t) which relates to the Power (P) of the chip in question.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Energy itself, lets remember, is like a wound up toy, or a battery, all prepped to do work if allowed to, like a runner before the starting gun.&amp;nbsp; The energy is &quot;stored&quot;, in the form of chemical stockpiles in the runner&#39;s case.&amp;nbsp; Bullets depend on a reservoir of gunpowder.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
E = Mcc might get us saying &quot;c squared&quot; but we&#39;re also allowed to view an expanding equilateral triangle in place of an expanding square, if we&#39;re from a different subculture.&amp;nbsp; The mathematics itself is the same.&amp;nbsp; Cubism is cultural.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
E = hf is another statement of how we wind up the toy, by turning the key at some frequency, where a key turn is mass for a distance at some speed (mass times velocity times distance).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In Newtonian units:&amp;nbsp; f = 1/t; E = (mvd)/t = mvv, which is where our mcc comes from, unit-wise.&amp;nbsp; The units of mvd are referred to as &quot;action&quot; and we use h for Planck&#39;s minimal action, a discrete minimal delta or change.&amp;nbsp; Those happen over time, and add up in terms of Energy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When you have a complicated multi-dimensional program to run, just because the CPUs are going at full throttle doesn&#39;t mean your program finishes quickly.&amp;nbsp; Some computations take many epochs, even eons, to finish, even if running at the speed of C.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5215222350619343571'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5215222350619343571'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/07/speed-of-c.html' title='Speed of C'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-9001408057294434956</id><published>2018-07-24T06:41:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-24T06:41:10.765-07:00</updated><title type='text'>B2 Party</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Atlantic Monthly&lt;/i&gt; not long ago shared an argument that the DC idea of a &quot;president&quot; is broken.&amp;nbsp; The same magazine likes to share PR for what I call the &quot;B2 Party&quot;, which is behind the B2 bomber and its forays.&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Atlantic Monthly&lt;/i&gt; likes to shill for the B2 Party sometimes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Am I saying every major weapons system deserves its own party?&amp;nbsp; Something like that.&amp;nbsp; The names &quot;Democrat&quot; and &quot;Republican&quot; have outlived their usefulness.&amp;nbsp; We have Beltway Bandits and... ?&amp;nbsp; Oh yeah, Wall Street.&amp;nbsp; Political discourse would make so much more sense if we could get our analysis more in those terms, versus always reading about zombies (DNC and GOP).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A lot of Americans are really into war porn and crave it.&amp;nbsp; Stroking the weapons, making them shiny, glistening, on camera is a part of it.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re taught this is an OK perversion, and indeed we&#39;re encouraged, as viewer voyeurs, to get sick in the head in this way, between shopping trips.&amp;nbsp; Shop, then go home and bliss out on B2s, is the reduced instruction set.&amp;nbsp; Many of us comply.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets combine the fact that the presidency is a joke (an undoable job, mostly a scapegoat position, designed for soaking up blame), with the fact that the war porn is a kind of mental illness (DSM anyone?).&amp;nbsp; No wonder a lot of folks are casting about for a more meaningful discourse.&amp;nbsp; Intuitively, they understand the political diet they&#39;re being fed is pretty hopeless.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, getting a weak ghost of a government to do the bidding of war profiteers is pretty easy.&amp;nbsp; Just harness its lingering claims to legitimacy and piggy-back on its PR values, and you have a decent chance of getting a war going.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s the big payoff and many are working overtime on it, doing their best to build tensions with &quot;America&#39;s enemies&quot; (not seeing themselves as the ultimate killers of a once proud sovereign state).&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9001408057294434956'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9001408057294434956'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/07/b2-party.html' title='B2 Party'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6914962868113701108</id><published>2018-07-21T23:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-10T16:34:29.961-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Back to School</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I&#39;ve been hard at work teaching code school stuff all summer, so it&#39;s not &quot;back to school&quot; for me.&amp;nbsp; I never left.&amp;nbsp; However, that&#39;s part of the summer retail cycle:&amp;nbsp; back to school stuff appears on the shelves in late July.&amp;nbsp; Some kids get nervous, as the mortality of their summertime carefree self begins to see shadows.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That documentary about John James Audobon I saw at Glenn&#39;s made a lasting impression.&amp;nbsp; Back in the day I was casting Portland as &quot;Toon Town&quot; where we&#39;d lap up screen content, produce it, critique it.&amp;nbsp; That happened for me.&amp;nbsp; The documentaries have been pouring in.&amp;nbsp; Lindsey used to snag them at &lt;i&gt;Laughing Horse&lt;/i&gt;, but even then I was already into them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Audobon shot tons of birds (literally) to get them just right in his giant colored etching recordings.&amp;nbsp; He was reminding us of what was about to go away in many cases.&amp;nbsp; People ask if the climate has been changed by humans, when it used to feature hours-long migrations of billions of passenger pigeons.&amp;nbsp; All gone.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was planning to yak about Emoji, now included within Unicode.&amp;nbsp; When back in school, will you be learning about ASCII and UTF-8?&amp;nbsp; Is this a code school?&amp;nbsp; Or might this be a school about music?&amp;nbsp; Or both?&amp;nbsp; Computing and music have an intimate relationship.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m thinking of a numpy array of emoji in some &lt;a href=&quot;https://colab.research.google.com/github/tensorflow/models/blob/master/samples/core/tutorials/keras/basic_classification.ipynb&quot;&gt;Google Colab notebook&lt;/a&gt;, or maybe on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bradleypallen/keras-emoji-embeddings&quot;&gt;a Github Jupyter Notebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6914962868113701108'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6914962868113701108'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/07/back-to-school.html' title='Back to School'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8813146566359196492</id><published>2018-07-18T14:54:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-19T20:10:48.226-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Imperative versus Declarative</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
A theme in machine learning these days is &quot;imperative versus declarative&quot;.&amp;nbsp; Tensorflow versus Pytorch instantiated this difference.&amp;nbsp; Do we draw a graph of the computation and then compile it?&amp;nbsp; Or do we just write the script?&amp;nbsp; The latter style is &quot;imperative&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
She (Sarah Bird) just now said &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/07/greek-mythology.html&quot;&gt;Just Use It&lt;/a&gt;&quot; with respect to the Python ecosystem.&amp;nbsp; The &quot;ad campaign&quot; is going well, even if I do say so myself.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s Google versus Facebook in terms of teeth (FANG). However with Tensorflow 1.9 we&#39;re seeing more emphasis on imperative.&amp;nbsp; The differences are less obvious by OSCON 2018, among the AI research labs. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
All very geeky, right?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The tools are free so people (social engineers especially) might get in on the ground floor tooling up around those tools.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I know some readers will be concerned regarding my use of &quot;social engineer&quot; as somehow a role, as for many that hearkens back to a much vilified system called &quot;centrally planned&quot; meaning the genius of cybernetics was stifled.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Bureaucrats would try to second guess what could much better be handled by &quot;market forces&quot;.&amp;nbsp; However, given &quot;social media&quot; and &quot;programming&quot; are already neighboring nodes in some word-oriented vector space, I don&#39;t see much hope in fighting &quot;social engineers&quot; as a consequent.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets just make sure they know about cybernetics.&amp;nbsp; As in previous ages, we need our engineers to have people skills.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re simply too dependent on technology, while being people, to overlook this aspect of their training.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, &lt;i&gt;The Time Machine&lt;/i&gt; by H.G. Wells does merit a segue here.&amp;nbsp; Morlocks were anti-social from the Eloi point of view.&amp;nbsp; The engineering species had gone its own way (underground) on the &quot;not humanities&quot; side of the chasm (C. P. Snow&#39;s) and were eating the Eloi for lunch (literally).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s the dystopian outcome we hope to avoid, and so the Eloi of today are contributing to Morlock sensitivity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On that note, our current speaker is trans, goes by she, and speaks boldly to the issue of bias, a theme of our show.&amp;nbsp; She swears and speaks way more frankly than many in polite society (a characteristic of engineers per the movie &lt;i&gt;Titanic&lt;/i&gt;), and has a through the roof IQ.&amp;nbsp; This is all a part of our training.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re unphased.&amp;nbsp; Beam, Tensorflow, Spark, Apache Flink...&amp;nbsp; DL w/ Big Data is our topic.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Helping people around me jack in (to the power strip) meant losing my own link for a short period. This ancient Mac Air has been known to shut down in these circumstances, not because of its battery. Yay for not going down this time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So Python and Go are developing their ability to talk to Apache Beam.&amp;nbsp; Beam seems to ship containers around, containing Tensorflow, serving as worker bees against big data.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re looking at the Chicago Taxi data set.&amp;nbsp; Python is doing some preprocessing.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re talking about a demo of parallel stuff happening in the cloud.&amp;nbsp; A lot of this stuff only works well inside the Google Cloud (she&#39;s from Google).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
With all these geeks so highly trained in following &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/07/codes-of-conduct.html&quot;&gt;codes of conduct&lt;/a&gt;, and thinking about their biases, a question may arise:&amp;nbsp; will they help us win wars?&amp;nbsp; Were you talking cyber-wars then?&amp;nbsp; Most of us haven&#39;t had any time for firearms stuff.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Pyspark talks to Apache Spark... the TensorFlowOnSpark demo runs slowly, given all the pickles and JSON involved.&amp;nbsp; Lets try it with Apache Arrow instead.&amp;nbsp; I understand a lot of this stuff given my own meager background in machine learning with little data.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not much a cloud guy at this point.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Go wordcount demo didn&#39;t work, but we were impressed with the command line skills, and the people skills.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8813146566359196492'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8813146566359196492'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/07/imperative-versus-declarative.html' title='Imperative versus Declarative'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4905560639640947275</id><published>2018-07-16T08:23:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-19T20:32:27.664-07:00</updated><title type='text'>OSCON 2018</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/42553705485/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Name Badge&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Name Badge&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1782/42553705485_31232df3f3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m with my flock (geekonius) having strong coffee in the convention center, badge around my neck, awaiting a tutorial.&amp;nbsp; Open Source Convention is a no nonsense affair, a well oiled machine, thanks to California showbiz, meaning the event logistics business, Sebastopol a hallmark.&amp;nbsp; I refer of course to O&#39;Reilly, a former company of employment, though I wasn&#39;t working in the home office.&amp;nbsp; That was some years back, when an experimental code school tested the waters, toe in the pool.&amp;nbsp; Quite the shark tank, we found out (long story).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
O&#39;Reilly was prescient, even when we closed (not for lack of business, let me tell you), in seeing Jupyter Notebooks would be big, which they are.&amp;nbsp; However I don&#39;t think any of us were envisioning the hype around DL / ML would take off the way it did.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s Deep Learning / Machine Learning. In fact, my upcoming tutorial is on TensorFlow, with which I&#39;m a white belt.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve been working out over in scikit-learn and feel ready to set foot in this Dojo.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The school was originally established to teach calculus, spinning off from Dr. Jerry Uhl&#39;s operation, University of Illinois. However that turned out to be a rather esoteric business in the midwest and the dream of California induced a morphification into the new code school, with calculus still in the picture, and indeed a whole university.&amp;nbsp; However establishing a new ee-dee-yu (edu) from scratch is way harder than creating a dot com.&amp;nbsp; Try creating a new dot gov for a sense of what it&#39;s like.&amp;nbsp; Speaking of which, O&#39;Reilly did inspire memes in government.&amp;nbsp; I went to a GOSCON right here in Portland in fact.&amp;nbsp; You&#39;ll still find Ignite Syllabus and such, based on our Lightning Talk format.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I joined the school after all this change was well under way.&amp;nbsp; Although I never got to meet Jerry Uhl, I felt initiated into the world of Champaign-Urbana, home office for Wolfram, with which the school had at first been intimately connected (during the calculus chapter, with &lt;i&gt;Mathematica&lt;/i&gt; the workout bench).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My registration came with a bus pass.&amp;nbsp; I live in Portland, so this is one of the conferences I hope to get to, as a way of upgrading / updating my state of the art.&amp;nbsp; Pycon was here for two years, a blessing as well.&amp;nbsp; Pycon roves around whereas OSCON moves far less frequently, in terms of venue.&amp;nbsp; In the meantime, Portland has been changing a lot itself, becoming more a jewel of the Pacific Rim. We have a cable car now, an overhead tram.&amp;nbsp; Compared to the ones in Switzerland, its trajectory is approximately horizontal.&amp;nbsp; However that&#39;s still a legitimate use of the technology.&amp;nbsp; We have a hospital complex on the upper end.&amp;nbsp; Portland is about health care, as well as free software (free as in freedom).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of Pycon, I shared &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2018/07/headline-news.html&quot;&gt;the headline news&lt;/a&gt; in my other blog about the transition in power within the PSF, the intellectual property owner for Python and its trademarks.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Guido announced he was taking a vacation from his role as BDFL (Benevolent Dictator for Life), deliberately creating a power vacuum.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s feeling pretty confidant about the future of the Python language and wants to spark more creative ferment in governance.&amp;nbsp; Dictators rarely have an exit strategy.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re grateful to Guido for having one (part of his being benevolent).&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s not giving up being influential.&amp;nbsp; He has the juice, or what we Quakers call &quot;weightiness&quot; (a metaphysical attribute not connected to literal poundage).&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4905560639640947275'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4905560639640947275'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/07/oscon-2018.html' title='OSCON 2018'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4311371830996735888</id><published>2018-07-14T10:11:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-14T10:11:57.523-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Bizmo Sighting</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/29522152328/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;P1050891&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;P1050891&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/916/29522152328_c615bf8cdc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: on SE Hawthorne, turning north onto Chavez ::
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4311371830996735888'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4311371830996735888'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/07/bizmo-sighting.html' title='Bizmo Sighting'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5062701485854384291</id><published>2018-07-08T08:58:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-17T16:27:58.494-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Parallel Processing</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/42332790424/in/album-72157695209731812/&quot; title=&quot;P1050666&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;P1050666&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/844/42332790424_9bcda39ba2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I got some flak on Facebook from one of my friends, wondering why I bother to curate Youtubes like that, using one social medium to access another.&amp;nbsp; Think of stamp collecting.&amp;nbsp; The latest series had to do with rebuilding Aleppo, the grand mosque there.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Chalk it up &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2018/07/cyber-tourism.html&quot;&gt;to cyber tourism&lt;/a&gt; and wanting to &quot;go there&quot; with my friends.&amp;nbsp; This blog or journal was designed as the log book for a crew on the road, doing useful stuff like helping rebuild Aleppo.&amp;nbsp; Crews want to look back and tell their kids what they helped rebuild.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Bizmos have their fans, some of whom channel them funding to catalog order this or that artifact.&amp;nbsp; We see the transactions in the bright of day a lot of the time (bizmos leave audit trails).&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kirbyurner/electrons-rule-ac5f19d2996d&quot;&gt;Electrons move&lt;/a&gt; from here to there.&amp;nbsp; The crew will return in a future episode to help the locals install this pump.&amp;nbsp; Hospitals get stocked this way too.&amp;nbsp; Schools.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At the other end:&amp;nbsp; people in coffee shops, but maybe not that into coffee.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m borrowing from romanticized Paris, where we posit existentialism was born in meme form, only to percolate through coffee shops to show up on bookshelves, further catalyzing osmosis.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
CSN doesn&#39;t assume &quot;existentialism&quot; is the philo du jour, yet draws in those scholarly fumes, mixed with Borges, Arabia, Alexandria.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s a look and feel conducive to study.&amp;nbsp; In that atmosphere, you also have arcade games (we call them that for a reason) whereby becoming a champion may be of service to one&#39;s favorite crews in the field.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A team of three is cruising from Kabul to Istanbul and stops off in Shiraz.&amp;nbsp; Here we find some drawings by a street kid that lead us to this clutch of artists making some highly interesting models.&amp;nbsp; This crew specializes in mathy art, ala M. C. Escher and many more.&amp;nbsp; Think of that conference &lt;i&gt;Bridges&lt;/i&gt;, which said &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/incomprehensible.html&quot;&gt;&quot;my&quot; A &amp;amp; B modules&lt;/a&gt; were for the birds.&amp;nbsp; And tweeting I did:&amp;nbsp; let&#39;s 3D print these things, Makers!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Actually &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/12/convergent-friends.html&quot;&gt;my art work&lt;/a&gt; was called &lt;i&gt;Holding It Together&lt;/i&gt; in a Cyrillic language, and features six beveled faces of a cube pulled inward and held by tension on six cables to a smaller tetrahedron inside.&amp;nbsp; No glue.&amp;nbsp; If the faces are closed, there&#39;s a ship in a bottle feel to it.&amp;nbsp; Tension compression.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/16140315443/in/album-72157654417641521/&quot; title=&quot;Держись!&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Держись!&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7589/16140315443_6a3e6389b5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
Держись!
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, that&#39;s the science fiction backdrop against which this journal is written.&amp;nbsp; Then we need Control Rooms to help dispatch and coordinate the bizmos.&amp;nbsp; This would not be efficient without the caravans and convergences.&amp;nbsp; Health care teams can&#39;t all squeeze in one vehicle.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Control Room is a sister blog, suggesting the role.&amp;nbsp; I worked for Clackamas County in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/01/fragment-of-day.html&quot;&gt;dispatching driver fleets&lt;/a&gt;, an early template for the Uber model.&amp;nbsp; People bring different experiences to the table.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A lot of Africans are asking for borderless driving.&amp;nbsp; I was negotiating with some nationalists the other day, suggesting we could have a balance of Berlin Walls and lengthy queues, versus wide open areas in which distance driving was a given, a freedom.&amp;nbsp; No road blocks with checkers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The thing about Africans is most were never consulted regarding the map of nations to begin with, so they&#39;re freer to start fresh with an unmarked globe, only to mark it up with other markup.&amp;nbsp; Substance control check points, like freeway weigh stations, need not be barriers across a road.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Picture a cargo container with QR-code and RFID getting off loaded in North Africa and making its way inland.&amp;nbsp; The sensors it drives by register its progress and GPS is involved.&amp;nbsp; People know the contents and blockchains know how to move tokens around.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Keeping a cargo container on schedule factors in ample time for the driver to find this a doable lifestyle (citizen diplomats need to compare notes at truck stops, sharing news and views, for the health of the economy and Pareto optimizing).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Remember drivers might hand off trucks.&amp;nbsp; Sometimes the drivers linger, enjoying coffee shops, taking classes for credit.&amp;nbsp; Sometimes its the truck that stays behind, on a charging station.&amp;nbsp; No one said a driver has to drive more than five hours a day.&amp;nbsp; Maybe some do but the rule books is flexible.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you wanted to do some substance control, this might be the place, at the stopover, where electric tractor truck A switches its pulled container to electric tractor B.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Batteries may not support the long hauls characteristic of peak oil.&amp;nbsp; Tractors queue longer as well.&amp;nbsp; Drivers jump from rig to rig.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some Bizmo fleets work the same way.&amp;nbsp; A lot of the customization (e.g. favorite tunes, dashboard instruments) get stored in the cloud.&amp;nbsp; I tool around town in this mobile office charged near the airport, only to turn it in three days later.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll be continuing my work in another city, taking meetings where I need them.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5062701485854384291'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5062701485854384291'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/07/parallel-processing.html' title='Parallel Processing'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-743384402317754773</id><published>2018-07-06T18:25:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-06T18:49:58.218-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Choreography and Computer Science</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
In some documentary I&#39;m forgetting the title of at the moment, a solar dish technology, maybe just a solar oven, gets introduced not as a finished good, but as a manufacturing process.&amp;nbsp; The female choreographers take it on and make up a song with a rhythm that helps govern an efficient concurrent process.&amp;nbsp; Solar ovens roll off the &quot;assembly line&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Operations research goes back to complicated manufacturing and PERT analysis, finding the critical path.&amp;nbsp; Shorten this process, and the overall rate of submarine production holds constant, whereas if these two threads join perfectly, as when a body lowers down over a chassis, there&#39;s less waiting along an eigen-process and submarines appear more quickly.&amp;nbsp; Or Teslas.&amp;nbsp; Or...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Along came concurrency in computer programming, which by now needs attention from the get go. The question is will mathematicians deign to wade into the seas of time and join the engineers in spatial-temporal considerations. Of course they will, or at least the polymaths will. STEAM is STEAM.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, lets not pretend parallel processing was just invented in the 1900s, as Universe has been running in parallel all along.&amp;nbsp; The human body is a miracle of process management, replacing blood, skin, muscle and nerve cells from cannibalizing chemistry labs (the body&#39;s internals).&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not saying humans eat humans (a few do, according to anthropologists), just that chemicals self-harvest along many simultaneous supply chains in the human body.&amp;nbsp; Octopus bodies do this do.&amp;nbsp; Life processes embody concurrency, even as they spawn progeny.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Likewise, ordinary living requires engaging in many tasks, some of which need to run in parallel.&amp;nbsp; &quot;A watched pot never boils&quot; was a reminder to kitchen amateurs to not block on a process when there&#39;s so much work to be done.&amp;nbsp; Efficient choreography is a highlight of cooking shows, especially where teams are involved.&amp;nbsp; The clock is ticking.&amp;nbsp; Submarine sandwiches head out to the crew.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The all this time pressure, the response being organizational skills (scheduling, prioritizing), we see where schools miss being efficiently parallel themselves, if looking solely at computer science and not understanding the need for practice in team playing.&amp;nbsp; Links to sports and dance are not just &quot;nice to have&quot; as the skills we&#39;re talking about are essential in later life.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Math is an Outdoor Sport&quot; is one of my old slogans.&amp;nbsp; The idea was to get outdoors, perhaps with GPS, doing geocaching like activities, exploring a terrain, graphing a topology, making maps of many kinds.&amp;nbsp; Scoring well on a test might involve exerting oneself physically.&amp;nbsp; Of course that&#39;s nothing like the rows and columns math class of today.&amp;nbsp; However now that computer science is becoming involved...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2014/11/141103114236.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2014/11/141103114236.htm&quot;&gt;Theater and Choreography&lt;/a&gt; go together here.&amp;nbsp; Think of a Broadway musical and all the singers needing to change costumes backstage as the show continues center stage.&amp;nbsp; The exits and entrances, the meetups, the duets, the solos... the cuckoo clock of computer science, Newtonian and later quantum mechanics.&amp;nbsp; Life is a turning of gears, even if these be only metaphorical and therefore &quot;softer&quot; (more &quot;nerf&quot;) than real gears in some way.&amp;nbsp; Real gears play too.&amp;nbsp; Life encompasses mechanical processes, even if we sometimes use dance to rebel against too much predictability.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/743384402317754773'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/743384402317754773'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/07/choreography-and-computer-science.html' title='Choreography and Computer Science'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6572741864273125035</id><published>2018-07-05T16:55:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-06T18:05:49.900-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Refugee Science in NYT</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/41397779400/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Refugee Science&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Refugee Science&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1770/41397779400_b68e455c3d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt; has been giving column inches to an important branch of planning in our world today. Given mass migration patterns, humans are settling in camps.&amp;nbsp; Sometimes these camps become the most salient features of a given geographical region.&amp;nbsp; However, well before then, the signs and trends deserve and require concerted attention.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When does Health and Human Services work with United Nations agencies on various camps?&amp;nbsp; Asking Mexico to fund a wall was pretty stupid, but having an international community work on camps is not.&amp;nbsp; Before risking any HR process devised by DC&#39;s Beltway defense contractors, sometimes of limited imagination, you might want to find a Rehab Campus on friendlier turf.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m no expert on Drug Wars politics, where Drug Wars stretch back in time to Opium Wars and British mercantile enterprises versus Mandarins.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The idea of &quot;customs&quot; implies some shared ethic regarding substance controls, and a lot of the earlier consensus reality has broken down, with a new one yet to emerge.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve looked to the Thirteen Grandmothers for guidance, and instructed my Coffee Shops Network baristas (a front line) to keep an open mind.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For those just tuning in, CSN is about risk-taking for charity, and channeling cyber-currencies towards worthy causes.&amp;nbsp; Perhaps conventional currencies will likewise have a role?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Think of Video Poker as sponsored by Oregon State.&amp;nbsp; Your losings are the State&#39;s winnings.&amp;nbsp; Imagine instead that were you to win, you would have philanthropic powers to channel the winnings.&amp;nbsp; Psychologically, this model introduces far less cognitive dissonance, which may explain all the &quot;likes&quot; we&#39;re getting on Facebook.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Suppose you&#39;re really great in video game X, written in Rust, and want to commit your winnings to Refugee Science.&amp;nbsp; You understand these families need educations and want to see scholarship rewarded with redeemable coupons.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Study microbe biology, get a microscope.&amp;nbsp; Become skilled in some way, in response to positive reinforcement.&amp;nbsp; Educators around the world already understand this model, and therefore appreciate the positive role of blockchain technology.&amp;nbsp; Kids earning high grades have the potential to help their families.&amp;nbsp; Kids earning low grades still get to eat.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some of our prototype circuitry, in particular Netdispenser, failed to gain the blessings of EFF.&amp;nbsp; On the other hand, Freedom Toasters and TuxLabs have already made the grade, at least in an African context.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Game developers who help refugee kids get some traction, through One Laptop per Child or whatever, are in themselves a worthy cause.&amp;nbsp; CSN supports their valiant efforts.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6572741864273125035'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6572741864273125035'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/07/refugee-science-in-nyt.html' title='Refugee Science in NYT'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6055097697697836556</id><published>2018-07-03T15:40:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-03T15:40:37.647-07:00</updated><title type='text'>From a Facebook Friend</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;encrypted-media&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;739&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fthekirbster%2Fposts%2F10156392321303965&amp;amp;width=500&quot; style=&quot;border: none; overflow: hidden;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6055097697697836556'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6055097697697836556'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/07/from-facebook-friend.html' title='From a Facebook Friend'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-551773410578564680</id><published>2018-07-02T10:36:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-03T15:39:30.471-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Approximating a Bizmo</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/43102204291/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Trending, not quite a Bizmo&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Trending, not quite a Bizmo&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1790/43102204291_8cc2af8777.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Bizmo Diaries (this blog) anticipates more use of vans in help-the-world scenarios.  We&#39;re not quite there yet.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve always been well ahead of my time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/04/more-bizmotica.html&quot;&gt;Dave Ulmer&lt;/a&gt; was another pioneer of this lifestyle.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/42197369865/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Getting There&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Getting There&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/922/42197369865_961a9271ed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/551773410578564680'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/551773410578564680'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/07/approximating-bizmo.html' title='Approximating a Bizmo'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8330295315586007516</id><published>2018-06-26T22:55:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:17:47.742-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Thy Kingdom Come, Thy Will Be Done</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IpXVoSZyHXM&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I don&#39;t think &quot;globalism&quot; always translates to fantasies about one world government. It&#39;s just a fact that 8+ billion humans are embedded in a spherical biosphere, a Babel University. It&#39;s neither hubristic nor utopian to point that out.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our awareness of this context is more acute than ever, given the faster feedback loops. Observing accelerated evolution and describing it ain&#39;t the same as fomenting revolution.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mark Twain mocked artists&#39; conceptions of Heaven (angels, harps...) as uber-boring and anything but utopian. What would Jordan Peterson offer as a vision of Heaven in light of his claim that humans hate predictability. Nirvana = Samsara? Is Buddhism giving more of a clue? But then &quot;marriage of heaven and hell&quot; is a Christian theme also.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tower of Babel: 8 billion brains imagining reality in various ways = nothing sensical, yet something invisible, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/08/elitism.html&quot;&gt;the sum total Ouija Board&lt;/a&gt; re-weighting of weights. There&#39;s gravitas, but does it speak anything close to a language we might understand?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Spaceship Earth == Babel University == Global U (a teaching hospital).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Suggesting humans have room to be less awkward and uncoordinated in their collective self management hardly strikes me as a totalitarian vision. Extrapolate from trends?  Haven&#39;t we learned something as a species?  The question is have we learned enough to keep it going.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Certainly the fate of humanity is cliffhanger enough to satisfy most anti-utopians.  Dystopianism is pretty easy to promulgate.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yet is the Lord&#39;s Prayer not a promise of obedience to eternal principles?  What choice do we really have in the end?  Humanity might self discontinue. Utopia or Oblivion suggests a preferred direction, a gradient.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8330295315586007516'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8330295315586007516'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/06/thy-kingdom-come-thy-will-be-done.html' title='Thy Kingdom Come, Thy Will Be Done'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/IpXVoSZyHXM/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4203342084723745311</id><published>2018-06-21T11:22:00.005-07:00</published><updated>2020-11-18T23:30:16.613-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Occupy Portland (a flashback)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157696532818981&quot; title=&quot;Anti ICE Protest&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/1809/42214201164_28ea7906d8_w.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Anti ICE Protest&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The day after watching &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/06/isle-of-dogs-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Isle of the Dogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, I found myself cycling down to a kind of Occupy in south Portland, where a group of campers was protesting against the concentration camps, organized by the Federales, for undocumented immigrants not going through proper bureaucratic channels, a rather hopeless labyrinth.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We see multiple languages in operation in that context as well, plus an agenda to close borders that were never closed, historically speaking.&amp;nbsp; The logic of the purchase of this territory from Napoleon requires a stronger literalness.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Winning some battle with Mexico in another era never included Mexico&#39;s agreeing to foot the bill for a literal wall between the two jurisdictions.&amp;nbsp; That battle was only recently lost, and not by Mexico.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Nationalism (a memeplex) is working overtime to solidify itself, even as governments themselves are hollowed out by globalist networks working in concert.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Shoring up the nation-state system is the only way some supranationals see their way clear to keeping a hold on their own legitimacy.&amp;nbsp; How would they stay in business without strongly patriotic sentiments and a terror of possibly diseased invaders, infected with alien ideologies and religions?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Melody and I visited the camp by bicycle, reminding me I need better nighttime lights, as we came back in the dark, stopping at &lt;i&gt;Dots&lt;/i&gt; on Clinton Street for a single beer each.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The camp is at the base of the ICE detention center tucked away in a new area of town featuring high rise apartments and the cable car up to OHSU.&amp;nbsp; Getting there by bicycle is really easy, thanks to Tillikum Crossing.&amp;nbsp; I took lots of pictures.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4203342084723745311'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4203342084723745311'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/06/occupy-portland-flashback.html' title='Occupy Portland (a flashback)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6286274067141910638</id><published>2018-06-08T13:03:00.005-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-08T13:05:43.904-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Turning Tables</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I see a lot of people in Congress hoping to build their careers by making political hay out of Facebook&#39;s indiscretions around sharing personal data.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The EU is pushing back using legislation, written by lawyers more engineeringly informed.&amp;nbsp; Having to read patent after patent is a way lawyers continue to be Einsteins.&amp;nbsp; They don&#39;t just capitulate to the emerging cast of engineers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, some breeds of lawyer may not be sufficiently sensitive to the hypocrisy involved in pursuing private companies for amassing data that the government itself has seen fit to harvest, with equally base business motives in mind.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The national security surveillance state is sometimes portrayed as being &quot;behind&quot; Google, and of course there&#39;s lots of continuity around In-Q-tel and all that.&amp;nbsp; However, we may also tell the story as one of self reinvention, or even rebirth.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not like the old intelligence apparatus is still running things.&amp;nbsp; Rather, the IC of yesteryear gave up the ghost, which now inhabits a new body.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The District of Columbia still has a lot of pride in being cutting edge, maybe years ahead in terms of scenario planning.&amp;nbsp; Lets distinguish between WDC as a geographical area, where anyone might live, and as an icon or symbol in journalistic accounts.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s a difference between map and territory.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In my view, DC is of diminishing relevance vis-a-vis other capitals as a result of changes in political circuitry.&amp;nbsp; Decentralization is more efficient unless we&#39;re going to re-polarize and fight some wars.&amp;nbsp; DC is venturing into trade wars as a theme, and appears eager to foment more violent outward wars as well, which somewhat accounts for its waning influence.&amp;nbsp; People would prefer &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/06/fire-starters.html&quot;&gt;a less gloomy future&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6286274067141910638'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6286274067141910638'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/06/turning-tables.html' title='Turning Tables'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2995571195820357763</id><published>2018-06-06T14:51:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T22:43:40.434-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Princeton Chatter</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/41036734020/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;VNC to 2D&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;VNC to 2D&quot; height=&quot;313&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1830/41036734020_7e17340517.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I set myself up for a battery of medical office visits and tests, all the same day.&amp;nbsp; What better time to catch up on &lt;i&gt;Princeton Alumni Weekly&lt;/i&gt;? PAW we call it.&amp;nbsp; Clever.&amp;nbsp; Tigers...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The cover story of the June 6 issue features Olga Russakovsky, a professor looking at the issue of bias in Machine Learning.&amp;nbsp; If those gathering the data were racists (believed in races), chances are the machines will find those patterns all over again, thanks to the labeling.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The article &lt;i&gt;Why America Stumbles...&lt;/i&gt; on page 19, seemed an example of how bias equals inertia.&amp;nbsp; Rick Barton looks at Syria, but not from an existential point of view.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Does Syria exist?&quot; is not in question, even though its sovereignty is violated daily.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Does the USA exist?&quot; would be another question to ask, regarding this post Constitutional Banana Republic that took upon itself to bomb Syria recently, with great fanfare, in an effort to prove itself the Final Authority, complete with Nikki Haley&#39;s &quot;dead baby&quot; performance in the UN.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
From recent revelations about how Netanyahu of Israel (so-called) has been trying hard to start a war with Iran (Persia), the US (i.e. DC) complicit, we see that &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/05/judgement-day.html&quot;&gt;a certain cabal&lt;/a&gt; is eager to set that tinderbox called Mesopotamia alight, and by extension the world.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Apparently the feigned chemical weapons attack in Britain was intended as part of the same war plan.&amp;nbsp; Get everyone hating the Russians, accuse Assad of chemical weapons use in April, and then go on the offensive, with the public eager for a big show.&amp;nbsp; That almost happened.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fortunately cooler heads prevailed.&amp;nbsp; We know the hotheads are busily at work on their next subterfuge. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Announcing the end of the Nation State Era has become an exercise in self and species preservation at this point.&amp;nbsp; Clearly the puppet masters are eager to pull whatever strings they believe they have.&amp;nbsp; Telling uncomfortable truths is better than sounding phony all the time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However &lt;i&gt;Princeton Alumni Weekly&lt;/i&gt; is not prepared to be on the cutting edge, except insofar as its president reminds us on page 2 that universities often outlive nations.&amp;nbsp; That much is true.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So do they read &lt;i&gt;Grunch of Giants&lt;/i&gt; in the Woodrow Wilson School?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I agree with Chelsea Manning&#39;s recent remark in Berlin, that we&#39;re all machine learners.&amp;nbsp; We modify our existing belief systems in light of new data coming in -- or we don&#39;t.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re all implicitly Bayesians, with brains reprogrammable by mind.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Continuing revelation is a reality, the most sobering reality we know.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sometimes belief systems freeze up and become specimens in some World Game museum. PAW is like that in some ways.&amp;nbsp; Stick to belief systems the alumni are comfortable with.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s not that I expect the peoples of Spaceship Earth to spontaneously start up a new chapter by all gravitating to the same page all of a sudden.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s some eternal truth in that Tower of Babel myth.&amp;nbsp; We never all had a chance to agree on those Nations in the first place.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s just that it&#39;s a Small World After All, at the end of the day.&amp;nbsp; Universities know that better than most sometimes.&amp;nbsp; Congratulations to Maya Lin on the new installation.&amp;nbsp; I look forward to visiting it, maybe for my fiftieth reunion in 2030?&amp;nbsp; &lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2995571195820357763'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2995571195820357763'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/06/princeton-chatter.html' title='Princeton Chatter'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>