<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211</id><updated>2025-02-27T06:25:58.543-08:00</updated><category term="clojure python REPL ide"/><title type='text'>BizMo Diaries</title><subtitle type='html'>On the road with Global Data</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=901'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=876&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=926&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1905</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>901</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3246624357968090627</id><published>2013-09-23T20:50:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2013-09-23T21:20:04.974-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Drug Policy</title><content type='html'>One reason I&#39;m skeptical that English may be used to write laws (I&#39;m sure it is, but likely bad ones), is how it has three ways of thinking about drugs:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
(a) you abuse them, which includes using them recreationally&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
(b) you need them for your illness or&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
(c) you need them but can&#39;t get them, for one reason or another (this can make you seem pathetic on fictionalized cop shows on television, where you&#39;re another meth junkie / walking dead).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These categories overlap.&amp;nbsp; English are moralistic and often see illnesses as morally deserved, so (a) leads to punishable illness (b) for which (c) is the punishment.&amp;nbsp; Hah hah, funny English.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But when you say meth do you mean speed?&amp;nbsp; Lots of business executives, male and female, are chugging through life on speed and I don&#39;t just mean caffeine.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some have ADHD and take Vyvanse, Adderall, Ritalin for a reason, because they&#39;re sick.&amp;nbsp; Others are doing these recreationally, which is illegal, unless an &quot;unscrupulous&quot; doctor let them in on a lucrative diagnosis.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I say &quot;unscrupulous&quot; in quotes because I resent those who patronize psychiatrists who use their own judgement as to who gets the speed.&amp;nbsp; Mrs. Jones is slowing down big time and we could go into the reasons, but she really picks up on an ADHD drug, and Mr. Jones likes it better that way too.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You could do a big favor to that household if you wrote them a prescription.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But even that whole system is so patronizing.&amp;nbsp; If people had more freedom to self-medicate, with all the dangers to self and others that implies, then they would need to spend a lot more time learning to think, behave, and have the ethics of medical doctors.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They would need to be more health-aware and compassionate in general, because compassionate people don&#39;t &quot;drink and drive&quot; in all the billions of ways that can happen (no alcohol need be involved, where kool-aid is concerned).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If we had the ID thing down, then if you&#39;re the equivalent of an Eagle Scout, then go ahead and customize what&#39;s in your own medicine cabinet, you&#39;re Tom Cruise or Bruce Wayne and this is the science fiction future already.&amp;nbsp; The board is waiting.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Write scholarly journal articles about it and upload your biometrics, participate as a guinea pig in human subjects experiments, openly on the Internet, where lots of people can audit and see you&#39;re not mistreated.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You signed up for this.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A lot of people do drugs in this fashion, but usually only to (b) cure an illness.&amp;nbsp; If you do it to get better at sports, or at math, you&#39;re a criminal (if you think in English).&amp;nbsp; I mean yes, it is cheating the way some rulebooks are written, but where are the sports for which it&#39;s &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; cheating.&amp;nbsp; Give us those too.&amp;nbsp; Tours de Something.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s missing from the English language is the concept of using drugs for work, like Protestant work ethic work, i.e. not because you have an insurable illness but because some medicines are tools of the trade (whatever trade -- jazz musician the stereotype).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People who use drugs in religious ceremonies are about the only ones carving a new space in English law, and their progress has been slow, because the cultural IQ is low and rising only slowly (a vicious circle, don&#39;t you see).&amp;nbsp; I used to visit the Voodoo House (a spoofy misnomer), an institution connected to this new space in the law.&amp;nbsp; Not that I ever got to try their kool-aid, an opportunity missed I guess.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So yes, I come out in favor of more OTC solutions, perhaps with ID checking and rule-based authentications.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m going to watch the NRA closely because they&#39;ve been all over this territory in trying to persuade people about why a world with guns is a safer place.&amp;nbsp; Abusing guns is dangerous but guns in their place have their place.&amp;nbsp; Likewise, I&#39;m saying, with controlled substances:&amp;nbsp; that you don&#39;t have to be sick to wanna use them responsibly (unless English is the box you think in).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Does this mean I&#39;m for banning &quot;recreational&quot; as a category in favor of some new &quot;professional&quot; use?&amp;nbsp; No, I think the recreational category should stay.&amp;nbsp; But it&#39;s usually just lumped with abuse as another illegal activity and in that sense I&#39;m saying &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/12/repeal-day.html&quot;&gt;Prohibition&lt;/a&gt; is still wasting too many resources on its hopeless fight against Pandora.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Far less expensive is reinterpreting Pandora.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s somewhat overwhelming, yes, how much was in that box, a cornucopia, but it&#39;s not just the bad stuff, it&#39;s the good stuff. &amp;nbsp; And it&#39;s not always the stuff&#39;s fault, but how we&#39;re klutzy in using it.&amp;nbsp; We win a lot of Darwin awards, as humans.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
She&#39;s more like a Santa, this Pandora.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Using Pandora as a scapegoat was what the &quot;blame religions&quot; were into, religions that focused &quot;blame&quot;.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ve all met these religions.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re a pain aren&#39;t they?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;re even rescuing Medusa with snaky hair from always being so scary-ugly.&amp;nbsp; Her visage awakened a conscience in Perseus and led him to consult with Wise Athena about matters of the heart.&amp;nbsp; His &quot;slaying the gorgon&quot; was not some triumph over an archetype, an impossibility, but a sign of his own journey in self mastery, a stage along the way in his personal Jihad.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Others can take it from there, you see where I&#39;m coming from.&amp;nbsp; Less moralizing would be good.&amp;nbsp; English moralizing gets in the way of doctors without borders, all too often.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3246624357968090627'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3246624357968090627'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/09/drug-policy.html' title='Drug Policy'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-9111689436073501399</id><published>2013-09-21T23:34:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2013-09-21T23:54:06.855-07:00</updated><title type='text'>The Heat (movie review)</title><content type='html'>Having the FBI lady meet the USPO lady in a bar made a lot of sense as both the FBI and USPO are government pressure cookers where people of varied ethnic background are expected to get lots of work done, sometimes really difficult work.&amp;nbsp; Ethnicity gets in the way sometimes, or makes for a diverse crackerjack team.&amp;nbsp; It can tip both ways depending on the day, if the team is still bonding.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The &quot;team&quot; in this movie is a duo and spans a stereotype range in the night sky (of stars), roughly from Sandra Bullock to Rosie.&amp;nbsp; A particular spectral band of womanhood post Wild West chapters, the gun toting still there, amped up even.&amp;nbsp; Rosie has a fridge full of guns, which Sandra admires.&amp;nbsp; No, I&#39;m not making fun of the actresses by calling them by these wrong names.&amp;nbsp; They are both hardworking and competent.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The nerdy girl complex targeted by the FBI closely matches the nerdy Osama tracker&#39;s in &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/02/zero-dark-thirty-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thirty Dark Zero&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; [sic].&amp;nbsp; The homework pays off, redeeming these strong readers from wallflower unpopularity.&amp;nbsp; We spend a lot of time on the lonely lady&#39;s high school year book, speaking volumes about the &quot;to whom&quot; this movie is addressed.&amp;nbsp; Rosie is from Jersey City where I probably taught her sister&#39;s niece or something.&amp;nbsp; Just kidding.&amp;nbsp; Any resemblance to non-fictitious people or places is purely coincidental (except we&#39;re allowed to say Boston).&amp;nbsp; All my best to both characters in their policing careers.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The film is out-and-out comedy, tongue-in-cheek to the max.&amp;nbsp; This helps offset the believability.&amp;nbsp; Girls are being pushed by urban America into a life of fighting crime.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s what Americans do.&amp;nbsp; We have good people and bad people and tourist attractions if you&#39;re just visiting.&amp;nbsp; Not like we&#39;re imaginative or anything.&amp;nbsp; And even if we&#39;re cops, we&#39;re free to abuse alcohol all we like.&amp;nbsp; Whiskey gets a field day, as does Mercedes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The cathartic violence against the &quot;john&quot; based on Rosie&#39;s mind reading powers, rewards its primary audience with instant street justice, the kind of gratification they&#39;re there for.&amp;nbsp; If you&#39;re an anthropologist, new to North America, and want to learn some ropes, see this film, not just &lt;i&gt;Borat&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; See it at a brewpub like I did, one that happens to show movies, eat some pizza, down some beer (they were out of 20 oz pints so I got two of the 16ers).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Was it risky to target an albino for the kind of joke where you make fun of someone&#39;s appearance?&amp;nbsp; The movie insists its harmless slapstick, basically vaudeville.&amp;nbsp; People are just funny, what can we say?&amp;nbsp; The other guy spoofs &quot;bad actor&quot; and that dovetails with our unconscious expectations.&amp;nbsp; But this film is more wicked than predictable.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not going to diss it, so much as hold it out for anthropological study.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d like more psychological anthropologists on the job, not shrinks so much as people who analyze culture.&amp;nbsp; Saw a bunch &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/04/roller-coaster-at-reed.html&quot;&gt;at Reed College&lt;/a&gt; that time.&amp;nbsp; Impressive.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9111689436073501399'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9111689436073501399'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/09/the-heat-movie-review.html' title='The Heat (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8297240957514956355</id><published>2013-09-20T15:06:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2013-09-22T10:36:41.014-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Lunch at Maru</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/9844179825/&quot; title=&quot;DSCN4478 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCN4478&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7381/9844179825_0a6eaaf608.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mom and I were agreeing, over Japanese fare, that now was a fine time to be confessing how few and far between had been any diplomatic contacts between Tehran and Washington, DC, since the Shah was deposed, and yet we were already up to bombing again (Syria this time) &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/09/failures-in-logic.html&quot;&gt;a few days ago&lt;/a&gt;, from zero to sixty.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Military action is supposed to be a last resort after all diplomacy has failed but here is evidence of not even trying.&amp;nbsp; When diplomacy breaks down is when you need a flurry of diplomacy, or have US colleges and universities completely dropped the ball in teaching this stuff.&amp;nbsp; Has Woodrow Wilson School been replaced by West Point, when it comes to how conflicts should be handled?&amp;nbsp; May the historians investigate. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If John Kerry derailed the attack for the time being, he was just doing his job.&amp;nbsp; Diplomats should avert wars as a matter of course.&amp;nbsp; State should steal &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; the business, &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; the limelight, from the Pentagon from now on.&amp;nbsp; We don&#39;t want, need or care about the Cruise Missile Porn, generals on TV with their model jets, stroking their smooth lines, slobbering over the mayhem they&#39;re about to unleash &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/08/chicago.html&quot;&gt;on CNN&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/03/argo-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/03/argo-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Talk to Hollywood&lt;/a&gt; about that if that&#39;s your kinky complex.&amp;nbsp; Get your own Adult Movies studio.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We talked about Citizens Diplomacy or &quot;second track&quot;, which in years gone by State has advocated.&amp;nbsp; Whatever happened to Citizens&#39; Diplomacy?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s just they&#39;re so rusty at diplomacy over there in the State Department -- overworked at the top, feckless around the middle -- that any talk of a &quot;second track&quot; immediately sounds threatening, potentially disruptive to one&#39;s career. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Like when the amateur athlete presumes to challenge the reigning champ.&amp;nbsp; The champ just hasn&#39;t been working out lately.&amp;nbsp; The smell of &quot;rout&quot; is in the air.&amp;nbsp; State is ashamed to take its shirt off and reveal there&#39;s nothing there and/or a lot of flab.&amp;nbsp; Been letting the military fight your &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/07/dirty-wars-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;dirty wars&lt;/a&gt; eh?&amp;nbsp; Nice vacation?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We have &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/iranian-festival.html&quot;&gt;lots of Iranians&lt;/a&gt; in Portland, including a family I interviewed for Princeton, one of many.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re talking intelligent professionals with satellite TV, lots of skills, highly personable.&amp;nbsp; If DC is too quick on the draw to reach for the cruise missiles, even before deigning to pick up a cell phone, then maybe we should help those poor slobs out, so desperately out of shape they&#39;ve become?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;DC, you have three years to get back up to steam, in the meantime Portland will assume all your diplomatic responsibilities, free of charge, simply to save our own skins and build up tourism&quot;.&amp;nbsp; Sounds like a generous proposition.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ll give &#39;em four years if they can&#39;t hack it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So, hey, Iran, whaddya wanna talk about?&amp;nbsp; You wanna go back to calling it Persia and stop caring about old Anglo maps with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/07/pr-for-pl.html&quot;&gt;stupid countries&lt;/a&gt;?&amp;nbsp; Yeah, that sounds like a conversation, we&#39;ve been thinking that too.&amp;nbsp; Greetings from Cascadia.&amp;nbsp; How&#39;s the weather?</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8297240957514956355'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8297240957514956355'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/09/lunch-at-maru.html' title='Lunch at Maru'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2613045515279638670</id><published>2013-09-14T22:45:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2013-09-19T15:03:44.026-07:00</updated><title type='text'>AFSC Fundraiser</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/9754902911/&quot; title=&quot;DSCN4454 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCN4454&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7392/9754902911_c49aa52ccc_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I returned to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/02/report-from-afghanistan.html&quot;&gt;Metanoia Peace House&lt;/a&gt; on 18th Street this evening.&amp;nbsp; Eddy Crouch and John Munson organized this check-writing ceremony on behalf of the local office, i.e. checks were to be coded a certain way so the money wouldn&#39;t be dispersed as general funds.&amp;nbsp; Call it earmarking.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I lured Lindsey into coming on the chance some Quaker Voluntary Service people were there, and there were, but I didn&#39;t know they were there, nor who they were, silly me.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Plus I&#39;d made the mistake of describing them as &quot;professional revolutionaries&quot; to Lindsey which she interpreted a specific way.&amp;nbsp; I guess I was being somewhat tongue in cheek about anyone using that label, but then Linsdey had a plastic ID tag that touted strong credentials along those lines.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Her plan to publicly thank the Peace House for past support (food provisions) and to discuss a new serving site nearby, that might make use of the kitchen, did not come off.&amp;nbsp; At least she got to see the place and meet some of the people.&amp;nbsp; She came by bicycle of course, while Carol and I took her car (originally hers).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our focus theme this evening was empowering young people to grow into leadership roles, and that in part meant making television.&amp;nbsp; Portland Community Media had a sign next to AFSC&#39;s and some of the thank you speeches included expressions of gratitude from AFSC to PCM.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/9754924082/&quot; title=&quot;DSCN4461 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCN4461&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7422/9754924082_93356a2f7c_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Because the focus was showing videos, the Door Project was not specifically mentioned, nor was Opt Out (Truth in Recruiting) nor some of the other youth-focused things we&#39;ve been doing.&amp;nbsp; Instead, the &quot;if I had a trillions dollars&quot; program was featured.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Whereas that program was certainly apropos given the focus, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/06/recent-meetings.html&quot;&gt;my own personal viewpoint&lt;/a&gt;, the &quot;If I Had a Trillion Dollars&quot; campaign / contest does not represent AFSC at it&#39;s most brilliant.&amp;nbsp; Portland isn&#39;t to blame.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s a national program, and not one I personally have much love for.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But that&#39;s OK, it&#39;s not my role to automatically give a thumbs up everything the AFSC does.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not a robot, or at least not that mindless a one.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The movie by and about migrant &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/06/our-global-u-advertisement.html&quot;&gt;Global U&lt;/a&gt;&quot; students, on the other hand, had much more serious content.&amp;nbsp; It featured high school and college aged individuals without social security numbers (SSNs) and therefore with very limited prospects.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Refugees around the world are stuck in limbo, as the nation state system was never about serving everyone.&amp;nbsp; In theory maybe it was, but in practice it never worked out that way.&amp;nbsp; Millions of people are stateless as well as homeless.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s no reason to hope that nation states will ever fix this problem.&amp;nbsp; They have proved themselves incapable, on many levels.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A paid signatures collector came to our door today, asking us to petition Oregon State to rescind the governor&#39;s decision to issue watered down driver&#39;s licenses to people without social security cards, (presuming they pass a driving test) and to let people vote on the issue instead.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As Pedro explained later, these licenses make the roads safer, as those without SSNs don&#39;t feel obligated to dodge the DMV.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But as I explained to the signatures collector, these are less powerful IDs than real Oregon State drivers licenses as they can&#39;t be used with the TSA to verify identity when boarding an airplane.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s a watered-down ID.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The signatures collector had no idea about any of that, as those responsible for his training had done a cursory job.&amp;nbsp; We didn&#39;t sign in any case.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2613045515279638670'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2613045515279638670'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/09/afsc-fundraiser.html' title='AFSC Fundraiser'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7424601613865592557</id><published>2013-09-12T12:04:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2013-09-12T12:20:41.243-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Practicing Democracy</title><content type='html'>Quakers bring skills from their professional lives to the life of their Meeting.&amp;nbsp; At the start of a recent meeting the clerk said &quot;I&#39;d like to start this call by...&quot; and then self-corrected (this wasn&#39;t a conference call).&amp;nbsp; Another committee member started talking about the integrity of &quot;the firm&quot; as she&#39;s a lawyer at work or in some such professional practice.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The profile of a typical Quaker some hundred plus years ago, might be &quot;slave owning businessman&quot; with a conflicted conscience.&amp;nbsp; The anti-slavery movement was strong in England right from the get go.&amp;nbsp; And yet where did Jesus ever come out against &quot;slavery&quot;?&amp;nbsp; We talk about &quot;human trafficking&quot; today which should alert the more sensitive that we&#39;re in stormy waters:&amp;nbsp; the meaning is in the usage pattern, less so in the &quot;word itself&quot; (whatever that means).&amp;nbsp; &quot;Slavery&quot; is alive and well today (unfortunately) but goes by different monikers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The profile of a typical Quaker today might be more &quot;social worker&quot; or perhaps &quot;school teacher&quot;.&amp;nbsp; We have become less of an entrepreneurial class, charged with running big institutions, and now frequent the world of &quot;nonprofits&quot; and &quot;NGOs&quot;.&amp;nbsp; That was my professional sphere, starting with CUE, though also Project VOTE! (Americans for Civic Participation, 501(c)(3)) before that.&amp;nbsp; Then I became a self-employed entrepreneur (1990) with Dawn (we created DWA, like a law firm) but we both continued to serve the same clientele:&amp;nbsp; the non-profits of Greater Portland (and beyond -- e.g. Clackamas and Washington counties).&amp;nbsp; We had a business license and everything (DWA was literally a &quot;partnership&quot; in IRS jargon, filing a 1065 every year, Dawn the experienced bookkeeper of the two).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our Quaker Meetings are a lot like theme parks, like Oaks Park.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The committees are the rides.&amp;nbsp; In joining the life of a Meeting, you get to &quot;simulate democracy&quot; by involving yourself in a business process that&#39;s probably not run like your place of work is run.&amp;nbsp; Lots more rotation.&amp;nbsp; Lots more volunteerism.&amp;nbsp; The metaphysics is not particularly money-focused but there is a focus on paying the bills and planning for the future.&amp;nbsp; Whatever it&#39;s like &quot;at work&quot;, here you get to play on Quaker-designed &quot;monkey-bars&quot; and that may stimulate fantasies of a future utopia in which more of the world works by these principles.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Serving on Oversight is like riding the ferris wheel (the Big O):&amp;nbsp; you get the great overview.&amp;nbsp; Birth, marriage, death -- it&#39;s all there in microcosm.&amp;nbsp; Go on and go off, then go on again.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s what I&#39;ve been doing (going off in 2014).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Just got a call from &lt;i&gt;The Open Bastion&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; One of the interns has found a new job and we&#39;re taking her out to lunch to celebrate.&amp;nbsp; She was recruited from Code Scouts as I recall, a nonprofit Michelle manages.&amp;nbsp; My daughter interned here this summer, earning her keep in helping to scout out sponsorships for Djangocon.&amp;nbsp; So there&#39;s a lot of continuity in what I do, even though I&#39;m more the standard for-profit sector worker in 2013, with DWA retired as a partnership (my wife died of IBC).&amp;nbsp; My level of volunteerism is still high.&amp;nbsp; Food Not Bombs.&amp;nbsp; Quakers.&amp;nbsp; AFSC.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The conspiracy (a weak one) to rebrand Oversight Committee as Pastoral Care Committee within NPYM has something to do with the trend towards Pastoral / Protestant Christianity more generally, among more reactionary older groups, mostly grays, like me.&amp;nbsp; The gist is &quot;Oversight&quot; and &quot;Overseer&quot; sound &quot;too severe&quot; or even &quot;slave owny&quot;.&amp;nbsp; To me, it&#39;s a deliberate shying away from plain speech in favor of corporate &quot;word-smithing&quot;.&amp;nbsp; Protestant Christians are spiritually immature (witness the Baptists of Buckman).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fortunately, Quakerism is no longer completely controlled by the exclusively Christian among us, so we have some stronger overeers than you&#39;d likely find among average Xtians of more mediocre faith.&amp;nbsp; Quakerism stands well-protected against too much dumbing down I&#39;d hazard.&amp;nbsp; We must remain vigilant.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7424601613865592557'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7424601613865592557'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/09/practicing-democracy.html' title='Practicing Democracy'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3013492456877558953</id><published>2013-09-08T21:26:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2013-09-08T22:04:18.570-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Ghost Cities</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/Nc6tO9w8Nmw&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was out hunting for new-to-me memes tonight and tracked down &lt;i&gt;Agenda 21&lt;/i&gt;, thanks to Wanderers (our widely flung intelligence gatherers -- e.g. harvesting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/people/2100593/terry-gross&quot;&gt;from Terry Gross&lt;/a&gt; on NPR and such).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Agenda 21&lt;/i&gt; is scary to free-wheeling capitalists as it represents the more Borg side of humanity, those eager to fit in well enough to build great Cathedrals (not &quot;just&quot; Bazaars the way they see it).  Lets do something planned, top-to-bottom, not a patchwork, not sprawl.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Ghost Cities look to me more like China&#39;s learning from the sprawlers&#39; mistakes.  Portland has had its own &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/2926871961/&quot;&gt;little Ghost City&lt;/a&gt; recently, but it seems to be filling fast.  People don&#39;t throng to a construction zone, but do to a spanking new neighborhood, if the alchemy is right.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
China isn&#39;t stupid about &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feng_shui&quot;&gt;Feng Shui&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The whole Ghost Cities meme is maybe somebody&#39;s marketing ploy to get free publicity for these lifestyle options.  Clever. &amp;nbsp;The lure of the mysterious. &amp;nbsp;&quot;We&#39;re moving to a Ghost City.&quot; How cool.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, I like that this guy (the videographer) is out there with his videocamera, following up on &lt;i&gt;60 Minutes&lt;/i&gt;.  We all know &lt;i&gt;60 Minutes&lt;/i&gt; goes over the line sometimes.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/03/stewart-brand-at-reed-college.html&quot;&gt;Stewart Brand&lt;/a&gt;, the Reed alum (like Jobs) and visionary, welcomes highly concentrated cities.  Humans seem well adapted to pack and stack, but that doesn&#39;t mean they can&#39;t enjoy the wilds. &amp;nbsp;Just mount your bike and head out. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The wilds will be vaster and freer of humans to the extent humans concentrate and leave nature well enough alone.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Better a smattering of Borg Cubes &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/incoming.html&quot;&gt;by Paolo Soleri&lt;/a&gt; than strip malls 24/7/365 as far as the eye can see.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I think he has a point there.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The flip side of concentrating humans in cities is purging more nature of human beings.  Not in the sense of totally forbidding access to thrill seekers, but not encouraging human settlement on a large scale either. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The infrastructure won&#39;t be there for that, though for a light powdering of humans, as in agriculture, there may be. &amp;nbsp;Those wanting small communities in relative isolation need not be disappointed, and again, people willing to be concentrated in high rises are helping them enjoy that option.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The same people may go back and forth of course. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;m not talking about a daily commute but about life being in chapters. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Your school is in the wilderness, though amply high tech, while your first teaching job is in a densely populated area. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then you take a wilderness job. &amp;nbsp;Then back to some brave new Soma City with some unique hive mind vibe. &amp;nbsp;Delphi had a vibe too, many over the years. &amp;nbsp;Humans achieve new synergies in cities. &amp;nbsp;Why diss that lifestyle?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Just because &quot;both&quot; (urban / non-urban) ecosystems exist doesn&#39;t condemn any given individual to an either/or choice of lifestyles. &amp;nbsp;Experiment with a full gamut. &amp;nbsp;Life is short, yes, but that&#39;s the hand you&#39;re dealt in being human.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3013492456877558953'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3013492456877558953'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/09/ghost-cities.html' title='Ghost Cities'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6686287999802251298</id><published>2013-09-04T19:26:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2013-09-04T20:16:10.262-07:00</updated><title type='text'>O&#39;Reilly School:  Regional HQS</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/9675643654/&quot; title=&quot;DSCN4215 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCN4215&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7377/9675643654_311fa40094.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/9672499713/&quot; title=&quot;DSCN4270 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCN4270&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5516/9672499713_645171be02.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/9675640616/&quot; title=&quot;DSCN4211 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCN4211&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7356/9675640616_fc41ac0947.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6686287999802251298'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6686287999802251298'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/09/oreilly-school-regional-hqs.html' title='O&#39;Reilly School:  Regional HQS'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2845604163309428711</id><published>2013-08-29T19:41:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2013-08-29T20:08:23.735-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Code for America Projects?</title><content type='html'>I have two new areas for Code for America to consider, or maybe not new as I&#39;ve not been privy to C4A&#39;s meetings.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My only real contact was with their CTO at the last OSCON, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/07/oscon-orm.html&quot;&gt;at the chairman&#39;s party&lt;/a&gt; (we were saying good bye to Edd Dumbhill in that role, a team effort, with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oscon.com/oscon2013/public/schedule/speaker/3476&quot;&gt;Simon St. Laurent&lt;/a&gt; rotating in).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
(1)&amp;nbsp; get enough volunteer parents who speak Laotian, Vietnamese, Russian or whatever, all the languages of ESL kids, and help them learn Python.&amp;nbsp; In teaching ESL with Python, we&#39;re focusing on a technical subject, requiring technical English, yet there&#39;s room to better their skills typing in their native languages.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s a lot to work out and I&#39;m not saying only Python should get to play.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
(2) get enough traveling troupes together to help make the Internet come alive, as a culture and play space, for institutionalized or incarcerated individuals who might benefit.&amp;nbsp; This is a huge job and working with nursing homes is probably easier than working with prisons.&amp;nbsp; You want a population that&#39;s well briefed enough to stay safe enough to have the experience be rewarding.&amp;nbsp; Like when learning to scuba dive or roller blade, both potentially dangerous.&amp;nbsp; The Internet is not necessarily physically dangerous but it could do damage to your bank account.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Neither of these may seem sexy enough, but the anthropologists tell us that closing the grandparent / grandkid loop is one of the great secrets of a healthy culture.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s no reason grandpa shouldn&#39;t continue to poke around in C or C# with those fifty years his junior.&amp;nbsp; Nor should a teen shy away from having some grandmas in the queue wanting questions answered about HTML.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m not saying anyone has to go to anyone else&#39;s house to make this happen, though I do have the CareWheels model ever at my fingertips.&amp;nbsp; That was &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/07/wanderers-meeting-200575.html&quot;&gt;Ron Braithwaite&#39;s program&lt;/a&gt;, a collaborative effort, to have non-invasive people monitoring services that kept older and frailer people safely in their homes for longer.&amp;nbsp; In that model, dispatching would be notified if Mildred needed a home visit.&amp;nbsp; My work &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/07/deq.html&quot;&gt;with Clackamas County&lt;/a&gt; helped me envision the dispatching side of the business.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Imagine going to school and having a parent-engineer (doesn&#39;t have to be &lt;i&gt;your&lt;/i&gt; parent) speaking Vietnamese while also teaching you English, with &quot;learning Python&quot; a conversation piece.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You don&#39;t feel &quot;held back&quot; as learning Python is learning a STEM-relevant skill, plus you&#39;re addressing the topics of internationalization, world languages, Unicode, head on. &amp;nbsp; Here&#39;s a safe spac to &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/01/economics-of-happiness-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;yak about culture&lt;/a&gt; and what it&#39;s like when they &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/04/richard-stallman-at-psu.html&quot;&gt;encounter one another&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The engineer might be there as an aide, along with two or three more aides, all of whom speak different languages.&amp;nbsp; They help students at their terminals, giving them suggestions.&amp;nbsp; They go back and forth between English and whatever else.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The main thing we&#39;re all watching might just be cartoons.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s a way to rewind and pause.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But then you can watch them again at home (on Youtube?).&amp;nbsp; Each one comes in multiple languages but in ESL there&#39;s an emphasis on learning English (of course).&amp;nbsp; Keep going back and forth, learning Python and Unicode in between.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s an ESL course many EFLers could benefit from.&amp;nbsp; Sign me up.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2845604163309428711'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2845604163309428711'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/08/code-for-america-projects.html' title='Code for America Projects?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1345694607333130534</id><published>2013-08-25T01:00:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2016-11-16T15:30:11.634-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Chernobyl and Fukushima</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dS3WvKKSpKI&quot; width=&quot;420&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DGXTZxMMflM&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/e6iUMYbfEtg?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1345694607333130534'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1345694607333130534'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/08/chernobyl-and-fukushima.html' title='Chernobyl and Fukushima'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/dS3WvKKSpKI/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3453777457066256390</id><published>2013-08-21T21:19:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2013-10-06T00:22:35.072-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Planning Committees</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/8521078558/&quot; title=&quot;AFSC and YM Regions by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;AFSC and YM Regions&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8377/8521078558_ddc9e33cb4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;North American Regions, American Friends Service Committee&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As one of the NPYM reps with the AFSC corporation, I&#39;m on the lookout for opportunities to integrate the AFSC&#39;s machinations within a Quaker context, which isn&#39;t the same thing as seeking exclusive control.&amp;nbsp; AFSC is a shared enterprise, an alliance builder.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My latest memos focused on the Doctrine of Discovery, whereby in some imaginations, vast lands became the property of some King or Queen or President or one of those, even as the people who lived there were informed of their new &quot;undocumented&quot; status.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Doctrine of Discovery was part and parcel with &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/07/migrants-everywhere.html&quot;&gt;the migrant worker policy&lt;/a&gt; of exporting excess populations to &quot;bases&quot; in the colonies, aka the New World (&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/10/new-atlantis-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;New Atlantis&lt;/a&gt; -- many visions were projected, many of them focused on the element gold (&lt;a href=&quot;http://education.jlab.org/itselemental/ele079.html&quot;&gt;Au&lt;/a&gt;), not that the silver (&lt;a href=&quot;http://education.jlab.org/itselemental/ele047.html&quot;&gt;Ag&lt;/a&gt;) people would be without their say).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Given these &quot;bases&quot; were that far away there was little to stop them from banding together and declaring their independence from the King, little beyond their own inability to get along.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You likely recognize this old story, which has actually been repeated many times, with different names and faces.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/03/from-afsc-corporation-meeting.html&quot;&gt;The Wabanaki of the Maine area&lt;/a&gt; sent delegates to our last AFSC corporation meeting in March.&amp;nbsp; They were interested in talking about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://home.epix.net/~landis/histry.html&quot;&gt;Carlisle Industrial School&lt;/a&gt;, which Quakers had a hand in, and in this Doctrine of Discovery, recently repudiated by the Episcopalians, and a focus of the Parliament of World Religions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our internal documents spin on a shared web server we call &lt;i&gt;Star Cafe&lt;/i&gt;, which sounds somewhat &lt;i&gt;Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide&lt;/i&gt; to my ears.&amp;nbsp; The 18 page overall National Plan is there, mostly about demonstrating the efficacy of non-violent development over wonton destruction, in terms of raising living standards.&amp;nbsp; You&#39;d think that&#39;d be a no-brainer but remember this is &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/08/hotel-world.html&quot;&gt;only 2013&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The regional plans, more detailed, get a bit more in to the nitty gritty (but not a lot).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Given the recent redrawing of the AFSC North American regions, there&#39;s a sense that our current drafts have a ways to go, but that&#39;s usual for living documents.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s always inertia, things that already have momentum and can&#39;t be expected to just turn on a dime.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Whether the Doctrine of Discovery is mentioned explicitly or not in current draft language, I feel in a position to say it&#39;s topical among Friends, and a current focus of some &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/07/npym-annual-session-2013.html&quot;&gt;intra-NPYM communications&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;ll talk more about it all when the Area Support Committee next meets.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;For further reading&lt;/i&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.doctrineofdiscovery.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.&lt;wbr&gt;&lt;/wbr&gt;doctrineofdiscovery.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discovery_doctrine&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/&lt;wbr&gt;&lt;/wbr&gt;Discovery_doctrine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cms.yesmagazine.org/peace-justice/episcopal-church-repudiates-doctrine-of-discovery&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://cms.yesmagazine.org/&lt;wbr&gt;&lt;/wbr&gt;peace-justice/episcopal-&lt;wbr&gt;&lt;/wbr&gt;church-repudiates-doctrine-of-&lt;wbr&gt;&lt;/wbr&gt;discovery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.parliamentofreligions.org/news/index.php/tag/doctrine-of-discovery/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.&lt;wbr&gt;&lt;/wbr&gt;parliamentofreligions.org/&lt;wbr&gt;&lt;/wbr&gt;news/index.php/tag/doctrine-&lt;wbr&gt;&lt;/wbr&gt;of-discovery/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/10112433796/&quot; title=&quot;DSCN4695 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCN4695&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3669/10112433796_9da3f8bca1_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;click pix for more context&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3453777457066256390'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3453777457066256390'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/08/planning-committees.html' title='Planning Committees'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6100167316003264950</id><published>2013-08-15T21:26:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2013-08-16T23:26:47.838-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Testing Diets</title><content type='html'>Doug Strain volunteered as a guinea pig during &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/09/wanderers-200597.html&quot;&gt;human subjects trials&lt;/a&gt; for the military.&amp;nbsp; He preferred to be in a freezing box car, eating various gruels, than being ordered by others to open fire or whatever.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The military study ascertained that a high protein diet was necessary to counter extreme cold, an unhappy outcome in the judgement of various bean counters, who were hoping cheap lard, maybe wax, would be the ticket.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of diet, schools that have switched to healthier fare have sometimes noticed dramatic improvements in student mood and attentiveness.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m sure there&#39;s some truth in the view that just sending the message one cares enough to improve the cafeteria offerings (add a salad bar) begets reciprocation, but there&#39;s even more truth in the view that a healthier diet helps stabilize and improve mood.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Food Not Bombs&lt;/i&gt; sometimes tests that theory by providing &quot;green gruel&quot; (as if we&#39;re back in that box car with Doug), somewhat like Popeye&#39;s spinach, to front liners into today&#39;s psycho-battles. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Do the tent people brighten up as they get more fresh Willamette Valley produce, rescued from a composting room when still in prime condition?&amp;nbsp; If they do in schools, why not in tent cities?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve been a consultant for the Oregon Food Bank and respect the personnel and professionalism I encountered.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I also have no special ax to grind against Fritos or the Frito-Lay division of Pepsi, but lets face it, if you bring home a box of Mac &#39;n Cheese to be followed by Doritos then Fritos, you&#39;re not very high on the food pyramid.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not what the health-conscious executives eat in any of these companies, except for occasional snacks at company venues.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Replacing healthy meals with snacks only is what that &lt;i&gt;Supersize Me&lt;/i&gt; guy tried, and look how he almost died.&amp;nbsp; I don&#39;t think the McDonald&#39;s Corporation would &lt;i&gt;recommend&lt;/i&gt; doing the experiment he did.&amp;nbsp; Just because one opens a roller coaster park doesn&#39;t mean one encourages addicts to ride them 24/7.&amp;nbsp; Your company &lt;i&gt;doesn&#39;t need&lt;/i&gt; fiends and ghouls to channel decent profits back to stakeholders.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lindsey, one of the FNB cooks, was hard at it again today, throwing together a fresh fiesta salad with another pot of lightly cooked vegetables, generously spiced.&amp;nbsp; I had a bowl of the latter, having just treated mom and myself to &lt;i&gt;Burgerville&lt;/i&gt;, complete with milk shakes and Walla Walla onion rings.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I could feel the &quot;two cultures&quot; contending for my body.&amp;nbsp; At &lt;i&gt;Burgerville&lt;/i&gt;, I ordered from a car.&amp;nbsp; Lindsey takes her food downtown by bicycle.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
She lives in the world like the world &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a gym.&amp;nbsp; I need a special place called a &quot;gym&quot; or I&#39;ll turn to jello.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of which, it&#39;s time for a &lt;i&gt;Guinness&lt;/i&gt;!</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6100167316003264950'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6100167316003264950'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/08/testing-diets.html' title='Testing Diets'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6638347868841392451</id><published>2013-08-12T02:13:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2013-08-17T21:54:25.360-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Leveraging Python</title><content type='html'>Some people come to Python because they heard you could get a website up and running in not that many steps, if you downloaded and installed something called Django.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s more to it than that of course.&amp;nbsp; You need a public-facing web server with something in DNS (a name, a URL).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Should I say &quot;an URL&quot; and pronounce it &quot;Earl&quot;?&amp;nbsp; Some people do, whereas others say &quot;You R eL&quot;.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m aware of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/whats-urner.html&quot;&gt;pun on Uri&lt;/a&gt;, not far from CERN, where http was invented.&amp;nbsp; URLs were originally URIs, Universal Resource Indexes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/05/aunts-uncles.html&quot;&gt;Uncle Bill&lt;/a&gt;, 88, swung through today, enjoying public transportation, looping from Seattle.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;d been to the &quot;big Powell&#39;s&quot; downtown, where a PSU professor just happened to be haunting the stacks, and directed him to well respected tomes on (a) the life and times of Mohammed and (b) the early spread of Islam -- topics of interest to many readers, and especially those steeped in history, like my uncle.&amp;nbsp; I recalled a book called &lt;i&gt;The Arabists&lt;/i&gt; from Free Press.&amp;nbsp; I found the letter Adam Bellow sent me, son of Saul, when he sent me that book.&amp;nbsp; He was with Free Press then.&amp;nbsp; I dug it out of the garage, thanks to synchronicity, and gave it to Bill.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At &quot;little Powell&#39;s&quot; (across from &lt;i&gt;The Bagdad&lt;/i&gt;), Bill and I looked at books on HTML and Python.&amp;nbsp; I was sketching some history of how / where I work and wanted to point to the publisher&#39;s logo.&amp;nbsp; I also had a copy of &lt;i&gt;Make:&lt;/i&gt;, the &quot;danger issues&quot;, all about making &quot;sugar rockets&quot; and a tesla coil &#39;n stuff.&amp;nbsp; The founder of that had discovered this math teaching school and corralled it for Sebastopol.&amp;nbsp; The Python book was &lt;i&gt;Learning Python&lt;/i&gt;, but mostly we talked about HTML (&lt;i&gt;Head First&lt;/i&gt; series) which I traced back for him to Boeing.&amp;nbsp; Boeing is familiar to Seattlites like Bill.&amp;nbsp; SGML came from there, from which were derived other ML flavors, such as XML and XHTML.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We crossed back over to &lt;i&gt;The Bagdad&lt;/i&gt; and Steve Holden joined us, on his way for ice cream down the street at &lt;i&gt;Ben &amp;amp; Jerry&#39;s&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Bill and I had just had breakfast at &lt;i&gt;Cup &#39;n Saucer&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s probably easiest to grok is &quot;substitution&quot; i.e. the Madlibs kind of thing, otherwise known as &quot;fill in the blanks&quot;.&amp;nbsp; You start with the whole story then punch some holes it it, make those variables, which gives you a realm of possibilities.&amp;nbsp; If we&#39;re filling in with (x,y,z) coordinates, and the story is about objects such as cylinders and spheres, then we get colorful renderings in Pov-ray.&amp;nbsp; I worked for a toy company doing that for awhile, making realistic images of &lt;i&gt;StrangeAttractors&lt;/i&gt;, which was actually manufactured in a last bid to put a great geometry toy in the hands of both children and adults.&amp;nbsp; Another plastic rod and ball-bearing affair, with detachable magnetic tips, cone-shaped.&amp;nbsp; The dimensions were those used in ZomeTool.&amp;nbsp; They came color-coded.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Doing the math requires rotation matrices.&amp;nbsp; You can do quaternions too, as &quot;math machines&quot; or &quot;math objects&quot; to make polyhedrons turn.&amp;nbsp; This was where &lt;i&gt;Stickworks&lt;/i&gt; came in, my 3rd party library.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m still hearing the admonitions at OSCON to put licenses on all my code.&amp;nbsp; Apache&#39;s would work.&amp;nbsp; I just haven&#39;t gotten around to it.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not even on github.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s a social faux pas in geek world these days.&amp;nbsp; Gotta be on github.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My lightning talk at the &lt;i&gt;Pycon EduSummit&lt;/i&gt; took us through an hypothetical fifth course in our series out of Sebastopol (actually the servers are in Illinois).&amp;nbsp; Cellular automata ala Wolfrom.&amp;nbsp; Not unlike the PSU systems curriculum in some ways.&amp;nbsp; Doing next, next, next... in the sense of exercising a Python generator, is a really good idea.&amp;nbsp; I have a whole farm, a kind of midwest place, built as a place for Tractors (instead of turtles).&amp;nbsp; We get into it.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6638347868841392451'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6638347868841392451'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/08/leveraging-python.html' title='Leveraging Python'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-955181542224143560</id><published>2013-07-29T23:37:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2013-07-31T00:19:05.061-07:00</updated><title type='text'>The Great Gatsby (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&quot;I was the same man inside and outside&quot; is one of the refrains.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So is he betraying erstwhile friends in spilling these beans, or do we know from the get go it&#39;s a fantasy?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Gatsby is a self made man, in the estimation of our morbidly alcoholic in patient.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We think our Old Sport gets out, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/11/seven-psychopaths-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;by telling his story&lt;/a&gt;, restoring perspective and sobriety.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At least he&#39;s learned some self discipline, thanks to a kind doctor who wants to nudge him along.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Like, if you study literature at Yale, what makes you think you&#39;re cut out to sell bonds?&amp;nbsp; No, you need to fall in love with your characters.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He&#39;s sailed around the world, went to Oxford, a war hero, and now he&#39;s at the top of the heap, all for love.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s the hero of his own life, defined by his quest.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, whatever the critics say, I&#39;m fine with this blending of imaginative, faux reality, with everyday movie-making competence.&amp;nbsp; We saw some of that in &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/11/j-edgar-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;J. Edgar&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, even &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/05/aviator-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Aviator&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Coal World (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/more-about-narnia.html&quot;&gt;a Machine World&lt;/a&gt; -- a Matrix) with the all-seeing billboard is clearly the occult unconscious, that feared-yet-attractive place, black and bleak, a place on which the rich project their darkest fantasies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our storyteller is initiated into this underground through his mentor&#39;s &quot;game world&quot;, through a gas station, which for me echoed with &lt;i&gt;eXistenZ&lt;/i&gt; and the gas station there.&amp;nbsp; Be a player.&amp;nbsp; Hop in.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What sustains the Gatsby&#39;s hope is his dream has come so far.&amp;nbsp; The dream-like quality of the scenery continues to feel like &quot;in someone&#39;s head&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The storyteller is in a sanitarium we remember, with a case of writer&#39;s block.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re living his dream, of perfection.&amp;nbsp; An alter ego.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Gatsby pushes too hard but who can blame him when he&#39;s so close.&amp;nbsp; He kind of blows it, there&#39;s a train wreck (metaphorically) and we, the omniscient voyeurs, see the waves of fear coming in.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;The best she could come up with was...&quot; another refrain.&amp;nbsp; We fall short.&amp;nbsp; Tragic.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Operatic&lt;/i&gt;, that&#39;s the word.&amp;nbsp; The sets seem &quot;fake&quot; only in the sense that all fiction is &quot;fake&quot; -- a forgivable (indeed encouraged) playing with our truths.&amp;nbsp; An exploratorium, this skulletarium.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The grand estate-based aristocratic lifestyle with many servants, a choreographed affair, added to the sense of &quot;a musical&quot; with an all-dancers cast.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The panorama of the parties is very cabaret, like &lt;i&gt;Moulin Rouge&lt;/i&gt;. &quot;Very Fellini&quot; said mom, astutely, thinking of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0064940/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Satyricon&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The city is very Gotham.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s even a bat mobile of sorts.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Underwater again... love seems to end this way for DiCaprio.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Slinky Debicki was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/media/rm1656202752/nm4456120&quot;&gt;the perfect glamor girl&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/955181542224143560'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/955181542224143560'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/07/the-great-gatsby-movie.html' title='The Great Gatsby (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3231444616011798025</id><published>2013-07-29T17:00:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2013-07-30T19:39:02.464-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Iron Man 3 (movie review)</title><content type='html'>Hah hah, I went to &lt;i&gt;Laurelhurst Theater&#39;s&lt;/i&gt; web site and clicked on trailer for &lt;i&gt;Iron Man 3&lt;/i&gt;, and got a notice the trailer was blocked by one or more of the content owners.&amp;nbsp; Blocking their own trailers are they?&amp;nbsp; Well, never mind about the film then.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve heard from enough people that this is a miserable / terrible film to just leave it at that.&amp;nbsp; Fine with me if the &quot;owners&quot; lose money and reputation on this one.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3231444616011798025'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3231444616011798025'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/07/iron-man-3-movie-review.html' title='Iron Man 3 (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3363577683498902433</id><published>2013-07-22T10:56:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2013-07-22T10:57:11.291-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Car Show in Forest Grove</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe align=&quot;middle&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/slideShow/index.gne?set_id=72157634752655678&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol and I went to this after Annual Session. &amp;nbsp;Our red wrist bands got us in. &amp;nbsp;Matt Ryan was there, a car enthusiast. &amp;nbsp;The weather was perfect: &amp;nbsp;bright sunlight with lots of glinting.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3363577683498902433'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3363577683498902433'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/07/car-show-in-forest-grove.html' title='Car Show in Forest Grove'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4569290566669300339</id><published>2013-07-21T06:59:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2013-07-30T20:44:02.648-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Of Mind and Body</title><content type='html'>I got in a long talk with David Koski after dinner last night.&amp;nbsp; Annual Session is still going strong (I made it to both Open Mic and most of Community Night -- in time to see the Friend in Residence juggle (he&#39;s professional grade, can do five balls etc.)).&amp;nbsp; Great to meet someone who reads my blog at dinner, a novelist (I think of my blog as &quot;like a Russian novel&quot; sometimes -- so many characters).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A night or two before, I&#39;d been watching &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=khTqmN2Lths&quot;&gt;this interview of Mike Judge&lt;/a&gt; by Alex Jones, the guy behind &lt;i&gt;Idiocracy&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/04/idiocracy-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;the movie&lt;/a&gt;) as well as &lt;i&gt;King of the Hill&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Beavis and Butthead&lt;/i&gt; (animations).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I found talking to Koski to be the ultimate contrast.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s still fired up, in a comic book kind of way, (flashing on Crumb) but it&#39;s about such cerebral material: vZome and Zome Tool, the upcoming Bridges, dissections of the enneacontahedron and the five rhombic dodecahedrons within (was it five?).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He&#39;s also enthralled with that Archimidean set of Eureka! ratios:&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/08/tabor-walk.html&quot;&gt;the sphere and cone in the cylinder&lt;/a&gt;, with volumes 4, 1, 6 respectively (cylinder = two &quot;tuna cans&quot; marked by the sphere&#39;s equator, each of volume 3).&amp;nbsp; I imagine the animation, veering off into colorful geometry as David holds forth, passionate, weaving together stories with heroes and villains, holding our attention.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
David had just finished reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meandlee.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Me &amp;amp; Lee&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, after I turned him on to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/05/murder-mystery.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mary&#39;s Mosaic&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (thanks to Lanahan). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In my science fiction (fantasies about some future), there&#39;s more walking between centers, hikes through the woods, more like &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/05/wqm-spring-2013.html&quot;&gt;that Girl Scout Camp&lt;/a&gt; but even more spread out.&amp;nbsp; This helps with staying in shape and burning calories (as well as not concentrating too much power in any one &quot;lodge&quot; or &quot;HQS&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Here at &lt;i&gt;Pacific University&lt;/i&gt;, I have but yards between vast quantities of food, and my dorm room.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s almost as bad as at home, where I can waddle back and forth from mentoring to kitchen.&amp;nbsp; I think of ways to change the environment, such that I keep burning those joules at a higher rate.&amp;nbsp; Sharing the gym membership helps a little.&amp;nbsp; Having the second bike stolen added delays.&amp;nbsp; Food Not Bombs is healthy living.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of which, Lindsey got a workout &lt;a href=&quot;https://network23.org/lindseywalker/2013/07/20/food-not-bombs-east-of-82nd/&quot;&gt;pulling those two trailers&lt;/a&gt; (I&#39;ve done that, but only one or two times and for less distance), helping to widen our radius.&amp;nbsp; This neighborhood had probably never heard of FNB.&amp;nbsp; Tomorrow the world (no wait, we&#39;ve already got that covered -- only thinly).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
OK, time for breakfast.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4569290566669300339'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4569290566669300339'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/07/of-mind-and-body.html' title='Of Mind and Body'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2191935588428789339</id><published>2013-07-11T21:47:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2013-07-11T23:07:53.098-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Layers / Anthropology</title><content type='html'>Those who stare at GIS displays a lot (not me these days) know that data comes in layers. &amp;nbsp;Check out Google Earth or one of those: you can turn the layers on and off. &amp;nbsp;Turn the roads on and off. Check out the I-net. Highlight different features.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I think that meditation was in part kicked off by &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/05/the-age-of-carbon.html&quot;&gt;Applewhite&#39;s saying&lt;/a&gt; &quot;tomographic&quot; with respect to &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/06/gobbledygook.html&quot;&gt;Synergetics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/i&gt;(in &lt;i&gt;The Futurist&lt;/i&gt;), a word found in PET, positron emission tomography. Positrons don&#39;t last very long but they&#39;re integral primitive objects with their key roles. &amp;nbsp;Solar fusion &lt;a href=&quot;http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/astro/solarpp.html#c1&quot;&gt;is positronic&lt;/a&gt; along one path. &amp;nbsp;CERN is really into positron channeling, not just hadrons.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
ESRI&#39;s ArcView and related products, give you layers from datasets. &amp;nbsp;Superimpose this and that, learn from the patterns. &amp;nbsp;Like when slime molds define a transportation system, do the math.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some tribes speak of the ancestors stacked up on one&#39;s shoulders, like a totem pole I suppose. &amp;nbsp;Some journal-keepers might have branded that &quot;superstitious&quot; denying them their metaphors for what we in the computer programming business take for granted: &amp;nbsp;the objects have their lineage, their parents.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When a community is stressed, you will see the alchemy at work, as personalities differentiate and assume a foreground. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/11/great-pirates.html&quot;&gt;Winston Churchill&lt;/a&gt; was the war time leader for Britain, a product of those times. Or does it go the other way? &amp;nbsp;Historians debate these chicken and egg matters. &amp;nbsp;How does one explain Hitler or Napoleon?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Let me point to the TV remote as one of the great equalizers we didn&#39;t have back then. &amp;nbsp;We&#39;re freer to register &quot;ratings&quot;, a level of approval / disapproval. &amp;nbsp;Some people say Hitler would have been that many more times a monster if Nazis had today&#39;s TV. &amp;nbsp;But would his series have taken off? &amp;nbsp;Things have to check out to some degree, and with television comes a new level of scrutiny -- or not if the newsies get lazy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/omnitriangulating.html&quot;&gt;Omni-triangulating&lt;/a&gt; and integrity go together. &amp;nbsp;We have a lot of well-placed faith in not coming across utter contradictions. &amp;nbsp;How well placed is that faith? &amp;nbsp;I&#39;d turn that around and ask what else there is to have faith &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt;? &amp;nbsp;Utter capriciousness? &amp;nbsp;How does one &quot;surrender&quot; to that? &amp;nbsp;We&#39;d rather surrender to &quot;eternal laws&quot; I&#39;d usually think, though we do respect freedom and heroic postures.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, back to layers, we see them in people. &amp;nbsp;Shades come to the foreground, as a new persona takes over, slowly solidifies. &amp;nbsp;We all create / cast each other. &amp;nbsp;Projection is that powerful. &amp;nbsp;It takes a village to have a self, or at least a self of the kind we think social, in shape to interact. &amp;nbsp;We get new levels with greater aggregates or &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/11/physics-emergent-isepp-lecture.html&quot;&gt;piles&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The hermit gets tired of social interaction and retreats to a life away from the rat race. &amp;nbsp;We sometimes call that retirement in this country. &amp;nbsp;In India, they see &quot;holiness&quot; in that, but then &quot;holiness&quot; is a chief form of entertainment in the land of Ganesh.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2191935588428789339'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2191935588428789339'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/07/layers-anthropology.html' title='Layers / Anthropology'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6023831302026285122</id><published>2013-07-07T01:56:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2013-07-07T16:21:44.735-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Melancholia (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1527186/&quot;&gt;The special features&lt;/a&gt; focus on the two sisters, Justine and Claire, not so much on the other characters, and casts one as the wannabe nurse for the clinically depressed other, the bride, Justine, at the end of the day not truly happy at her wedding, the happiest day of her life in some romance novels.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It doesn&#39;t seem that happy to us either though, to our wandering know-nothing camera, &quot;we&quot; the voyeurs.&amp;nbsp; The guy is someone dug up by the boss.&amp;nbsp; The boss is hounding the bride to make him rich, as he squanders money seeking influence, power and control over those around him, eager to corner her talents.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Of course Justine blows a fuse after awhile, fights back, and ends up losing the guy, who was an appendage anyway.&amp;nbsp; She&#39;s figuring out the puzzle and not liking what she&#39;s finding, and fighting back.&amp;nbsp; Not melancholia and not romantic either.&amp;nbsp; She&#39;s just doing the math.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
She&#39;s ending up a stupid trophy wife and it&#39;s not going to be fun.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s got it all figured out and springs it on her (&quot;I wasn&#39;t going to tell you until later but...&quot;).&amp;nbsp; Was she consulted in any way?&amp;nbsp; How d&#39;ya like them apples?&amp;nbsp; She doesn&#39;t.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As the voyeur audience we&#39;re trying to figure it out with her. Who are &quot;these people&quot; we&#39;ve suddenly intersected with?&amp;nbsp; We do the math too.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For sure these people have all coped in various ways, which makes them appear insane to the know-nothing camera.&amp;nbsp; The stupid dad plays a dumb &quot;trick&quot; with the spoons, putting them in his pocket and bugging the waiter for more.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s an idiot for entertainment and in real life as well. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
His wife hates being married to him and is bitterly watching her daughter enter a similar arrangement.&amp;nbsp; She&#39;s as comforting as nails, a prototype melancholic.&amp;nbsp; Both parents are present, yet unavailable.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The fighter girl bounces around looking for comfort but ends up proving the stronger one who then gets to comfort the others.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The others have tried to be strong in their various ways.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The men stand for science and some kind of authority.&amp;nbsp; The women look to them for reassurance but then have their intuitions and just know, like the horses.&amp;nbsp; Yes that sounds formulaic but then this film plays with well-known patterns, stitching them together in novel ways. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
With the end of the world looming, are we able to trust them to really tell us?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Wouldn&#39;t that just mean panic?&amp;nbsp; Why not lie to us instead?&amp;nbsp; Like we do about other stuff?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m half remembering science fiction along those lines: a few scientists know but elect not to tell us.&amp;nbsp; Maybe it&#39;s some other finding, like a spreading disease with no cure.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;d tell us then, eventually, as it would be obvious soon anyway.&amp;nbsp; But in &lt;i&gt;The Walking Dead&lt;/i&gt;, the CDC guy had his secrets, even post Apocalypse.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That brings me to where I was focused at first: seeing this as science fiction and wondering how close this would match a real end of the world catastrophe.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Until the special features set me right, I had the planets reversed and during the overture (tricked into listening to Wagner, tsk) I was seeing Earth as Melancholia, thinking a smaller planet, more moon size, was hitting ours, not ours crashing into something much bigger, more gaseous.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Either way, it would have been a huge calamity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Something much smaller could do us all in. A moon-sized object hitting the Earth would be &quot;game changing&quot; as they say, plus so much depends on velocity.&amp;nbsp; Cosmic speeds.&amp;nbsp; We sit around a table at what we call the Linus Pauling House (he lived there as a boy for a short while) and consider these scenarios, given so many of us are astronomy buffs of one kind or another.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m thinking gravity would have worked rather differently and the weather would have gone much crazier, not just the horses like before an earthquake.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The movie worked hard to create an atmosphere and reached into our psyches more than it tried to lecture us about science.&amp;nbsp; The suspense builds, even though we&#39;ve peaked at the ending.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Another focus was the living standard these folks were enjoying.&amp;nbsp; Early 21st Century pre cell phone, with palatial estate living complete with butlers, stables, no apparent limit on luxury.&amp;nbsp; Yet there was weirdly no TV, no flat screen telling us about Melancholia.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Claire sneaks on the Internet furtively checking to see if her husband might be concealing something from her.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s more the feeling that they&#39;re withholding a diagnosis because you&#39;re not considered capable of facing the truth.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What do we hide from ourselves?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Having a giant planet in your face, looming, is like the elephant in the room, a loud reminder of personal mortality in microcosm, a ticking clock no matter how privileged your access to palatial gardens with sundials.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Are we having fun yet?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Suffering from a hatred of life when it&#39;s so precious leaves us feeling disloyal, or is it just that we&#39;re immortal and are loathe to face up to it, plus we&#39;re still mortal enough to have to die and die again, and who knows how many times get married, if not to a person to a company maybe?&amp;nbsp; To a lifestyle?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People posit &quot;Heaven&quot; as &quot;happily ever after&quot; just so they don&#39;t have to think about it, Hell the same way.&amp;nbsp; Mark Twain poked at those conventions, poking fun.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6023831302026285122'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6023831302026285122'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/07/melancholia-movie-review.html' title='Melancholia (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1896650440486157825</id><published>2013-07-02T18:34:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2013-07-03T01:31:58.900-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Beast of Burden</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/BtRnzlO7m_M?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/08/crazy-horse-play.html&quot;&gt;X-Ref re &quot;Army Mule&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VXJZVZFRFJc&quot;&gt;Spoof Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1896650440486157825'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1896650440486157825'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/07/beast-of-burden.html' title='Beast of Burden'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8882709292417312695</id><published>2013-06-28T14:19:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2013-06-29T11:39:03.830-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Privatizing Public Parks</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/5031900343/&quot; title=&quot;FNB Picnic by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;FNB Picnic&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm5.staticflickr.com/4125/5031900343_551c3016de.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;city contemplates padlocking public facilities to placate vocal private home owners&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Free access to Colonel Summers during posted hours, to the rain protection structure in particular, may soon be prevented if neighbors to the park are successful in privatizing this public property.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A vocal minority would like to lower property values for others by behaving as if they lived in a gated community with the right to control public access, a short radius from downtown in a major metropolitan area, with public parks zoned for public use.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That includes sharing the roads, not just the parks, with cyclists and pedestrians, with people looking to get out of the rain sometimes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At the other end of the spectrum are the more enlightened capitals, which keep municipal restrooms open, well lighted, spic and span during posted hours, with attendants as necessary.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes that costs money and yes that&#39;s what public funds are for, not locking restrooms and gating kiosks.&amp;nbsp; Civics 101.&amp;nbsp; Yes trash accumulates.&amp;nbsp; Pay to have it removed.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s a park.&amp;nbsp; Remember &quot;park&quot;?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The city&#39;s plan to kill its own parks is of course counter-productive as it lowers land values for everyone to have a city that&#39;s unintelligently managed and advertising that fact by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/afscportland/9096632775/&quot;&gt;padlocking the bathrooms&lt;/a&gt; it can&#39;t manage to operate.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Ugly porta-potties replace stately FDR era public works, more evidence of an Idiocracy in charge, squandering our collective inheritance.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Protecting urban ecosystems and subcultures from gentrification and conformity is part of no one&#39;s job description.&amp;nbsp; This is how wetlands get paved over and intellectual hubs get destroyed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Summers has been &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/09/switchboard-activity.html&quot;&gt;a switchboard&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Food Not Bombs&lt;/i&gt; uses it to serve healthy vegan food to triathletes and marathoners.&amp;nbsp; A youth-knit subculture that helps keep communities in touch runs through here, connecting the Americas by bicycle.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s a migration stop for exotic species -- of human.&amp;nbsp; Some of them make noise.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Enlightened neighbors would (some do) feel blessed and privileged that their park is valued and used in this way.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not a boring deserted vacant space, a park in name only.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Isn&#39;t this close to Hawthorne and Belmont, reportedly cultured?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Doesn&#39;t Portland have a reputation for weirdness, self-cultivated, business supported?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Can one have the talk without the walk?&amp;nbsp; Isn&#39;t that called hypocrisy?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What a great way to bring death and rigor mortis to a neighborhood.&amp;nbsp; Run &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/10/american-pop-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;a pogrom&lt;/a&gt;, by hijacking the city to play the heavy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve spent a ton going back and forth between that park an the nearby &lt;i&gt;Barley Mill&lt;/i&gt; as well as eating for free, or serving my friends.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s my playground too, a favorite destination by bicycle, sometimes Tri-Met.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Forgive me if I sound pissed.&amp;nbsp; Lets say I despise bullies, especially / including the ones who hide behind the mask of anonymity.&amp;nbsp; We all know that bullies are the worst of cowards.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8882709292417312695'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8882709292417312695'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/06/privatizing-public-parks.html' title='Privatizing Public Parks'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4327615636031040836</id><published>2013-06-24T19:17:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2013-07-11T16:03:56.174-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Odd Vid Clips</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/SuQGfk9Gmgo?list=FL9Ntx-EF3LzKY1nQ5rTUP2g&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;dialectical materialism&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;( machine world )&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/qwtFsmz6J44?list=FL9Ntx-EF3LzKY1nQ5rTUP2g&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;camera room&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/WF34N4gJAKE?list=PLF01E830B4D8793B4&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;post WWII civilian economy (&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/05/american-look-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;USA&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;( machine world ) &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
with thanks to cyriak</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4327615636031040836'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4327615636031040836'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/06/odd-vid-clips.html' title='Odd Vid Clips'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/SuQGfk9Gmgo/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3590700477619860867</id><published>2013-06-23T14:58:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2013-06-24T21:45:19.134-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Retreat Conversations</title><content type='html'>Lew Scholl today at Meeting updated me on some of the things happening with &lt;i&gt;Google Earth&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d noticed that his painstaking &lt;a href=&quot;http://sketchup.google.com/3dwarehouse/details?mid=784c529ace3127661955e09f18bdf60c&quot;&gt;rendering of the Pauling House&lt;/a&gt; appeared to have been replace with something more sketchy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Were they over-taxing their computer power, extending beyond their own reach, and now needing to dumb things down a little more? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/9121333770/&quot; title=&quot;linus_pauling_house by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;linus_pauling_house&quot; height=&quot;303&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7395/9121333770_659316e2fc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of &lt;i&gt;Google Earth&lt;/i&gt;, we were talking about &quot;ask not what Dufur can do fer you but rather what you can do fer Dufur&quot;, a apocryphal town motto attributed to Dufur, Oregon (not Darfur),&amp;nbsp; and I &quot;flew&quot; there in &lt;i&gt;Google Earth&lt;/i&gt; and then started absent mindedly following route 197 in a northerly direction... woah, what&#39;s that?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/9121405982/&quot; title=&quot;celilo_station by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;celilo_station&quot; height=&quot;365&quot; src=&quot;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5528/9121405982_87865486e3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Celilo Converter Station off Route 197&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A very space-alien looking facility, something to attract the attention of the paranoid.&amp;nbsp; We checked it out.&amp;nbsp; Ah so, the northern terminal of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-voltage_direct_current&quot;&gt;HDVC&lt;/a&gt; Pacific Intertie twixt the Columbia River and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blue-marble.de/nightlights/2012?ll=34.310833,-118.489167&quot;&gt;LA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Europe has a bunch of these links too, with more on &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/02/connecting-with-friends.html&quot;&gt;the global drawing board&lt;/a&gt;. The old mercury arc types are giving way to those using thyristors.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Of such stuff is a Wanderers conversation made, not trying to scare ya off or anything.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s a Nerd Fest you might say.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3590700477619860867'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3590700477619860867'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/06/retreat-conversations.html' title='Retreat Conversations'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7360197484899473382</id><published>2013-06-22T01:11:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2013-06-22T01:59:31.839-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Solstice Retreat</title><content type='html'>I returned to the scene proclaiming &quot;BS&quot; to be OK, defending it.&amp;nbsp; That might have been a kind of ice breaker, but the conversation was already rolling.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I think I missed Michael&#39;s didj playing.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d retreated from the retreat earlier, after pizza arrived, to check on my family.&amp;nbsp; This was the Summer Solstice.&amp;nbsp; Wanderers acknowledge these astronomical days.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Glenn is a font of information about the &quot;goal posts&quot; (solstices), and the zig zag path of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analemma&quot;&gt;the Annalemma&lt;/a&gt; between them, the lines of the so-called tropics.&amp;nbsp; Many an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Archaeoastronomy&quot;&gt;ancient statue&lt;/a&gt; has these goal post arms.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Michelle&#39;s group had joined us.&amp;nbsp; Good to catch up.&amp;nbsp; Thanks also to Christine, Helen, David DiNucci.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I started reading about the history of &lt;i&gt;Earlham College&lt;/i&gt; today, having invested in the book after &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/06/touring-earlham-college.html&quot;&gt;my tour of the campus&lt;/a&gt; thanks to a student from Kazakstan:&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Earlham College:&amp;nbsp; A History from 1847 to 1997&lt;/i&gt; by Thomas D. Hamm.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Quakers were found to be subversive by grand juries in some states because of their stance against slavery from the late 1700s forward.&amp;nbsp; The position was nuanced in that some Quakers asserted the slavers&#39; rights on the principle of church and state separation.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As long as the state said it was legal, who were these churches to say otherwise?&amp;nbsp; The War of Independence had been fought for a reason, one being to end the tyranny of church dogmas, be those the Church of England&#39;s or any other.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But the fact that Quakers had disowned any of their own who kept slaves, a painful enough process, gave them that &quot;holier than thou&quot; aspect that rubbed &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/04/django-unchained-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;slaverholders&lt;/a&gt; the wrong way.&amp;nbsp; Plus everyone knew they encouraged escapees to continue north, rather than turn them in to the authorities.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Indianapolis to this day has that central monument to the Civil War, in which it fought on the side of the Union.&amp;nbsp; When Quakers started escaping the South, that future war was as yet prophesied (projected) by only a few.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The split between Orthodox and Hicksites was also still somewhat new, and was rending meetings.&amp;nbsp; The alchemy of these &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/4120827538/in/set-72157622719474211/&quot;&gt;many splits and distillations&lt;/a&gt; is not that easily followed, with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/09/logistics.html&quot;&gt;&quot;Quaker guts&quot; posters&lt;/a&gt; telling only part of that tale.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Too often, the tale of slavery gets divorced from the tale of Indian Wars.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/09/indian-summer.html&quot;&gt; Indiana&lt;/a&gt; was named that for a reason.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Helen, of Jewish heritage, had been quizzing me whether &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/11/seven-psychopaths-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Quakers&lt;/a&gt; prayed aloud to God in meeting.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I explained about our silent worship format, and the fact that when Friends break the silence, as moved by the Spirit, they might use &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/08/quakers-101.html&quot;&gt;any number of formats&lt;/a&gt; or templates, including sometimes a spoken request of a singular deity, a form one might label &quot;prayer&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A worship discussion, more like Sunday Morning Adult Discussion (SMAD) allows more in the way of direct commentary and feedback.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Unlike those training in Roman oratory, Friends do not have a direct debate format.&amp;nbsp; Himalayan schools &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0201840/&quot;&gt;apparently have this&lt;/a&gt; and it might be to our benefit to develop in this direction.&amp;nbsp; The say Quakers avoid confrontation sometimes to their detriment.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Also at the Wanderers retreat, we used &lt;i&gt;Google Earth&lt;/i&gt; on my Android to circle &lt;i&gt;Breitenbush Hot Springs&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Detroit Lake&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Christine has helped clear a lot of trails around there, while another of us present had grown up in a dam-building family, like Glenn&#39;s did, his dad a chief engineer for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oregonencyclopedia.org/entry/view/detroit_dam/&quot;&gt;the Detroit Lake dam&lt;/a&gt;. </content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7360197484899473382'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7360197484899473382'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/06/solstice-retreat.html' title='Solstice Retreat'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5748140403026933154</id><published>2013-06-16T19:43:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2013-06-16T19:59:24.720-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Mr. Lonely (movie review)</title><content type='html'>Per the &quot;Making Of&quot; movie in Special Features, on this DVD edition, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/05/gummo-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Harmony&lt;/a&gt; had wanted to make a film about communal living, but then also had this Mexican Michael Jackson impersonator kicking around in his head.&amp;nbsp; How could these fit together?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Marilyn Monroe &quot;from the dead&quot; scene well captures the projection, of a girl idol whom in real life also died (suicide unless you&#39;re &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/08/blaming-castro.html&quot;&gt;a conspiracy theorist&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;nbsp; Her impersonator is true to the role, with Charlie Chaplin too jealous and brutish.&amp;nbsp; Michael was more kind and shy, and likewise projected upon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I noted how hammers were used and included that in &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/WittrsEX/message/5049&quot;&gt;a subsequent post&lt;/a&gt; to Sean&#39;s Wittgenstein list.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I confess I dozed off during the sheep slaughter, whereas the slaughter of innocents (innocence) is somehow a theme.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d had a long day.&amp;nbsp; Some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/9062180354/&quot;&gt;great tree bark&lt;/a&gt; in the park (communing with nature).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The impersonators congregate on this commune and stage a show.&amp;nbsp; The innocent sheep are a subplot that connect us to another subplot someplace else in the world where the Werner Herzog character is hoping to meet up with the Pope, thanks to a miracle.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That a Marilyn impersonator would stop a guy from using a fake rubber hammer to pound his own head is a gesture towards the masquerade carnival, the world of unreal identities.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s a high level of faux (farce), a lightness of being.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When an unreal identity encases a real one, might it take over?&amp;nbsp; Wrapping oneself in the mantle of a ready-made persona, that&#39;s what actors and actresses do, isn&#39;t it?&amp;nbsp; They play at playing themselves playing others.&amp;nbsp; Michael&#39;s agent is skeptical he&#39;ll ever be &quot;real&quot; (like casting one&#39;s sights too high).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The &quot;commune living&quot; scenario was very &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U8-UT3-0_Ms&quot;&gt;R.D. Laing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We each bring our own baggage, hopefully not too much of it.&amp;nbsp; Create something with the people there if you can.&amp;nbsp; It sometimes works.&amp;nbsp; That &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/10/remembering-dead.html&quot;&gt;Greatful Dead clan&lt;/a&gt; had a good ride.&amp;nbsp; Tribal villages may be hauntingly surreal and worth haunting if you have the chance.&amp;nbsp; Go in character.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5748140403026933154'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5748140403026933154'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/06/mr-lonely-movie-review.html' title='Mr. Lonely (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-379727076536715125</id><published>2013-06-10T23:47:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2014-08-07T12:26:10.696-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Right To Dream Too</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;375&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;flashvars&quot; value=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157633894585826%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157633894585826%2F&amp;set_id=72157633894585826&amp;jump_to=&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=143270&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;embed type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; src=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=143270&quot; allowFullScreen=&quot;true&quot; flashvars=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157633894585826%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157633894585826%2F&amp;set_id=72157633894585826&amp;jump_to=&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: the door project ::
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/379727076536715125'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/379727076536715125'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/06/right-to-dream-too.html' title='Right To Dream Too'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>