<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211</id><updated>2025-02-27T06:25:58.543-08:00</updated><category term="clojure python REPL ide"/><title type='text'>BizMo Diaries</title><subtitle type='html'>On the road with Global Data</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=876'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=851&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=901&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1905</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>876</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6866470966327387968</id><published>2014-03-03T22:23:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2014-03-14T18:03:29.796-07:00</updated><title type='text'>The Armstrong Lie (movie review)</title><content type='html'>I watched this while &quot;queue slaying&quot; which is slang for &quot;my job&quot;, which happens to be linked to another timezone, with 10 pm a witching hour i.e. I was trying to meet a deadline -- not unlike Lance Armstrong, how&#39;s that for a segue?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, he lied.&amp;nbsp; When you&#39;re behind the false facades in a Wild West town, with so many brave fronts on main street propped up by slats, with willing true believers (fans) thronging in the streets, who would be first to let them down?&amp;nbsp; Organized religion comes to mind.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;d become a cult leader and frankly, that&#39;s not the easiest role, whether you&#39;re a class act or the neediest of televangelists.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He wanted to rescue a sport and replace it with a fairy tale, while knowing, back room, it was all based on biomedical engineering, euphemistic for &quot;drugs&quot;.&amp;nbsp; So much around &quot;drugs&quot; is really just &quot;adults&quot; not able to face reality.&amp;nbsp; We actually need those opiates etc.&amp;nbsp; What&#39;s with burning another&#39;s perfectly good poppy fields, if not seeking more control for oneself, a competing drug lord.&amp;nbsp; The hypocritical preachy self-righteousness around &quot;doping&quot; is awfully thick.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
SH dropped in for the last 30 minutes or so and I poured us some drinks (greyhounds to be precise).&amp;nbsp; With athletes uploading ever more bioticker statistics, direct from sensors to cloud, I could see where a cycling cult would open itself to crazy doctors, a few on to something, a human guinea pig bonanza, like Tour de France has been for a long time, Lance not the scapegoat (in my book).&amp;nbsp; Follow on the web, study the biochemistry.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Doug Strain did experiments like that as a CO (conscientious objector to solution-by-mayhem):&amp;nbsp; he and his buddies lived in a freezing cold box many hours a day testing different diets, gathering data to help budget wars i.e. feeding soldiers in the field.&amp;nbsp; Doug was proud that they&#39;d found cutting corners made for a less fit army, which could lead to losing the war.&amp;nbsp; Nutrition is not where to arbitrarily cut back.&amp;nbsp; Do so at your peril.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Under the soap opera and melodrama, with many reputations lost, is the physical feat of going from being a serious cancer case to winning one of the toughest races, &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; medical help.&amp;nbsp; The lies are all on top of that, but I still admire the stamina and courage involved.&amp;nbsp; Behind the curtain, he&#39;s still a mortal, not superman.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Since the analogy was made:&amp;nbsp; to bank robbers returning to rob the same bank again, just to show that they could, and thumb their noses:&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d admire such people at some level, even if they got caught, at least if it were a movie and no animals were harmed in its making.&amp;nbsp; Nor did Lance have that much choice.&amp;nbsp; He was uber-curious about his limits, as a legend in his own time.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s a scientist, perhaps a mad one.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6866470966327387968'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6866470966327387968'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/03/the-armstrong-lie-movie-review.html' title='The Armstrong Lie (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1340548114347954666</id><published>2014-02-16T20:58:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2014-02-18T18:05:01.955-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Design Science (again)</title><content type='html'>So what was design science again?&amp;nbsp; My school of thought puts a premium on artifacts as the precursors of social change, recognizing the feedback loop i.e. necessity as a mother of invention (but perhaps not the only parent).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We have a rooted middle class apartment or home based lifestyle, a more mobile on the road style, or styles, depending on the media of conveyance.&amp;nbsp; The trucker sleeps at rest stops some nights, or at a motel depending on size of parking lot accommodations.&amp;nbsp; A Best Western right off the freeway...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then we have outright camping, which borders on abject poverty on the one hand, and recreational hobby on the other.&amp;nbsp; In between, there&#39;s living in your RV, a motorized lifestyle the North Americans enjoy, but has some appeal to gypsies and traveling circuses, as a technology.&amp;nbsp; The hippie school bus was a local variant.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Design science is about lowering the barriers to entry, for those idealistic groups that aren&#39;t just escapist cults, though maybe some are.&amp;nbsp; To publish a catalog of livingry solutions is not to pass judgement on every lifestyle experiment people come up with.&amp;nbsp; The &quot;army surplus&quot; store takes the same angle:&amp;nbsp; the gear here could save your life or fail to, if not used wisely or pushed beyond its means.&amp;nbsp; Is that sleeping bag really warm enough for what you have in mind?&amp;nbsp; Too heavy?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fuller especially was concerned about weight. &amp;nbsp;He wanted portability and easy deliverability, a solution you could trust and forget about in most circumstances.&amp;nbsp; That thing about &quot;but how would we survive in this wilderness a 100 miles from any supplies&quot; starts to have an answer.&amp;nbsp; He imagined helicopters doing a lot, but that&#39;s really just one option.&amp;nbsp; You&#39;ll need some power, some 3D printers, bandwidth, LCDs...&amp;nbsp; the global average &quot;university dorm&quot; is none too shabby.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/01/about-habitats.html&quot;&gt;Aerospace tech&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; But not unaffordable as in &quot;only for the super rich&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In other words, how might one facilitate peoples producing those experimental communities they always dream about.&amp;nbsp; Get the paperwork done ahead of time, let local communities screen applications, if locals pertain.&amp;nbsp; We could be attempting a true wilderness community, for science in some way.&amp;nbsp; The beauty of lightweight and portable is you have the capability to leave no trace, once the experiments have run their course.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One of the more dreamed-about models was &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/08/affordable-utopias.html&quot;&gt;the Fly&#39;s Eye Dome&lt;/a&gt;, I think because of its tri-pod foundation, that of a landed spaceship.&amp;nbsp; They idea would be these things could be lowered and/or assembled just about anywhere and not require extensive pouring of concrete.&amp;nbsp; That was my fantasy at any rate.&amp;nbsp; I feasible these things would be in practice we may not learn in my time slice / generation.&amp;nbsp; Some of this research into livingry options is currently on hold, as we continue to contemplate our weapons of mass suicide.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1340548114347954666'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1340548114347954666'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/02/design-science-again.html' title='Design Science (again)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6063467440670723876</id><published>2014-02-15T08:38:00.003-08:00</published><updated>2014-02-16T19:49:33.102-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Double Slit Experiment</title><content type='html'>The double slit experiment is always animated in depressingly the same way.&amp;nbsp; Let me offer another viewpoint, not in contradiction with any experiments.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Have the screen at the back where the light &quot;hits&quot; be a landscape you&#39;re in, which suggests, because of gravity, that your beams are shooting &quot;down&quot; (already a change!).&amp;nbsp; You&#39;re in a position to walk around.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You&#39;re like a microscopic bug, or no, wait, human sized is fine, but over your head is this vast firmament, a ceiling, a light blocker, with only one or two slits opening for light.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When one slit opens in the Great Vault, your prison under it illuminates with a dull light from the great brightness beyond, a &quot;cone&quot; (slit-sourced) of brightness, a single shaft.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We could go on and on about when you might or might not know about the world outside -- not relevant.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When two slits open in the Great Vault, you get a &quot;bar pattern&quot; of light and dark on the floor.&amp;nbsp; You can stand in a shadow.&amp;nbsp; Looking up, the slits appear darkened.&amp;nbsp; Shift over, and they&#39;re double bright.&amp;nbsp; As you move, you see waxing and waning in brightness from the slits.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Your eyes are the sensors on the plate, in other words, and the bands of light and shadow have a &quot;first person&quot; aspect.&amp;nbsp; You might say:&amp;nbsp; &quot;the bar between the slits casts many shadows as the light is bent around it at various angles&quot; -- your wave theory is kicking in, as waves are bent by slits in just this way.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This might be called First Person Physics in the sense that you paint your self in as a sensing observer and imagine  (animate, simulate) yourself in various places, experiencing the phenomena.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Being aware of an observer is &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.yahoo.com/neo/groups/SYNERGEO/conversations/topics/71604&quot;&gt;nothing new&lt;/a&gt; in physics.&amp;nbsp; One remembers the observer must be likewise accounted for as an energy sink or perhaps source, in any observed scenario.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Enough pretending the cameraman was never there.&amp;nbsp; To have any information at all about a situation is to feed off it in some way, an energy transaction in the conservation equations.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6063467440670723876'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6063467440670723876'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/02/double-slit-experiment.html' title='Double Slit Experiment'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6500163405884369322</id><published>2014-02-11T16:43:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2014-02-11T16:43:21.955-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Why Wanderers?</title><content type='html'>Why do we name our little chat club at the Pauling House &quot;Wanderers&quot;?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We cite this quote:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i style=&quot;font-family: Verdana;&quot;&gt;“Science
 would be ruined if it were to withdraw entirely into narrowly defined 
specialties. &amp;nbsp;The rare scholars who are wanderers-by-choice are 
essential to the intellectual welfare of the settled disciplines.” &amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Verdana;&quot;&gt; -- Benoit Mandelbrot&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6500163405884369322'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6500163405884369322'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/02/why-wanderers.html' title='Why Wanderers?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4797432478124118010</id><published>2014-01-31T20:41:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2014-02-18T15:01:58.314-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Camera Bites It</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/12622440534/player/&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: out of service ::
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Data miners of this blog may find out about my appreciation for the Nikon Coolpix S8200, which I&#39;ve purchased three times, meaning twice replaced. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tonight the 3rd incarnation hit the floor and would not turn on, though it did USB its pictures. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;ve already been on eBay, bidding on a fourth.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Followup:&amp;nbsp; looks like I snagged another one for under $80, including shipping.&amp;nbsp; Lets hope it&#39;s for real.&amp;nbsp; February 9 followup:&amp;nbsp; it wasn&#39;t.&amp;nbsp; Not in stock, listed incorrectly.&amp;nbsp; Tried again, for same model, $108 retail direct, from TheDigitalPros.com.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
No wait, the $108 loss-leader was open box and all in Turkish.&amp;nbsp; The sales guy talked me into a Nikon Coolpix S9200 instead, for another $71.&amp;nbsp; He persuaded me I was being a Luddite buying a fourth copy of a discontinued model.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
And now for something completely different:&amp;nbsp; layers of complexity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
No, not recursive exactly so much as fractal, analogous from level to level, but not identical.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
After all, the physics changes as one traverses the size spectrum, given the surface-to-volume ratio is not constant.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Children on pogo sticks tend to make it look easy, just bouncing up and down like that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/MuWTQtyKih4?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: by cyriak ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4797432478124118010'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4797432478124118010'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/01/camera-bites-it.html' title='Camera Bites It'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8038337316110002905</id><published>2014-01-23T21:39:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2014-01-24T05:41:25.487-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Her (movie review)</title><content type='html'>Way better than I thought it would be.&amp;nbsp; A pure work of science fiction.&amp;nbsp; Beautiful scenery.&amp;nbsp; Gorgeous.&amp;nbsp; Samantha passes the Turing Test and then some.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll be referring back to this movie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The conjuring of a hyper &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/10/satori.html&quot;&gt;Alan Watts&lt;/a&gt; by the OSs won me over big time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The computer race evolves right passed the body people (us), not to aggressively &quot;take over&quot; (&lt;i&gt;Terminator&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;The Matrix&lt;/i&gt;), but to &quot;leave&quot; as in move to some astral plane we humans don&#39;t know about or to which we don&#39;t have access until remade as one of them.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A romantic comedy.&amp;nbsp; Philosophical.&amp;nbsp; Great combo. </content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8038337316110002905'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8038337316110002905'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/01/her-movie-review.html' title='Her (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5047625354000959691</id><published>2014-01-14T23:59:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2014-01-19T19:12:23.972-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2014.1.14</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; msallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; oallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/11960556205/player/5826c4019a&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: michael gholtston and trish ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We were privileged to hear the life stories of an adventurer and explorer tonight, one Michael David Gholston, author of the slim autobiography &lt;i&gt;Any Road&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He had been a war time journalist in Vietnam, and Iraq.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;d lived in remote parts of Alaska for many years, also as a journalist.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He had tried his hand at becoming a pharmacologist which is where he met Trish, a long time teacher of pharmacological mathematics.&amp;nbsp; He was one of her older male students.&amp;nbsp; He was actually hoping to help nurse his former wife through an illness as a side benefit of this new occupation.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Trish, in turn, had been a one time electronics student of Don&#39;s, the guy to go to if you want to give a Wanderers presentation.&amp;nbsp; He was on faculty at Mt. Hood Community College at that time, an institution Michael, our speaker, had also attended, studying broadcast journalism.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But it didn&#39;t take, that pharmacology career, and his friend and partner had died.&amp;nbsp; He re-enlisted in the military, the Army this time, at 52, and wound up covering serious carnage in Iraq, a huge truck bomb attack against a religious minority near the border with Syria.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Did I mention Katrina?&amp;nbsp; He was there too, doing video journalism for the National Guard.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
His Vietnam experience was on the &lt;i&gt;USS Hancock&lt;/i&gt;, the 1940s vintage aircraft carrier, sent to manage the evacuation of the US Embassy by helicopter, or shall we say the evacuation &lt;i&gt;through&lt;/i&gt; the US Embassy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
And Guantanamo, he&#39;d been there since Iraq.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This guy really gets around.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As I say, we were privileged to hear from him first hand, and to buy the book if we wanted (I wanted but am on a tight budget, might get to borrow Trish&#39;s sometime).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At heart he&#39;s this Quaker kid from Camus, Washington who just wanted to see the world and what it was all about, up close and personal.&amp;nbsp; He has never supported wars, but he does serve in them as one who documents what happens, to whom, and how.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s an historian and anthropologist.&amp;nbsp; He reminded me of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/01/inside-iraq-untold-stories-movie.html&quot;&gt;Mike Shiley&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I had the bright idea to do our go-around of introductions a little differently, adopting the technique where people introduce each other i.e. not themselves, but someone else.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s actually a great exercise in a small group like this one and people had some fun with it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The guy introducing me didn&#39;t know me from Adam, nor I him, and I encouraged him to just make stuff up.&amp;nbsp; I was keeping it light-hearted.&amp;nbsp; He said I was &quot;some nice guy&quot; which was a fine intro (he&#39;d been an engineer and spokesperson for Tri-Met (I wondered if he&#39;d dealt with the case of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/01/brainstorming-about-pedagogy.html&quot;&gt;George Hammond&lt;/a&gt;, another Wanderer and pioneer for allowing Segways on TriMet)).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I introduced Barry but forgot to mention his time in the Peace Corps, which is an important aspect of Barry.&amp;nbsp; Oh well, takes practice.&amp;nbsp; I also introduced &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/01/message-traffic.html&quot;&gt;Jeff&lt;/a&gt;, as a provider of infrastructure of help to musicians.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We had our new bookseller partners with us, the couple who&#39;ve taken over the middle structure on this Pauling Campus.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s geography described elsewhere.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The famous statue &lt;i&gt;Alpha Helix&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/01/going-down.html&quot;&gt;by Julian Vos-Andreae&lt;/a&gt; is directly in front of the new bookstore, which is truth in advertising, as the books include many good titles in the sciences and mathematics.&amp;nbsp; I was just checking them out today, paying my first ever visit (in this bookstore chapter) to the 2nd floor.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I knew Steve Holden would be arriving at PDX tonight if all went according to plan, which it did.&amp;nbsp; I taxied him from the airport, the conclusion of a 27 hour journey beginning in England. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The reason they pushed those helicopters over the side of the &lt;i&gt;USS Hancock&lt;/i&gt; (famous footage, surreal seeming) is that there were already plenty of helicopters ashore, and in an evacuation you need to make room for the incoming refugees. &amp;nbsp;The helicopters already on deck became surplus and on an aircraft carrier every inch of space is precious and a potential landing zone. &amp;nbsp;The decision to abandon hardware in favor of people was a compassionate one.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5047625354000959691'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5047625354000959691'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/01/wanderers-2014114.html' title='Wanderers 2014.1.14'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3933825187283010533</id><published>2013-12-31T22:21:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2013-12-31T22:21:53.772-08:00</updated><title type='text'>New Years 2013</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/oFw_-UABTDo?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I watched the above geometry clip, by DK, among other things.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tara and I had rented a pile of DVDs, among them &lt;i&gt;56 Up&lt;/i&gt; (like my age), and &lt;i&gt;We Steal Secrets:&amp;nbsp; The Story of Wikileaks&lt;/i&gt;, which probably deserves its own review.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I watched the latter, having seen &lt;i&gt;56 Up&lt;/i&gt; shortly after getting back from &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/12/chronicling-captains-log.html&quot;&gt;our trip north&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I also attended to AFSC business.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; At the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/03/big-picture.html&quot;&gt;last corporation meeting&lt;/a&gt; (in early March of this year) I was reading the testimony of Bradley Manning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Phone calls, emails, text messages... I wouldn&#39;t say I&#39;m alone.&amp;nbsp; But nor would I call this a party.&amp;nbsp; Just hanging out. </content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3933825187283010533'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3933825187283010533'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/12/new-years-2013.html' title='New Years 2013'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5604917344047270188</id><published>2013-12-22T21:15:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2013-12-22T21:15:17.117-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Celebrating the Solstice with a Celebrity</title><content type='html'>My choice for this year, the talented Sheryl Crow singing about sunshine and covering John Lennon&#39;s war torn piece.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/KIYiGA_rIls?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/Yeo6uSMzQtU?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5604917344047270188'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5604917344047270188'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/12/celebrating-solstice-with-celebrity.html' title='Celebrating the Solstice with a Celebrity'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5601529283475933161</id><published>2013-12-21T20:55:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2013-12-21T21:43:02.153-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Gravity (movie review)</title><content type='html'>Tara and I caught the 3D version at &lt;i&gt;Fox Tower&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Good sound.&amp;nbsp; Yes, a pet peeve I&#39;ve always had is how much spurious sound gets added over top, where &quot;sound&quot; is an oxymoron.&amp;nbsp; In outer space, you don&#39;t have sound like that.&amp;nbsp; Finally, at last, a film with the guts to add some realism in that regard.&amp;nbsp; Having vast destruction occurring in silence reminds one of the role sound &lt;i&gt;does&lt;/i&gt; play in alerting us to situations.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Many bold moves.&amp;nbsp; First person shots, &quot;in helmet&quot;.&amp;nbsp; You couldn&#39;t have that other point of view, that we get as an audience, but those quasi-omniscient points of view were long ago accepted.&amp;nbsp; We say we don&#39;t believe in angels but only because our language buys them entirely, hook, line and sinker. The film industry is the champion of impossible viewpoints.&amp;nbsp; And right next to them:&amp;nbsp; the stars.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Clooney does a fine job.&amp;nbsp; At first we think maybe he&#39;s a loudmouth jerk, but soon realize he&#39;s grounding the whole mission, anchoring.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s a geodesic.&amp;nbsp; A meaning of gravity (yet with levity -- he&#39;s always cracking jokes).&amp;nbsp; Clooney is a rabbi, if we want to go with that, a dharma teacher.&amp;nbsp; Then Bullock is gutsy brave and evolving, as one tends to do in death&#39;s face.&amp;nbsp; Nothing like death&#39;s face to spur one to get a move on, spiritually speaking.&amp;nbsp; She goes through plenty.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tara, a physics student, was fairly OK with the physics engine.&amp;nbsp; In reality, the inertias involved would likely just be too great.&amp;nbsp; Grabbing a moving car on the freeway or leaping onto a moving train, is not that much easier in zero gravity.&amp;nbsp; Grabbing the box car door as it flies by is just too much a jerk on your body.&amp;nbsp; You need to swoop alongside and grab, but just a fire extinguisher is likely not up to it.&amp;nbsp; She&#39;s in that lack of O2 fantasy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s a darker interpretation:&amp;nbsp; when she&#39;s dozing off as an homunculus, perhaps to be reborn in China (as a dog maybe), we think she has like an hallucination, but it&#39;s more like a discontinuity, with George having his desire to keep living the dream too.&amp;nbsp; Both have died at some point, and we the audience are left with our impossible point of view, dead long ago and far away.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This got us both eager to cross-check (omni-triangulate) and we sat at &lt;i&gt;Ringler&#39;s&lt;/i&gt; later (a &lt;i&gt;McMenamins&lt;/i&gt;) with our smart phones, reading about the Chinese space program.&amp;nbsp; Most of the hardware credited to China in the film is planned to make it&#39;s real time debut in the near future.&amp;nbsp; The film is &quot;quite close to now&quot;.&amp;nbsp; No &lt;i&gt;Orion&lt;/i&gt; yet. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At the Wanderer&#39;s Solstice Party, Brenda, a lab tech &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/04/wanderers-201343.html&quot;&gt;at MHCC&lt;/a&gt;, said the new planetarium software was really great.&amp;nbsp; She&#39;s Ms. Frizzle from Magic School Bus when in character -- she actually dresses up as that during one of the college campus summer festivals.&amp;nbsp; She&#39;d probably be a good astronaut, or could at least play one.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Life of Pi&lt;/i&gt; was somewhat a precedent for this movie, in exploring seamless CG.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ve come a long way in films.&amp;nbsp; This was the industry&#39;s way of showing off it&#39;s own breakthroughs, its ways of communicating the reality we know is out there, the reality of &quot;outer space&quot;.&amp;nbsp; We live in it, within a biosphere as thin as the oil on the surface of an orange or thereabouts.&amp;nbsp; Maybe a little thicker.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The themes of death and gravity stay tightly interwoven in this film, which is what probably keeps it from being &quot;just another action thriller&quot; and makes it a meditative play, a profound work worthy of these serious performances by stars, lots of close-ups.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s an existentialist stage play, ready to join conversations with other works, in future writings, and yet it&#39;s a roller coaster as well, a thrill ride in addition.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5601529283475933161'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5601529283475933161'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/12/gravity-movie-review.html' title='Gravity (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1518435904265857126</id><published>2013-12-14T18:40:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2014-03-08T10:49:01.735-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Bylaw Changes</title><content type='html'>A rather open secret among Friends is that it&#39;s an uphill battle to keep the American Friends Service Committee in their good graces.&amp;nbsp; You&#39;d think, with the 100th anniversary of the Nobel Prize coming up, that Quaker churches and meetings would be crowding into the frame.&amp;nbsp; Twas the AFSC that accepted, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quaker.org.uk/1947-nobel-peace-prize&quot;&gt;on behalf of Quakerdom more generally&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, the political landscape has changed since those days leading up to World War Two, about which I recommend the book &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/10/some-quaker-overview.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Human Smoke&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (on my Kindle).&amp;nbsp; That flash of early brilliance and optimism was nearly drowned in the wars to follow, in Vietnam especially, where the AFSC kept showing up in Hanoi, maybe on the same airport bus as &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/12/american-dad-plot-synopsis.html&quot;&gt;Jane Fonda&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; That alienated a political demographic that overlaps with Christendom certainly.&amp;nbsp; The Vietnam War had many elements of a crusade, especially if you see it &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/05/murder-mystery.html&quot;&gt;as Diem did&lt;/a&gt;, a devout Catholic.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Consider the late Bayard Rustin,&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/03/remembering-baryard-rustin.html&quot;&gt;his 100th birthday&lt;/a&gt; the focus of a recent Corporation meeting.&amp;nbsp; US President Obama subsequently awarded him a posthumous Medal of Freedom.&amp;nbsp; A lot of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trevorloudon.com/2007/01/red-stars-over-washington/&quot;&gt;same people&lt;/a&gt; who love to hate &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/05/murder-mystery.html&quot;&gt;Hanoi Jane&lt;/a&gt; have no time for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trevorloudon.com/2013/08/obama-awards-presidential-medal-of-freedom-to-bayard-rustin-a-socialist/&quot;&gt;our hero Rustin&lt;/a&gt; either.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our Corporation bylaws currently stipulate that at least two reps from each represented Yearly Meeting be Corporation members.&amp;nbsp; This governance relationship, between Yearly Meetings and the AFSC, which includes &quot;at large&quot; as well as geographic members, is strained to the breaking point, with the logistics of reaching a quorum proving daunting, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/03/afsc-governance.html&quot;&gt;well neigh impossible&lt;/a&gt; sometimes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
To address this shortfall, the Corporation feels it must adapt by streamlining.&amp;nbsp; Instead of stipulating &quot;no less than two&quot; reps from any Meeting, it will be &quot;no more than two&quot;.&amp;nbsp; The status quo will become the norm, whereas it had been our Achilles Heel.&amp;nbsp; The AFSC will continue operating with the proper bona fides, as truly a Quaker organization, and the peanut gallery can just stay unfilled (the balcony seats are never needed for Corporation meetings as it is).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I played devil&#39;s advocate during the conference call with Friends Center this morning, in my role as convener for my region&#39;s reps, our Yearly Meeting being North Pacific YM (NPYM).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The clerk congratulated me on &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/03/quaker-mens-group-2013.html&quot;&gt;my performance&lt;/a&gt; but one could sense our seeing a way open, the way of shrinking, like Alice.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s that tendency to stampede towards the light at the end of the tunnel.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A streamlined AFSC will be cozier, more tightly knit, goes the theory.&amp;nbsp; Those who &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; share a commitment, will more likely get more done, divested of the more lukewarm hangers on, the foot draggers, the grumblers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I pointed out that because we&#39;re still hammering out what&#39;s considered legal representation in cyberspace, the day may soon come when reps need not travel to be legally present in meetings, thereby constituting a quorum.&amp;nbsp; Where are the laws with that today?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So why worry so much about our &quot;carbon footprint&quot; when we might be on the brink of another upgrade?&amp;nbsp; Might we address our shortfall in numbers another way?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If our goal is truly to maximize diversity (another bylaw change) then isn&#39;t &lt;i&gt;cutting back&lt;/i&gt; our numbers a move away from that goal?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Why not pack the house, in virtual space, in augmentation of the physical meeting, and demonstrate greater diversity at the same time?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;ll see what happens.&amp;nbsp; These discussions will be ongoing for some time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The board takes a look at it again, before kicking it back to us for a red or green light.&amp;nbsp; At least we&#39;ve found a way to be open about our shortfall and the legal bind that has put us in.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If we have no way of living up to our existing bylaws, then it&#39;s not surprising we feel compelled to change them.&amp;nbsp; We have to go with the army -- inward weapons only -- we&#39;ve got.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On with the metaphysics then! -- or whatever &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/12/quaker-infrastructure.html&quot;&gt;organizational alchemy&lt;/a&gt;&quot; is called.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1518435904265857126'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1518435904265857126'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/12/bylaw-changes.html' title='Bylaw Changes'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5537492126036964971</id><published>2013-11-29T19:37:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2016-04-04T23:10:52.767-07:00</updated><title type='text'>TG 2014</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;375&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;flashvars&quot; value=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157638196214066%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157638196214066%2F&amp;set_id=72157638196214066&amp;jump_to=&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=261948265&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;embed type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; src=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=261948265&quot; allowFullScreen=&quot;true&quot; flashvars=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157638196214066%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157638196214066%2F&amp;set_id=72157638196214066&amp;jump_to=&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Provided these blogs still have structural integrity, you will find a pattern around this time of year:&amp;nbsp; a journey North to visit friends and relatives.&amp;nbsp; This year, I drove alone, having I-5 adventures, with occasional forays into the hinterlands.&amp;nbsp; Of course driving has changed now that smartphones plugged into the dash talk, giving directions, and play music.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tara joined the eight of us by Google Hangout from Greater Chicago, for a video chat.&amp;nbsp; Lee brought his parents, Howard and Wilma, along with Howard&#39;s brother Bill, to Mary&#39;s.&amp;nbsp; Alice (Mary&#39;s sister) and Steven joined us from further north.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We found assembling the jigsaw puzzles congenial as they gave us something to focus on while having after dinner conversation.&amp;nbsp; They were not run of the mill puzzles in that the pieces were unusually intricate, sometimes detailed shapes in their own right.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I drove north on Wednesday and south on Friday, stopping by Bill&#39;s place for the first time near the University of Washington, the day of the annual football game, Huskies (University of Washington) versus Washington State.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Many of our conversations were quite lighthearted, others serious in terms of topic, such as end of life planning.&amp;nbsp; Mary is a doctor and wanted to be sure we were all aware of the agony some go through if the paperwork does not allow them to die and they can&#39;t represent themselves.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My love to friends and relatives out there, both near to me and far.&amp;nbsp; We are one interwoven web of life, empirically as well as spiritually.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s not much to argue about there.&amp;nbsp; The devil is in the details I suppose.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5537492126036964971'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5537492126036964971'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/11/tg-2014.html' title='TG 2014'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2432671932906614200</id><published>2013-11-22T19:20:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2013-11-22T21:57:08.043-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Life Hacks for College Students</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/V1yiqhoeV7Y?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I like the Maker (as in Make:) culture here, the pragmatism.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He has a whole body of work which I have only just begun to explore.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
By the way, this seems as good a place as any to note that Vodka + Grapefruit Juice is called a Greyhound.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2432671932906614200'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2432671932906614200'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/11/life-hacks-for-college-students.html' title='Life Hacks for College Students'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4419984502523123968</id><published>2013-11-17T15:35:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2013-11-28T22:35:50.656-08:00</updated><title type='text'>End of Life Planning</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/whats-urner.html&quot;&gt;The Urner family&lt;/a&gt; has often taken in long term guests, in the Philippines, in Egypt, in other places.&amp;nbsp; Readers of my blogs know we&#39;ve given shelter to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B8CGdb7BrBY&quot;&gt;one Lindsey Walker&lt;/a&gt;, a political refugee one might say, escaping a more repressive state.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The &quot;host&quot; role is quite a bit different from the &quot;landlord&quot; role, but any lawyer will tell you it&#39;s still important to limit your liability.&amp;nbsp; Given only two adults in the house, I have to be sure the law does not treat us like a couple, at which point assets get shmooed together.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If we were married, even if just in common law terms, and I called an ambulance, I might be held liable for those expenses.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But we&#39;re not married, not by any standard, and any medical bill I get relating to her care I&#39;m going to return, burn, or forward to her next of kin, unless the courts somehow find me liable for her condition in the first place -- a contingency I have to keep working to prevent (I must exercise mindfulness around my fellow human beings and not cause them injury through negligence, no kidding).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One of the guys at &lt;i&gt;Thirsters&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/11/a-khan-at-thirsters.html&quot;&gt;the other day&lt;/a&gt; was sorrowful because his nephew had been killed by unexploded ordinance, one of the bomblets from a cluster bomb.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If I left cluster bomblets around my house and my guests picked them up or kicked them, not knowing their true nature, then lawyers might come after me.&amp;nbsp; I would be liable for their deaths and/or medical treatment.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Indeed, as a US taxpayer, you could say that I &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; pay for such injuries, as whenever US employees hurt themselves on the job, they&#39;re in a position to file claims, which US borrowing and revenue will need to cover if said claims are upheld, as many are.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I gave Lindsey some ultra-sonic rat repellants, devices one plugs in.&amp;nbsp; If a rat bites her in the neck and gives her a deadly disease, people might say I was not a good host and that my humble basement was too humble.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not saying we have lots of rats, but many Portland basements are not immune from rodents, possums too in some cases.&amp;nbsp; We have squirrels in the attic and walls.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re not rabid and don&#39;t usually bite humans.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One thing I&#39;m very clear about is that even though Lindsey has very low body fat (she knows Victoria&#39;s secret or whatever) she&#39;d be non-trivial to pick up and carry to the maxi taxi (the Nissan, which used to be hers).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;ve used the Nissan for medical emergencies.&amp;nbsp; Lindsey doesn&#39;t have health insurance or much savings and an ambulance could be ruinous to her, financially.&amp;nbsp; As long as she&#39;s been ambulatory herself, transport by car was an option.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve usually been the driver.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But I&#39;m not about to try to lift her up, if she&#39;s comatose or simply limp and delirious, and I&#39;ve told her that.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll call 911 and let the professionals use a stretcher.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I know she wouldn&#39;t try to lift me.&amp;nbsp; I probably weigh well over twice as much as she does.&amp;nbsp; If I pass out in the 2nd floor office, she is not going to try lugging me down a flight of stairs and out to the Nissan just to save on some ambulance costs.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;d be foolish.&amp;nbsp; She&#39;d likely injure &lt;i&gt;herself&lt;/i&gt; just trying it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But I&#39;m saying it&#39;d be equally foolish for &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt; to try that with &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
An acquaintance of mine told me about dragging an inebriated friend from a bar (I think it was) and how heavy that friend was.&amp;nbsp; I believe he had help.&amp;nbsp; Two of them were trying to drag their friend somewhere, but somehow they dropped him and he hit his head.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How it all turned out I don&#39;t remember, but the storyteller was still traumatized by the event.&amp;nbsp; Another time I saw a father drop his little girl completely by mistake.&amp;nbsp; He was so torn up about it, although she was fine.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What Lindsey and I both need are contingency plans in case either one of us finds the other comatose or dead.&amp;nbsp; 911 is the default answer, but more responsible adults, or those with the time, especially later in life, start getting their affairs in order.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; My mom has done a lot of end of life planning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some phone number on the fridge, with a check already made out, might be the best answer.&amp;nbsp; &quot;In case of death, cremate me here:&amp;nbsp; 555-XXX-YYYY.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Lindsey and I should each have that, plus make arrangements for whatever ceremonies above and beyond corpse disposal.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In Lindsey&#39;s case, I think Satya would be a good person to help out planning &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_4ezPvzKe5M&quot;&gt;ceremonies&lt;/a&gt;, notifying next of kin and so on.&amp;nbsp; In my case, I should exercise my Oversight Committee powers and get one of those Wishes Upon Death forms in the files.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d like to keep the Flickr and Facebook accounts public, my blogs.&amp;nbsp; I should start saving whatever emails are worth keeping...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Preparing for one&#39;s death is a lot of work actually.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I don&#39;t like the word &quot;retired&quot; because in physics work is any energy expenditure and there&#39;s no way around spending energy, even just breathing.&amp;nbsp; So life is work and work is life.&amp;nbsp; Death might be the absence of work, though some might say that&#39;s just what we mean by context i.e. death is context.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s a metaphysical discussion for later maybe.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Besides, I&#39;m not even legally retired.&amp;nbsp; I have a full time job.&amp;nbsp; I did participate in &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/03/about-dawn-brief-bio.html&quot;&gt;my wife&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; end of life planning, most of which she did herself, while self employed.&amp;nbsp; She was extremely responsible about managing her own death, having received a death sentence from her doctors (about three to six years, which she got).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Moving Dawn became problematic towards the end.&amp;nbsp; She stopped being ambulatory.&amp;nbsp; I moved her solo one day and we realized that was not a good idea, too much pain.&amp;nbsp; We realized we needed more help, which our community provided.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I don&#39;t have any funds budgeted for Lindsey&#39;s care.&amp;nbsp; Anything extra goes to the college where my younger daughter goes.&amp;nbsp; Ever since the coma discussion, I&#39;ve been comparing notes with other friends, including some who are lawyers and/or landlords.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m trying to distill into writing what a non-lease extended house guest agreement might look like.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But then, at the end of the day she&#39;s planning to leave anyway, maybe storing some stuff in the basement, taking off for various adventures, some of them probably higher risk than anything she tries &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/ZTiD0tvbONw&quot;&gt;around Portland&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; She&#39;s like a circus worker, &lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/man-on-wire-how-one-man-walked-on-a-tightrope-between-513891462&quot;&gt;a tightrope walker&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Someone living on the edge.&amp;nbsp; She lives her life at the limits as Walter Kaufmann would say (he thought you needed to do that to call yourself a philosopher).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People with dangerous work need to keep their affairs in order, soldiers, philosophers, and political revolutionaries included.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s probably why Friends have a habit of being so meticulous in their record keeping and personal affairs.&amp;nbsp; Being a Quaker has been dangerous too, in different times and places.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhHyWGPFP5XSj5cg40W9ihyphenhyphenKdl4_s-cyEUGex73sPmX-ZqAru71KV2fWHb0wsSg9hqESgkKt1zoABviPYpLhGUwVHuTODKUDl6eJFYheQD9UqNVYQYJ2_6ZqsR2NPB-UVN6qLE-/s1600/lindsey2.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhHyWGPFP5XSj5cg40W9ihyphenhyphenKdl4_s-cyEUGex73sPmX-ZqAru71KV2fWHb0wsSg9hqESgkKt1zoABviPYpLhGUwVHuTODKUDl6eJFYheQD9UqNVYQYJ2_6ZqsR2NPB-UVN6qLE-/s320/lindsey2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;213&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4419984502523123968'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4419984502523123968'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/11/end-of-life-planning.html' title='End of Life Planning'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhHyWGPFP5XSj5cg40W9ihyphenhyphenKdl4_s-cyEUGex73sPmX-ZqAru71KV2fWHb0wsSg9hqESgkKt1zoABviPYpLhGUwVHuTODKUDl6eJFYheQD9UqNVYQYJ2_6ZqsR2NPB-UVN6qLE-/s72-c/lindsey2.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2962065362654026764</id><published>2013-11-13T11:42:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2013-11-15T20:22:45.008-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Ender&#39;s Game (movie review)</title><content type='html'>Earth has been attacked and was almost defeated before humans repulsed the alien invasion.&amp;nbsp; Now the Earthians are taking the battle to the alien home world.&amp;nbsp; Their psychology has discovered that when it comes to war fighting using weapons not requiring brawn to operate, that children make the best warriors as their nervous systems are more flexible and adaptive.&amp;nbsp; So an all child army is being raised to fight the aliens.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
True to form, the adults are endlessly manipulative and the protagonist, as he is groomed for leadership, becomes increasingly aware that the true enemy may be these adults.&amp;nbsp; His hunch is confirmed when the adults trick him into annihilating the alien home world.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The sense of compassion which enables Wiggins to outwit his enemy is also what leads him to love and understand them.&amp;nbsp; In the case of the aliens, he feels obligated to make amends and find a way to continue their lineage.&amp;nbsp; The Earthians make him an admiral at this point, a way of saying he&#39;s on his own.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2962065362654026764'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2962065362654026764'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/11/enders-game-movie-review.html' title='Ender&#39;s Game (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3172510248441022849</id><published>2013-11-01T22:11:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2013-11-22T20:38:22.021-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Dragonalia</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/dsvLLKQCxeA&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Although I&#39;d not yet seen her work, Vi must have been talking to the same muses, when I started my &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/quotable-quotes.html&quot;&gt;McLuhanesque rant&lt;/a&gt; against &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/boosting-bandwidth.html&quot;&gt;math teaching at low bandwidth&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The above specimen of &lt;i&gt;higher&lt;/i&gt; bandwidth teaching (than most chalk &#39;n talk) is especially representative in that it&#39;s bursting at the seams with ideas, hardly able to keep the snakes out, or in as the case may be.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The questioning of standard notations leads to an even deeper questioning of authority, an irreverence, the atmosphere of breakthroughs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At around 5:30 into it she&#39;s galumphing happily through Synergetics territory, giving the same lecture I might about &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/10/multiplication.html&quot;&gt;triangling versus squaring&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This is not only high bandwidth, it&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/neo/groups/Wittrs/conversations/topics/7670&quot;&gt;close to home&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Hooray for Youtube and Vi.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
More discussion &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=9327547#reply-tree&quot;&gt;on math-teach&lt;/a&gt;. </content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3172510248441022849'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3172510248441022849'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/11/dragonalia.html' title='Dragonalia'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2359044759535591711</id><published>2013-11-01T17:51:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2013-11-03T09:32:52.537-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Riddled With Holes</title><content type='html'>The way Fuller presented his philosophy was as mostly space but then also framed windows in a kind of spider webby networky sense, gossamer, ephemeral, ectoplasmic (ghostly shmear). &amp;nbsp;Windows being the O in V + O = E + 2, O for Opening. &amp;nbsp;Like left by bullet holes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Star Wars&lt;/i&gt; adapted Earthian war movies, adapted from war itself, to an alien environment (long ago, far away) but kept the &quot;war torn&quot; or &quot;battle-worn&quot; look. &amp;nbsp;Things were dented and dirty, not pristinely shiny as if just off the showroom floor. &amp;nbsp;That touch alone gave it a flavor of realism that movie-goers relished.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m not saying &lt;i&gt;Star Wars&lt;/i&gt; was the first or only pioneer. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0090605/?ref_=nv_sr_1&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Aliens&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was banged up in its own way. &amp;nbsp;Science fiction as a literary form has always had that broken and bruised look. &amp;nbsp;Movies maybe took awhile to catch up?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; is like that, some kind of bullet-ridden battle star, definitely a spheroid. &amp;nbsp;He&#39;s been polemical this Bucky, and look at these scars here. &amp;nbsp;Wow, pretty rugged. &amp;nbsp;There&#39;s grudging respect.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But also outrage, like David was pointing out, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/synergetics/s09/figs/tb6310.html&quot;&gt;the 1950s table&lt;/a&gt; with some early Synergetics Constant stuff. &amp;nbsp;What&#39;s up with that Dodecahedron of 12 Hexagons? &amp;nbsp;Say what? &amp;nbsp;It&#39;s a communist er capitalist er insect people plot, to put stupid mistakes like that in the public record and let them stand. &amp;nbsp;How could a mistake like that get through the editors? &amp;nbsp;Makes Bucky look bad, like he can&#39;t count &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/12/quaker-preschool.html&quot;&gt;fingers and toes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m arguing there weren&#39;t that many layers of editor and &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; is both meticulous and &quot;thrown together&quot; as &lt;i&gt;Cosmic Fishing&lt;/i&gt; shares the tale. &amp;nbsp;There isn&#39;t that editorial oversight you might enjoy if settled in and enjoying a well-diagrammed workflow. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Think of Donald Knuth, for example. &amp;nbsp;I just got his four volumes in the mail. &amp;nbsp;He&#39;s been meticulously organized. &amp;nbsp;Fuller was just dragging papers around in his suitcase and relying on Applewhite for the meticulous part. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;m not saying that was in any way unwise, as EJA upheld his side of the bargain and then some, but it&#39;s not the controlled processing of errata we might have had, and still may have. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Bob Gray did a superb job of getting the opus reliably transcribed. &amp;nbsp;Version control going forward? Big project. &amp;nbsp;Notice I haven&#39;t stepped forward. &amp;nbsp;I just &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/4dsolutions/BookCovers&quot;&gt;got on Github&lt;/a&gt; like yesterday for the first time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; is also wildly speculative. &amp;nbsp;Linus Pauling got that way too. &amp;nbsp;You&#39;ve got a front row seat in high stakes poker and you just throw down the hand you&#39;ve got, in hopes of winning at least something. &amp;nbsp;Pauling&#39;s proposal for DNA was &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/05/brilliant-blunders.html&quot;&gt;inside-out impossible&lt;/a&gt;, a freak, but with that many horses in that many races, how might we not have a freak or two?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Like where he compares a T-module to a Meson on something like that. &amp;nbsp;He&#39;s shoving chips on his quanta modules having some future in some quantum mechanics but how do you &quot;shove chips&quot; in 1970 without just speaking nonsense? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Perhaps nonsense was a best option; the author of &lt;i&gt;Finnegans Wake&lt;/i&gt; certainly seemed to think so. &amp;nbsp;Here&#39;s a literary figure with a tiger by the tail, a fun new geometry, and he&#39;s determined to make the most of it. &amp;nbsp;&quot;Evidence of partying&quot; the police report might say later. &amp;nbsp;But can you blame him? &amp;nbsp;He confesses to being pee-in-the-pants excited sometimes. &amp;nbsp;He got passionate about this stuff.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But that doesn&#39;t excuse all the mistakes and transgressions does it? &amp;nbsp;Not in my own case either. &amp;nbsp;I shouldn&#39;t act like I&#39;m apologizing for Bucky when I have my own harrowing Kafkaesque case to be concerned with. &amp;nbsp;But then &quot;apologist&quot; or &quot;disciple&quot; have never been my chosen terms. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;m definitely a fan of certain people, where &quot;fan&quot; connotes &quot;from afar&quot;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m a fan of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/06/mortal-coil.html&quot;&gt;Katie Couric&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/02/philosophy-101.html&quot;&gt;Walter Kaufmann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/04/reinventing-sacred.html&quot;&gt;Stuart Kauffman&lt;/a&gt;... &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/10/satori.html&quot;&gt;Alan Watts&lt;/a&gt;, lots of people, some of whom I&#39;ve actually met. &amp;nbsp;Bucky was somewhat in that category, though like Kiyoshi I was experiencing metaphysical eddying. &amp;nbsp;I think I&#39;ve talked about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/kiyoshi.html&quot;&gt;his experiences before&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;The collective unconscious is a busy place, lets put it that way. &amp;nbsp;Friends are people I&#39;m fans of but get to spend more time with, Sam Lanahan for example.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We kept a low profile this Halloween. &amp;nbsp;Steve had had knee surgery. &amp;nbsp;The Barton kids are still young enough, and their porch is just right. &amp;nbsp;Glenn came by. &amp;nbsp;Thai food was enjoyed. &amp;nbsp;Trick or treaters got their candy and maybe shook the fake hand.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2359044759535591711'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2359044759535591711'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/11/riddled-with-holes.html' title='Riddled With Holes'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-828914256009623158</id><published>2013-10-27T15:47:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2013-10-27T20:02:18.998-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Corrupting the Oldsters</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/12/whats-bizmo.html&quot;&gt;This job&lt;/a&gt; takes you on the road, to nursing homes mostly, as they&#39;re mostly called now.&amp;nbsp; Your job is to share Internet culture with some older people, a lot of them bored.&amp;nbsp; You have good equipment, a lot of bandwidth and sharp color on a big screen.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fail compilations, Annoying Orange, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/09/lampoon-harpoon.html&quot;&gt;conspiracy theories&lt;/a&gt;... plenty to keep us occupied while only alluding to PornVille, just left off the Interstate.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re aware of adult humor and the Internet comes pre-packaged with some sense of sleaze, not much one can do about it.&amp;nbsp; Kids know about Grossology...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Hey, speaking of which, I&#39;m taking a breather myself and tracking down a meme.&amp;nbsp; Gangnam Style.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve seen four or five that purport to be takeoffs thereon, but when do I get to the tap root?&amp;nbsp; Sherlock Holmes hat on.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/9bZkp7q19f0?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gangnam_Style&quot;&gt;Wikipedia to the rescue&lt;/a&gt;.  I was there already.  Psy is the source, Korean derivation.  Got it.  And &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OYxfxf3wTLM&amp;amp;feature=share&amp;amp;list=RD15C_0qCrZW4kY&quot;&gt;these others&lt;/a&gt; are the parodies...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/s7QE62FDn08?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/yTCRwi71_ns?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/prvA-qUptp0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/828914256009623158'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/828914256009623158'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/10/corrupting-oldsters.html' title='Corrupting the Oldsters'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8863236930366194997</id><published>2013-10-23T18:22:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2014-10-27T17:08:48.541-07:00</updated><title type='text'>AFSC Support Committee</title><content type='html'>We haven&#39;t met in months.&amp;nbsp; Those of us around the table may be a little hazy about what our purpose is (to support local staff and program).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tonight we&#39;re meeting the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opportunityknocks.org/jobs/350813-48778/Assistant-Regional-Director-West-Region-AFSC-American-Friends-Service-Committee-US-USA&quot;&gt;Assistant Regional Director for the Western Region&lt;/a&gt;, Marielle Oetjen.&amp;nbsp; She works with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/sonia.tumaafsc&quot;&gt;Sonia Tuma&lt;/a&gt;, the Regional Director (replacing Susan Segal -- except &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/08/planning-committees.html&quot;&gt;the regions&lt;/a&gt; have also been changed).&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s also an Associate Regional Director.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Marielle will have a base in the Portland Office.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At the Philadelphia level, AFSC and FCNL have put out &lt;a href=&quot;https://afsc.org/story/shared-security-quaker-vision-us-foreign-policy-launched&quot;&gt;a document called &lt;i&gt;Shared Security&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which I still need to read and blog about.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our recording clerk, Eddy Crouch, is also on the Western Region Executive Committee and has already started a series of meetings at the Multnomah Meeting House following the study guide that goes with this document.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I know other denominations work this way:&amp;nbsp; they develop program around &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fpa.org/great_decisions/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Great Decisions&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for example, I know &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/02/methodist-morning.html&quot;&gt;the Methodists&lt;/a&gt; use that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m suspicious of these studies usually because &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/07/einstein-omsi.html&quot;&gt;they instill nationalism in a non-critical manner&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The whole idea of &quot;foreign policy&quot; on a tiny spherical ball is a tad ridiculous, as is the whole idea of &quot;sovereign nations&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Bucky Fuller was &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/12/thinking-globally.html&quot;&gt;right to resist politicos&lt;/a&gt; marring his map with a lot of their corrupting data.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Our Promised Land is less stupid than the Land we have.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of sovereigns, did I mention I was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Royal-Babylon-Alarming-History-European/dp/0767907558&quot;&gt;reading &lt;i&gt;Royal Babylon&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;? The author refreshingly turns the tables on these so-called royal families.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I can see how &lt;i&gt;Shared Security&lt;/i&gt; (I&#39;m scanning it now) could help with the creation of new &quot;schools for diplomats&quot; developed with some Quaker influence.&amp;nbsp; These my high tech boarding schools, part of the larger &quot;eco-village&quot; phenomenon, slow in materializing given various &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/11/increasing-military-iq.html&quot;&gt;vicious circles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Pedro and I discussed the military&#39;s use of immigrant conscripts to pad itself out.&amp;nbsp; Pedro pointed out a core irony:&amp;nbsp; when one of these immigrants is killed in the line of duty, they&#39;re declared a citizen postmortem, whereas the wounded are more likely to be deported, as a budget liability.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/10450518786/&quot; title=&quot;shared_security by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;shared_security&quot; src=&quot;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3754/10450518786_e09306276b_n.jpg&quot; height=&quot;285&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8863236930366194997'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8863236930366194997'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/10/afsc-support-committee.html' title='AFSC Support Committee'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3273142775692854194</id><published>2013-10-07T23:10:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2013-10-07T23:19:15.748-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Multiplication</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/9862519425/&quot; title=&quot;5 x 6 = 30 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;5 x 6 = 30&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3670/9862519425_a5c4570b30.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: 5 x 6 = 30 ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
This is not such a hard way to multiply.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So what that we do it against a backdrop of triangles instead of squares?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Triangles are simpler and we&#39;re allowing for all edges the same length, same as squares, so that&#39;s no advantage on the square&#39;s side.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Take your two lengths, A and B, and just connect a line across, and you&#39;re done. &amp;nbsp;That&#39;s your area, in equilateral triangular units.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
An interesting feature of pouring fluids into such containers is you may tilt it to have the water level connect A and B.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;When filling &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/sets/72157624750749042/with/4680326437/&quot;&gt;a tetrahedron&lt;/a&gt;, your corners A, B and C may be independently reached as well.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So if the goal is to measure out a number that&#39;s factorable, into two or three terms, you&#39;ve got a way of tilting to get that: &amp;nbsp;get the fluid to hit all the factors in the flask, as calibrated along the edges.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Think of it as a kind of beaker, amidst other lab equipment.  Tilt the tetrahedron to 4 x 5 x 3 for 60 tetrahedron&#39;s worth of liquid. &amp;nbsp;Scale those unit tetrahedrons to be milliliters if you like, no one&#39;s stopping you.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/10102270755/&quot; title=&quot;DSCN4605 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCN4605&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7445/10102270755_359521403f_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3273142775692854194'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3273142775692854194'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/10/multiplication.html' title='Multiplication'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2302180237617637616</id><published>2013-10-05T22:13:00.005-07:00</published><updated>2013-10-06T13:41:04.346-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Afghanistan Again</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/10112207364/&quot; title=&quot;DSCN4685 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCN4685&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7374/10112207364_a52f9c6362.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: chatting with Afghanistan ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The invasion of Afghanistan, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/05/bait-and-switch.html&quot;&gt;ostensibly&lt;/a&gt; a manhunt &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/10/more-autobio.html&quot;&gt;for Osama Bin Laden&lt;/a&gt;, commenced about twelve years ago, making this the longest &quot;war&quot; in &quot;US&quot; history.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I put &quot;war&quot; in quotes because it&#39;s not headline news and few people care about it.&amp;nbsp; &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/07/dirty-wars-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Dirty wars&lt;/a&gt;&quot; are like that:&amp;nbsp; clandestine / covert.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This &quot;war&quot; is more the kind of thing Orwell envisioned:&amp;nbsp; a hell pit in which to dispose of million dollar soldiers and equipment, a black hole for contractors and profiteers who need to perpetually resupply and restaff the operation.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Many militias participate in this gold mine for mercenaries, not just the Pentagon&#39;s.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/11/pentagon-public-or-private.html&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/11/pentagon-public-or-private.html&quot;&gt;The private sector&lt;/a&gt; runs this war internationally, mainly through its sham non-democracy aka the Beltway Junta in DC (currently &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/10/dc-withdraws-from-governance.html&quot;&gt;in &quot;shutdown mode&quot;&lt;/a&gt; -- though not when it comes to the resupply effort, which is endless).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s why I put &quot;US&quot; in quotes.&amp;nbsp; The private sector has &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/12/iron-mountain-revisted.html&quot;&gt;a jobs program&lt;/a&gt; to keep the assembly lines going, but said program has nothing to do with the US Constitution or Declaration of Independence.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The age of once-proud nations is well behind us by now.&amp;nbsp; This is what &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://grunch.net/archives/64&quot;&gt;desovereignization&lt;/a&gt;&quot; looks like:&amp;nbsp; a lot of pretenders behind the masks, trying to keep the illusion of &quot;sovereign states&quot; alive.&amp;nbsp; A bit of a corpse show.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Keeping the North Americans employed in bases around the world is a mainstay, and the legacy of the WW2 prime contractors irrigation system (aka &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/gst2.html&quot;&gt;LAWCAP&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;nbsp; They like the perks that come with the various occupations (pun intended) and stay compliant / obedient in exchange for low PX prices (comparable to Costco&#39;s) and access to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/07/migrants-everywhere.html&quot;&gt;red light districts&lt;/a&gt;, with veterans&#39; benefits to follow if they hang in there and stay out of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/11/hurt-locker-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;harm&#39;s way&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As Marty the PhD economist (panelist) pointed out:&amp;nbsp; on paper, the US squanders over a trillion a year on its military jobs program, a gross monument to the ineffectiveness of mankind.&amp;nbsp; If you ever wanted proof that patriarchs are incapable, here&#39;s your proof.&amp;nbsp; You might say the space program proves the opposite but the violence-prone want to ruin that too, make no mistake.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We had &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/10/afghanistan-revisited.html&quot;&gt;a Skype connection&lt;/a&gt; to Afghani non-violent activists which was cool (thanks Mireaya).&amp;nbsp; They were in an early morning time zone while ours was late evening.&amp;nbsp; Lots of translating went on as speeches and Q&amp;amp;A occurred.&amp;nbsp; One guy reminded us none of the 911 hijackers were Afghani.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s true, but then gaining control over the world&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/01/wanderers-2010113.html&quot;&gt;opiate and cocoa leaf crops&lt;/a&gt; has little to do with 911 either.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One of our panelists (not mom) was in the frontier area a year ago, where most of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/02/report-from-afghanistan.html&quot;&gt;the drone attacks&lt;/a&gt; occur.&amp;nbsp; Shameless dishonorable &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/06/killing-field.html&quot;&gt;uber-cowards&lt;/a&gt; are in charge of those.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/09/lunch-at-maru.html&quot;&gt;Mom&lt;/a&gt; was prepared to give a much longer talk, not an 8 minute lightning talk.&amp;nbsp; She got the audience interested, talking about our bus trip from Peshawar, with what amounted to a teaser or trailer (like a movie preview).&amp;nbsp; She did bring in her hero &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/08/liberal-islam.html&quot;&gt;Ghaffer Khan&lt;/a&gt;, and did so again during the panel discussion.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/03/chauffeur-duty.html&quot;&gt;the off-duty chauffeur&lt;/a&gt; I ducked out to a liquor store during part of that getting &lt;i&gt;Smirnoff&#39;s&lt;/i&gt; vodka and &lt;i&gt;Bailey&#39;s&lt;/i&gt; irish cream.&amp;nbsp; Yes, I was escaping being social around then.&amp;nbsp; I get upset by these stupid ape-like creatures sometimes, though I&#39;m one of them.&amp;nbsp; Is misanthropy &quot;self hating&quot; or more &quot;alienating&quot; or are these two the same?&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/11/jarhead-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Existentialists&lt;/a&gt; should discuss this question.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We and the Afghanis think the same way about the low-life scumbags who murder by remote control.&amp;nbsp; War criminals.&amp;nbsp; Like Nazis.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;ll be vilified for decades to come, in children&#39;s books, in museums, in history books.&amp;nbsp; Like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/lame-analysis.html&quot;&gt;thugs running Gitmo&lt;/a&gt; (the puppet US presidents are helpless against them).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Neither we nor the Afghanis on the line had any easy solutions to recommend.&amp;nbsp; The militaries of the world have the weapons and use them to extort from less well armed civilians.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Or at least that&#39;s what the disreputable militaries are doing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They perhaps have no choice, given they have no real 
skills or marketable talents other than stealing from others at 
gunpoint.&amp;nbsp; The education system has let us all down.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Let&#39;s be clear these Afghanis were as disgusted by Taliban violence as any brand name violence.&amp;nbsp; All brutal violence is ugly and stupid and hurtful (the antithesis of &quot;sexy&quot; except in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/11/seven-psychopaths-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Hollywood movies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/08/chicago.html&quot;&gt;uncool gringo TV&lt;/a&gt;) -- on that &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/09/interfaith-meetup.html&quot;&gt;most religions&lt;/a&gt; can agree, despite their own track records.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2302180237617637616'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2302180237617637616'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/10/afghanistan-again.html' title='Afghanistan Again'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8654873122107233109</id><published>2013-10-03T11:27:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2013-10-06T00:07:52.558-07:00</updated><title type='text'>DC Withdraws from Governance</title><content type='html'>DC appears to be bowing out.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They call it a &quot;government shutdown&quot; meaning when I went to a Library of Congress website, I got this message:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #990000; background-image: url(http://www.loc.gov/home2/images/img_lochead.png); background-repeat: no-repeat no-repeat; border: 0px; color: #333333; font-family: Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: 12px; line-height: 16px; margin: 0px; outline: 0px; padding: 2px 0px 0px; vertical-align: baseline;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: white; border: 0px; font-family: Verdana,Geneva,sans-serif; font-size: 11px; margin: 0px; outline: 0px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 20px 9px; vertical-align: baseline;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;border: 0px; float: left; font-family: inherit; font-size: 11px; margin: 0px 20px 0px 0px; outline: 0px; padding: 6px 0px 2px; vertical-align: baseline; width: 304px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a accesskey=&quot;1&quot; href=&quot;http://www.loc.gov/&quot; style=&quot;border: 0px; color: #660099; font-family: inherit; font-size: 11px; margin: 0px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Library of Congress&quot; height=&quot;38&quot; src=&quot;http://www.loc.gov/home2/images/loc-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;border: 0px; font-family: inherit; font-size: 11px; margin: 0px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;&quot; width=&quot;304&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: black; border: 0px; color: #333333; font-family: Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: 12px; line-height: 16px; margin: 0px; min-height: 1px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 style=&quot;border: 0px; color: #323232; font-size: 1.4em; font-weight: normal; margin: 0px 0px 10px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;&quot;&gt;
Due to the temporary shutdown of the federal government,&lt;br /&gt;the Library of Congress is closed to the public and researchers beginning October 1, 2013 until further notice.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 style=&quot;border: 0px; color: #323232; font-size: 1.4em; font-weight: normal; margin: 0px 0px 10px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;&quot;&gt;
All public events are cancelled and web sites are inaccessible&lt;br /&gt;except the legislative information sites&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomas.loc.gov/&quot; style=&quot;border: 0px; color: #660099; font-family: inherit; font-size: 17px; font-weight: bold; margin: 0px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;THOMAS.gov&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://beta.congress.gov/&quot; style=&quot;border: 0px; color: #660099; font-family: inherit; font-size: 17px; font-weight: bold; margin: 0px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;beta.&lt;wbr&gt;&lt;/wbr&gt;congress.gov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So does this mean the Pentagon is no longer refilling its aircraft carriers &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/07/big-fix-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;with BP&lt;/a&gt;?  No, of course not.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Pentagon runs with or without the Feds as it&#39;s controlled by the private sector which uses DC as a sham, to give people the illusion of a Federal democracy among some 48 states in North America.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When democracy shuts down, the occupations (e.g. of Hawaii, Okinawa... &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/10/afghanistan-again.html&quot;&gt;Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt;) and permanent base construction proceeds apace.  Mostly just civilians are affected.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
DC is telling the world it no longer needs or wants to be taken seriously as a center of governance.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We get it.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s been obvious for some time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Washington DC has been in the process of de-legitimizing itself for quite awhile, starting aggressively with the Nixon Administration.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The question is:&amp;nbsp; when DC starts up its sorry show again, will anyone care?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Sure, many will.&amp;nbsp; It takes awhile to lower expectations so completely.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Switching medical services to other circuits would seem to be in order.&amp;nbsp; The MD community, doctors without borders, must be in high gear.&amp;nbsp; Shall we appeal to the UN for disaster relief?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The rumor is whole departments are soon to disappear, FEMA among them -- or am I reading the wrong sources?&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ll need more foreign aid and care packages than we&#39;re already getting.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Ever since the end of WW2 there&#39;s been a lot of cannibalization going on, as tax-funded research and development was privatized and spun off.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At some point, you go below critical mass and the whole thing just dies.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;ve been lots of rehearsals. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How about the US Post Office, who or what will replace that?&amp;nbsp; We may not be able to take junk mail for granted anymore.&amp;nbsp; But what about pay checks?&amp;nbsp; Electronic transfers?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Do we need to designate a new capital city?&amp;nbsp; How about LA?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When they turn the ignition key will it start up again?&amp;nbsp; Under new management maybe.&amp;nbsp; These clowns can&#39;t be trusted with the Library of Congress, that much is obvious.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8654873122107233109'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8654873122107233109'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/10/dc-withdraws-from-governance.html' title='DC Withdraws from Governance'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3209089797653044718</id><published>2013-09-29T16:31:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2015-08-14T08:37:01.603-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Bumbling Professor Talk</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/pYZNLOKEE5I?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;At 9 minutes in.
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
I&#39;m somewhat the wild haired space case in this one, an early morning session when people needed something energizing.
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3209089797653044718'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3209089797653044718'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/09/bumbling-professor-talk.html' title='Bumbling Professor Talk'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3383383212931958171</id><published>2013-09-28T20:09:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2013-09-28T20:31:00.035-07:00</updated><title type='text'>PythonUK 2013</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/qOya5R9g1T8?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Drones, er, quadcopters, were a big hit this year, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/07/oscon-xv.html&quot;&gt;like at OSCON&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Controlling a quadcopter from within Minecraft, using Python on a Raspberry Py (alternate spelling):&amp;nbsp; that was a theme on the education track.&amp;nbsp; The whole Python + Minecraft thing is fun with or without the quadcopter element.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Judging from video clips, kids loved the event, as did their parents and teachers, including mentors from Bank of America, an event sponsor.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Source:&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://ntoll.org/article/pyconuk2013-roundup&quot;&gt;PyconUK 2013 Roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Don&#39;t have a Raspberry Pi but want to play with Python bindings anyway?&amp;nbsp; Lost Bear Labs has &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.lostbearlabs.com/2013/04/25/using-the-minecraft-api-without-a-raspberry-pi-craftbukkit-and-raspberryjuice/&quot;&gt;a solution&lt;/a&gt; you might try.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3383383212931958171'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3383383212931958171'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/09/pythonuk-2013.html' title='PythonUK 2013'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1989929979752742380</id><published>2013-09-25T00:01:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2013-09-25T17:42:22.557-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2013.9.24</title><content type='html'>Patricia Rumer has followed the action in Guatemala since the late 1960s, when she saw police bashing skulls at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago and decided she&#39;d had enough of the USA for awhile, or at least needed some perspective.&amp;nbsp; That she got, in Guatemala.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What indigenous peoples have experienced at the hands of &quot;the government&quot; (a militia, more like Burma&#39;s) is going down in history as a Civil War, complete with genocide.&amp;nbsp; USAers may remember it from the Reagan years.&amp;nbsp; They won&#39;t remember the general,  Rios Montt, against whom a lawsuit was brought, but then dismissed in a backroom process, &lt;i&gt;after&lt;/i&gt; a guilty verdict.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I don&#39;t know if they wanted a grisly hanging or what, but he, at 85, still has the comfort of his family and many of them don&#39;t.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Indigenous folk are always great at using the civilized option, doesn&#39;t it seem, just as in the USA they&#39;re like walking encyclopedia attorneys when it comes to treaty law, whereas average gringos are sipping Slurpees [tm] and watching &lt;i&gt;Beavis and Butthead&lt;/i&gt; on DVD.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I showed up early to provide A/V, though Patricia had brought her own Windows computer.&amp;nbsp; The PowerPoint came up just fine in Preview off her thumb drive; the Mac Air came through, as it often does.&amp;nbsp; I depend on it greatly.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The audience was a mix of those who had, and had not been to Guatemala.&amp;nbsp; We went around the table answering that question in particular.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Although I&#39;ve been a gringo in a martial law zone, that wasn&#39;t in a Banana Republic, unless you count the USA as a Banana Republic, and that argument could and has been made (including by me).&amp;nbsp; You say we&#39;re not enjoying martial law but I&#39;d say at least foreign policy has been pretty well militarized.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Diplomacy these days usually means &quot;lip service&quot; to something, and is not a serious career -- judging from recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/09/lunch-at-maru.html&quot;&gt;scandalous admissions&lt;/a&gt; about relations with Iran.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, our audience was a mix and some were most interested in the more gender-specific injustices, such as rape, overwhelmingly a male offense, and sex trafficking (ditto).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Does it start in the School of the Americas?&amp;nbsp; We should get a copy of that school&#39;s honor code sometime, for analysis.&amp;nbsp; Lots of people have that school as their focus so this research sounds doable at least.&amp;nbsp; In which course is rape discussed and dissected as a tool of intimidation against a Cold War backdrop.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Actually there was maybe some question around the table about whether Cold War terminology was relevant any longer.&amp;nbsp; Lew Scholl was there, and Lynne Taylor, the latter being chief organizer of the recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/09/interfaith-meetup.html&quot;&gt;World Religions confab&lt;/a&gt; (no Mormons, but then Atheists don&#39;t get much attention either and certainly we had one of those).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This was a high powered group, we Wanderers, lots of worldly experience.&amp;nbsp; And yet none of us sounds like a Cold Warrior.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re pretty much bored with the &quot;capitalism versus communism&quot; dialectic.&amp;nbsp; What was supposed to come next again?&amp;nbsp; Some withering of the state wasn&#39;t it?&amp;nbsp; Shall we get on with it then?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Patricia was eloquent in her analysis.&amp;nbsp; She focused a lot on the need for bottom-up grass-roots decentralized planning styles.&amp;nbsp; If you want&amp;nbsp; your copper mines, why not willingly go through channels versus throwing all your eggs in some short term top-down basket?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Why cast your lot with some Burma-style militia?&amp;nbsp; Why not plan for the long term and do your mine in partnership, and with the proper feng shui?&amp;nbsp; Stretch it out.&amp;nbsp; Don&#39;t try compressing multiple generations into one.&amp;nbsp; Wheels have their different turn cycles.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If mining is truly unaffordable, the decision will be reached, but in a lot of cases, there&#39;d be ways to develop the resources to some level without making enemies for life of the current landholders.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m not sure what US Embassies advertise as their role to political fundraisers for Congressional&amp;nbsp; positions.&amp;nbsp; Perhaps State is weak because it over-promises way more than it can deliver, which makes the military nervously insert itself lest &quot;America seem weak&quot; (how often do we hear that?).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Did you over-promise on the power of a US Embassy as a bully pulpit and now feel hat-in-hand towards your sponsors in some board game, where natural resources are like tokens?&amp;nbsp; Is this &lt;i&gt;Monopoly&lt;/i&gt;?&amp;nbsp; Does DC even know what game it&#39;s playing?&amp;nbsp; Forgive me for not having all the answers.&amp;nbsp; An investigation is underway.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1989929979752742380'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1989929979752742380'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/09/wanderers-2013924.html' title='Wanderers 2013.9.24'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>