<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211</id><updated>2025-02-27T06:25:58.543-08:00</updated><category term="clojure python REPL ide"/><title type='text'>BizMo Diaries</title><subtitle type='html'>On the road with Global Data</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=1076'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=1051&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=1101&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1905</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1076</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8136883074691913872</id><published>2011-03-04T08:11:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2021-05-31T12:33:39.368-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Corporation Meeting</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157626076057099&quot; title=&quot;AFSC Meeting&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/5260/5497825655_e5d9536a19_w.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;AFSC Meeting&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: AFSC Corporation Meeting ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Quakers have this business-oriented vocabulary stretching back to the early days.  They (we) actually have &quot;Meeting for Worship for Business&quot; which to skeptical ears could sound like we worship the almighty dollar or some cash cow (golden calf).  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Are Quakers the moneychangers in the temple?  At one time maybe.  I had &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/01/2011-day-one.html&quot;&gt;a recent thread with Ed Cherlin&lt;/a&gt; about all that, on mathfuture of all places.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
So I&#39;m at the annual meeting of &quot;the corporation&quot; i.e. the American Friends Service Committee. I&#39;m at Friends Center, affectionately known as &quot;the Quaker Vatican&quot;.  My role is &quot;Yearly Meeting Appointee&quot;.  North Pacific Yearly Meeting being the region I&#39;m representing, along with my peers.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Hugh Thomforde is here, whom I haven&#39;t seen since around 1970 in Rome.  We used to go to his family home for Quaker meeting on Sundays.  Great family!  His dad worked for FAO (Food and Agricultural Organization).  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Hugh, these days based in Arkansas, is savvy about fish farming, other things aquatic. Based on his experiences in the Philippines, he helped establish a pearl farming industry in the Cook Islands, working for USAID.  That project had Cold War origins and at first encountered much skepticism as the &quot;nuclei&quot; needed to start pearls sounded too much like the &quot;nuclei&quot; associated with nearby nuclear testing by &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/12/countdown-to-zero-game.html&quot;&gt;organized criminal syndicates&lt;/a&gt; (highly unpopular with the locals). We might call this a &quot;name collision&quot;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
My mom (Carol Urner) is here too, flying in from Whittier, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/03/back-wired.html&quot;&gt;Tom Head&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
The clerk is using a Tibetan &quot;singing bowl&quot; to anchor her introductory talk.  She&#39;s about to introduce our new &lt;a href=&quot;http://afriendlyletter.com/index.php/hard-core-quaker/flash-afsc-picks-shan-cretin-as-new-gen-secty/&quot;&gt;General Secretary, Shan Cretin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
My work with AFSC in Portland was youth-focused.  I helped launch a new chapter, as volunteer clerk, after my internship as contributing editor of &lt;i&gt;Asian-Pacific Issues News&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/06/prisoners-for-pelau.html&quot;&gt;apprenticing under Paulette Wittwer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/02/notes-from-lunch.html&quot;&gt;AFSC has been influential&lt;/a&gt; on my thinking in that it tends to focus on &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/07/marketing-campaigns.html&quot;&gt;various media campaigns&lt;/a&gt; which often go against the grain of contemporary popular opinion.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Quakers, especially our branch (so-called &quot;unprogrammed&quot;), are pretty tiny and esoteric. Getting anything done requires making strategic alliances, sometimes with unexpected collaborators.  Somewhat in jest (and to raise eyebrows), I&#39;ve been known to refer to the AFSC as &quot;the Quakers&#39; Machiavellian agency&quot;.  If you know your history, that&#39;s somewhat apropos.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
One focus of AFSC these days is the exploitation of workers, modern forms of slavery.  We probably need to give up the popular conceit that slavery has been &quot;abolished&quot; (according to whom?).  Many businesses are slave drivers and participate in human trafficking.  Exploitation of the undocumented (so-called &quot;illegals&quot;) is another way a &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/07/pr-for-pl.html&quot;&gt;broken and decrepit nation-state system&lt;/a&gt; has been corrupted to feed the rapacious maw of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/grunch.html&quot;&gt;unethical moneymakers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8136883074691913872'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8136883074691913872'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/03/corporation-meeting.html' title='Corporation Meeting'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3191069575243437774</id><published>2011-02-12T03:23:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2011-02-13T16:17:33.689-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Remembering a Person</title><content type='html'>Jim Person was the son of my grandma Esther&#39;s older brother, August.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Esther was my father Jack Urner&#39;s mother (Carl was his father).  Margie was my grandmother on &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/10/wilpf-meets-wanderers.html&quot;&gt;my mother Carol&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; side of the family, Tom Reilley her father.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Bill Lightfoot, Howard, Bo, Eddy and Eve, were grandma Esther&#39;s sister Elsie&#39;s kids.  August was one of Esther, Elsie and Alice&#39;s brothers, along with Robert, Dick, Dud and Ernie (all Persons), and all Swedish settlers on Mercer Island.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Augie was an impressive human being by many accounts, a top Rotarian in his early 30s before he succumbed to pneumonia, and a radio man (repairs and operations) much in demand from Astoria to Portland.  His widowed wife married Walt Tornblad and her young son Jim thereby gained his younger half brother Paul.  They moved to Cherry Grove.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This was a memorial for the young son Jim, by now an old guy.  His wife Martha Jane Person had died &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/05/lost-in-oregon.html&quot;&gt;in May of 2009&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I was learning a lot of these details for the first time. I took some pictures of the literature available to the public.  I wish I&#39;d taken one of the preacher, a friendly giant and community servant.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Jim died peacefully in a way some of my relatives envy and seek to emulate.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Bill Hancock&#39;s dad was from nearby Glencoe (we were in Cornelius for the service). His wife &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/07/independence-day-weekend.html&quot;&gt;Barbara is Harold&#39;s daughter&lt;/a&gt;, Harold (Dud).  Harold Persons sisters were my grandma Esther, Elsie and Alice.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Elsie had many children, among them Bill Lightfoot, who picked me up at the house in his Aztec and drove me there and back. We adjourned to &lt;i&gt;Back Stage&lt;/i&gt; for a beer afterwards.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5437880873/&quot; title=&quot;In Cherry Grove by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4118/5437880873_5f5513b190_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; alt=&quot;In Cherry Grove&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3191069575243437774'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3191069575243437774'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/02/remembering-person.html' title='Remembering a Person'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4118/5437880873_5f5513b190_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1285760100023328341</id><published>2011-02-09T21:29:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2011-02-12T17:56:02.301-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Another Space Case</title><content type='html'>Although I mess around with &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/12/nato-professor.html&quot;&gt;the professor archetype&lt;/a&gt; (senex etc.), I&#39;m averse to falling into that trap of &quot;absent minded&quot;.  Averse or no, the laptop is probably in a good place, but I won&#39;t be sure until tomorrow, so movie night didn&#39;t happen.  Long story.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Hey, I&#39;ve been thinking about how to translate &quot;samsara&quot;, am aiming to consult with Satya on this. This has probably been thought of, but I&#39;m thinking &quot;sorrow&quot; as in &quot;river of sorrow&quot;.  But then, for me, there are connotations, like with Krishnamurti saying as much.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/01/return-to-icu.html&quot;&gt;Hi Nick and Quinn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In rough translations, there might be some attempt to link samsara to Hades or even hell as an afterlife, but that&#39;s to miss it&#39;s one&#39;s life today.  This is also our world of joys (nirvana).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We&#39;d have these philosophical discussions while in the Kia sometimes, Urners, Dawn Wicca, Tara, our tribe.  Julie had been to Grahamstown as well.  We took the scenic route back to Cape Town.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;One could also call it one&#39;s &quot;time tunnel&quot; which has the look and feel of a &quot;world line&quot; (but with thickness).  The &quot;partially overlapping scenarios&quot; idea was a remark about shared grammar, one might say, whether one uses this remote (esoteric) vocabulary or some other.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We had Thai food, per plan.  Only then did I discover I&#39;d probably set her down, movie still in the drive.  I&#39;m back to &quot;absent minded&quot; and how it haunts me.  Part of the human condition I realize. Something about &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/01/at-work.html&quot;&gt;P.D. Ouspensky&lt;/a&gt;.  Hi Gary.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Academia should have no problem with &quot;dharma talks&quot; as a genre, whether these be about genomics, neuro-science, other hybrid subjects (as if we were somehow done with alchemy). &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Lining up polyhedrons and &quot;the elements&quot; may seem like a strange thing to do, yet we should acknowledge that this was done.  Tracing the history of a meme game doesn&#39;t require making it one&#39;s own, though one may, on occasion.  I covered some of this during Martian Math, using the free Web to omni-triangulate.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;m drifting in and out of a Python theme.  It&#39;s become a kind of calligraphy for me, simple, spare programs &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2011-February/010191.html&quot;&gt;for STEM teachers&lt;/a&gt;.  I&#39;m seeing our bridge again, twixt natural numbers, partial sums, partial sums of those sums.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Hey, at PPUG last night I was yakking with the gmpy guy again (picking up from work by Alex Martelli).  He said arbitrary precision complex numbers are on the way.  It&#39;s not like they&#39;ve not been implemented in other libraries.  Bringing them into Python is what he&#39;s working on doing.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;My movie-goers were kind and empathized with my loss, did not begrudge me the missing movie.  The disk is Bob Smith&#39;s though.  Fingers crossed I get it back.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Thinking about relatives and friends in different chapters, moving round the karmic wheel.  Jim Person recently passed away.  The aging process is inevitable.  The impulse to plan for a better world remains though, an indication that we&#39;re drawn forward, not just impelled from behind (fear vs. longing: pursued vs. drawn towards).&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1285760100023328341'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1285760100023328341'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/02/another-space-case.html' title='Another Space Case'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4407254236878978924</id><published>2011-02-06T23:09:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2011-02-07T09:42:56.927-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Tell the Truth and Run (movie review)</title><content type='html'>My thanks to Marian Rhys and Bob Smith of Multnomah Friends for bringing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.happinessonline.org/MoralCode/LiveWithTruth/p7.htm&quot;&gt;this enlightening documentary&lt;/a&gt; to my attention.  &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I served as projectionist at the meetinghouse tonight, sharing it with a tiny elite, including Sonya Pinney and Harriet Holling, our elder stalwarts and a source of memories going way back.  Their kids were my contemporaries (hello to Sonya&#39;s Eric, Lael, Heather and to Harriet&#39;s Alice and Linda).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The movie: &lt;i&gt;Tell the Truth and Run&lt;/i&gt;, a biography of George Seldes (1996).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/books/00/11/26/specials/schlesinger-culture.html&quot;&gt;His brother, Gilbert&lt;/a&gt;, was the well-connected arts and letters guy, friend of Picasso and James Joyce, who took over &lt;i&gt;The Dial&lt;/i&gt; from Bucky&#39;s great aunt Margaret (with a few owners and editors in between).  These brothers had grown up in a Jewish intentional community known as &lt;i&gt;The Alliance&lt;/i&gt;, losing their mother early to TB, and strongly influenced by their dad&#39;s engagement with world affairs and uncompromising intellect.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;George was on the right side of history in so many ways.  When this documentary was made, people had the benefit of more hindsight and were happy enough to pile on honors and accolades. He lived to be 104.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In the actual battle for a freer press, he was the quintessential &quot;muckraker&quot; in the most positive sense, taking on the unholy alliance between advertisers, publishers, and what news that&#39;s fit to print (nothing that might hurt owner/sponsor profits, if at all possible).  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;He challenged journalists to live up to their own ethics (if they had any).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v9UneDolVz8&quot;&gt;What were his radical positions&lt;/a&gt; that branded him a muckraker?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;He refused to suck up to El Duce (Mussolini) when so many were doing just that, on both sides of the Atlantic.  He was in Rome at the time, as a foreign correspondent for the &lt;i&gt;Chicago Tribune&lt;/i&gt;, and he was eventually evicted, and might have been dragged off the train to Paris and killed had it not been for some British officers giving him cover in a hastily arranged ploy.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;After WW1 he went behind enemy lines and learned the average Germans were not the despicable people (&quot;huns&quot;) he had helped dehumanize as a war correspondent. War itself was the enemy. General Pershing would not let him publish about the horrors of war. War correspondents enlisted in the Army were there to build morale, not question the dominant paradigm.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;He well understood that &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/11/into-fire-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;the Spanish Civil War&lt;/a&gt; was a dress rehearsal for Fascism versus democracies.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;He reported accurately on the approach of WW2, seeing the militarization of youngsters as the unmistakable harbinger of what was to come.  He already knew &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/04/v-for-vendetta-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;the fascist psychology&lt;/a&gt; pretty intimately and recognized its features in his homeland as well as overseas.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;After WW2 he fought big tobacco companies and their huge propaganda machine.  Americans were (and are) easy targets for addictive drug pushers and their spurious health claims (&quot;more doctors smoke &lt;i&gt;Camels&lt;/i&gt;&quot;), plus consumers &lt;i&gt;wanted&lt;/i&gt; to believe their American dream, not explore its dark side or wake up in some &quot;matrix&quot;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Lets remember that readers / viewers are often complicit, in insisting the media reinforce their world views. It&#39;s not just the moneyed who shape media campaigns.  There&#39;s an unspoken social contract whereby the moneyed end up paying for what the &quot;me tooers&quot; ardently hope might be a sustainable model of reality.  Given sufficient commitment and education, this might prove a more viable model &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/11/kicking-can-down-road.html&quot;&gt;down the road&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;George made a career of fighting corruption, conflicts of interest, hypocrisy, and made a lot of enemies in the process. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;After quitting the &lt;i&gt;Chicago Tribune&lt;/i&gt; (too much corruption), he and his wife retreated to Vermont and set up their own four page weekly called &lt;i&gt;In Fact&lt;/i&gt;, which developed quite a following. It reported on stories no one else would touch (such as the links between cigarette smoking and lung cancer). &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fair.org/&quot;&gt;FAIR&lt;/a&gt; was in some ways a successor.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;By the time we get to the McCarthy Period, he&#39;s one of those vilified as a Red, along with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/07/einstein-omsi.html&quot;&gt;Albert Einstein&lt;/a&gt;, Aaron Copeland, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/10/good-night-and-good-luck-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Edward Murrow&lt;/a&gt; and other &quot;subversives&quot;.  Stoking public fears against dissenters, using &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/12/random-wanderers-post.html&quot;&gt;the &quot;Commie&quot; memeplex&lt;/a&gt;, was a convenient, if cowardly, ploy.  People were afraid to subscribe to &lt;i&gt;In Fact&lt;/i&gt; lest their names show up on some FBI watch list, and the journal went out of business in 1950.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;George Seldes was in many ways a meta-journalist in that he discussed the business of journalism and the editorial process.  Many of his readers were themselves professional journalists.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Having seen how newspapers sell themselves from this angle, it&#39;s harder to rush to their defense in &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/09/note-to-journalist.html&quot;&gt;this age of the Internet&lt;/a&gt;.  What if &lt;i&gt;If Fact&lt;/i&gt; had been an on-line publication?  We&#39;ve gotten to the point where money is less a factor than having &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/omnitriangulating.html&quot;&gt;facts that cross-check&lt;/a&gt;.  This is potentially good news for democracies.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4407254236878978924'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4407254236878978924'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/02/tell-truth-and-run-movie-review.html' title='Tell the Truth and Run (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8533009084283996407</id><published>2011-01-29T13:54:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2018-06-07T22:28:34.714-07:00</updated><title type='text'>States in Flux</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Grunch of Giants&lt;/i&gt; (by Bucky) is in part about a contrivance known as &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/07/corporation-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;the corporation&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, an on-paper invention in legal fiction that defends the shareholders against losses beyond their original investments.  If the ship goes down, only your share goes with it, not your entire estate.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Nation states, on the other hand, were deemed less &quot;flash in the pan&quot; (less here today, gone tomorrow) so &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vancouversun.com/business/Sovereign+default+remains+2011+risk/4097870/story.html&quot;&gt;securing debt against them&lt;/a&gt; might be a better proposition in the long term.  Many a bank specializes in loans to &lt;a href=&quot;http://grunch.net/archives/64&quot;&gt;sovereign nations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
As of the 1980s, the flim-flam was becoming more obvious, as the press for financial mechanisms to sustain a weapons buildup was pushed forward.  Dragging Uncle Sam under was a part of the plan. He was the addict, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/11/hurt-locker-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;war was the drug&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Fast forward to 2011, and we find the English schoolboy reality of &quot;nation states&quot; still failing to fit the facts on the ground.  High ideals continue to wrap themselves in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gla.ac.uk/~dc4w/laibach/nsk.html&quot;&gt;the claptrap of statehood&lt;/a&gt; however, whether these states &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/01/cyber-nations.html&quot;&gt;be virtual&lt;/a&gt; or even fictional.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/07/epcot-makeover.html&quot;&gt;Theme parks&lt;/a&gt; abound, Burma&#39;s among them, a sacred space.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Egypt&#39;s is a great civilization, as is Israel&#39;s, yet they permeate the globe by this time.  Localizing to shrines, sacred sites, tourist attractions, continues to make sense.  Carving the world into &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2005/12/thinking-globally.html&quot;&gt;some jigsaw puzzle&lt;/a&gt;, ever changing, makes ever less sense.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
An ethnicity needs airstrips and dots on the map (campus footprints) but vast contiguous tracts, in the shape of nations?  We share a commons, that much is obvious. Resource managers have important responsibilities.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/64761&quot;&gt;Count me a skeptic&lt;/a&gt; where schoolboy politics is concerned.  Too much emphasis on &quot;boy scout math&quot; had gotten us into this pickle.  Our Promised Land is not as much a &quot;house divided&quot; as the nationalists presume.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/10/new-atlantis-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Our New Atlantis&lt;/a&gt; is nothing other than the Global U itself, our&lt;i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/11/about-secularism.html&quot;&gt;Novus Ordo Seclorum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Ecosystems pay no heed to political districting.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
I&#39;m all for &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/more-from-97214.html&quot;&gt;zip codes&lt;/a&gt; however, as a way to deliver and assess demographics.  I respect Bhutan&#39;s Dzongkhags, and Switzerland&#39;s cantons.  We still need organs for local administration, systems for delivering mail and/or goods.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8533009084283996407'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8533009084283996407'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/01/states-in-flux.html' title='States in Flux'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1056229837973818572</id><published>2011-01-26T15:09:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2011-01-26T15:12:39.861-08:00</updated><title type='text'>HNY (Rabbit)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5388568759/&quot; title=&quot;Year of the Rabbit by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5051/5388568759_c3f3244050.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Year of the Rabbit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They&#39;re looking into &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/01/next-frame.html&quot;&gt;Nick&#39;s case&lt;/a&gt; pretty deeply at the hospital.  He&#39;s receiving the same standard of care they&#39;d give to anyone with his medical condition.  Lots of friends coming by.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It&#39;s almost Chinese New Year and the hospital is decorated accordingly.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1056229837973818572'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1056229837973818572'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/01/hny-rabbit.html' title='HNY (Rabbit)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5051/5388568759_c3f3244050_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6180396047262377434</id><published>2011-01-24T08:56:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2011-01-24T08:56:59.009-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Snakes Alive!</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;311&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/Pg1VfkSd1bo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6180396047262377434'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6180396047262377434'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/01/snakes-alive.html' title='Snakes Alive!'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/Pg1VfkSd1bo/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1039516314377722018</id><published>2011-01-09T19:01:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2011-01-11T00:32:28.948-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Next Frame</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/64371&quot;&gt;Nick appears better&lt;/a&gt;.  We chatted about a wide range of topics today.  He didn&#39;t see why Internet access should even be an issue in this day and age.  Why do we settle for the problems we nurse along, specialize in not solving?  I&#39;d been whining about my failing laptop, which shut down during social hour at the meetinghouse today.  I need to try rescuing some pictures at least.  I&#39;ll grab everything I can get.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We&#39;re convening a first board meeting, in recent memory (I&#39;m fairly new to this gig), to brainstorm more about the future of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isepp.org/&quot;&gt;ISEPP&lt;/a&gt;.  I was exulting this evening about how Terry had managed to pull off the most stellar and illustrious lecture series in the history of the planet to date.  Jet airplanes were only recently invented after all, and a lecture series isn&#39;t quite the same thing as a circus, though such analogies are inevitable.  Stephan J. Gould, Jane Goodall, Stephan Hawking, Carl Sagan, Sir Roger Penrose, Susan Haack... James Burke.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Yes, the OMSI pubs are way cool, as are the TED Talks.  We&#39;d wanted to do more with streaming video.  The right people never came out of the woodwork I guess.  We do have an &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/06/taking-inventory.html&quot;&gt;inventory of some interesting tapes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tara secured top awards, best speaker, top debater, at the Pacific University meetup this weekend (an overbooked two day event that ended up going seven rounds).  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I slogged through multi-hour Quaker business meetings in the meantime, made endurable by the people in them.  I&#39;m of course proud of Tara, as are the Friends.  I was bragging to mom on the cell today (as well as listing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5345138099/in/photostream/&quot;&gt;my woes&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Portland has done some really stellar service, and our achievements should be more celebrated. I&#39;m not sure &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AVmq9dq6Nsg&quot;&gt;the new sitcom&lt;/a&gt; is helping (I&#39;ve yet to see it). Of course I&#39;ve been indulging in such boosterism for years. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Perhaps I&#39;m fighting a deeply ingrained inferiority complex?  Having lived in many cities around the world, I think Portland deserves to capitalize on its successes, yet one of the memes is we&#39;re too lazy to amount to much.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;Synergeo&lt;/i&gt; is just a &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/64383&quot;&gt;Punch &#39;n Judy show&lt;/a&gt; these days.  Why try to keep it serious when there&#39;s no hope of doing so.  Yet there&#39;s content to work in.  I&#39;m being the dedicated scholar, scrounging up those passages from &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; like I always do, trying to prove to the world that our agenda wasn&#39;t all that off target.  Listen to Portland for a change?  Not that we&#39;re all into esoterica to that degree.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=7353844&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;My brand of geekery&lt;/a&gt; is one of many on tap.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;d think a supranational looking for positive PR would be salivating for a slice of Portland pie. I&#39;ve already stuffed these blogs with enough &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/06/hunger-project-on-synergeo.html&quot;&gt;science fiction&lt;/a&gt; to put my preferred future on the map.  Others have their own storyboards, which they&#39;re free to be up front about.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1039516314377722018'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1039516314377722018'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/01/next-frame.html' title='Next Frame'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2781185271735968246</id><published>2011-01-07T22:38:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2011-01-07T23:24:28.897-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Return to ICU</title><content type='html'>I got a cell call from Gideon this morning that Dr. Consoletti was truly ill, and going by train to Portland.  My instructions were to get him to the ER right away, and that I did.  He&#39;s getting good quality professional care from Providence, one of the best hospitals around.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Quinn, a Chinese medicine teacher, was on the phone with the ER doc (Dr. Goldstein), and later met with him in person. No one was in disagreement.  The question to Nick was whether he was willing to fight for his life with them.  He&#39;s greatly in need of some sleep, but ICU is more about keeping people conscious, at least under these conditions.  I&#39;m not a medical doctor and spent much of the time eying the computer equipment, judging their aesthetics.  Pretty functional.  Getting more compact.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Nick has been hitch hiking for longer than most people in this galaxy.  He&#39;s been given rides by Carlos Santana, Gregory Bateson, Jerry Garcia, even Krishnamurti.  He worked with Ervin Laszlo&#39;s Club of Budapest as in intern with The Union &quot;without walls&quot; Institute and attended Schumacher College in England (David Bohm was supposed to be teaching that semester, but his health was failing -- Nick did his thesis on &quot;Bohmian Dialog&quot; which emerged from meetings between David Bohm and Kirshnamurti).  He&#39;s wandered Europe as a busker, playing the dulcimer and other instruments. He&#39;s a scholar and a gentleman and well known to friends of Bucky Fuller.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Quinn likened him to Forrest Gump as we talked later at &lt;i&gt;American Dream Pizza&lt;/i&gt;.  I went back to say g&#39;night.  Quinn will visit first thing in the morning, me later.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tara, away at &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/12/judging-day.html&quot;&gt;a debate tournament&lt;/a&gt;, made finals (she usually does, as one of Oregon&#39;s finest debaters, objectively speaking).  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;ve been working on a design pattern I call Combing Medusa&#39;s Hair that I could use some more help with.  Medusa is a reference to an old asynchronous listener, a precursor of Twisted (these are Python language resources).  The hair-like threads represent many spawned processes. This is for COM objects inside a working model truck dispatcher, mostly implemented in VFP.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;ll have more to include about Nick and his adventures as events unfold. I ask you to hold him in the light.  It&#39;s touch and go for the guy.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;ve notified several key Wanderers (Nick is one, if anyone is) and left voice mail for Gideon with an update.  I need to contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/10/king-lear-play-review.html&quot;&gt;Johnny Stallings&lt;/a&gt;. Quinn is also spreading the word.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Nick has enriched my life with many lasting and nurturing relationships.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2781185271735968246'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2781185271735968246'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/01/return-to-icu.html' title='Return to ICU'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6022065129066839263</id><published>2010-12-31T20:33:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2010-12-31T20:33:43.901-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Looking Back on 2010</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5311359012/&quot; title=&quot;Car 4 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5081/5311359012_85ec29e703.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Car 4&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6022065129066839263'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6022065129066839263'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/12/looking-back-on-2010.html' title='Looking Back on 2010'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5081/5311359012_85ec29e703_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5745640856194497848</id><published>2010-12-29T09:22:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-12-29T11:16:17.769-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2010.12.29</title><content type='html'>I came to the Linus Pauling Center all hot to trot about this new &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?messageID=7344243&amp;amp;#7344243&quot;&gt;&quot;weapons inspector&quot; major&lt;/a&gt;.  The feedback I&#39;ve been getting ranges from &quot;too narrow&quot; to &quot;too broad&quot;, as one would inspect in such academic discussions.  The idea of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/12/from-day-to-day.html&quot;&gt;hosting facilities in the Philippines&lt;/a&gt; is sparking interest among Japanese sources.  Could a consortium of universities look at Okinawa too?  MIT?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Glenn and Steve are hold forth on their gemology studies.  Glenn is a hard worker and makes stuff.  His turquoise may take about three hours to buff.  Now they&#39;re talking about welding.  Jeff and Bill have done this with electronics a lot.  Jon Bunce is here as well, the musician.  He&#39;s the coffee beans keeper, one of the few official roles we&#39;ve designed into this institution (Wanderers).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We&#39;ve had a suggestion from &quot;off camera&quot; (from someone not here, using the Internet) to watch a particular TED talk, dunno if we&#39;ll get to it.  Glenn is back with some welded jewelry, other finery.  We&#39;re moved to a discussion of taboos, inter-breeding, and hemophilia within the British royal family (Queen Victoria a carrier).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m more in the &quot;too narrow&quot; camp (re weapons inspector PhD).  The environmental sciences department is seeing the need for sensors, lots of IP numbers, DNS coverage of hydrofracture sites, hundreds of thousands of &quot;bubble villages&quot; (the cleanup crews).  Radio-toxins such as crews grapple with at Hanford need not be the sole focus of a given Global U student.  Deploying sensors, taking readings, designing visualizations, is simply GIS in action and applies equally to theme park planning (like a roller coaster theme park, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Six Flags&lt;/span&gt; near LA for example, a First Person Physics project, open to physics majors).  When you transfer to the bubbles around Subic Bay, you may or may not have Johnston Atoll on your &quot;to visit&quot; list (maybe you just came from there?).  Routing through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/07/pets-as-gifts.html&quot;&gt;Manas Transit Center&lt;/a&gt;?  You may or may not be in field dress.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What am I reading these days?  Lots of stuff, but this one hardcover in particular is worth yakking about.  I passed it around the table.  The first chapter is about a group not unlike &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Heaven&#39;s Gate&lt;/span&gt; in some ways, of Hale-Bopp fame.  &quot;They got the wrong Applewhite&quot; quipped Ed on the phone, me at Russ &amp;amp; Deb&#39;s for the PNW Synergetics Confab (with other confabs since).  Here&#39;s the book:  &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Apocalypse Pretty Soon:  Travels in End-Time America&lt;/span&gt; by Alex Heard (W.W. Norton Company, 1999).  The Unarians weren&#39;t into abducting themselves in quite that way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We&#39;re immersed in dinosaur imagery here, literally.  &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Craigmore Creations&lt;/span&gt; operates in many of the chambers throughout this Center, turning out quality graphic novels about science, mostly set in the geological (prehistorical) past.  Although human observers may be present, which gets a plot line going, you need some pseudo-science to get them there (a time machine perhaps, like in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Idiocracy&lt;/span&gt;).  Per Dr. Fuller (recent meeting), Karplus invented Mr. O, a little observer character with one palm painted (to define left-right orientation), the Observer (or &quot;first person&quot;) of any physical vista.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bill found us this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.subblue.com/blog/2010/3/29/the_formula&quot;&gt;amazing video stream&lt;/a&gt;, very fractal.  Sharing links is part of the &quot;groupthink&quot; (usually a &quot;bad word&quot;, right up there with &quot;hive mind&quot;).  For example, David Tver has a text sample in image format, in a language as yet unrecognized, discovered in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Jewish-Archive-Old-Cairo-Civilization/dp/0700713123&quot;&gt;Genizah in Cairo&lt;/a&gt;.  Pat was off to see her friend Kitty, age 98.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jeff is showing me Pivotal Tracker, which we can use for &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/12/storyboarding-engineers.html&quot;&gt;our storyboard planning&lt;/a&gt; (he&#39;s already using it at work).  I could invite faculty from New Mexico Tech to join me here vs. using Facebook or one of those.  Bill:  what&#39;s atan2? (used in the &quot;3D Mandelbrot&quot; he&#39;s studying).  We found it &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?messageID=7344243&amp;amp;#7344243&quot;&gt;on Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5745640856194497848'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5745640856194497848'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/12/wanderers-20101229.html' title='Wanderers 2010.12.29'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2114868726797180043</id><published>2010-12-25T09:01:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-12-25T09:03:27.644-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Mir</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiytvaby5t8ksq91In_69YRiA70t3ZzSsUTMzlP9q0X5XMFqAa_IzNWCLQQTFcPalU6huIN2ck5bknHrMmzEsexQdMlHAfXwGPLz2mZ4UmnjcIL56XxSFE5UoRN9f3n5MqH4nL2/s1600/hippiexmas.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 400px; height: 265px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiytvaby5t8ksq91In_69YRiA70t3ZzSsUTMzlP9q0X5XMFqAa_IzNWCLQQTFcPalU6huIN2ck5bknHrMmzEsexQdMlHAfXwGPLz2mZ4UmnjcIL56XxSFE5UoRN9f3n5MqH4nL2/s400/hippiexmas.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5554666426580773298&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2114868726797180043'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2114868726797180043'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/12/mir.html' title='Mir'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiytvaby5t8ksq91In_69YRiA70t3ZzSsUTMzlP9q0X5XMFqAa_IzNWCLQQTFcPalU6huIN2ck5bknHrMmzEsexQdMlHAfXwGPLz2mZ4UmnjcIL56XxSFE5UoRN9f3n5MqH4nL2/s72-c/hippiexmas.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-910833444315491690</id><published>2010-12-18T14:52:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2011-01-30T14:29:12.762-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Rock On Portland</title><content type='html'>Typos fixed, &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/63869&quot;&gt;links added&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--- In &lt;i&gt;Synergeo&lt;/i&gt; &quot;coyote_starship&quot; &lt;kirby.urner@...&gt; wrote:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&gt; Another meme that makes the rounds is that &quot;conspiracies are bad&quot; i.e.&lt;br /&gt;&gt; you&#39;d never want to throw a surprise party, or be in league with some&lt;br /&gt;&gt; friends and work to steer the company in a positive direction. No,&lt;br /&gt;&gt; those&#39;d be collegial networks among peers, whereas a &quot;conspiracy&quot; is&lt;br /&gt;&gt; by definition nefarious. &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/63868&quot;&gt;This FBI guy&lt;/a&gt; doesn&#39;t seem to have much&lt;br /&gt;&gt; immunity to the &quot;conspiracies are bad&quot; meme.&lt;br /&gt;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is where I&#39;d go back to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/63784&quot;&gt;memeplex&lt;/a&gt; I was hammering on with an influential McLuhanite (newmedia) with &lt;i&gt;Church of Bob&lt;/i&gt; connections. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwgrayprojects.com/SynergeticsDictionary/SDCards.php?cn=10229&amp;amp;tp=1&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Synergetics Dictionary&lt;/i&gt; -&gt; M -&gt; Marshall McLuhan&lt;/a&gt; gives us a scene wherein Marshall &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/01/quotable-quotes.html&quot;&gt;shows up on Bucky&#39;s radar&lt;/a&gt; going &quot;I&#39;ve read your books, and I want to &lt;i&gt;join&lt;/i&gt; your conspiracy&quot;. Said in a cheerful, affable style no doubt, with a tinge of mischief.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The word &quot;conspiracy&quot;, meaning &quot;to breathe with&quot;, also has that &quot;piracy&quot; meme embedded (there it is, right in the spelling -- aren&#39;t memes fun? not unlike numerology, a sub-branch of memetics). Pirates conspire. Or Pyrates.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now here in Portland, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/09/yar.html&quot;&gt;we like Pirates&lt;/a&gt;, think they&#39;re cool, might dress and &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/02/adventures-in-radio-land-part-2.html&quot;&gt;talk like pirates&lt;/a&gt; on some days. So we might like conspiracies too then? Let&#39;s say we do. &lt;/kirby.urner@...&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;kirby.urner@...&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/kirby.urner@...&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;kirby.urner@...&gt;A radical bookstore &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/back-at-laughing-horse.html&quot;&gt;like&lt;i&gt; Laughing Horse&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is where people are likely to know a lot about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/63870&quot;&gt;various conspiracy theories&lt;/a&gt; (&quot;911 inside job&quot; is a bevy of theories, not just one). They&#39;re like librarians, or at least the more experienced ones are. More like Giles or the female equivalent &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/more-tv-talk.html&quot;&gt;in &lt;i&gt;Buffy the Vampire Slayer&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/kirby.urner@...&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;kirby.urner@...&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/kirby.urner@...&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;kirby.urner@...&gt;Portland as a city is quite well read, with some enormous famous bookstores (Powell&#39;s especially, but others too) and a really excellent library system (the on-line stuff works). So it stands to reason that Portland, even without a Library of Congress, is able to serve as a decent intelligence gathering headquarters. &lt;/kirby.urner@...&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;kirby.urner@...&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/kirby.urner@...&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;kirby.urner@...&gt;Our analysts are nothing to sneeze at.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kirby&lt;/kirby.urner@...&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3711555080/&quot; title=&quot;Geed Squad by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2453/3711555080_30954a0011_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;180&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; alt=&quot;Geed Squad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/910833444315491690'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/910833444315491690'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/12/rock-on-portland.html' title='Rock On Portland'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2453/3711555080_30954a0011_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7398265465305368298</id><published>2010-12-17T17:04:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-12-17T17:08:18.373-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Santa&#39;s Elves (movie preview)</title><content type='html'>This one is about North Americans gleefully making bombs, designing new kinds of horrors, with many of them professing some kind of twisted &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/10/religulous-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;religulosity&lt;/a&gt;&quot; to justify their livelihoods.  &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Disturbing.  Reminders of &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/03/why-we-fight-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Why We Fight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Keeping most of it a cartoon is a cute touch, as an offset to the grim realities. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I can see where &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/09/toontalk.html&quot;&gt;the Elves&lt;/a&gt; wouldn&#39;t want to tarnish their good image (&lt;i&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/i&gt; was too kind), and their morale is Santa&#39;s concern.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Will it come out in 3D?&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7398265465305368298'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7398265465305368298'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/12/santas-elves-movie-preview.html' title='Santa&#39;s Elves (movie preview)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8930411982481357095</id><published>2010-12-12T14:10:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-12-15T19:54:04.890-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Hanukkah 2010</title><content type='html'>We&#39;re getting &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/09/wanderers-2010914.html&quot;&gt;closer to Judaism&lt;/a&gt; in making Hanukkah our December event after Thanksgiving.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We used to throw &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/sets/72157611469130829/with/3129058411/&quot;&gt;a big Solstice Party&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dawn didn&#39;t proclaim herself Christian, though she was cleared as &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/08/quakers-101.html&quot;&gt;a Quaker&lt;/a&gt;, was a member of the Religious Society of Friends through Multnomah Meeting.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We enjoy schmoozing with those doing the tree thing in their living rooms, even if we don&#39;t do one ourselves.  More ornaments should be polyhedrons.  A virtual tree would do (on the LCD). The scene would keep changing.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2010/04/smart-bar-lcds.html&quot;&gt;A reverie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m somewhat predatory, though appropriately diplomatic when it comes to nuts, eggnog, other winter cheer.  I got a ride in a Cadillac today, to the supermarket.  Our kitchen was somewhat bare again.  Last night I tried boiling vegetables, including some greens and marinated tofu.  Not half bad.  But I do like a box of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Coca Krispies&lt;/span&gt; now and then, and lots of coffee.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The hanukkah gifts were generous.  Soaps and chocolate, socks, stuff we really do use.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I grabbed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3695572071/&quot;&gt;an Advent Calendar&lt;/a&gt; out of the garage awhile back, a wooden one that Dawn hoped we&#39;d use -- she was raised Catholic and recognized the power of rituals.  I set it atop the upright piano, a gift from the Braithwaite family years ago.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This time of year, I tend to truck out my &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/07/xmas-in-july.html&quot;&gt;Fourth King&lt;/a&gt;&quot; myth, but I haven&#39;t thought of anything new to add.  Maybe others will take it on (they weren&#39;t Christians either, those kings -- no one was back then).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of Christmas, Sam Lanahan his been like Santa Claus lately, mailing out &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/10/art-of-note.html&quot;&gt;his beautiful book&lt;/a&gt; to a long list of people (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/09/buckyball-day.html&quot;&gt;Dave Koski&lt;/a&gt; was pleased to find his, under a pile of snow on his doorstep, in the midst of a blizzard).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sam is also giving away &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flextegrity.com/free-samples.php&quot;&gt;free samples&lt;/a&gt; of the prototype materials.  Customers need only pay shipping.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;FNB was also distributing some hanukkah &quot;geld&quot; (chocolate money) thanks to Satya.  He offered the bag to me but we agreed it was for younger children than mine.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8930411982481357095'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8930411982481357095'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/12/hanukkah-2010.html' title='Hanukkah 2010'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4370813542321194936</id><published>2010-12-10T18:55:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2010-12-10T21:13:53.016-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Office Work</title><content type='html'>As I was complaining to Patrick:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote style=&quot;border-collapse: collapse; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; &quot;&gt;Today I&#39;m regretting not taking you up on some summer time offer to pour trailer park slop on my upper deck, which needs a new sealant. I just went up and relaid the tarp, in the faint hope that&#39;ll help.  The ceiling in my office, in the meantime, is cracking along seams (latex paint layer).  The electrical tape solution was ugly and pointless (the glue melts when damp).  This surgical tape solution, porous to let the blood through, might be just the ticket for now...&lt;/blockquote&gt;The bookkeeper&#39;s computer is rebooting at will.  I took it outside for a dusting, but there may be deeper damage.  It reboots even from within BIOS.  Maybe a hard disk transplant into another skeleton computer would solve the problem.  I&#39;d have to dig one up somewhere.  That&#39;s also the network printer controller...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My equipment is out of date, as is my domicile more generally (1905).  In some experimental prototype community of tomorrow, &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/63777&quot;&gt;a leading buckaneer&lt;/a&gt; wouldn&#39;t be some &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/06/wall-e-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Wall-e in a junkyard&lt;/a&gt;, all intelligent life on vacation (Orlando?).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m glad mom is doing OK in average 70 degree weather (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/12/whittier-usa.html&quot;&gt;Whittier&lt;/a&gt;).  Tara was gung ho to hit &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/12/judging-day.html&quot;&gt;the debate circuit&lt;/a&gt; again this weekend, but her team (and coach) need their rest.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;d gladly upgrade the Blue House to meet Global U codes (and help define them), but that&#39;d require some planning and organization, both of which are in short supply in this day and age, at least where &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/63780&quot;&gt;radical math teaching&lt;/a&gt; is concerned.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Walker took off after dark for a remote tool shop on the outskirts of town.  Why do everything nocturnally?  My senses reel.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The &lt;i&gt;Dead Mathematicians Society&lt;/i&gt; (DMS) has been suggesting I give a talk.  I just submitted a proposal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My attempt to do multi-threaded COM was successful, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2010-December/010139.html&quot;&gt;the code is quite &quot;mickey mouse&quot;&lt;/a&gt; as my scuba instructor Gill Gilleland was wont to say -- exMarine, professional recovery diver.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mark Hammond himself dropped by on comp.lang.python on response to my query, wow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I made some baby steps forward with OST as well.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Writing to Nirel:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote style=&quot;border-collapse: collapse; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; &quot;&gt;As individuals we&#39;re brilliant.  As teams working together, you&#39;d think we could do more. Anyway, that&#39;s how it seems tonight -- thinking about teams.&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4370813542321194936'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4370813542321194936'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/12/office-work.html' title='Office Work'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3230995636326492272</id><published>2010-12-08T23:10:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2010-12-08T23:28:51.200-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Choosing a Flavor</title><content type='html'>The next generation of forms handling is XForms, another W3 standard.  &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;ve been experimenting with ODK Build, which allows one to build phone-ready forms for the Android.  &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The &quot;ice cream factory in Havana&quot; might be one of the simulations, keying off &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.discoverthenetworks.org/individualProfile.asp?indid=2038&quot;&gt;Senator Leahy&#39;s remarks&lt;/a&gt; about getting a &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/06/hunger-project-on-synergeo.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ben &amp;amp; Jerry&#39;s&lt;/i&gt; in Cuba&lt;/a&gt;, in a manner consistent with zoning and city ordinances.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5245493111/&quot; title=&quot;ODK Build by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5242/5245493111_eba47027ab_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;194&quot; alt=&quot;ODK Build&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4867478861/&quot; title=&quot;Ice Cream for Einstein by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4139/4867478861_264e5cc99c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Ice Cream for Einstein&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3230995636326492272'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3230995636326492272'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/12/choosing-flavor.html' title='Choosing a Flavor'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5242/5245493111_eba47027ab_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8238830533674716272</id><published>2010-12-07T18:24:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2010-12-07T18:28:57.153-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Facebook Excerpts</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjMOnGXC4gpnnUruPCFzw54PnDLnlV83EHnmdydBFCA-hvVorSaI4LEOU448L_3ug2ysnDUHQbX-dJHJ_pc4jCTBSEOQYZWFeyJ-h0-2BiaDLhnWZYzmGF7hlmLh9M3geJiZnHb/s1600/fnb2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 320px; height: 269px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjMOnGXC4gpnnUruPCFzw54PnDLnlV83EHnmdydBFCA-hvVorSaI4LEOU448L_3ug2ysnDUHQbX-dJHJ_pc4jCTBSEOQYZWFeyJ-h0-2BiaDLhnWZYzmGF7hlmLh9M3geJiZnHb/s320/fnb2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5548132746644590210&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEghrhfWZaURYxTGon6BC2Ux9AUUKOhJCgaLOorg41vRK6zD2mw1gX-jOb7y125R6kT0ewevcom2QQmE9j4tk6ic-3GGW0nw_dE0921q4GeLhPEiPk7VcWikCB7X7QkBXnLiDYdf/s1600/nirel_facebook.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 320px; height: 242px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEghrhfWZaURYxTGon6BC2Ux9AUUKOhJCgaLOorg41vRK6zD2mw1gX-jOb7y125R6kT0ewevcom2QQmE9j4tk6ic-3GGW0nw_dE0921q4GeLhPEiPk7VcWikCB7X7QkBXnLiDYdf/s320/nirel_facebook.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5548132059065401010&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiIUoDqar5R-5A28NUvTVE09joGHYNbbJTuedNwNEdlQfns_R2ApGltMZyef0L7ZT1yAWp783kKRvjiAb8QRxTRtSenR5QmLn85lY_YiancfoM3DG_s2rCNaWaRbdsspPGkq740/s1600/free_web.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 320px; height: 164px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiIUoDqar5R-5A28NUvTVE09joGHYNbbJTuedNwNEdlQfns_R2ApGltMZyef0L7ZT1yAWp783kKRvjiAb8QRxTRtSenR5QmLn85lY_YiancfoM3DG_s2rCNaWaRbdsspPGkq740/s320/free_web.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5548131931582570370&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi4dC4XrbZAhl99v_VU1_n-kH61LuP-4plZM5JJdaYsolTGEvrb9nfG8VABzEt5GHnf1jz-ugvtlgQm17U8IFZzJRNkT84i9ROgRzogikNWd9T_n4n6qicBtwuPPntvWTjoAy5a/s1600/extraordinary_rendition.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 320px; height: 242px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi4dC4XrbZAhl99v_VU1_n-kH61LuP-4plZM5JJdaYsolTGEvrb9nfG8VABzEt5GHnf1jz-ugvtlgQm17U8IFZzJRNkT84i9ROgRzogikNWd9T_n4n6qicBtwuPPntvWTjoAy5a/s320/extraordinary_rendition.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5548131819255630722&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8238830533674716272'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8238830533674716272'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/12/facebook-excerpts.html' title='Facebook Excerpts'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjMOnGXC4gpnnUruPCFzw54PnDLnlV83EHnmdydBFCA-hvVorSaI4LEOU448L_3ug2ysnDUHQbX-dJHJ_pc4jCTBSEOQYZWFeyJ-h0-2BiaDLhnWZYzmGF7hlmLh9M3geJiZnHb/s72-c/fnb2.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2679144804609285631</id><published>2010-11-29T13:22:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-11-29T22:26:31.249-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Olive Branch</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhTYwQQHy49eKN-GILWDcnt40Xc77AWKJxvVGWVi1AYUr4VU-5NeQ0AZQkaPGe2i3TOxWpNQac284UNE5pqgJP0WEPpL3gBM6MEyAh7f53ie0LNmeXIS4WRfgSoc0LoPnC4UH7n/s1600/DODECAEDRO+SIMB%25C3%2593LICO+30.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 400px; height: 312px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhTYwQQHy49eKN-GILWDcnt40Xc77AWKJxvVGWVi1AYUr4VU-5NeQ0AZQkaPGe2i3TOxWpNQac284UNE5pqgJP0WEPpL3gBM6MEyAh7f53ie0LNmeXIS4WRfgSoc0LoPnC4UH7n/s400/DODECAEDRO+SIMB%25C3%2593LICO+30.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5545088367501729138&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;featured artist: &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mariomarin-poliedros.com/&quot;&gt;Mario Marn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I held out &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.geneseo.edu/pipermail/math-thinking-l/2010-November/000687.html&quot;&gt;an olive branch&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/03/two-track-solution.html&quot;&gt;the functional programmers&lt;/a&gt; today.  They&#39;ve been &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.geneseo.edu/pipermail/math-thinking-l/2010-February/date.html&quot;&gt;registering their distaste&lt;/a&gt; for what some have called the &quot;object oriented paradigm&quot; (OOP), saying it&#39;s not really a &quot;paradigm&quot;.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;That might be true.  Or if it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a paradigm, it&#39;s a &lt;i&gt;very old&lt;/i&gt; one, embedded in natural language. Animals have behaviors signified by verbs.  Animals, signified by nouns, inherit characteristics (adjectives, properties) from their ancestors.  What&#39;s new about that?  Nothing.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;What&#39;s proved a lasting innovation was the &lt;i&gt;notation&lt;/i&gt;, and that notation is &quot;dot notation&quot; (DN).  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So instead of writing &quot;object oriented notation&quot; in place of &quot;object oriented paradigm&quot;, I merely substitute &quot;dot notation&quot;, with the caveat that some OO languages don&#39;t actually use it (which is fine, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/06/aristotle-was-right.html&quot;&gt;diversity rocks&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2679144804609285631'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2679144804609285631'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/11/olive-branch.html' title='Olive Branch'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhTYwQQHy49eKN-GILWDcnt40Xc77AWKJxvVGWVi1AYUr4VU-5NeQ0AZQkaPGe2i3TOxWpNQac284UNE5pqgJP0WEPpL3gBM6MEyAh7f53ie0LNmeXIS4WRfgSoc0LoPnC4UH7n/s72-c/DODECAEDRO+SIMB%25C3%2593LICO+30.JPG" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3473203850589280195</id><published>2010-11-26T22:04:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-11-26T22:10:39.495-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Conversations about Bizmos</title><content type='html'>Friends and relatives know I&#39;ve had this idea for a long time, of roving vehicles that aren&#39;t just recreational, get work done. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We already have lots of utility vehicles on the road, including some that provide health care.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This trip north have provided some more opportunities to discuss the idea.  I just filed &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/63675&quot;&gt;another brain dump&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergeo&lt;/span&gt; on the topic.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ve got a lot of interesting science fiction going, way better than most IMO, in the sense of realizable.  So much dilly-dallying goes on.  Where&#39;s the beef?</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3473203850589280195'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3473203850589280195'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/11/conversations-about-bizmos.html' title='Conversations about Bizmos'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4164879338463136472</id><published>2010-11-22T10:06:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-11-22T20:27:07.196-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Yakking with Patrick</title><content type='html'>Sir Patrick was by yesterday evening, one of our resident geniuses (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/04/back-in-97214.html&quot;&gt;97214&lt;/a&gt;:  the zip code of geniuses in the city that works).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dr. Nick came in later, and we screened &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/10/necessary-ruin-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;A Necessary Ruin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; against the classroom wall (same arrangement I&#39;m using to teach Python).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We also talked about &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=7303061&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;girl scout math&lt;/a&gt;, which LW is pioneering -- a kind of bridge between Supermarket Math and Neolithic Math per my Heuristics for Teachers.  One needs to shop wisely, meaning &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/11/visit-with-architect.html&quot;&gt;a lot of homework&lt;/a&gt; goes into the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/gst1.html&quot;&gt;BE phase&lt;/a&gt; (GST).  One simulates, plays &quot;what if&quot; in one&#39;s head.  Then you jump out of a helicopter or whatever (perhaps as a rescuer, perhaps as an occupier, perhaps as a company shill... many language games might apply).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also shared &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g40KpZa4hSI&quot;&gt;this little cartoon&lt;/a&gt; that&#39;s good for learning Wittgenstein&#39;s philosophy. I used it in my last Python class as well, given the nominalist (name -&gt; object) model it well illustrates, antithetical to pragmatic operationalism but in an edifying way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Given Barton&#39;s connections to Hollywood, I&#39;m always left thinking about documentaries when he leaves.  There&#39;s a lot of retarded slowness in getting those S3 cartoons imported.  We&#39;re coming up on &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/more-from-97214.html&quot;&gt;another NFL&lt;/a&gt; that&#39;ll just show off how &quot;left behind&quot; is the Lower 48, or so I&#39;m anticipating.  The USA is now the basket case of the world, refusing to upgrade, putting future shock off onto everyone else.  That&#39;s a theme of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Idiocracy&lt;/span&gt; and deserves to be played up.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Blaming King Obama for not waving his magic wand fast enough might give rise to a Harry Potter for president movement.  Lets watch for tell tale signs of that happening.  Without proper civics training in the schools, USAers fall back on monarchy and the claptrap of the Ivory Tower and its royal societies.  We&#39;re back to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/07/making-waves-in-dc.html&quot;&gt;courtly models&lt;/a&gt;, socialites buzzing around a throne. The socialism of the celebrity class, bejeweled and tawdry, is just more &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Lord of the Flies&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m no Anglophobe &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/05/surveying-history.html&quot;&gt;ala LaRouche&lt;/a&gt;, but then I&#39;m not into &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/07/hp-half-blood-prince-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;kowtowing to Hogwarts&lt;/a&gt; when it comes to ethics, faith and practice.  That&#39;s one school among many.  We&#39;ve got &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/03/celebrating-wicca.html&quot;&gt;better witches&lt;/a&gt;, and more &quot;right stuff&quot; free software, a better meme pool overall.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4164879338463136472'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4164879338463136472'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/11/yakking-with-patrick.html' title='Yakking with Patrick'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1390936414967828687</id><published>2010-11-18T15:46:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-11-18T17:22:16.119-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Walking with Nick</title><content type='html'>I joined Dr. Consoletti for a saunter to 17th and Hawthorne, site of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/09/quaker-curriculum.html&quot;&gt;the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Barley Mill&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (a &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Grateful Dead&lt;/span&gt; capital) where we dined on tater tots, coffee and beer.  This was a chance to catch up, reminisce, compare notes.  Nick knows a lot, has been around the town a few times.  I value his information, much of which is in the category of &quot;news&quot; i.e. I knew nothing about it.  I&#39;m far from omniscient, lets make that clear.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now I&#39;m back at the meetinghouse, juggling logistics.  It&#39;s a crazy wet day and I forgot my bike lock again (Lindsey brought it).  My flashlight is underpowered.  I&#39;m not appropriately equipped.  Call out the National Guard right?  When the absent minded professor decides he &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;does&lt;/span&gt; wanna be president (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/07/einstein-omsi.html&quot;&gt;thinking of Albert&lt;/a&gt; again), stand back everyone, maybe lend an umbrella.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I went back to &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/63614&quot;&gt;my yak of the morning&lt;/a&gt;, which is that (a) an aphoristic style ala both &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/02/philosophy-101.html&quot;&gt;Nietzsche&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/03/airplane-reading.html&quot;&gt;Norman O. Brown&lt;/a&gt; is apropos and (b) it&#39;s more up to self-professed humanities experts to grapple with &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Synergetics&lt;/span&gt;.  Leaving it to physicists and mathematicians is quite the opposite of stepping up to the plate.  You&#39;ve got your philosophy of mathematics if you need to blend into the woodwork on occasion.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2010/07/on-wittgenstein-and-fuller.html&quot;&gt;Wittgenstein&#39;s stuff&lt;/a&gt; is almost custom made, for talking about cubing versus not-cubing, where 3rd powering is concerned.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That&#39;s something to look at between your readings &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/06/literary-investigation.html&quot;&gt;of Emerson and Thoreau&lt;/a&gt;, maybe &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2010/05/buzz-about-shops.html&quot;&gt;Logicomix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;  Don&#39;t push it off on those &quot;engineers&quot; you need to vilify.  This is common heritage, a contribution to the vernacular, obtuse as it may seem.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We talked about &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/10/blast-from-past.html&quot;&gt;Bonnie DeVarco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/63594&quot;&gt;at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Bioneers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (way overpriced for depressing times, Nick thought), in the early days of BFI&#39;s founding.  We share a number of names in common.  You could call that a &quot;namespace&quot; if so inclined.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yes, I heard about the Medal of Freedom.  Sounds like there&#39;s more of a story there than most people know to tell.  How might we encourage future curriculum writers to delve more deeply?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We also talked about the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Coffee Shops Network&lt;/span&gt;, a way to get &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2010/06/streaming-sg.html&quot;&gt;faster geometry&lt;/a&gt; to the public without needing a visa from &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/07/screen-tests.html&quot;&gt;the gulag&lt;/a&gt;.  Sit sipping your espresso, and see some of those memes you might have encountered in prose.  Maybe you&#39;ve been a loyal reader of these blogs?  If so, you&#39;ll probably know it when you see it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m drenched and there&#39;s no one here (here&#39;s Justin).  I should get to work, washing those pots and pans.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1390936414967828687'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1390936414967828687'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/11/walking-with-nick.html' title='Walking with Nick'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6578993606192599540</id><published>2010-11-10T12:58:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2010-11-14T18:06:40.701-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Visiting Speaker</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5176309839/&quot; title=&quot;Quaker Institution by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4088/5176309839_6618a292f0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Quaker Institution&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kathy Bergen has a long history working in that area of the planet commonly associated with stories in the Bible, Koran, Torah.  She&#39;s been with AFSC and now helps out with other Quaker assets in the region.  The prophetic or &quot;book&quot; religions, as some call them, each have many denominations or branches, all of which want floorspace in this intensively trafficked region.  Lots of tourists coming through, along with pilgrims, airline pilots, people with hidden agendas, as well as open ones.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We learned about Ramallah and the water situation.  There&#39;s running water only a few days a week.  Makes me wonder what &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Philadelphia Inquirer&lt;/span&gt; was crowing about, saying that city was doing well, but then I didn&#39;t see the article (just heard it reported on).  The nearby gated community suburbs are like these Neocon flats, where people live more like &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/05/squanderers.html&quot;&gt;squanderous Portlanders&lt;/a&gt; in their opulent palaces (water 24/7), shopping at &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/09/debate-in-97214.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;New Seasons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and driving around in their Priuses, feeling proud to be so green.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Not that I&#39;m against running water 24/7 mind you.  I&#39;d like that for Ramallah too, but do engineers have the competence?  Getting &quot;smart grids&quot; to actually be smart, requires intelligent consumers, not mindless ones.  Software can&#39;t do everything.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Waste and inefficiency is a problem all over.  Introducing some realistic simulations as games one might enjoy playing, is a time-tested way to develop skills.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They say religion has something to do with all this, but I&#39;m not sure what exactly (so many conflicting stories).  Those &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/02/jesus-camp-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;book people&lt;/a&gt;&quot; never made a whole lot of sense to me, even though I&#39;m one of &#39;em.  Been there done that etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jesus was definitely a great Bodhisattva, I think many Asians would agree.  Let&#39;s see how much &quot;Peace on Earth&quot; rhetoric we get this time through Santa&#39;s tunnel, how much &quot;Good Will to all Men&quot; that&#39;s not hollow.  Or has Christianity finally gone belly up?  Maybe &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/08/quakers-101.html&quot;&gt;Quakers&lt;/a&gt; got out just in time?  Jesus was Jewish, a great rabbi.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When I was in Ramallah in the 1970s, you could still be an Arabic-speaking local with family going way back, and get permission to use dynamite from the authorities.  There&#39;s lots of rock in that area and building just about anything requires blasting and pneumatic drills.  The attitude was relatively laid back.  By most measures, the world IQ has been plummeting since the 1970s, at least in some subcultures.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The distopian hell hole this region has become for so many does not reflect well on the programming, a point &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=7273378&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;Bishop Tutu&lt;/a&gt; was making at the University of Portland the other day.  It&#39;s hard to be proudly a Christian, and besides, there are many preachings against vanity.  Wasn&#39;t it &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/10/new-atlantis-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Sir Francis Bacon&lt;/a&gt; who wrote:  &quot;life is a tale told by an idiot?&quot;   Idiocracy R Us right?  They oughta do more on South Park.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kathy showed lots of interesting slides and the event was well attended, at least by oldsters such as myself.  Younger people tend to read more manga (comics) and are maybe not as infatuated with this part of the world, hard to say.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Geographic literacy is down across the board.  You&#39;d think with Google Earth and all... but then many schools aren&#39;t using that, because it&#39;s new, and schools don&#39;t do &quot;new&quot; -- too busy letting adults relive their childhoods, which keeps them kinda retro.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They say the second half of life is all about nostalgia for the first half.   The future is something we back into inadvertently, as we make other plans.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some schools are maybe not as like that, teach more &quot;listening to Abba&quot; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newadvent.org/cathen/01006d.htm&quot;&gt;however translated&lt;/a&gt;), i.e. &quot;attending to Spirit&quot; (as some Quakers say).  One might hope.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6578993606192599540'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6578993606192599540'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/11/visiting-speaker.html' title='Visiting Speaker'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4088/5176309839_6618a292f0_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2883255978835575318</id><published>2010-11-06T06:56:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2010-11-06T07:09:06.832-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Carnival Bizmos</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;306&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/dvUddowLZBg?fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en_US&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/dvUddowLZBg?fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en_US&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;306&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/rB02mfFVusI?fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en_US&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/rB02mfFVusI?fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en_US&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;More petro-fueled truck-based than van-based, but we&#39;re open minded around here.  My thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://ovo127.com/&quot;&gt;Ovo&lt;/a&gt; for referring me to &lt;a href=&quot;http://pinktentacle.com/&quot;&gt;PinkTentacle&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2883255978835575318'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2883255978835575318'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/11/carnival-bizmos.html' title='Carnival Bizmos'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4434108573867227850</id><published>2010-11-04T22:39:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-27T16:35:22.898-07:00</updated><title type='text'>GOSCON 2010</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157625315757940&quot; title=&quot;GOSCON 2010&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/1416/5126604370_f28eb64ed0_w.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;GOSCON 2010&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: GOSCON @ The Nines (PDX) ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4434108573867227850'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4434108573867227850'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/11/goscon-2010.html' title='GOSCON 2010'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>