<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211</id><updated>2025-02-27T06:25:58.543-08:00</updated><category term="clojure python REPL ide"/><title type='text'>BizMo Diaries</title><subtitle type='html'>On the road with Global Data</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=976'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=951&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=1001&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1905</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>976</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5440767684906350373</id><published>2012-08-28T11:49:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-08-28T11:50:18.962-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Diversity Statement</title><content type='html'>&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #500050; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px;&quot; type=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;
Фонд Программирования Python (Python Software Foundation) и&lt;br /&gt;
международное сообщество программистов Python приветствуют и поощряют&lt;br /&gt;
всех участников. Наше сообщество основано на принципах взаимоуважения,&lt;br /&gt;
терпимости и взаимопомощи, и мы стараемся помочь друг другу следовать&lt;br /&gt;
этим принципам. Мы хотим, чтобы наше сообщество стало по-настоящему&lt;br /&gt;
разнообразным: кто бы Вы ни были, с каким бы то ни было опытом, добро&lt;br /&gt;
пожаловать к нам!&lt;/blockquote&gt;
With thanks to the Python Software Foundation members list.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5440767684906350373'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5440767684906350373'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/08/diversity-statement.html' title='Diversity Statement'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1069404274027858685</id><published>2012-08-23T21:16:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2012-08-23T21:16:19.284-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Scatter Brained</title><content type='html'>I&#39;ve been disciplining myself to keep track of my toys in conjunction with this leather satchel I carry around, but that discipline broke down yesterday apparently.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The new &lt;i&gt;Nikon Coolpix&lt;/i&gt; has been a joy, purchased &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/03/music-as-water.html&quot;&gt;in March&lt;/a&gt; of last year.&amp;nbsp; The last picture I took with it:&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Sick Jokes&lt;/i&gt; (a collection) and my quad shot latte, at &lt;i&gt;Fresh Pot&lt;/i&gt; adjacent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.powells.com/locations/powells-books-on-hawthorne/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Powell&#39;s on Hawthorne&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Presumably I threw it back in the satchel at that point.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However there&#39;s no indication (so far) the camera ever made it home, although that&#39;s where I went next.&amp;nbsp; Maybe it&#39;ll turn up.&amp;nbsp; Probably it went to the same Negative Universe as my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/2925326629/&quot;&gt;Paul Kaufman hat&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; I find it disturbing when I can&#39;t put my finger on just when and where the sleight of hand occurred, me that dupe of my own legerdemain.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I still have the &lt;i&gt;Olympus Stylus&lt;/i&gt; as a fall back.&amp;nbsp; Those 14x zoom shots and richer colors will be absent from the Photostream for awhile, looks like.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Actually, I&#39;m so attached to this camera that, finding it on sale for only $207, I grabbed another (free shipping).&amp;nbsp; If I find the other one I&#39;ll make it, or the new one, a gift to someone.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I learned from Math Forum that Dr. William Thurston has died at age 65.&amp;nbsp; He was one of my professors at Princeton, for honors calculus. </content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1069404274027858685'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1069404274027858685'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/08/scatter-brained.html' title='Scatter Brained'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7007031918261357531</id><published>2012-08-12T16:39:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2012-08-13T11:46:04.799-07:00</updated><title type='text'>From a Gothamite</title><content type='html'>&quot;Gotham&quot; is supposed to be &quot;any city&quot; as you know, but there&#39;s that &quot;Goth&quot; right in the name, and the Dark Knight might be portrayed as a goth comic in some ways (yes, I&#39;m referring to &lt;i&gt;Batman&lt;/i&gt;, see post below).&amp;nbsp; But then &quot;Gotham&quot; fades into &quot;metropolis&quot; as in &quot;metropolitan&quot; which tends to mean any concentrated urban area, a CBD (central business district) especially.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The word &quot;business&quot; is fun as it contains &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/09/djangocon-day-two.html&quot;&gt;bus&lt;/a&gt;&quot; as in &lt;i&gt;Magic School Bus&lt;/i&gt;, or that bus on a motherboard that conveys data, perhaps in parallel.&amp;nbsp; In the urban center, things get &quot;bussy&quot; (pertaining to buses and business).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m in such a place now, one of those open inventory caverns, air conditioned, where people flock to take goods, to each according to her charge card allowance.&amp;nbsp; I conveyed a shopper here, from the bank, not by bus but by motorcar, in the 4-wheeler sedan I&#39;ve called &quot;maxi taxi&quot; or &quot;torture taxi&quot; depending on mood and lighting.&amp;nbsp; She&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/search/?w=17157315%40N00&amp;amp;q=taxi&amp;amp;m=text&quot;&gt;an older &lt;i&gt;Nissan&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/search/?w=17157315@N00&amp;amp;q=Razz&quot;&gt;successor to Razz&lt;/a&gt;, the raspberry colored &lt;i&gt;Subaru&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Lloyd Center Mall&lt;/i&gt;:&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/09/across-from-blue-nile.html&quot;&gt;posted from here before&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Back then, I was being cynical about the wifi and the nickle &amp;amp; dime me approach.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/history-is-surreal.html&quot;&gt;Nixon&lt;/a&gt;:&amp;nbsp; America&#39;s answer to communism.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Hey, I&#39;ll give &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/05/cowardly-capitalism.html&quot;&gt;a pro-capitalism speech&lt;/a&gt; why not?&amp;nbsp; First, let me explain how I tend to use the word &quot;capitalism&quot;, even as I struggle to bring it back to everyman&#39;s way.&amp;nbsp; I think in terms of capitals, i.e. major cities, or mover and shaker places, hubs, key players.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Like when they say &quot;London believes&quot; in some propositions, as if cities could have beliefs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Portland agrees with Tehran&quot; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/WittrsEX/message/4863&quot;&gt;some issues&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Phrases like that bespeak &quot;capitalism&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Another meaning is &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/07/coffee-shop-capitalism.html&quot;&gt;using one&#39;s head&lt;/a&gt;&quot; as in &quot;thinking cap&quot; as in &quot;being one&#39;s own boss in the &#39;what I think&#39; department&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m in a vast (OK, big) mall, and people just help themselves to goodies.&amp;nbsp; Yes, they have to pay for them, sometimes (often) on credit.&amp;nbsp; But it&#39;s a layaway economy that one designs for oneself.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s latitude for self expression.&amp;nbsp; You prefer &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/10/at-ikea.html&quot;&gt;the &lt;i&gt;Ikea&lt;/i&gt; look&lt;/a&gt;?&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s fine.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s a sense of choosing for oneself on a level it makes sense to offer choice, rather than a sense of having a thing meted out, preferentially awarded based on impossible criteria.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In a relative distopia, you&#39;ll never get that pair of shoes, because you&#39;re not allowed to just pay for them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In a fixed price (same price for all), catalog-based economy, you don&#39;t have to do it for favors or quid pro quo.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You do it because you put your time and energy in, in some other way, in some faraway land.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You are not beholden.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You walk away from the merchant, goods in hand, not owing that merchant.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Now it&#39;s between you and Visa, and that&#39;s how you want it to be.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s just a lot less karma, or lets say freedom to create your own karma.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s back to Alaska or whatever, to one&#39;s own adventure&#39;s, not some state&#39;s, though you may be a state&#39;s agent.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That being said, I came here, used the free wifi, and moved on.&amp;nbsp; My intent was consumerist though: I was thinking to upgrade the phone, from this hand me down first generation Android.&amp;nbsp; But this branch of &lt;i&gt;Verizon&lt;/i&gt; doesn&#39;t stock HTC 1x, just Incredible and Rezound, so it&#39;s out the door and off to a blogging place.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My shopper is shopping.&amp;nbsp; She doesn&#39;t always get to be in such a large metropolis, with its many charms and wonders.&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Bridge Pedal&lt;/i&gt; was today.&amp;nbsp; I stayed home and caught up on some studies.&amp;nbsp; I also am reconnecting with &lt;i&gt;Free Geek &lt;/i&gt;thanks again to &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/02/open-secrets.html&quot;&gt;Holden Web / Open Bastion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, a great web of connections.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7007031918261357531'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7007031918261357531'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/08/from-gothamite.html' title='From a Gothamite'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2846890675438485207</id><published>2012-08-05T15:18:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2012-09-09T00:08:24.021-07:00</updated><title type='text'>The Dark Knight Rises (movie review)</title><content type='html'>If you&#39;d forgotten &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/batman-begins-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;all previous Batmans&lt;/a&gt; and just walked in on this one, you may not remember how Bruce had fallen in with this cult in the Himalayas that plays &quot;angel of death&quot; to a moribund humanity.  The theme, as always, is misanthropy.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Bruce is paradoxically a philanthropist, but he&#39;s enough in touch with the dark side to know why it wants Gotham to be gone.  His own wasting away, in the wake of past trauma (PTSD) is taking its toll on Gotham psychically.  He is thrown in a pit of despair and we dare him to climb out of it.  He&#39;s just another sick and twisted little kid like all the others.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/7720704694/in/photostream&quot;&gt;Pee Wee Herman&lt;/a&gt; for example?
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There seemed to be some references to Occupy, but not many.  The rich are always having that fantasy about the mob rising up, and batman films always feature Gotham going crazy, by design of some Dr. Evil type, or perhaps a dynamic duo of Evils.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Actually, it&#39;s a whole cult that&#39;s evil, with the Himalayan cult a kind of reverse &lt;i&gt;Avengers&lt;/i&gt;, here to squelch, once and for all, a disgusting humanity, undeserving of God&#39;s love -- not forgiven, a narrative at variance with the Christian myth on the surface, but then Christians plan for an end of the world Judgement Day as well, so not that different really, more like Rosicrucians perhaps?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Law enforcement gets to be &quot;the good guys&quot; in Batman, which is how it&#39;s supposed to be. If you&#39;re on the police force and want to take your daughter to a film that doesn&#39;t demonize police, this could be it. &amp;nbsp;They bravely follow orders. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/11/post-thanksgiving.html&quot;&gt;guys in blue&lt;/a&gt; only fall down when they give up, or when they fail to rethink those orders and upgrade their performance with plot developments.  The power of intuition plays a big role in bat space. &amp;nbsp;The commissioner and the bat are attuned psychically, the meaning of that beacon (the bat is awkwardly close to being the commissioner&#39;s &quot;secret friend&quot; -- he&#39;s somewhat lucky it&#39;s a mass psychosis or he&#39;d have a hard time holding that job).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The reason Robin maxes out of the ranks, by way of detective (private eye), is he sees the blindness of &quot;just following orders&quot; as an only fall back. &amp;nbsp;There&#39;s a rule that you need to give the grunt on the ground, the man in the street, the woman salonstress, a strong sense of the big picture. &amp;nbsp;They&#39;re supposed to have deeper motives than &quot;I just wanted to be a robot, so sue me&quot; (the usual war cry at the war crimes tribunal).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s the suggestion at the end that he (the bat man) has learned to become much more invisible than before.  Bruce Wayne still alive was high profile, even when a waning millionaire or billionaire or whatever (the fall is as fascinating as the rise). Bruce Wayne as only seen by a chosen few is &quot;back to the bat cave&quot; in some ways. &amp;nbsp;The theme of Resurrection is just beneath the surface, after an ultimate sacrifice.  
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I guess I&#39;m thinking the darkly gothic &lt;i&gt;Batman&lt;/i&gt;, of all the superheros, is perhaps doing the most for a kind of old time Catholicism.  He&#39;s a role model for all of those in the pits.  He knows deep disappointment (like Pee Wee).  He is our champion and our defender, little men and women that we be, the Gothamites, so looked down upon by those show off lofty Himalayans.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/bdb2w1Yu97E&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2846890675438485207'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2846890675438485207'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/08/the-dark-knight-rises-movie-review.html' title='The Dark Knight Rises (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/bdb2w1Yu97E/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2555870983265833059</id><published>2012-07-27T10:24:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2012-07-28T01:59:41.069-07:00</updated><title type='text'>BuckyBalls:  Consumer Ban</title><content type='html'>Consumers have been banned from buying &lt;i&gt;Bucky Balls&lt;/i&gt; on the open market. &amp;nbsp;No, this does not refer to C60, the molecule, or its family, but to a toy that had made an earlier appearance under a different brand but was then marketed as &quot;Bucky Balls&quot;. &amp;nbsp;These small, powerful, spherical magnets are a subject of study in STEM, or have uses as a lab / studio supply. &amp;nbsp;STEM labs often work with controlled substances, including live animals that might kill you if let out of their cages (&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/06/more-movies-mcmenamins.html&quot;&gt;Cabin in the Woods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; type places (Joss Whedon)).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Oregon is home to some companies that make very dangerous chemicals, whereas other extremely dangerous chemicals (EDCs) are just stored here. &amp;nbsp;You&#39;ve heard of the NIMBY syndrome (&quot;not in my back yard&quot;) -- well, Oregon is &quot;someone else&#39;s back yard&quot; to a lot of people. &amp;nbsp;Externalizing waste i.e. the true costs of doing business, is a way to avoid having an ecosystem come together, i.e. it&#39;s more a wealth prevention strategy (masked in short term profits).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Instead of &quot;Oregon&quot; (named for smelt?), I should speak of Cascadia more regionally, as Hanford, a major seepage site, detritus of the Manhattan Project (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/06/fathers-day-weekend.html&quot;&gt;Ellsberg&#39;s Manhattan 2&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/05/wanderers-2010511.html&quot;&gt;has vented chem trails as well&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Vital research up close to nuke plants is a biomedical activity that only risk takers engage in, like Navy SEALs. &amp;nbsp;That tick of the Geiger counter may be your best signal to back away. &amp;nbsp;Or call it &quot;eco-tourism&quot; of as an extreme sport perhaps. &amp;nbsp;Like Mt. Everest, the study of externalized waste streams, as a field, a discipline, is riddled with the corpses of dedicated scientists. &amp;nbsp;Fukushima has contributed exponentially to the supply of recruits, many of them unwitting, feeling committed by fate.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One of the weak boundaries in STEM is between climatology, CDC style epidemiology, and EPA style &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/07/big-fix-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;studies of toxic waste&lt;/a&gt; (radiotoxins included). EDCs certainly alter the economy in a big way, as civilizations cope to prevent and/or deal with a major disaster, and/or many scattered deaths in the case of swallowed Bucky Balls (the magnets). &amp;nbsp;How does one avert one&#39;s eyes from these climatological effects and only focus on CO2 levels? &amp;nbsp;Aren&#39;t Hanford&#39;s and Johnston Atoll&#39;s chemtrails a fact of geological history? &amp;nbsp;I studied the latter when editing &lt;i&gt;Asian-Pacific Issues News&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt; (APIN).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Responsible management of controlled substances remains an elusive goal as organized crime typically competes with governments with investments in selling arms. &amp;nbsp;Escalation or continuous low grade warfare lines the pockets of various stakeholders, who also profit from the &quot;illicit&quot; (full of loopholes) trade. &amp;nbsp;The medical profession is traditionally overruled by the legal profession in this area, except in some categories. &amp;nbsp;With the right medical documents, one is entitled to STEM inventory, not unlike the governmental classification system for secret document librarians (a set of circuits sometimes short circuited, per Ellsberg and the &lt;i&gt;Pentagon Papers&lt;/i&gt; or as a result of blackmail, strategic leaks, inadvertent misplacement).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the end, it&#39;s all well and good to ban &quot;mindless consumers&quot; from various forms of access. &amp;nbsp;Of you have a clear research need or medical requirement, that puts you in a different category. &amp;nbsp;Where small magnets are concerned, other toys have them and Bucky Balls circulate aplenty in the after market (not always by that brand), one more hazardous material that could endanger others or oneself if used irresponsibly, another poison. &amp;nbsp;Mindless consumers didn&#39;t know how privileged they were, until they lost that freedom. &amp;nbsp;Mindfulness is forged in relative bondage sometimes where those &quot;bonds&quot; may be relationships, commitments, obligations.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2555870983265833059'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2555870983265833059'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/07/buckyballs-consumer-ban.html' title='BuckyBalls:  Consumer Ban'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-9142613762104067799</id><published>2012-07-25T21:57:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-07-27T09:46:47.090-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2012.7.25</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;http://holdenweb.blogspot.com/2012/07/fun-and-games-at-oscon.html&quot;&gt;Steve Holden&lt;/a&gt; and I were to present, post OSCON, about our sense of Open Source and so on. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s up with the FLOSS revolution? &amp;nbsp;Whiter teeth?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As anticipated, I had to skip the first hour. &amp;nbsp;Per Facebook from the night before, I&#39;ve been doing car trips to Union Station, connecting with Amtrak and Greyhound. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d also wanted to check in with Officer Walker at City Hall, where she&#39;s been undertaking logistics. &amp;nbsp;I shared that with the Quakers etc., Facebook Friends, in the context of updating my profile on several topics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I came into the room to find &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/02/wanderers-2007228.html&quot;&gt;John Taylor&lt;/a&gt; had joined us. &amp;nbsp;He&#39;s on a stint from Indonesia. &amp;nbsp;At age 77, he&#39;s semi-retired, looking for a landing spot, maybe in Portland, for himself and his soon to retire younger wife. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d helped John find temporary quarters while in town, after mom had offerred him Lindsey&#39;s storage studio, but I didn&#39;t think his head would survive the low rafters.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
FNB seems to be in flux again, with SE chapter not always so alone. &amp;nbsp;I sometimes get inquiries whether the Quakers might offer their kitchen again, one day a week. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;d certainly be game. but I&#39;m not clear what the routine would be. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That was something Lindsey and I did together for a year, before we went our separate ways in that namespace. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Although I still play an administrative role as an anarcho-boss, I&#39;ve been less of a fixture at Colonel Summers Park, and not just because of OSCON, Indiana.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve sketched &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/70293&quot;&gt;more FNB science fiction&lt;/a&gt; in the background.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My take on Open Source was it has become a recruiting tool in some ways. &amp;nbsp;If your company is not contributing something freely, of quality, then maybe your company has not much to offer? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mine (ours) puts a lot of courseware out there for free, plus of course &lt;i&gt;O&#39;Reilly Media&lt;/i&gt; is behind OSCON itself, the Open Source Convention. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I gave the example of Conoco-Phillips and the graphics package it maintains, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/07/python-in-control-room.html&quot;&gt;one of the topics&lt;/a&gt; at Europython a few years back.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But what what does &quot;of quality&quot; mean? &amp;nbsp;Do we recommend&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance&lt;/i&gt; at this point (&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zen_and_the_Art_of_Motorcycle_Maintenance&quot;&gt;by Pirsig&lt;/a&gt;)?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I confess I&#39;ve been saying some relatively uncharitable things &lt;a href=&quot;http://fcw.com/articles/2010/08/27/mumps-va-vista-system-roger-baker.aspx&quot;&gt;about VistA&lt;/a&gt;, the medical records system from the VA. &amp;nbsp;I had a run in with MUMPS (the M-language) earlier in my career and I just can&#39;t bring myself to think anything MUMPS has much of a half life. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I say this as someone who has actively looked at the recruiting problem (how to get more M programmers?), made proposals (on &lt;i&gt;math-thinking-l&lt;/i&gt; especially). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m not one of those who thinks that just because something is &quot;open&quot;, it is thereby &quot;of value&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some of our group adjourned from the &lt;i&gt;Pauling House&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;Pepino&#39;s&lt;/i&gt; down the street, for an outdoor eating experience. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I worked from then forward until &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/05/afsc-program-committee-meeting.html&quot;&gt;the AFSC meeting&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;We&#39;ve been meeting monthly, with a bunch of us phoning in. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;ve been hearing a lot of stories about the immigration situation.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When the French donated the Statue of Liberty, with its inscription about &quot;send us your poor, your huddled masses&quot;, what was the assumed debt? &amp;nbsp;What was owed? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Did &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/10/new-atlantis-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;the New Atlantis&lt;/a&gt; at one point promise the world to always serve as a beacon of hope? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One could say that was a part of the Telos, a promised land archetype, a Next / Other World. &amp;nbsp;A New Jerusalem. &amp;nbsp;God had led His people to less godforsaken parts, less mired in past soap operas.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://grunch.net/archives/117&quot;&gt;The USA operating system&lt;/a&gt;, now global, has a more closed feel about it, true, since Planet Earth is a ball. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
She&#39;s not a &quot;closed system&quot; however, not in the thermodynamic sense. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We (as a species) have reason to hope for a breathable gas mix for some time to come.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, I saw the stories about Greenland. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/07/condors.html&quot;&gt;Brian&lt;/a&gt; came on strong, about the 97% melt off. &amp;nbsp;But the footnotes did not escape me. &amp;nbsp;We&#39;ve been here before, in like 1889, and the ice record tells a story: &amp;nbsp;every 150 years or so. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But given how many other curves are out of rhythm, or apparently so, it&#39;s hard to interpret what we&#39;re seeing. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Climatology is properly a part of STEM, at least that much is obvious.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9142613762104067799'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9142613762104067799'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/07/wanderers-2012725.html' title='Wanderers 2012.7.25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5562488145713412487</id><published>2012-07-19T11:05:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-07-19T20:00:25.384-07:00</updated><title type='text'>OSCON Day Two</title><content type='html'>Steve and I left the car on Senate Street and Maxed it, arriving before the doors opened.&amp;nbsp; O&#39;Reilly knows attendance at an early morning plenary will be down the 2nd day, so the walls were rolled in, curtailing the space, yet still it was huge, bigger than many churches, if not cathedrals.&amp;nbsp; Yet here we were, the bazaar economy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mark Shuttleworth did the best keynote in the sense of most technical, introducing Juju and the direction Canonical has taken with their new desktop.&amp;nbsp; I went up to him during Office Hours (an Expo Hall service) and thanked him for the boost he gave to curriculum writing / programming, including mine.&amp;nbsp; The opportunity to hang out &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/04/at-summit.html&quot;&gt;with Alan Kay&lt;/a&gt;, Guido etc., in person, for &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/04/home-to-pdx.html&quot;&gt;three days in Kensington&lt;/a&gt;, was fantastic.&amp;nbsp; That was some years ago.&amp;nbsp; He again mentioned his early fascination with Smalltalk based Squeak as a trailblazer environment.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Cloud business is an evolved reiteration of the ISP business, with customers wanting more control over what&#39;s on their servers.&amp;nbsp; Juju is about porting ecosystems of connected applications between systems and designing their API interconnections using &quot;charms&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My Quakers have converged at annual session by this time.&amp;nbsp; Although &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/10/thinking-about-afsc.html&quot;&gt;I&#39;m an AFSC rep&lt;/a&gt;, I&#39;m leaving it to Eddy Crouch to run the interest group and help manage the NPYM / AFSC interface.&amp;nbsp; Getting more Quaker services into the Cloud, education-related, sounds like an interesting project.&amp;nbsp; That might just mean a bookstore, branching out into access to archives.&amp;nbsp; History, timelines, biographies, scanned minutes, records, journals... a kind of archive.org for Quakers?&amp;nbsp; New branches could start an instance this way, by customizing templates.&amp;nbsp; New classes of Friend... (in the sense of types or species)... we shall see.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m in HP&#39;s sponsored talk on its Cloud services at the moment.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;ve moved into the data center business more, following Amazon and others.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Facebook keynote was also good.&amp;nbsp; The fact that so much hardware is still closed design has led to the same basic wheels being re-invented over and over with lots of incompatible variations.&amp;nbsp; Secrecy begets duplication and meaningless resource-wasting inconsistencies, such as train tracks with different gauges.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
OpenStack on the software side has its parallel initiatives on the hardware side.&amp;nbsp; Facebook is supporting that. &amp;nbsp;Standardizations begets savings. &amp;nbsp;It&#39;s the old pendulum, between a tightly knit civilization and a more every-man-for-himself Wild West kind of place. &amp;nbsp;Oscillations occur.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5562488145713412487'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5562488145713412487'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/07/oscon-day-two.html' title='OSCON Day Two'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2789372995376662474</id><published>2012-07-14T18:16:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2012-07-15T06:17:02.265-07:00</updated><title type='text'>To Tell the Truth</title><content type='html'>Anthropologists may question whether a form of government still based in theocracy can afford the same levels of hypocrisy as an oligarchy with democratic aspirations.&amp;nbsp; Of course I&#39;m thinking of Iran and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csmonitor.com/World/Middle-East/2010/0504/NPT-101-Is-Iran-violating-the-nuclear-treaty&quot;&gt;its official line&lt;/a&gt; that it&#39;s not lying about not wanting to break the NPT, but is rather intending to enforce it (in a coalition of the willing), to the point of global divestment.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d say global divestment is an official policy of many in the Pentagon for cynical military reasons:&amp;nbsp; wars used to accomplish something, maybe we could get back to that.&amp;nbsp; I think it&#39;s more a mind over brain thing, meaning &quot;upgrades are possible&quot;, so going back to the old kind of &quot;theater&quot; may or may not be in the cards (not a given, despite Satan&#39;s fond hopes).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What swept the so-called West was &quot;real politik&quot;.&amp;nbsp; I would refer you to CFR docs and the writings of Henry Kissinger to get a stronger idea of what that means.&amp;nbsp; One might call it Machiavellianism.&amp;nbsp; The job of politicians was not to communicate truthfully, which was handed off to journalism, which could be bought; the job of politicians was to say what was necessary to win the allegiance of key constituencies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The constituents could know you were lying (open secret) as they did it themselves.&amp;nbsp; Lying was just another tense, like past perfect or future.&amp;nbsp; This was actually consistent with the linguistic turn in some ways, and Nietzsche&#39;s critique of the will to truth, of which he was justifiably suspicious (oppressive moralism wears the mantle of truth in various &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/12/team-america-world-police-movie-review_04.html&quot;&gt;clownish guises&lt;/a&gt; -- this was pre psychoanalysis lets remember).&amp;nbsp; Theologists were given handicapped parking with the intention to grandfather them out as old school.&amp;nbsp; Iran, also Israel, are anachronistic to the extent clerics, rabbis, imams, any of those, are given undue influence.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In retrospect, we might agree this attack against one brand of ideologue by another, perhaps seen as realistic in the light of scientism, was not especially likely to result in a clear win for either side.&amp;nbsp; The religious have felt on the defensive, with secularism and democratism a real check on their power.&amp;nbsp; However the religious have some ethics and disciplines that keeps them viable.&amp;nbsp; The question is to what extent hypocrisy (disconnecting self characterizations from one&#39;s actions and intent -- relates to overall credibility and authenticity) is able to fly in these circumstances.&amp;nbsp; Does one side have an edge or &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/07/psy-war-whos-losing.html&quot;&gt;stand to lose more&lt;/a&gt; if mouthing phony shibboleths?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The question is this:&amp;nbsp; if Iran is theoretically a theocratic state and is essentially telling the truth about its strategy, then when does it morph into a global champion of the NPT against defiant rogue states such as Colorado and other states allowing nuke weapons in storage, or in launch position, in their homelands?&amp;nbsp; Or have these states been colonized?&amp;nbsp; Do they really have much say?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Iranian weapons inspectors, somewhat inspired by Scott Ritter and other &quot;just the facts mam&quot; intelligence analysts, enlist for duty both at home and overseas, under the auspices of the IAEA and others, ready for duty in Australia, Chernobyl, whatever Restricted Zones of possible weapons contamination, sometimes amidst pristine natural beauty (a subject of ecotourism, other extreme tourism genres).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The teams are diverse, multi-ethnic, with some recruits &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/03/stewart-brand-at-reed-college.html&quot;&gt;from Reed College&lt;/a&gt; in Portland.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A career as an supranational pro-Earthian warrior is rewarding in itself.&amp;nbsp; Foil the Dr. Evil types.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The question facing Pakistan is whether to join Iran as another Muslim state with a Countdown to Zero agenda.&amp;nbsp; India has been asking for admission into the nuclear club under the terms of the NPT without making divestment of nuclear weapons its priority, turning away from any course Gandhi would have advocated.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/07/einstein-omsi.html&quot;&gt;Einstein&lt;/a&gt; would likewise have been for an anti-nuke weapons Israel.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We might see India&#39;s deterioration into having nuke weapons as evidence of the impotence in India&#39;s engineering caste and/or the relative moral immaturity of Hinduism. If Pakistan flips the switch, ala South Africa, and joins Iran in its leadership role, the contrast with the Islamic states will only be heightened.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Islam is about ridding the world of nuclear weapons.&quot;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/jihad.html&quot;&gt;I would agree&lt;/a&gt; with that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A youthful more hopeful movement is showing signs of wanting to go this route, as Occupy / Arab Spring spreads a Countdown to Zero message.&amp;nbsp; Reversing a lot of the eco-damage committed in the 1900s looks like ethical work, the work of healing.&amp;nbsp; The need for pro-Earthians is medical, as much as religious.&amp;nbsp; Science and engineering &lt;a href=&quot;http://4dsolutions.net/mycartoons/cartoon2.html&quot;&gt;shake hands&lt;/a&gt;, are on the same page.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Abbreviations:&lt;br /&gt;
NPT:&amp;nbsp; Non-proliferation Treaty&lt;br /&gt;
CFR:&amp;nbsp; Council on Foreign Relations &lt;br /&gt;
IAEA:&amp;nbsp; International Atomic Energy Agency</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2789372995376662474'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2789372995376662474'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/07/to-tell-truth.html' title='To Tell the Truth'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-277399884254129908</id><published>2012-07-12T22:59:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-07-13T19:27:09.757-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Condors</title><content type='html'>I was on duty chauffeuring, drinking coffee at the base of the tram.&amp;nbsp; A guy zoomed up in his wheel chair.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Is that a computer?&quot; he asked, in child-like wonder.&amp;nbsp; Hadn&#39;t seen an Air before. I emphasized it was light weight (unlike its owner).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then who should walk in to the scene but Brian Sharp, one of our Wanderers, but often remote, in central Oregon, and mostly contacting by list (Yahoo group).&amp;nbsp; We talked for awhile about this and that, then it was off to Providence, from OHSU.&amp;nbsp; Back to OHSU later.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Brian followed &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/03/social-security-for-condors.html&quot;&gt;pilot projects&lt;/a&gt; to reintroduce the condors to North America.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;d had a life here in Oregon, per records, but have long since died out.&amp;nbsp; Brian does not see a way to bring them back in our particular era; the problems are insoluble at the moment.&amp;nbsp; But he has been working on a book about what it used to be like, and why they once thrived here.&amp;nbsp; That book is due out soon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Why they can&#39;t survive now traces mainly to man-made substances in the environment that subvert their lifestyle.&amp;nbsp; Lead shot in animal carcasses proves toxic over time, but also the pabulum they regurgitate to infants:&amp;nbsp; these have more plastics in them, fragments of non-biodegradable things.&amp;nbsp; These tend to clog up digestive systems.&amp;nbsp; Not enough survive to make it a viable community.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Brian was recently back from a San Diego championship tournament wherein his soccer team was best in the over-64 class. He&#39;s run the circumference of planet Earth three times if you add up his frequent player soccer miles.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/277399884254129908'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/277399884254129908'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/07/condors.html' title='Condors'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3693884249302857490</id><published>2012-07-12T08:52:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2012-07-12T09:32:23.701-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Another Goodbye</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4835450730/&quot; title=&quot;Titty by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Titty&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;http://farm5.staticflickr.com/4126/4835450730_1df2d81a20.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lindsey brought her from Savannah, where she&#39;d bonded with this already mature animal.  Titty lived in the Blue House as an indoor cat, after &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/04/waning-moon.html&quot;&gt;Moon Kitty&lt;/a&gt; died.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;She was gradually transitioned to an outdoor lifestyle, which she seemed to enjoy for the most part, after learning to defend her turf, although an altercation with some other animal was a likely cause of death eventually, the wound going undetected for too long (she did not exhibit behaviors of someone in pain).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
She lived a full lifespan for an outdoor cat. She was&amp;nbsp;occasionally&amp;nbsp;recruited for indoor service during the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/6605035513/in/photostream&quot;&gt;Great Rat War of 2011&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;She had access to the basement studio through a tiny window during colder months.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
She will be missed.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thank you to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/6497556595/in/photostream&quot;&gt;Joe Snyder&lt;/a&gt; for a veterinarian&#39;s advice, and to&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Pet Samaritan&lt;/i&gt; for the 9th hour consultation, where Lindsey and I took her yesterday on short notice.  She died peacefully amidst expressions of affection.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3693884249302857490'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3693884249302857490'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/07/another-goodbye.html' title='Another Goodbye'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8959753958617797583</id><published>2012-07-04T11:51:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-07T06:29:29.960-07:00</updated><title type='text'>The Big Fix (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7538046806/&quot; title=&quot;Avatar Meetup by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Avatar Meetup&quot; src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8016/7538046806_7821068333.jpg&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This movie makes the case that BP has specialized in &quot;bad boy&quot; high risk game playing and has been rewarded in the past for recklessness.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The consequences of a cavalier and above-the-laws-of-nature psyche are still incalculable, but in the meantime we get some good X-ray snapshots of how the appetite for oil and its attendant sums of petrodollars, can deprive us of trillions of dollars worth of ecosystem assets, shortening many lives, human as well as nonhuman.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;s somewhat a repeat of the war of 1812 as the UK-Pentagon axis plunders and rapes North America, while the patriots drive their hippie (sometimes biodiesel) buses around, taking inventory of the devastation. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Great Britain has conquered what used to be considered more French territory.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Orlando is an outpost for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.baesystems.com/home&quot;&gt;British Aerospace&lt;/a&gt; and Guantanamo is where Her Majesty keeps the puppet US fall guys (the patsies) cynically undermining their own government (on paper not a monarchy). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/02/lame-analysis.html&quot;&gt;Gitmo&lt;/a&gt; (which the movie does not mention) is a potent weapon against American democracy on both continents, a violation of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monroe_Doctrine&quot;&gt;Monroe Doctrine&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; But the BP-Pentagon has no way of shedding &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/09/lampoon-harpoon.html&quot;&gt;its imperialist reflexes&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; That programming runs deep.&amp;nbsp; Puppets get used to their assigned roles.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The movie considers Huey &quot;The Kingfish&quot; Long as inspirational to these coastal peoples, colonized by an empire yet wanting to stay non-violent and democratic about it (having already won the Revolution).&amp;nbsp; The filmmakers have family ties to the coastal peoples themselves, although their accents are not as colorful as some of those interviewed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The movie does a nice job of tying the story &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/03/argo-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;back to Iran&lt;/a&gt; nearer the beginning, and to Saudi Arabia.&amp;nbsp; The BP-Pentagon is ravenous for more fuel, if only to carry-out its fuel-happy plans to get more fuel.&amp;nbsp; Flying jets like that is great fun, especially on the 4th of July, with colored contrails.&amp;nbsp; If some people get ill as a result, just make them the enemy -- like Louisiana is now infested with insurgent ecoterrorists (many former fishermen) which BP will fund TV and universities to help us demonize as dirty oil-covered hippies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Greg Palast is funny.&amp;nbsp; Lindsey cracked up at the &quot;Frankenstein machine&quot; remark, about how they just churn out another CEO when the last one has absorbed enough punishment in exchange for a compensation package. Other talking heads stake their reputations in various ways, carving out their positions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
From an emailed review:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
The movie is ambitious in that a wife-husband team try to take in a grand sweep of history view.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They point out various semi-obvious things, such as the fact that the military machine runs on BP etc., so one can&#39;t expect much protection from the more violence-prone based in DC, UK etc.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The dispersant used to make the oil sink to the bottom is having consequences that are still being studied. &amp;nbsp;Big dead zones in the Gulf. &amp;nbsp;Many unknowns.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lots of people sick from all the spraying (the atmosphere has changed).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s somewhat amazing is how it&#39;s up to amateur non-scientist filmmakers to bring just about any of this to light, as the monied media have little interest in investigative journalism anymore.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
There&#39;s a kind of born-yesterday innocence to the viewpoint, as if &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/09/investigating-how-things-work.html&quot;&gt;corruption&lt;/a&gt;&quot; were only just now being revealed.  We need a better word for the fact that world history does not always unfold according to our imagined ideals.  Of course it&#39;s a struggle to resist colonization and enslavement by one&#39;s fellow humans.  We have a pattern of forcing one another to work against our own best interests.  The right and freedom to pursue happiness?  Really? Even for &quot;little people&quot;? What &lt;i&gt;will&lt;/i&gt; they think of next?&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8959753958617797583'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8959753958617797583'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/07/big-fix-movie-review.html' title='The Big Fix (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-806572987194393841</id><published>2012-06-30T12:03:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2012-06-30T22:33:56.171-07:00</updated><title type='text'>What was est?</title><content type='html'>What was &lt;i&gt;est&lt;/i&gt;?&amp;nbsp; This came up at a lunch meeting the other day, in that two of us had seen &lt;i&gt;Transformation:&amp;nbsp; The Life and Legacy of Werner Erhard&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; You can watch it for free &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hulu.com/watch/151134&quot;&gt;on Hulu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In a nutshell, Erhard understood that our sense of integrity as human beings is very bound up in our need to be right about stuff.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s just obvious grammatically (in Wittgenstein&#39;s sense).&amp;nbsp; Who wants to believe a lot of garbage and have wrong ideas about everything?&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s not cool.&amp;nbsp; We want to be suave, smooth, and knowing.&amp;nbsp; Or our need to be right takes other forms.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;d like to have the most appropriate responses to others in need.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not a &quot;bad thing&quot; to wish for integrity and to defend that one has it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Understanding that, the &lt;i&gt;est&lt;/i&gt; Training provided an environment that challenged one to become unstuck, where decisions and beliefs had actually led one astray.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s hard to look at, let alone admit, but the genius was having someone uniformly and in blanket fashion attack all belief systems at a metaphysical level.&amp;nbsp; Why do you suppose how you feel about something has anything to do with how things really are?&amp;nbsp; Why do you suppose your beliefs about things have anything to do with reality?&amp;nbsp; The trainer gives off a kind of extreme skepticism that anyone in the room really has a grip.&amp;nbsp; It takes a strong character to make hundreds of people wrong, but if you can pull it off in the right spirit (heh), you give even the most self-confident and self-secure an occasion to really question.&amp;nbsp; Why not?&amp;nbsp; Everyone else is, and you&#39;re not being singled out.&amp;nbsp; Everyone gets pretty much the same treatment.&amp;nbsp; The trainer makes everyone wrong.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then towards the end of the training, the trainer (a different person that weekend anyway) switches sides, metaphysically speaking, and makes you right.&amp;nbsp; Now that you&#39;ve had a chance to take a look, to make choices, you get to be responsible for what you&#39;ve decided to keep, to hold onto.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s something you&#39;ve chosen now, more than something you&#39;ve inherited or absorbed unexamined.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Of course in two weekends it would be impossible to look at every belief, assumption, character trait in that light, so it&#39;s more a matter of internalizing the process and contacting one&#39;s trainer within, a strong mentor or coach (in archetype) who is willing for you to let go of beliefs and attitudes that no longer serve you or add to the quality of your life or to that of the people around you.&amp;nbsp; This doesn&#39;t mean you&#39;ve been defanged or rendered less dangerous.&amp;nbsp; On the contrary, when you see yourself as freely choosing your racket / act / role in the world, you may be willing to amp it up, because you sense it&#39;s making a positive difference.&amp;nbsp; Certainly Werner&#39;s crew was behaving that way and I didn&#39;t blame them.&amp;nbsp; They were on to something.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/806572987194393841'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/806572987194393841'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/06/what-was-est.html' title='What was est?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1485873141851937445</id><published>2012-06-26T23:47:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-06-27T00:17:21.038-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Nature Boy</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/RSQyzit5OjA&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: celine dion ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/CzX0-05KHG4&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: afro blue jazz choir ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/iXprs8-U5nA&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: kurt elling ::&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1485873141851937445'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1485873141851937445'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/06/nature-boy.html' title='Nature Boy'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/RSQyzit5OjA/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5128817139881494838</id><published>2012-06-22T22:41:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2012-06-24T14:13:10.687-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Another OMSI Pub</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7434991730/&quot; title=&quot;OMSI Science Pub by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;OMSI Science Pub&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7276/7434991730_9685df05da.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I joined the OMSI Science Pub impromptu yesterday, knowing nothing 
about what it would be.&amp;nbsp; I grabbed a seat, saving the one next to me, 
and was going to Facebook &quot;come &#39;n get it&quot; but then thought to call 
Glenn and text Trevor.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lew Scholl has been to these before and I&#39;d 
texted him too.&amp;nbsp; As it turned out, Trevor could join me and our walking 
and meeting afterward was productive as usual.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This turned out to be one of two OMSI Science Pubs going on.&amp;nbsp; The subject was &lt;a href=&quot;http://biomimicry.net/&quot;&gt;Biomimicry&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The speaker, Richard Louv, said he didn&#39;t do slides, or had done, but proved inept at using them.&amp;nbsp; &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/04/roller-coaster-at-reed.html&quot;&gt;Not HTT material&lt;/a&gt;&quot; I could hear the generals thinking (big emphasis on PowerPoint in that program) -- more like a late model boy scout.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They used to make fun of the fat kid at camp, and how everything was so much harder on the obstacle course. &amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;Now we&#39;re all that fat kid (obesity&amp;nbsp;rates where front and center in the OMSI slides), so we&#39;ve toned it down quite a bit, so as not to offend ourselves. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Teasing is the most politically incorrect thing you can do almost, especially where there might be hurt feelings involved. Unless you&#39;re trying to make it funny. &amp;nbsp;There&#39;s some tough screening if so.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Richard Louv sings a lot of the same spirituals we do around Portland, he was clear about that.&amp;nbsp; He hadn&#39;t lectured in quite this setting before:&amp;nbsp; so much booze (the event is held in a brew pub).&amp;nbsp; Being not from around here, he&#39;s maybe not quite so relaxed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;What &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; nature?&quot; is actually a good question, as to think vast cities are not natural is to be a little bit crazy, I have to say.&amp;nbsp; But that&#39;s OK.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Richard sounded quite apologetic for his profession&#39;s being so invested in pessimism and despair sometimes.&amp;nbsp; He was speaking of journalism.&amp;nbsp; The message he wanted to deliver was there&#39;s still hope -- something along those lines.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5128817139881494838'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5128817139881494838'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/06/another-omsi-pub.html' title='Another OMSI Pub'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5625710895447527692</id><published>2012-06-19T09:14:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2012-06-19T10:29:02.368-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Looking Ahead</title><content type='html'>I just advised Koski to attend &lt;i&gt;Bridges&lt;/i&gt;, as he was already leaning, and to get to &lt;a href=&quot;http://synergeticscollaborative.org/snec.announce.event.2012.09.html&quot;&gt;the SNEC event&lt;/a&gt; about looking back at Black Mountain College, where &lt;a href=&quot;http://grunch.net/snelson/&quot;&gt;Ken Snelson&lt;/a&gt; and a lot of the Catlin Gabel people went to school. &amp;nbsp;Asheville is near Hendersonville where I used to camp out in a trailer with the maternal gypsy grandparent (gypsy more in lifestyle then per &quot;some secret&quot; gene only gypsies know about). &amp;nbsp;I could potentially get there. &amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Gathering for Gardener&lt;/i&gt; is another one I always plan to attend. &amp;nbsp;Had I gone the first year I was invited, I could have met him. &amp;nbsp;Now I&#39;m like &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/05/afsc-program-committee-meeting.html&quot;&gt;Muhammad Ali&lt;/a&gt; felt about Ho Chi Minh: &quot;if only I&#39;d gone earlier, we could have met.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I mention Ho because I&#39;ve again be &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=7838559&quot;&gt;revisiting that historical period&lt;/a&gt;, rereading about &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/history-is-surreal.html&quot;&gt;Nixon&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; secret bombings and the campaign against the dikes. &amp;nbsp;The idea that lying in the short term would not catch up with one was apparently accepted among the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/07/slowing-down.html&quot;&gt;&quot;real politik&quot; crowd&lt;/a&gt; of the day, which is all narrated from a back stage point of view these days in that we see everything. &amp;nbsp;Here&#39;s Jane Fonda on her way &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/10/hotel-oregon.html&quot;&gt;into Hanoi&lt;/a&gt;, looking out the airplane window. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What is it she sees? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7385102560/in/photostream&quot;&gt;I couldn&#39;t put it down&lt;/a&gt; and it was only like $6 one of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/06/our-week-in-indy.html&quot;&gt;Indiana&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; few well stocked bookstores. I gratefully acquired it and went on reading to the end. &amp;nbsp;The bottom line is she&#39;s got a brave heart and her relationships with the young men of her generation helped keep some &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/12/american-dad-plot-synopsis.html&quot;&gt;cultural cohesion&lt;/a&gt; going, whereas the Dr. Strangelovey types, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/03/stress-tests.html&quot;&gt;Blue Meanies&lt;/a&gt; (many of them DC-based) had simply gone off the deep end and lost touch with humanity. &amp;nbsp;They&#39;d been abducted in a bad way you might say, whereas our abductees generally benefit (insider joke).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The apartment on Chavez is starting to see more action, as the former chairman of Pythonia had intended. &amp;nbsp;Michelle has organized one of those &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/09/my-character.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;PyLadies&lt;/i&gt; events&lt;/a&gt; where men are allowed by invitation as guests, but don&#39;t get to run the show or even collude to do so. &amp;nbsp;Sometimes women feel undermined by men, who compare notes behind their backs in mysterious ways, but then that feeling is mutual. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Coming to a balance within oneself is the age old wisdom on this one. &amp;nbsp;If you&#39;re up to something positive, then there&#39;s no real guilt in being &quot;caught&quot; in the act. &amp;nbsp;It&#39;s like when Santa Claus is tip toeing around the tree and the lights go on. &amp;nbsp;&quot;Hey, just doing my job, gotta run!&quot;. &amp;nbsp;Who&#39;d wanna get in his way? &amp;nbsp;Psychiatrists, sure, but who else? &amp;nbsp;Anyway, the trainer will pitch her tent at Steve&#39;s, who is off in Spain or somewhere. &amp;nbsp;He doesn&#39;t like to see perfectly good resources going to waste. &amp;nbsp;That&#39;s an engineer for ya. &amp;nbsp;We multitask for a living.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I found out about &lt;i&gt;Catlin Gabel&lt;/i&gt;&#39;s ties to &lt;i&gt;Black Mountain&lt;/i&gt; when I was extended an invitation to one of their Thanksgiving gatherings at the Oregon coast many years ago. &amp;nbsp;I met some dear people and later went with more family, namely Dawn and Alexia (Tara was not born yet). &amp;nbsp;I was later to enjoy more correspondence and visits with Kenneth Snelson himself, with whom I associate that college. &amp;nbsp;I forget when &lt;i&gt;Thinking Out Loud&lt;/i&gt; came out on public television, but sometime after these Thanksgivings. &amp;nbsp;Lots of &lt;i&gt;Black Mountain&lt;/i&gt; in there too, including interviews with graduates.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My mom tried to switch me to &lt;i&gt;Catlin&lt;/i&gt; when I was little. &amp;nbsp;She was freaking out about New Math which just seemed too off the rails (not what she remembered from math class). &amp;nbsp;They must have had a different site back then, as I remember a large stone staircase (I went with her). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This was prior to our exodus from the US entirely and my transplantation into the British education system, in the context of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/06/machine-world.html&quot;&gt;Rome, Italy&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;New Math wasn&#39;t really happening there either. &amp;nbsp;Rome was a lot about geometry though. &amp;nbsp;Those geeky Greeks had really been into it, and the Romans weren&#39;t half-bad engineers. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d climb the dome of &lt;i&gt;St. Peter&#39;s&lt;/i&gt; to the copula with my friends, getting a sense the architecture. &amp;nbsp;I could see where a geodesic of whatever class would have its advantages. &amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Black Mountain&lt;/i&gt; was where Bucky drew enough strength to come up with working prototypes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://grunch.net/synergetics/domes/domehist.html&quot;&gt;Walter Bauersfled&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/02/octet-truss.html&quot;&gt;Alexander Graham Bell&lt;/a&gt; are sometimes cited for having dug deeply in the same soil that Fuller did later. &amp;nbsp;That&#39;s true, they did. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Fuller School as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/02/jihad.html&quot;&gt;noospheric&lt;/a&gt; (and biospheric) story wherein great minds think alike thanks to some zeitgeist or Holy Spirit (the term used in Synergetics) -- which doesn&#39;t mean you can&#39;t have competing models and/or complementary approaches. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bairdtelevision.com/&quot;&gt;Logie Baird TV&lt;/a&gt; was not the same a &lt;a href=&quot;http://philotfarnsworth.com/&quot;&gt;Philo Fransworth TV&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Betamax is not Blueray.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m still connecting some dots with &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/06/touring-earlham-college.html&quot;&gt;Earlham College&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; as well. &amp;nbsp;Middle America (so-called by some) is ripe for more bizmo fleets in my estimation. &amp;nbsp;These need not be emergency vehicles in a big hurry to get anywhere fast. &amp;nbsp;Driving at speed limit is fast enough. &amp;nbsp;Bizmos need not be rushed, are more like gypsy caravans, on the move but not under the lash of some harsh taskmaster. &amp;nbsp;More like Quakers in some ways (unprogrammed).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5625710895447527692'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5625710895447527692'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/06/looking-ahead.html' title='Looking Ahead'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5126864111046964734</id><published>2012-06-17T19:46:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2012-06-17T19:48:36.501-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Gay Pride</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7390424802/&quot; title=&quot;Gay Pride by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Gay Pride&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7214/7390424802_33d61dd914.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: Melody &amp;amp; Lindsey ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5126864111046964734'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5126864111046964734'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/06/gay-pride.html' title='Gay Pride'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4551904264840373862</id><published>2012-06-06T23:44:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2012-06-06T23:44:58.662-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Commencement 2012</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe align=&quot;middle&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/slideShow/index.gne?set_id=72157630063733172&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: Cleveland High School Commencement Ceremony, 2012 ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4551904264840373862'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4551904264840373862'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/06/commencement-2012.html' title='Commencement 2012'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1296643976645852910</id><published>2012-05-28T20:45:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2012-05-30T10:53:21.879-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Memorial Day</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7291741028/&quot; title=&quot;Meliptus in May by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Meliptus in May&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7085/7291741028_28f86c6e77.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: meliptus ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Memorial Day was a lot about community, thinking about our shared lot as humans.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At my lunch meeting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nohos.com/&quot;&gt;at &lt;i&gt;Noho&#39;s&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Clinton &amp;amp; SE 26th) the conversation turned to solitary confinement and the damage that does to people.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/05/loneliness.html&quot;&gt;Our last ISEPP speaker&lt;/a&gt; had mentioned wanting to learn more about what&#39;s up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/11/city-as-campus.html&quot;&gt;Colorado&lt;/a&gt;, where the percentage of prisoners in solitary is relatively high.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yet our brains are built to help with collaboration.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re great at being synergetic, given half a chance.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Meliptus&lt;/i&gt; is river-worthy again, after months out of commission.&amp;nbsp; We had a vet with us on that leg, and a conscientious objector, best of friends.&amp;nbsp; Stopped by the gas dock.&amp;nbsp; Watched some workers pull up a lost anchor.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I got back in time for dinner with Carol, Alexia and Tara at &lt;i&gt;Thanh Thao&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The service and food were excellent as usual.&amp;nbsp; We also like &lt;i&gt;Fujin&lt;/i&gt;, further west on Hawthorne.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Trevor later filled me in on the upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/waxpancake/xoxo-festival&quot;&gt;Xoxo event&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yale_Union_Laundry_Building&quot;&gt;Yale Union Laundry Building&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; He also showed me how to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tonido.com/&quot;&gt;Tonido WebShare&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The tool set is evolving quickly.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We must not have a lot of time left to dilly dally in faux stupidity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7291745696/&quot; title=&quot;Dinner Menu by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Dinner Menu&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7075/7291745696_90290bc0c8_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1296643976645852910'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1296643976645852910'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/05/memorial-day.html' title='Memorial Day'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5464209839767298029</id><published>2012-05-22T00:34:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2012-05-22T12:45:05.813-07:00</updated><title type='text'>More Meetings</title><content type='html'>I snored in Meeting on Sunday. &amp;nbsp;Embarrassing when that happens. &amp;nbsp;Pam yanked me back to consciousness.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d bicycled over around 8:15 AM, having chauffeured an MVP to the airport again (routine comings and goings).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, that was Steve, former PSF chairman. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/6830334728/&quot;&gt;Michelle&lt;/a&gt; was over the night before, helping &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.yahoo.com/open-django-central-brings-chicago-open-source-developers-120301828.html&quot;&gt;brainstorm about OpenDjango&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;She thanked me again for nominating her to the PSF and said she&#39;d read the thread about it in the members only archives. &amp;nbsp;Michelle and her husband are both skilled webbies, though in different ways.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This was the day of Portland&#39;s half marathon and many streets in the vicinity were blocked. &amp;nbsp;People came late (they do anyway -- Worship and Ministry is working on it, perennially).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hulu.com/watch/151134/transformation-the-life-and-legacy-of-werner-erhard&quot;&gt;At &lt;i&gt;est&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; if we weren&#39;t on time we got confronted and asked to look into our lives. &amp;nbsp;People were wanting to be called on stuff, to be confronted. &amp;nbsp;Some people have jobs where most the feedback gets suppressed -- especially bad around dictators and emperors, which may be why they get so dorky so fast, once ensconced.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Don&#39;t let them crown you, is good advice. &amp;nbsp;They&#39;re just abdicating their responsibilities and making you a convenient scapegoat.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Partly why I bicycled over was to participate in Sunday Morning Adult Discussion (SMAD), an institution for Multnomah Meeting going back many years. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We used to read entire books, such as &lt;i&gt;Perennial Philosophy&lt;/i&gt; by Aldous Huxley, but we&#39;re &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/09/friendly-discussion.html&quot;&gt;more free wheeling&lt;/a&gt; today. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Denny was through, from Shang Hai. &amp;nbsp;He gave me a cap with Shang Hai in English and Chinese. &amp;nbsp;This was the day Multnomah Meeting was to approve his membership, our clearness committee having recommended same to last month&#39;s meeting.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Today I had lunch with Mr. Aris, and dinner with Ms. Brenholtz and Ms. Urner.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol joins us in less than 24 hours, coming from St. Louis, by way of Chicago. &amp;nbsp;Her boxes have arrived from LA.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5464209839767298029'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5464209839767298029'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/05/more-meetings.html' title='More Meetings'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6308672161601862875</id><published>2012-05-11T22:25:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2014-03-14T00:08:49.178-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Staff Meeting 2012</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;375&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;flashvars&quot; value=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157629644242566%2Fshow%2Fwith%2F7184984106%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157629644242566%2Fwith%2F7184984106%2F&amp;set_id=72157629644242566&amp;jump_to=7184984106&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=140556&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;embed type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; src=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=140556&quot; allowFullScreen=&quot;true&quot; flashvars=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157629644242566%2Fshow%2Fwith%2F7184984106%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157629644242566%2Fwith%2F7184984106%2F&amp;set_id=72157629644242566&amp;jump_to=7184984106&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some long time readers of this blog know that I spend a lot of my time connecting to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/06/back-office.html&quot;&gt;a small server farm in Illinois&lt;/a&gt;, where I plow with my &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/10/at-wherecamppdx.html&quot;&gt;OST tractor&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, planting seeds, sewing, tending, reaping. &amp;nbsp;A job.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This used to be NetMath, connected to the University of Illinois, than acquired and moved to Sebastopol. Our leading lights are the Grays. &amp;nbsp;The staff is spread out. &amp;nbsp;Sometimes we send &quot;OST moles&quot; to conferences, recruiting students and faculty.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We hang out on Skype and have a faculty lounge on Facebook for round the water cooler conversations. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/02/make-mathematics.html&quot;&gt;When we get together&lt;/a&gt;, we do Show &amp;amp; Tell. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Bruce shared limericks and sang the blues for the Grays&#39; dog, Wilson, who recently died. &amp;nbsp;KB1 shared about her food van / bizmo, for sale on eBay. &amp;nbsp;KB2 shared about her boat slip, currently sublet while she works on the boat angle. &amp;nbsp;Steve showed slides from Brazil. &amp;nbsp;I shared my opening slides &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/10/occupy-portland-event.html&quot;&gt;from &lt;i&gt;Occupy Portland&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, celebrating FNB&#39;s central role. &amp;nbsp;Lorri mocked the genre with her &quot;favorite candle&quot; presentation.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mostly we do a lot of planning, comparing notes, future visioning. &amp;nbsp;That&#39;s what lots of companies do, including other schools. &amp;nbsp;Ours uses quite a bit of technology, in order to provide students with a learning experience. &amp;nbsp;The old idea of a &quot;correspondence school&quot; comes to mind, with the Internet making everything run faster.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Trish remarked on my Nirel-brand cuffka, a standard part of my costume these days. &amp;nbsp;She&#39;s a performer and shared a clip of one of her roles in &lt;i&gt;Guys &amp;amp; Dolls&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some of our crew are avid players of &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Settlers_of_Catan&quot;&gt;Settlers of Catan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. &amp;nbsp;I studied the rules for this language game, but am doubtful I would prove victorious against such serious players. &amp;nbsp;Debra won her round though, and she had not played before.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6308672161601862875'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6308672161601862875'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/05/staff-meeting-2012.html' title='Staff Meeting 2012'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2209020508233403924</id><published>2012-05-03T22:04:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-05-03T23:29:24.318-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Ending Hunger</title><content type='html'>More different kinds of commercial was what the Hunger Project was about. &amp;nbsp;We&#39;re conditioned to respond within a sphere of &lt;a href=&quot;http://grunch.net/archives/38&quot;&gt;familiar insignia&lt;/a&gt;, from stadiums to airport concourses, but where is the brand about ending hunger? &amp;nbsp;Are the big religions really leading that charge effectively? &amp;nbsp;Governments?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Enter &lt;i&gt;Food Not Bombs&lt;/i&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Stop the waste. &amp;nbsp;Close the loops.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The FNB event near Oaks Park was not any of my doing. &amp;nbsp;Lindsey checked it out and I&#39;m not begrudging anyone&#39;s participation, just trying to put limits on what Blue House gets credit for. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;ve got my curriculum writing, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/04/gotta-have-coffee.html&quot;&gt;Lindsey her music&lt;/a&gt;, everyone else has moved digs, except of course family members, soon to increase in number. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol is involved in many a global network, including WILPF&#39;s, which have proudly included Ava Helen Pauling among others. &amp;nbsp;Linus Pauling is a local hero, a symbol of so much that is best about people. &amp;nbsp;Carol has been bearing a pretty bright torch. &amp;nbsp;I look forward to hearing more about what &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/09/wanderers-200892.html&quot;&gt;Linda Richards&lt;/a&gt; has been up to. &amp;nbsp;Trevor&#39;s book on &lt;i&gt;Portland Memorials&lt;/i&gt; has the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.woh.pdx.edu/&quot;&gt;Walk of the Heroines&lt;/a&gt; at PSU, where mom&#39;s name is memorialized, with those of others she knew.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Death from malnourishment: &amp;nbsp;a broad spectrum of conditions, including simply a lack of good food, but not limited to that. &amp;nbsp;Eating to much of the wrong thing will take their toll. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You may not know how to shop and live affordably, adding unwanted pounds simply for lack of easy-to-acquire skills, but who has the time. &amp;nbsp;You have your own treadmill. &amp;nbsp;&quot;Variations in routine&quot; sound like a cake walk when you&#39;re not stuck in a rut.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In our &lt;a href=&quot;http://oreillyschool.com/&quot;&gt;distance education model&lt;/a&gt;, you can start and stop at will, with no metronome set by some meeting of &quot;classes&quot;. &amp;nbsp;The concept of &quot;attendance&quot; is muted. &amp;nbsp;We inherit from the correspondence schools, but in some sense that&#39;s just a mixin parent class, not our root. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As a metaphor for life we each &quot;build a portfolio&quot; and to some extent authentication is of concern i.e. is this really your own work? &amp;nbsp;The question has to do with expected results, along with unchallenged claims. &amp;nbsp;&quot;Any&amp;nbsp;liens&amp;nbsp;on the property?&quot; the lawyers might ask? &amp;nbsp;Even easements can be a problem.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As Chris, one of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/06/wanderers-summer-retreat.html&quot;&gt;our newer Wanderers&lt;/a&gt; points out, so-called successful people are not really &quot;self made&quot; so much as produced by others. &amp;nbsp;This jibes with my own experience of co-dependent origination, the core dharma of many a Buddhist sutra. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You&#39;ll have had your champions and been a champion for others. &amp;nbsp;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/04/our-hero-mr-ed.html&quot;&gt;Homer Davenport&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; case, the Arabian horses brought him reflected glory, a two way street. &amp;nbsp;Your champions aren&#39;t always humans.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
David Koski, myself, George Hart, other members of the Poly list (which I am not on), are all registering respect and positive sentiments towards the late &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mariomarin-poliedros.com/&quot;&gt;Mario Marin&lt;/a&gt;, a pioneering artist.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: rgba(255, 255, 255, 0.917969); color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;It is with sadness that I also join all other members of our polyhedral list on the death of Mario. &amp;nbsp;He certainly will be remembered for his profound contributions to the lore and lure of polyhedral creations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
writes &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/06/visiting-geometer-priest.html&quot;&gt;Magnus Wenninger&lt;/a&gt;, another great in that ballpark.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2209020508233403924'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2209020508233403924'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/05/ending-hunger.html' title='Ending Hunger'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5073234817706392364</id><published>2012-04-28T15:19:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-04-29T10:35:41.112-07:00</updated><title type='text'>World Affairs / Afghanistan</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/6976773740/&quot; title=&quot;Ministry Speaker by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ministry Speaker&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7253/6976773740_2ee388542b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I don&#39;t think I&#39;ve ever gone to the Schnitzer on two &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/04/science-religion.html&quot;&gt;consecutive nights&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m living the life of the high society deacon, pillar of my social club, balding, cigar smoking.&amp;nbsp; OK, not quite the right characterization, but around the theater, I can feel my identify field fluctuating, as other guys play me, or me them or whatever.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d hustled over from the salad bar at Safeway, enjoying the excuse to wolf food, alone, though I missed finding croutons.&amp;nbsp; I dropped the plastic container in torture taxi, having been trained to not treat plastic as an infinitely cheap waste product, contrary to cultural conditioning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks to PSU for the heads up and for snagging me a general seating ticket.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I got in fairly close on the far left.&amp;nbsp; The ushers didn&#39;t harass me about the no-flash pix -- I&#39;m somewhat in the habit from ISEPP events, where I&#39;m nominally on the video team (and the board), sometimes back stage. &amp;nbsp;World Affairs Council has different rules.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sima Samar is my contemporary and she remembers calmer more intelligent days, as I do.&amp;nbsp; My family hopped a bus in Peshawar that time, not especially iron clad or anything, and had an enjoyable ride to Kabul, not in fear for our lives, enjoying the famous Khyber Pass for its scenery and history.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/09/arabs-gone-wild.html&quot;&gt;Glenn Baker&lt;/a&gt; had enjoyed living around here too, in Islamabad, occasionally getting to Kabul for inter-school sporting events.&amp;nbsp; Next, our family hopped an Aeroflot in Kabul and flew to Tashkent, for friendly time with the Borats or whomever, on to Moscow etc.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Looking back, the 1970s were probably a high point in &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/08/internationalization.html&quot;&gt;civilization&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Not long before, I&#39;d worked with Palestinians in Ramallah helping with a swimming pool construction project.&amp;nbsp; Our local crew had explosives, with state authorities not being that worried.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
No wall or anything that stupid yet.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/01/memorable-meetups.html&quot;&gt;Bobby Fischer&lt;/a&gt; was at the peak of his career, at the apogee of the Cold War (at its least idiotic).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The long slow &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/04/idiocracy-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;slide into Idiocracy&lt;/a&gt; was yet to begin, with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/09/note-to-journalist.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Fox News&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; leading the charge.&amp;nbsp; Leave it to Australians to dumb it all down.&amp;nbsp; Talk about cultural imperialism.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, Sima is spearheading a long, slow (fast in geological time) slog by the XX half of the species to cut itself a better deal.&amp;nbsp; This is a global, multi-ethnic struggle and it&#39;s easy to pick on the Taliban or some other group while applying &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/04/erratum.html&quot;&gt;some double standard&lt;/a&gt; to one&#39;s own club or whatever (&quot;we allow women, as long as they let us run things&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So far, I&#39;d say the XXs are going about it intelligently, with many XYs actually helping, &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/vAFQIciWsF4&quot;&gt;including Barack&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Hillary (not present) drew some big applause from the audience.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m happy we have powerful women like Sima Samar doing brave and intelligent service.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not as concerned as she is about &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/11/standup-comedy-at-newmark-theater.html&quot;&gt;Iranian influence&lt;/a&gt; over some TV and news channels, not to mention &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/08/foss-in-afghanistan.html&quot;&gt;ISPs&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/iranian-festival.html&quot;&gt;a neighboring country&lt;/a&gt; after all.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It&#39;d be just like NATO to go on a bombing spree and take out all the transmission towers, given its own &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/02/news-and-views.html&quot;&gt;weak PR&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Shades of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/11/in-quandary.html&quot;&gt;Belgrade&lt;/a&gt;, where the out of control Clinton administration grounded its ship and blew up the Chinese Embassy.&amp;nbsp; Like I was saying, the world got seriously stupid really fast, as the aging boomers rose to power.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The era of total incompetence (and hyper-specialization) was upon us.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m still thinking &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/09/forbidden-lies.html&quot;&gt;Jordan&lt;/a&gt; is somewhat in the lead in countering old XY hierarchies, keeping them from just assuming they&#39;re entitled and behaving in brutal fashion.&amp;nbsp; Here and there, pockets of men will demonstrate true leadership skills and civilization will benefit.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/08/portland-knowledge-lab.html&quot;&gt;celebrate intelligence&lt;/a&gt; wherever we find it.&amp;nbsp; Sometimes it pays to be &quot;gender blind&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s no reason we can&#39;t have more inter-visitation of this kind (Cascadia - Central Asia), with less obstruction from WDC / State.&amp;nbsp; Sima had gone to Bend as well.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The story about getting visas was just another reminder of how higher education has not yet fulfilled its promise to humanity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets hope the pendulum starts swinging the other way again.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5073234817706392364'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5073234817706392364'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/04/world-affairs-afghanistan.html' title='World Affairs / Afghanistan'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2627749538496634684</id><published>2012-04-27T15:52:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2012-04-28T16:34:55.642-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Science / Religion</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/6973763244/&quot; title=&quot;DSCN0870 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCN0870&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8012/6973763244_9a2fe2c461_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was pleased Tara could join us again.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ve about run out of ISEPP lectures for the two of us at the same table, though perhaps there will be times.&amp;nbsp; I let her off at the entrance to the Schnitzer, while taking the car around to the City Park on 13th, just north of the Multnomah County Library.&amp;nbsp; I returned to the theater through the back entrance on the park blocks and didn&#39;t find Tara again until the Q &amp;amp; A.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Philip Clayton tells some interesting history and plays brief clips of key people, a lecture style I think he pulls off.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s an innovative guy.&amp;nbsp; I should be forgiven for my esoteric immersion lately in the Homer Davenport story, with links to Homer Simpson and therefore... &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/Dd5iDTQy1OM&quot;&gt;Ned Flanders&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; If he&#39;d said &quot;okaly dokaly&quot; I&#39;d have cracked up out loud.&amp;nbsp; &quot;They&#39;d probably like him at Earlham.&quot;&amp;nbsp; &quot;What&#39;s that supposed to mean&quot; (laughing).&amp;nbsp; Then it turned out he was Quaker.&amp;nbsp; So I was &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/11/more-election-day-news.html&quot;&gt;probably right&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Portlanders are pensive, serious thinkers.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not saying Portland is the only introspective city.&amp;nbsp; I think it helps to have Quakers, even if only a few.&amp;nbsp; Have esoteric Buddhist sects if you&#39;re lucky.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Science and religion had been getting along pretty well.&amp;nbsp; I was surprised he didn&#39;t mention Teilhard de Chardin.&amp;nbsp; I asked during the Q &amp;amp; A if he didn&#39;t think the best religions could still be ahead of us.&amp;nbsp; Instead of trying to make the old ones get along better, why aren&#39;t we busier inventing new ones.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ve learned a lot from these many civilizations, why not kick start a bunch of new ones?&amp;nbsp; Philip responded with the idea of retro-fitting or rehabilitating old ones.&amp;nbsp; Much more could be done with the teachings of Jesus than Christianity had ever yet tried, so why not re-animate from within an existing tradition?&amp;nbsp; I guess I wouldn&#39;t see it as either / or.&amp;nbsp; Inventing new religions is likewise a process of reinventing old religions.&amp;nbsp; Kneed that clay.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway (about twenty years ago was it?) that science / religion rapprochement all went kablooey and a major culture war got underway in which science and religion would appear to fight in a bitter way again.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For many, this felt like a throw back detour into a darker age.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Clayton&#39;s plea, transmitting Bronowski&#39;s (I remember that guy, a TV personality), was that we overcome the current impasse, the either / or mentality, and stop getting in one anothers&#39; way.&amp;nbsp; Portlanders couldn&#39;t find much to argue with there and left the theater upbeat, was my impression.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tara and I adjourned to the dinner, joining Jeff and a co-worker from Rumblefish.&amp;nbsp; The waiters were generous with me in particular when pouring red, perhaps for kindnesses exchanged, or so it seemed to me and Don.&amp;nbsp; Missed Nirel&amp;nbsp; (CSN) and other favorite people -- some just because they were at other tables, and we left before too late.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We seemed a small crowd.&amp;nbsp; Terry quizzed Tara about where she was going to college.&amp;nbsp; We talked about her 3rd place win in the state in a team she co-founded and co-led to glory.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve been very privileged to have been a father twice over, plus there&#39;s always &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/06/fathers-day.html&quot;&gt;that dad vibe&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The orbit through this theater, this hotel, has been a nurturing and satisfying one.&amp;nbsp; My thanks to Terry and the much larger cast that makes it possible, out to Mentor Graphics and beyond.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We also talked about DMSO and MSM, both stocked on the health food aisle.&amp;nbsp; You should not be surprised when close to the Linus Pauling neighborhood that you hear lots of complicated &quot;molecule talk&quot; regarding the possible pathways whereby the various ingredients might do their work.&amp;nbsp; Terry talked about chemical &quot;chaperons&quot; in the body, which may accompany complex molecules with a propensity to miss-fold, thanks to some inherited defect, and cause them to fold correctly nevertheless (hence the term &quot;chaperon&quot; although &quot;coach&quot; and/or &quot;guardian&quot; might also gain traction).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
After this enjoyable night out and some time with other Wanderers (ISEPP&#39;s cultish fandom), I retreated to the bat cave to catch up with my work.&amp;nbsp; Lots of people have an interest in Python these days.&amp;nbsp; Yes, I help whip that up, not ashamed to say that I do, no siree.&amp;nbsp; Here&#39;s a computer language that can take you places.&amp;nbsp; Not a waste of time to learn.&amp;nbsp; Steve, just back from points east, is in the same line of work.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For followup:&amp;nbsp; daft punk &amp;amp; IVM (back to designing those religions, Subgenius at work).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7119846175/&quot; title=&quot;DSCN0872 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCN0872&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8159/7119846175_c6028169c8_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2627749538496634684'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2627749538496634684'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/04/science-religion.html' title='Science / Religion'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-241796708988700884</id><published>2012-04-25T14:05:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2016-03-13T19:25:38.827-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Our Hero Mr. Ed</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;375&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;flashvars&quot; value=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157629531323168%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157629531323168%2F&amp;set_id=72157629531323168&amp;jump_to=&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=143270&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;embed type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; src=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=143270&quot; allowFullScreen=&quot;true&quot; flashvars=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157629531323168%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fkirbyurner%2Fsets%2F72157629531323168%2F&amp;set_id=72157629531323168&amp;jump_to=&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We were inner circle among inner circle last night at &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/JackLondonBar&quot;&gt;Jack London Bar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, a bar beneath a bar near 4th and Alder downtown.&amp;nbsp; Gus Frederick of Silverton was giving a far more refined and fleshed out talk regarding &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ochcom.org/davenport/&quot;&gt;the Homer Davenport scenario&lt;/a&gt;, beginning with his mystical mother, who had premonitions of his genius as a future cartoonist (and died when he was 3), followed by a succession of Gump-like events, except this guy was more bell curved another way.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In these circles, animals besides humans are held in high esteem.&amp;nbsp; We don&#39;t just appreciate our pets, they&#39;re family sometimes.&amp;nbsp; Such was Homer about chickens (fighting cocks especially) and horses (Arabians above all others).&amp;nbsp; They ran his life, one could say, and helped give him material, as the non-human world is a constant satire regarding our own.&amp;nbsp; Such an animist was the world&#39;s most highly paid political cartoonist at one point, a Hearst figurehead and friend.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
What is the statue of the girl on the bow of old pirate ships called? &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;The statutes very from ship to ship, but general its just called a figureheads. Thank you for using ChaCha!
    Answered
 
         by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chacha.com/guide/mommanette&quot;&gt;Jeanette F.&lt;/a&gt;
     
     - &lt;time datetime=&quot;2011-06-25T22:14:42Z&quot;&gt;304 days ago at 6:14pm on Jun 25 2011&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Homer was one of the cool people, in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=7804834&quot;&gt;with Mark Twain&lt;/a&gt;, who thought the aggressive thrust against the Filipinos, later repeated in Vietnam, was vicious and stupid.  America is home to a lower strain that expresses itself through naked imperialism.  These lowlife way over-compensate for their inferiority complex, and we all pay the price.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He also was friends with Theodore Roosevelt, having helped get him elected with some memorable cartoons. TR lent enthusiastic support to Homer&#39;s dreams of important Arabian stallions to North America, and in this exercise he succeeded.&amp;nbsp; Homer was personable, affable, befriendable, and became the toast of the Bedouin during his stay with them.&amp;nbsp; Upon this basis, Oregon continues to build a diplomatic safe corridor, uninterrupted by the forces of disquiet and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/02/islamic-cartoons.html&quot;&gt;shallow discord&lt;/a&gt; (not to be confused with Deep Discord and primeval chaos, which has been discovered to be innate and &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2012/04/exit-through-gift-shop.html&quot;&gt;protective&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y_PZPpWTRTU&quot;&gt;Mr. Ed the TV star horse&lt;/a&gt;, was a direct descendent from one of these imported Arabians, on his mom&#39;s or dad&#39;s side I forget which, the slides will tell. {Mom&#39;s side, from Wadduda].&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Gus&#39;s talk was scholarly, entertaining and well researched.&amp;nbsp; Another storyteller from Silverton,  Gordon Munro, who has likewise specialized in stories about Homer, regaled us with three or four after the intermission.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I got there and back by bus 14.&amp;nbsp; Steve Silverman and I talked about chickens, which turned out to be apropos.&amp;nbsp; Many other Wanderers were present, including Nate, Jon Bunce.&amp;nbsp; I took advantage of the occasion to notice &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/search?q=ToonTown&quot;&gt;we were in ToonTown&lt;/a&gt;, as the slides readily make obvious.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Matt Goening was on recently, according to Glenn, finally admitting to Oregon&#39;s being the Silverton, but then joking he says that about all the Silvertons.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s where &lt;i&gt;The Simpsons&lt;/i&gt; (simpletons) are from.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Quaker threads, which converge with Wanderers and Subgenius for me, have been flying by thick and fast. I&#39;ll do more to chronicle later, with the benefit of hindsight.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lifting from the thick traffic, this from Tom Head:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;helvetica&amp;quot;;&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot;; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;Also, people who could not attend tonight might be interested in the links to &quot;Speak Truth to Power&quot; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://afsc.org/document/speak-truth-power&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://afsc.org/document/&lt;wbr&gt;&lt;/wbr&gt;speak-truth-power&lt;/a&gt; and to Dan Seeger&#39;s talk &quot;Quakers and African Americans approach the New Jerusalem&quot; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://afsc.org/friends/quakers-and-african-americans-approach-new-jerusalem&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://afsc.org/friends/&lt;wbr&gt;&lt;/wbr&gt;quakers-and-african-americans-&lt;wbr&gt;&lt;/wbr&gt;approach-new-jerusalem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
As you can see, more of that &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/03/remembering-baryard-rustin.html&quot;&gt;Bayard Rustin theme&lt;/a&gt;, so prominent at the AFSC meeting at HQS the other weekend.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/241796708988700884'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/241796708988700884'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/04/our-hero-mr-ed.html' title='Our Hero Mr. Ed'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5226105427935294897</id><published>2012-04-18T10:48:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2012-04-20T14:50:36.371-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers 2012.4.18</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/6945069974/&quot; title=&quot;DSCN0642 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DSCN0642&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7221/6945069974_ab618c6824.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;re enjoying a total geek out this morning, doing Solar System 101.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/10/libyan-eclipse.html&quot;&gt;Jim Buxton&lt;/a&gt; is studying various periodic phenomena relating to Earth&#39;s tilt.&amp;nbsp; David DiNucci has his book ready to go, so we&#39;re looking at that too. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/4952432659/&quot;&gt;Lew&lt;/a&gt; was part of the hiking group finding &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ki-a-Kuts_Falls&quot;&gt;Ki-a-Kuts Falls&lt;/a&gt; in the 1990s, his idea for the name, and that&#39;s been reviewed on TV recently.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m short on sleep these days.&amp;nbsp; Our Ministry has shifted into high gear.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=2367924&quot;&gt;The joint statement&lt;/a&gt; from the NCTM and MAA opens the door to open source and/or &quot;gnu&quot; mathematics (a pun on &quot;new math&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I completed a course &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.detc.org/&quot;&gt;on accreditation&lt;/a&gt; in the USA jurisdiction, which social process relies on NGOs and the natural tendency of institutions to want to set standards.&amp;nbsp; Affiliations crisscross every which way as USAers police each other.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Earth zips along at a greater clip in the calendar around January, though given the orbit isn&#39;t that far from circular, these &quot;equal areas in equal times&quot; phenomena are not highly pronounced.&amp;nbsp; The motion is slightly slower at the aphelion.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.windows2universe.org/physical_science/physics/mechanics/orbit/perihelion_aphelion.html&quot;&gt;Animations&lt;/a&gt; tend to exaggerate.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Also, it takes another four minutes a day to turn around a little more to see the Sun in the same place, given the shifting viewpoint.&amp;nbsp; So that means adding four minutes a day every day, which adds up to about &amp;nbsp;a day&#39;s worth a year.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2012/04/spring-cleaning.html&quot;&gt;Nikki wondered&lt;/a&gt; if I was prepared for such a big bill.&amp;nbsp; Self employment takes its high tolls.&amp;nbsp; My income was 1099 based in 2011.&amp;nbsp; I said good bye to some $13K in one evening (including Oregon State taxes).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;ll scrape together some $ for debate clothes for Tara (she&#39;s combating at the state championship soon) and to fix the dryer.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ll slowly rebuild.&amp;nbsp; In the meantime, I&#39;m a harder target when it comes to politicking.&amp;nbsp; The numbers all check, within assertAlmostEqual floating point limits (geek joke).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Quakers were mostly in the dark about the minute on Occupy that was going around, so Business Meeting decided to &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/11/kicking-can-down-road.html&quot;&gt;kick the can down the road&lt;/a&gt; on that one.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/kustertherooster&quot;&gt;Josh &quot;the rooster&quot; von Kuster&lt;/a&gt;, was helping shepherd and officiate, though Occupy had its own representative (no, not me).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I don&#39;t see a need to conduct these national / international affairs at the NPYM level also, other than through the AFSC rep structure, which is active and high bandwidth.&amp;nbsp; Is FCNL involved in Arab Spring as well?&amp;nbsp; -- a question for Leslie (her nomination is seasoning).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I sent around a memo suggesting NPYM no longer bother with a Peace and Social Concerns Committee that meets face-to-face but once a year.&amp;nbsp; Our circuits need to be faster and more responsive than that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not that I&#39;m giving orders (this isn&#39;t the USN).&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m more just signalling Pam that Nominating could and should carry a lighter load (consistent with NPYM&#39;s founding goals per the lore (goal:&amp;nbsp; minimize the need for business at Annual Session)).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks to networks and networking (alluding to the &lt;i&gt;Grunch&lt;/i&gt; book), Quakers are moving to resonate at higher frequency (so should we call them Buzzers? -- like cell phones on vibrate?).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5226105427935294897'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5226105427935294897'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2012/04/wanderers-2012418.html' title='Wanderers 2012.4.18'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>