<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211</id><updated>2025-02-27T06:25:58.543-08:00</updated><category term="clojure python REPL ide"/><title type='text'>BizMo Diaries</title><subtitle type='html'>On the road with Global Data</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=476'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=451&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=501&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1905</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>476</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2524686359388749737</id><published>2018-03-24T19:57:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-03-24T21:42:20.120-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Drama Queens</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/k4EUTMPuvHo&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, this one is hilarious.  It hits so many movie-maker cliches right on the nose, the chords of melodrama.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I think a lot of the Boomer generation thinks the world suddenly got a lot more tabloid at some point, as if the supermarket checkout lane world just took over one day and won&#39;t ever let go.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The above trailer captures that sense of claustrophobia, wherein a mundane nuisance becomes an existential threat of gun blaster proportions.&amp;nbsp; Such a psyche tends to feed on itself.&amp;nbsp; From merely dramatic, we move to melodramatic, then off the scale (the so-called deep end) to surreal.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However surreal could be fun with a Dali throwing the party, so I&#39;m not saying all our reality TV shows &lt;i&gt;must&lt;/i&gt; be nightmarish, even if surreal sometimes. &lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2524686359388749737'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2524686359388749737'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/03/drama-queens.html' title='Drama Queens'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/k4EUTMPuvHo/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6863061817286900032</id><published>2018-03-20T11:27:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2018-03-20T11:39:24.202-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Paradigm Shift</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/39098593240/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Library Book&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Library Book&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/802/39098593240_ac283ee2df.jpg&quot; width=&quot;333&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This is the one to read after &lt;i&gt;Cryptonomicon&lt;/i&gt;, which is historical science fiction.  This newer one, &lt;i&gt;The Theory that Would Not Die&lt;/i&gt;, is availing itself of a lot of the same information.&amp;nbsp; As author Sharon Bertsch McGrayne points out:&amp;nbsp; a lot of this wartime business didn&#39;t start to trickle out until the 1970s.&amp;nbsp; The people who participated were forbidden to share their experience, for &quot;national security&quot; reasons.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The premise of the recent movie &lt;i&gt;Churchill&lt;/i&gt;, was that Winston had huge doubts about the wisdom of D-Day, and took comfort in the idea that the weather might be on his side.&amp;nbsp; He tried his best to talk Eisenhower out of it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
According to this recent history of Data Science, Eisenhower possibly had access to deeper secrets from the UK&#39;s own Bletchley Park than Churchill did, and knew, from intercepted and decrypted communications, that Hitler saw a Normandy landing as a likely bluff, and wanted his generals to gird for the &quot;real thing&quot; should it happen.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That told Eisenhower his deception was working.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I knew a guy who&#39;d served under General Patton in the UK, where the goal was to appear to be amassing a large army, such that aerial surveillance would be fooled.&amp;nbsp; The Germans would think those were tanks, but they were closer to inflated balloons.&amp;nbsp; The Churchill movie doesn&#39;t talk about all this.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I remember when this older guy I knew, a WW2 veteran, finally felt free to share his experience:&amp;nbsp; the &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt; had published a story on the fake army just that morning or thereabouts. This was way back in the 1980s.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Alan Turing, on the other hand, was never allowed to talk about his critical role saving Britain.&amp;nbsp; Churchill was very keen to have all evidence destroyed.&amp;nbsp; Exactly why again?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Why do politicians have the power to order mass destruction of anything, anywhere?&amp;nbsp; Because we authorize them to do so?&amp;nbsp; So we can scapegoat them later when things don&#39;t go as planned?&amp;nbsp; Yeah, something like that.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6863061817286900032'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6863061817286900032'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/03/paradigm-shift.html' title='Paradigm Shift'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8410769883180112713</id><published>2018-03-18T00:22:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2018-03-18T00:23:36.501-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Studying Wars</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Enough still unprocessed warring has gone on to last lifetimes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The violence voyeur is always seeking some new spectacle.&amp;nbsp; A younger generation comes along and asks itself &quot;how would I behave in wartime?&quot;&amp;nbsp; Some seek glory.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Maybe we don&#39;t need you to find that out?&amp;nbsp; How would you behave if war were not a goal?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Politicians continually need assurance they&#39;ll be able to whip up war fever, and float a lot of trial balloons in that regard, just to see where they stand with the minions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The minions, for their part, get bamboozled into one war after another, because they don&#39;t get the time or space to really study.&amp;nbsp; They repeat the same mistakes, having too little time to learn from mistakes already made.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Stop the world I want to get off&quot; is the cliche complaint people ridicule, knowing there&#39;s no stopping.&amp;nbsp; However, without reflection, life stays shallow and superficial.&amp;nbsp; What would it be like to let generations really learn their own past?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We have enough raw material to last many lifetimes.&amp;nbsp; Do we really need to create more gratuitous karma for ourselves?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Slow down and learn about what has already happened.&amp;nbsp; Wouldn&#39;t that be a huge luxury?&amp;nbsp; You could still tour, enjoy those cruise ships, explore museums.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We didn&#39;t need you to start new wars.&amp;nbsp; Maybe you did anyway.&amp;nbsp; You might have thought elective wars would get you elected? Is that what your donors told you?&amp;nbsp; Were they paying you to get a war on?&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8410769883180112713'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8410769883180112713'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/03/studying-wars.html' title='Studying Wars'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5649087629094971558</id><published>2018-03-14T13:45:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2018-03-14T13:45:56.423-07:00</updated><title type='text'>ML DL</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
We use these short little acronym in government (Cyberia) all the time.&amp;nbsp; ML = Machine Learning.&amp;nbsp; DL = Deep Learning.&amp;nbsp; If you don&#39;t know what these mean, you&#39;re likely a left-behind politician with too little time for engineering to really govern (steer).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As a newbie in the circle of ML / DL teachers, I&#39;m very humble.&amp;nbsp; I sit at the feet of favorite teachers and sponge it up, tasking my own neural net to re-weight and re-bias as necessary.&amp;nbsp; Get to the bottom of all these meanings.&amp;nbsp; Investigate.&amp;nbsp; Don&#39;t assume, coming in, that your namespace is well-tempered (well-tuned).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My approach is two-track.&amp;nbsp; First, I&#39;ve somewhat abandoned doing everything in Sphinx, not because I have any issues with Sphinx, but because of my own weaknesses and shortcomings with regard to Github.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s a final step wherein documentation might &quot;go live&quot; in world-readable (open source) space, but I&#39;m not taking it.&amp;nbsp; Second, I&#39;m staying with Python.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Track One:&amp;nbsp; manual skills, like when gardening, you need to know how to use a spade, trowel, shovel, bucket, weed whacker and so on.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Track Two:&amp;nbsp; conceptual grasp.&amp;nbsp; The latter comes slowly or at least at its own rate, less under conscious control, whereas practicing with matplotlib, numpy, pandas and scikit-learn APIs is eminently doable of one&#39;s own volition.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My focus is on polishing Track One manual skills and remaining patient with the &quot;slow dawning&quot; that is the gradual emergence (surfacing) of any knowledge domain.&amp;nbsp; I can&#39;t rush Track Two whereas if I burn the candle at both ends, I can practice the way athletes practice:&amp;nbsp; you keep at it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Keeping these tracks separate has one big advantage:&amp;nbsp; I don&#39;t have to apologize for taking the ten thousand foot view and going for broke on Track Two, all out of proportion to what my manual skills yet allow.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m barely able to dig a trench yet am already studying the intricacies of orchid raising, or beekeeping (not usually considered part of gardening, but then really everything is).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My humility does not translate into refraining from actually studying the magic.&amp;nbsp; I just have to admit I haven&#39;t practiced enough, nor re-tuned my model enough, to fully minimize the error function (cost function).&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m still getting to the bottom of ML DL (gradient descent).&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5649087629094971558'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5649087629094971558'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/03/ml-dl.html' title='ML DL'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1250869848189255641</id><published>2018-03-07T13:50:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2022-02-02T14:45:35.956-08:00</updated><title type='text'>World Game Continues</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Wanderers, who meet frequently at the Linus Pauling House on Hawthorne, tend to be familiar with the World Game idea, and a couple of us at least, have actually played it.&amp;nbsp; Francher showed up at the ones led by Buckminster Fuller himself.&amp;nbsp; I played it in Eugene, and in San Diego, when Tara was just taking her first steps.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;re reading about the passing of Jay Baldwin at 85, an American hero and lover of cars, who escaped New Jersey and headed for California along the open road.&amp;nbsp; His love of cars would steered him towards Fuller, who developed a three wheeled Dymaxion Car at a critical juncture.&amp;nbsp; Then came the Dymaxion House.&amp;nbsp; These were props we could use on the World Stage (where World Game is actually played).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m beginning a new course on data science tonight and want my students to get in touch with their internal data scientist.&amp;nbsp; I think some of us get turned off statistics for the same reason we don&#39;t really like economics:&amp;nbsp; the topics are too dismal, to fatalistic and deterministic.&amp;nbsp; &quot;I&#39;m not a statistic&quot; the ego cries, fitting the model.&amp;nbsp; I know I&#39;ve eschewed thinking like a data scientist most of my life.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll confess that, and discuss techniques for overcoming such limitations.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
World Game connects to Club of Rome in that humanity was newly becoming aware of its ability to model reality based on big data, or any data at all.&amp;nbsp; Computers could churn through the number crunching, according to whatever algorithms.&amp;nbsp; Humans would be free to focus on the algorithms.&amp;nbsp; We could turn our mathematical understanding into a better tool for forecasting.&amp;nbsp; These were seeming like superpowers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I wrote on the Club of Rome in eighth grade, for Mr. Craden&#39;s sociology class.&amp;nbsp; We had sociology at the Overseas School of Rome.&amp;nbsp; Dad subscribed to &lt;i&gt;The Futurist&lt;/i&gt;, was an urban planner in charge of drawing up fifty year plans for the government of Libya.&amp;nbsp; I took for grated that humans were meant to &quot;think big&quot;.&amp;nbsp; That was part of our role.&amp;nbsp; During a crisis period in Jersey City, I came to doubt that such thinking mattered, as it never seemed to gain traction.&amp;nbsp; History did its own thing, never mind how we planned it.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve come to a later synthesis, still being fine-tuned.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
World Game is all about anticipating, forecasting from data.&amp;nbsp; Even for that reason alone I should be grateful for this opportunity to retrain and change the relative weights in my neural nets, feeding more power and influence to my internal data scientist.&amp;nbsp; The free open source tools I&#39;m learning to use help me play World Game more effectively.&amp;nbsp; The very process of learning to use them helps me project what the personal workspace (PWS) of tomorrow will be like.&amp;nbsp; The PWS is a core concept within GST.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1250869848189255641'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1250869848189255641'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/03/world-game-continues.html' title='World Game Continues'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8879050616663661488</id><published>2018-03-05T23:09:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2018-03-05T23:09:22.309-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Big Sur (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/26774097688/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;P1040439&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;P1040439&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4784/26774097688_bb0866f442.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Glenn rented this one from Multnomah Public Library. He&#39;d read some Kerouac novels and grew up in the same generation, more or less.  Jack was a pack leader, of the Beat Generation, but feels ambivalent in his role.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Glenn recognized &lt;i&gt;City Lights Books&lt;/i&gt; as iconic and said the real one was bigger than the one in the movie.&amp;nbsp; He pulled out a book he&#39;d procured there.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mostly it&#39;s a movie about alcohol and its potentially devastating impact on many lives, extending well beyond the drinker&#39;s. The movie is also about truth-telling and keeping it real.&amp;nbsp; The characters care about one another, they&#39;re just not sure how to express it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Here&#39;s poor old Jack in what we might call a utopia, a cozy cabin at Big Sur, friendly supporters, and with a dream girl and her beautiful son. She&#39;s eager to be his life-long companion, and yet he&#39;s suicidal and in hell.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Viewer jealousy may be forgiven, but must Jack really suffer that much?&amp;nbsp; What were his sins that he cannot enjoy his own fame and fortune?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These beatniks were too undisciplined, drinking while driving, forgetting to make plans.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I understand they needed to escape an overly constraining, fiercely racist environment, and that the psychological cost of alienation was an occupational hazard.&amp;nbsp; Wavey Gravy, another beat poet, did a better job transitioning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The youthful rebellion gathered momentum, and by the hippie days was more self-defining.  Or was it?  Jack Kerouac transitions to Ken Kesey and the &lt;i&gt;Grateful Dead&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The hippie era was somewhat less blighted by alcohol perhaps, in that the hip cool thing was to explore psychedelics, which have different side effects. This movie doesn&#39;t need to tackle the subject of entheogens.
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8879050616663661488'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8879050616663661488'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/03/big-sur-movie-review.html' title='Big Sur (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5691850342352504532</id><published>2018-03-03T15:45:00.004-08:00</published><updated>2018-03-03T15:45:38.989-08:00</updated><title type='text'>From Facebook</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
Oregon acts to protect state election system from Russia &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/nLlg1fAQEo&quot;&gt;https://t.co/nLlg1fAQEo&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/USATODAY?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@usatoday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@thekirbster) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thekirbster/status/970081702461624320?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 3, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As an Oregon voter and taxpayer, I&#39;d like to know more about these new security protections Oregonians have a right to know more about. Anyone into cybersecurity knows its about adhering to open standards using source code anyone can check.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s how NIST designs stuff, around Elliptic Curve and AES. Oregon has Vote-By-Mail so I&#39;m curious what people see as vulnerable to Russian attack.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I know my curiosity will be met by a cloak of secrecy if the plan is actually to further heist the system by making it opaque (less transparent). That&#39;d be hard to do given the stated objectives and follow-up audits we&#39;ll be demanding.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Americans (in the US sense) have long distrusted the voting machine 
infrastructure, dating back several elections.  I haven&#39;t seen many 
claims that this sense of distrust traces to Russian propaganda.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Rather,
 it seems well-founded and based on actual cases of tampering that have 
come to light, most notably purges of voter rolls using deliberately 
sloppy techniques designed to spread collateral damage among specific 
demographics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Those who studied the black box voting machines found 
much to criticize.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So where is NIST in this picture?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Does the US commit
 any funds towards researching and developing the infrastructure of 
democracy?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If MAGA means anything at all, it would have to mean looking
 to the US for role model, trusted technology around voting, combined 
with best practices.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The US is very far from that now, with most 
judging bodies saying US elections no longer pass the sniff test.  There
 may be moves afoot to hold the Russians accountable for Stinky Politics
 Nation (SPN), but that could easily backfire. &lt;span class=&quot; UFICommentActorAndBody&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span data-ft=&quot;{&amp;quot;tn&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;K&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;UFICommentBody&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaming all one&#39;s problems on a convenient enemy has a way of not working out.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot; UFICommentActorAndBody&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span data-ft=&quot;{&amp;quot;tn&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;K&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;UFICommentBody&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5691850342352504532'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5691850342352504532'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/03/from-facebook.html' title='From Facebook'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5724172571373406529</id><published>2018-02-26T10:37:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-26T11:33:57.644-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Water for Elephants (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Really well filmed and acted. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1067583/&quot;&gt;Big name cast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One might argue it&#39;s a tad tabloid, histrionic, pulp fiction.  In a word: corny.  So there you are, the audience, perhaps with popcorn.  Here are your freaks:  more beautiful than average, in a world of cruelty.  Quite the novel (soap opera, whatever).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The setting is the time of hobos, men sans work, riding the railroads to redistribute their labor, much as Amazon caravaners, other Dead Head type tribes, do today.  Wandering gypsies, in a Gypsy Economy.  Welcome to 2018.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The plot features a triangle: circus impresario (reminds me of &lt;i&gt;Bug&#39;s Life&lt;/i&gt;) with stunning wife-horse act, hires protagonist of Polish background to work with the animals.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In a desperate economic gamble, an elephant is acquired, and it turns out she speaks Polish, meaning the impresario with anger management problems manages to not wreck his own circus for at least awhile longer.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, I was really impressed, especially by the elephant playing Rosie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Queued for Iranian TV?  Total film nuts, like the Japanese.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, I&#39;m proposing it for Pyconic conferences, for the movie track (similar to the hallway track, quite informal, more like BOFs).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&quot;The idea that “height, width, depth” fall apart into three independent  linear dimensions always seemed somewhat sleight-of-handy to me, and I  resonated with New England Transcendentalism when I found a like-minded  skeptic, one R. Buckminster Fuller.&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/j0UrMLTk2j&quot;&gt;https://t.co/j0UrMLTk2j&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@thekirbster) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thekirbster/status/968191016401432577?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 26, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5724172571373406529'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5724172571373406529'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/02/water-for-elephants-movie-review.html' title='Water for Elephants (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-278366384733605799</id><published>2018-02-22T02:42:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-22T02:47:27.029-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Free College</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/L4Trz6pFut4&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The progressives say Russiagate is distracting from the student debt problem, plus so many Americans are political prisoners of the Feds, post the ending of Prohibition (part 2) on the part of several states.  Facing these issues is too painful for those with no solutions, so the scapegoats are to blame.  An old story.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the meantime, geeks such as helped win WWII for the British, the Turing Types, have transformed the face of education to where the logical API is your dorm room studio aka home.&amp;nbsp; The lectures are all there, as are opportunities for two-way and multi-way communication.&amp;nbsp; Concentrating on making the home a true PWS (personal workspace) makes more sense than borrowing money to invest in someone else&#39;s digs.&amp;nbsp; How many homes might one person afford (a great many, in some cases)?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The point:&amp;nbsp; &quot;free college&quot; as some imagine it, might not be as brick and mortar nor as easily paid for on the backs of young people.&amp;nbsp; Getting relief from those loans might involve entering another service, one that pays loans back, but perhaps in a devaluing currency.&amp;nbsp; Inflation is on the side of borrowers right?&amp;nbsp; Not all M1 denominated in dollars are actually Treasury bills.&amp;nbsp; But I&#39;m getting ahead of my story.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Maybe we could pay them in Bitcoin or other cryptocurrency to redo college but in a different way, one that involves work/study which could mean world travel, and you might not have to wear a uniform or carry weapons.&amp;nbsp; The world is getting really sick of weapons and those who find them necessary to their survival.&amp;nbsp; Weapons used recreationally, not for crimes, are not actually weapons, nor sold as such.&amp;nbsp; A nuance of the language.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, I think patriots of all countries can rally around a university system that rescues more than it impedes.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s a transfer of wealth going on, in entropic terms, from the sun to the earth, meaning an increase in entropy there, leading to eventual gigantism or brown drawfism, is feeding syntropy here, or potentially is doing that.&amp;nbsp; Or ability to order information has gotten rather good, what with big data and server farms and all.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Russiagate looks like an attempt to stop hacktivism and assert Federal control in new overreaching ways.&amp;nbsp; The move to criminalize self expression is quite one sided, with corporations free to pour money into Federal coffers, but forbidden to engage in private ventures unless friendly to same, willing to pay tribute and bribes.&amp;nbsp; A kind of extortion is happening, whereas a lot of the geeks who worked hard on this railroad were not doing so for the aggrandizement of any District, of Columbia or otherwise.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;ll see if the FBI is successful, in combination with the Patriot Act and other tools, in continuing to prosecute anyone using social media in ways disapproved of by the DOJ or any of several players set up to enforce a set of rules within a particular jurisdiction.&amp;nbsp; Those using Facebook to advertise their post Prohibition product lines are engaging in activities the DOJ has criminalized, or so they might soon allege.&amp;nbsp; But how does one tell Facebook to deny Californians access to home grown social media?&amp;nbsp; Silicon Valley is not about to surrender its economy to east coasters who don&#39;t know bash or think Ubuntu is some kind of drink.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pVKEsiNMPNc&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/278366384733605799'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/278366384733605799'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/02/free-college.html' title='Free College'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/L4Trz6pFut4/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-904163979598662104</id><published>2018-02-19T02:39:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-25T17:04:18.064-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Magic Squares</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/40283905522/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;P1040345&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;P1040345&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4711/40283905522_e4a2b05088.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Magic Squares in NumPy, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/learning/numpy-data-science-essential-training/magic-squares-and-numpy&quot;&gt;who is doing them&lt;/a&gt;? I&#39;m not saying they need to be auto-generated. Copy some well known ones into code and run the NumPy version of sum along each of the two Magic Square axes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://scipython.com/book/chapter-6-numpy/examples/checking-a-sudoku-grid-for-validity/&quot;&gt;A sudoku&lt;/a&gt; would be another data structure to model.&amp;nbsp; You can get to each sector with what&#39;s called a &quot;view&quot; or slice into just those cells, no extra memory for the data, just the overhead of the frame. A sum in each sector keeps track of same.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As a former calculus teacher, now &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.scipy.org/doc/scipy-0.14.0/reference/generated/scipy.stats.norm.html&quot;&gt;into statistics&lt;/a&gt;, I&#39;m thinking we don&#39;t do enough in standard high school calc, to bridge &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Fvi9A_tEmXQ&quot;&gt;probability density functions&lt;/a&gt; (PDFs) with their integrals, their cumulative distribution functions (CDFs).&amp;nbsp; So what if closed forms don&#39;t always jump out at us?&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ve got the numerical tools to power through without those if need be.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m glad to have an API with the school system.&amp;nbsp; I thought &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2016/10/measure-97-again.html&quot;&gt;Measure 97&lt;/a&gt; might bring that about, and approached the Methodists about &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/03/n8v-american.html&quot;&gt;a certain Code Castle&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; I also named a sculpture in my living room &quot;code castle&quot; and covered it with stuffed dragons.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Instead, I got a part time teaching job after school and get to chat with parents and teachers, other guardians, several times a week.&amp;nbsp; When it comes to teaching adults, Californians are more ravenous for a geek diet than Oregonians it seems.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m happy to feed a hungry neighbor.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Code castle&quot; (the sculpture) is being recycled for parts and &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/07/base-10-ghetto.html&quot;&gt;the Spooky Castle&lt;/a&gt; (former church and community center) showed up in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/4dsolutions/Python5/blob/master/SpookyCastle.ipynb&quot;&gt;my Jupyter Notebooks&lt;/a&gt; on what we call &quot;context managers&quot; in Python.&amp;nbsp; They have their __enter__ and __exit__ methods, the latter perhaps charged up with Exceptions it needs to deal with.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Jupyter Notebooks, for those of you who wish to learn, are interactive web pages you may run locally (i.e. on localhost 127.1.1.1) that talk to a kernel such as Python or Haskell or maybe R, the statistics engine.&amp;nbsp; I need to remind my students:&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.revolutionanalytics.com/2015/09/using-r-with-jupyter-notebooks.html&quot;&gt;Jupyter&lt;/a&gt; came from Julia, Python, R as the initial target languages of an expanded I-Python Notebook project.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/904163979598662104'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/904163979598662104'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/02/magic-squares.html' title='Magic Squares'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6505180119520524969</id><published>2018-02-17T13:57:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-18T11:05:38.548-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Political Radar</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I&#39;m keeping an eye on my political radar, but when it comes to putting out blips of my own, I&#39;m finding Facebook most congenial.&amp;nbsp; Twitter too.&amp;nbsp; These platforms are ideal for PR, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2016/07/idiocracy-two.html&quot;&gt;PR is what I do&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Of course Twitter is infested with bots.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s an API to tweet from your programs.&amp;nbsp; Who wants to hire some poor stooge to make stuff up when you can just have a rotating queue.&amp;nbsp; Let C-level executives commit, just like Trump does, if you don&#39;t delegate to your CMO.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Along those lines, I&#39;m not seeing where PR firms based in Russia get off the hook in having their operations exposed, but then we also found out about Bell Pottinger, the UK-based PR firm that colluded to &quot;sow discord&quot; just as IRA (Internet Research Agency) is accused of.&amp;nbsp; Quoting &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2018/01/wanderers-2018131.html&quot;&gt;an earlier blog post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
The idea of Russians buying ads on Facebook doesn&#39;t bother me even a 
little.&amp;nbsp; The British do it too, which bothers me a little more.&amp;nbsp; I don&#39;t
 trust British suspicion of the Russians usually, as it relates back to 
their inheriting Roman Imperialism, a meme virus.&amp;nbsp; Americans were 
infected with that too, and tend to crow about it as a chief asset.&amp;nbsp; 
Just look at DC&#39;s architecture.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Anyway, the idea that nations seek to influence election outcomes does 
not disturb me.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s a tiny planet and we all have a stake in the 
various outcomes.&amp;nbsp; The sooner we acknowledge what goes on, and stop 
trying to deal with it by criminalizing it, the better. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As thought-leader &lt;span class=&quot; UFICommentActorAndBody&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-ft=&quot;{&amp;quot;tn&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;K&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;UFICommentBody _1n4g&quot;&gt;Kyle Kulinski (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/SecularTalk&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Secular Talk&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) points out, one man&#39;s &quot;collusion&quot; is another man&#39;s smart business plan.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s no law against making friends with friends of the enemy, unless one has such complete control of the law that one is able to legislate permanent &quot;good guy&quot; status.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s the tautological underpinnings of jurisprudence:&amp;nbsp; protect the jurisdiction of the jurists.&amp;nbsp; Give judges the right to judge.&amp;nbsp; Romans could tell us all about it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot; UFICommentActorAndBody&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-ft=&quot;{&amp;quot;tn&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;K&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;UFICommentBody _1n4g&quot;&gt;My theory, which traces back to a little reported story, is that Protestants in particular are feeling an existential threat from three sides at least.&amp;nbsp; Firstly, one of their chief Bible thumpers switched sides to Eastern Orthodox (the under-reported story). Secondly, the Second Coming of Christ (SCC) doesn&#39;t appear to be happening in our lifetimes (not a new problem). Thirdly, secularism isn&#39;t vanishing either.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot; UFICommentActorAndBody&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-ft=&quot;{&amp;quot;tn&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;K&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;UFICommentBody _1n4g&quot;&gt;The strategy has been to pursue the main corporate PR initiative of the last century:&amp;nbsp; link Christianity to both Capitalism (the dream of instant riches) and Patriotism (the willingness to die for capitalists) by injecting In God We Trust language and giving it a patronizing spin.&amp;nbsp; The heinous crime of the ages has always been heresy, and without calling it that, there&#39;s still a strong urge to demonize.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot; UFICommentActorAndBody&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-ft=&quot;{&amp;quot;tn&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;K&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;UFICommentBody _1n4g&quot;&gt;Speaking of powerful symbols, why was KKK cross-burning never seen as a desecration of the Cross?&amp;nbsp; Burn a flag and you&#39;re disrespectful. Burn a cross and you&#39;re a good old boy.&amp;nbsp; Makes no sense.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot; UFICommentActorAndBody&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-ft=&quot;{&amp;quot;tn&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;K&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;UFICommentBody _1n4g&quot;&gt;Anyway, the Russians seem a powerful threat because of Eastern Orthodox Christianity.&amp;nbsp; Israel is not a threat because it&#39;s expected to play into the &lt;i&gt;Book of Revelation&lt;/i&gt; and help make End Times happen.&amp;nbsp; The Middle East is a tinderbox people want to ignite in hopes of ending the world.&amp;nbsp; You might think such people don&#39;t exist, yet the mentally ill have always been legion.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6505180119520524969'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6505180119520524969'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/02/political-radar.html' title='Political Radar'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-564942559674609066</id><published>2018-02-10T22:20:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-24T16:49:15.181-08:00</updated><title type='text'>A Coxeter Biography</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/120725835&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/120725835&quot;&gt;The Man Who Saved Geometry.mp4&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/user37820902&quot;&gt;Siobhan Roberts&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Donald Coxeter is old and frail in this telling, yet made it to Hungary at age ninety-five, for a 21st century geometry conference.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Professor Coxeter is the man to whom RBF dedicated his two-volume snapshot of a work in progress, sometimes referred to as &quot;syngeom&quot;, however given a formal title of &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt; for the Macmillan publishings.&amp;nbsp; Its subtitle:&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Explorations in the Geometry of Thinking&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The writer for this film is Siobhan Roberts, who wrote the book with the same subtitle (&lt;i&gt;The Man Who Saved Geometry&lt;/i&gt;), as well as a bio of John Horton Conway, who features prominently, as another Coxeter fan with deep insight into what these polytopes and hyper-dimensional sphere packings were all about.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Having someone who has done so much homework write the script makes for confidant, as well as intimate, storytelling.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We come to see Donald as bravely defiant in the face of intellectual currents intent upon driving his kind (the Euclideans) from the face of the earth, though perhaps they were joking (Bourbaki was a practical joke).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Serious or not, geometry needs its champions in any age if the inter-generational torch is to be passed.&amp;nbsp; Mandelbrot, among others, drew great solace from Coxeter, as his own work was likewise veering into the visualizable, too accessible to Everyman for an elitist core to bless as orthodox.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not that higher dimensional polytopes are all that visualizable or renderable in the vernacular, though with projections into 3-space they are at least &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/tourable&quot;&gt;tourable&lt;/a&gt; (as gems with many rooms).&amp;nbsp; The Euclideans gave us something to strive for that&#39;s right brainy, as in exciting to graphical imagination.&amp;nbsp; At least &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coxeter%E2%80%93Dynkin_diagram&quot;&gt;Coxeter Diagrams&lt;/a&gt; won acceptance, as they verged on being purely lexical.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When the story gets to Fuller, the Montreal Dome of the 1967 World Expo gets the most focus, as well it should, as Dr. Coxeter was Canadian and his first encounter with geodesic domes was at this Expo, at least on a grand scale.&amp;nbsp; A treasure trove of archival scenarios unfurls.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My thanks to David Koski for underlining the relevance of this film.&amp;nbsp; Because I&#39;d read the book and watched a Siobhan&#39;s address to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/12/heptagons.html&quot;&gt;Gathering for Gardner&lt;/a&gt; crowd, I somehow assumed I&#39;d seen this, but I had not, until tonight.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/564942559674609066'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/564942559674609066'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/02/a-coxeter-biography.html' title='A Coxeter Biography'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7174072117053765460</id><published>2018-02-06T14:30:00.004-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-06T18:14:03.133-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Rambling</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I think The Ramblers could have been another term for The Wanderers, and maybe is, in some parallel universe (in science fiction).&amp;nbsp; Dr. Nick Consoletti was a Saunterer, so The Saunterers might have made do.&amp;nbsp; Whether we wander, ramble, or saunter, we end up learning more about our world, which is sort of the point I suppose.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of points, I&#39;ve been envisioning myself as a vector in a phase space, the vector sum from previous frames. &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/05/elastic-interval-geometry.html&quot;&gt;Elastic Interval Geometry&lt;/a&gt; taught me a lot about weighted sums, how the most tensed vector would be like the most important neuron in some hidden layer.&amp;nbsp; Back propagation is accomplished simply by yielding to forces in EIG.&amp;nbsp; Compromises get made.&amp;nbsp; Learning happens.&amp;nbsp; Reshaping occurs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
EIG was pioneered in the wake of Tensegrity, computer modeling a lot of the same concepts.&amp;nbsp; Gerald de Jong was consciously inspired by one of Kenneth Snelson&#39;s sculptures. He joined us in Seattle at Russ&#39; and Deb&#39;s place, along with Karl, Braley (not Brawley) and several others (me too), and much work got done.&amp;nbsp; I was a big EIG aficionado in those days.&amp;nbsp; Those creepy-crawlies of &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/_II-uESToOs&quot;&gt;Darwin at Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; got under my skin.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I purchased an O&#39;Reilly book about Bitcoin at Hawthorne Powell&#39;s yesterday, and stayed up late reading it, after finishing teaching. My students were learning all about TLS last night, Transport Layer Security, which involves browser and server employing the latest and greatest cryptographic techniques to make transactions secure.&amp;nbsp; We call it HTTPS and see the little padlock or other icon appear, next the the URL in the address bar.&amp;nbsp; I promised to apply all this knowledge to crypto-currencies when next we meet.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve been a fairly accomplished explainer of RSA for awhile now, getting turned on the cryptography anew by Neal Stephenson&#39;s &lt;i&gt;Cryptonomicon&lt;/i&gt; awhile back.&amp;nbsp; The whole story of how the NSA initially resisted declassification of this technique is fascinating in the rear view mirror.&amp;nbsp; The Web hadn&#39;t become established yet, so the future needs of eCommerce were not featuring in the vector sum. People were worried about &quot;activists&quot; i.e. &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/02/the-post-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Daniel Ellsberg types&lt;/a&gt;, more than they were thinking about the likes of WalMart and Amazon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These days, Elliptic Curve Diffie-Hellman (ECDH) has made deep inroads when it comes to initializing the session.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s where Bob and Alice establish a common secretly shared key they might then use for AES, or Advanced Encryption System, the winner of an international contest in the wake of the demise of DES.&amp;nbsp; Bitcoin, and the blockchain in general, use a lot of the same ideas.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People sometimes think encryption is all about evading scrutiny and carrying on with major transactions completely behind the scenes and off radar.&amp;nbsp; To some extent that&#39;s a misconception, as the transactions may be reported in the news, entered into ledgers, kept for future analysts.&amp;nbsp; A company without a coherent internal story is not in a strong position.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The encryption step is more about preventing hacks, subtle tricks, which could alter the course of history by corrupting the transaction.&amp;nbsp; Hacks lead to higher entropy, as what &lt;i&gt;should&lt;/i&gt; have made sense now no longer does.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Put another way, it&#39;s fine for the public to find out about all these transactions later on.&amp;nbsp; What&#39;s important is that at the time of their occurrence, there&#39;s no way to interfere with their content, such as by changing some charged amount or remittance, or substituting a new recipient.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The act itself needs shielding, not from the prying eyes of historians necessarily, but from the shenanigans of entropy creators.&amp;nbsp; Cryptography is about authentication, verifying the transaction is not counterfeit.&amp;nbsp; Bob might be completely sincere, but what does that matter if Alice gets the wrong message, one Bob didn&#39;t send?&amp;nbsp; Some forms of breakage aren&#39;t that easy to mend, as investors (stakeholders) of all types have come to discover for themselves.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For me, these blogs are more like Quaker journals, which pre-internet were kept somewhat like diaries, and not necessarily published, or were shared only posthumously.&amp;nbsp; Blogging is different, but nevertheless doesn&#39;t have to be about events now occurring in real time.&amp;nbsp; Whether the stock market is up or down needn&#39;t be our theme.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Blogs and the blogosphere tend to be more timeless in their focus, on average, than either newspapers or radio talk shows, less about what&#39;s special case.&amp;nbsp; We could say &quot;more philosophical&quot;.&amp;nbsp; Rovers... Rangers...&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7174072117053765460'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7174072117053765460'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/02/rambling.html' title='Rambling'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2838006876898635165</id><published>2018-02-03T12:25:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-03T15:28:56.408-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Bot Learning</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/R9OHn5ZF4Uo&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wvWpdrfoEv0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aircAruvnKk&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IHZwWFHWa-w&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2838006876898635165'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2838006876898635165'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/02/bot-learning.html' title='Bot Learning'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/R9OHn5ZF4Uo/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3032230932761658102</id><published>2018-01-29T16:48:00.003-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-29T22:42:50.689-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Saint Misbehavin&#39; (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/39944677212/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;wavygravy&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;wavygravy&quot; height=&quot;392&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4709/39944677212_daf43f5b30.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I watched this over at Glenn&#39;s today. He had me over for lunch, great soup. I brought some tallboy Olympia beers.&amp;nbsp; The movie is from the library.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve been aware of Wavy Gravy for a long time, but was out of the country during &lt;i&gt;Woodstock&lt;/i&gt; and would have been too young to attend on my own even if I&#39;d been on the continent.&amp;nbsp; The first hippies trace back to the beat generation.&amp;nbsp; Wavy Gravy was your classic beat poet, in Greenwich Village, except with a strong sense of humor that&#39;s carried him until now (he&#39;s 81 at the time of this writing).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve posted to &lt;i&gt;QuakerQuaker&lt;/i&gt; how I consider Richard Stallman to be a Bodhisattva, and now I&#39;ve got another candidate.&amp;nbsp; Not that it&#39;s up to me to be handing out this title.&amp;nbsp; More that I convey what I understand &quot;Bodhisattva&quot; to mean by pointing out whom I consider to be archetypal examples.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Woodstock&lt;/i&gt; had many of the same themes as Occupy a couple generations later.&amp;nbsp; Yes, these platforms give voice to political views, but equally if not more important was the experiment in non-violent cohabitation.&amp;nbsp; Could half a million people cram into a rural area and enjoy music without killing each other?&amp;nbsp; Could they stay fed?&amp;nbsp; Would they spawn epidemics?&amp;nbsp; Lets do some science and find out.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People are curious and want to evolve their logistical abilities.&amp;nbsp; Getting the Hog Farm (Wavy&#39;s community) to do &quot;Please Force&quot; security was a stroke of genius on the part of Woodstock organizers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/11/virtual-opdx.html&quot;&gt;Occupy Portland&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(OPDX) was likewise all about the free kitchen, which &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/search?q=FNB+lindsey&quot;&gt;Food Not Bombs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; started, but then turned over to others, given its own more stringent practices.&amp;nbsp; The downtown campers were eager to do science and see if they could live as economic refugees for awhile.&amp;nbsp; Portland supported the experiment for a matter of months, then pulled the plug.&amp;nbsp; The kitchen packed up the night before.&amp;nbsp; The data was in.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3032230932761658102'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3032230932761658102'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/01/saint-misbehavin-movie-review.html' title='Saint Misbehavin&#39; (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-9143532769727086697</id><published>2018-01-27T23:32:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-31T07:49:03.477-08:00</updated><title type='text'>More Thinking about AI</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/i3lEG6aRGm8&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve done something to my FireFox, to where the Twitter stuff doesn&#39;t come through all fancily formatted, like in the post below. Or maybe your browser doesn&#39;t render it either. I&#39;m still seeing the tweet content at least.&amp;nbsp; Even that might go away, right?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The hope is our committed records will have some permanence but that&#39;s all presuming it makes sense to keep all the server farms running.&amp;nbsp; A sense of heritage might fuel that, but will that be sufficient?&amp;nbsp; They say server farms are already eating 2% of the grid&#39;s energy.&amp;nbsp; Good thing President Trump is committing through Twitter, for Twitter.&amp;nbsp; Historians will want to keep that set of records.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not that Trump is the only tweeter the curators treasure, just he paves the way for Federal funding or something similar to keep universities training up new breeds of engineer, ready to tackle the challenge of keeping history plugged in.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s a technical challenge in not overwhelming ourselves with more information than we&#39;re prepared to handle, even power-wise.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Going back to recent themes...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The invocation of Kant in connection with Abbott:&amp;nbsp; was the latter breaking any rules in conceiving of beasts of fewer dimension?&amp;nbsp; We suppose that three dimensions &quot;encompass&quot; two, one, zero and none.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That volume goes up as a 3rd power seems ipso facto the key argument for dim 3 terminology, whereas 3rd powering as a rate of growth (or shrinkage) gets shoved on to Frequency in &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt;, which is about subdividing.&amp;nbsp; We have 3rd powering against a backdrop of a Fourness in pure shape, all change rates aside.&amp;nbsp; That was the 4D.&amp;nbsp; The F took the 3rd powering.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These shifts in meaning mostly serve a practical objective of making it OK for a cube of face diagonals 2, to have a volume of 3.&amp;nbsp; That works out when the shape of 3rd powering is either of the duo-tet&#39;s tetrahedrons.&amp;nbsp; With the cube-based model of 3rd powering, you have an edge of pow(2, 1/2) and therefore a cube of volume 2.828427..., not 3.&amp;nbsp; From this ratio comes S3.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I watched the video below today, as well as the one above. The below one is about brain power and what the chemistry might be, whereas the one above is about electronic circuits learning from feedback to ape, match or exceed human abilities.&amp;nbsp; AlphaGo.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets hope Google stays in business and our blogs live on.&amp;nbsp; Ditto Facebook and all that.&amp;nbsp; Scientific literacy means having the ability to grapple with issues while maintaining a cool head and a solutions focused mindset, even in the face of problems that seem insoluble.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A tetrahedron inscribed in any parallelepiped, any hexahedron with oppositely parallel faces, is going to have one third said hexa&#39;s volume.&amp;nbsp; In the case of the cube, the inscribed regular tetrahedron is complemented by four regions comprising the remaining 2/3rds i.e. 1/4 of 2/3 or 2/12 = 1/6.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The regular octahedron that complements the regular tetrahedron to fill space, has volume ratio 4:1, meaning the 1/8th octahedron corners that pack out from the reg-tet, each have volume 1/2. Four corners have volume 2, adding reg-tet gives 3, the cube&#39;s overall volume.&amp;nbsp; One half is one sixth of three.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These simple fractions work best when we give ourselves permission to have such a cube of volume 3, yet with edges that would normally not give that.&amp;nbsp; The shift is in making 3rd powering a Frequency operation inside an initially &quot;4D&quot; framework, the reg-tet itself, Unit Volume, edges 2R.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Once the logical path is established, go ahead and throw away the ladder and go back to &quot;space is 3D&quot; with an XYZ orientation.&amp;nbsp; When in Rome.&amp;nbsp; You&#39;ve got your touch stones, a way to your favorite garden, but go ahead and surround it with a more conventional brick and mortar wall.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Rather than fight tooth and nail for anything, we&#39;re motivated to continue our investigation. When did we come up with height, width and breadth as the names of three dimensions and to what extent do each of these partake of self nature?&amp;nbsp; A somewhat esoteric question perhaps.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The neural nets that program neural nets get credit for refining their art.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m talking about the humans, however quantum minded.&amp;nbsp; They needed a way to make trial and error count for something. Figure out a feedback loop that continues to fine tune in the face of consistent feedback regarding performance.&amp;nbsp; As long as the game holds still for awhile...&amp;nbsp; fortunately chess and Go do.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The sense that AI is &quot;winning&quot; is an over-collapse of an either-or logic, whereas the cell-silicon hybrid is on both sides of the fence.&amp;nbsp; We encounter our ancestors in the codes they embedded, as silicon learns to echo our sense of music, even logic.&amp;nbsp; Mutual recognition. A mix meets a mix.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We want to think what we consider thinking has held constant, with maybe machines catching up, but that&#39;s not it.&amp;nbsp; Machines have already changed what we consider thinking.&amp;nbsp; We needed that word (&quot;thinking&quot;) to stay up to date, and so we&#39;ve somewhat lost our sense of what it meant -- through the ages. Not a constant. What was thinking before electronics closed so many gaps? What was thinking before reading?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Wandering back around...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Keeping a large lawn watered is a chore, but humans have undertaken such duties long term and considered them a privilege to perform.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m thinking about servers again, and the spinning water wheels, the hydro-dams. When humans insist on sticking their nose in one another&#39;s business, is when many problems arise.&amp;nbsp; Yet closeness is a fact of life.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Sometimes we&#39;re not prying into others&#39; business so much as shielding ourselves from becoming inundated in too many details about affairs we can do nothing about.&amp;nbsp; The marriage of focus and attention with what&#39;s necessary work would need to have divine grace behind it, or some other extra human principle, as we have no idea how to go about consciously designing a reality to work that way.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Probably there&#39;s a sense of keeping a safe distance from what might get ugly, that pervades many disciplines.&amp;nbsp; Altercations you don&#39;t want to have to witness tend to drive behavior.&amp;nbsp; The train wrecks may never happen, and perhaps our avoidance maneuvers were actually constructive?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xx0SsffdMBw&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9143532769727086697'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9143532769727086697'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/01/more-thinking-about-ai.html' title='More Thinking about AI'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/i3lEG6aRGm8/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-9223182846867857959</id><published>2018-01-25T19:09:00.003-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-25T19:10:42.822-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Calling All Kantians</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
So what I want to know is was Edwin Abbott an anti-Kantian. He says perfectly flat beings could recognize each other but Kant says we&#39;re a priori in spacetime and spacetime has volume. Sounds anti-Abbott.&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@thekirbster) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thekirbster/status/956710031637954561?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 26, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
When did Western Civ decree that three dimensions each have independence from the other two?  Did Plato know his Platonic Five were 3D. I&#39;m pretty sure that came later.&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@thekirbster) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thekirbster/status/956710377529593856?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 26, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
Which is the most important of the three dimensions?&lt;/div&gt;
— Kirby Urner (@thekirbster) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thekirbster/status/956710566764007424?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 26, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9223182846867857959'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9223182846867857959'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/01/calling-all-kantians.html' title='Calling All Kantians'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1584490840525433809</id><published>2018-01-15T16:12:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T18:07:05.147-08:00</updated><title type='text'>MLK Day (2018)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/25847991078/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;MLK&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;MLK&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4609/25847991078_a40ae2d9e0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;410&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Apropos of MLK Day, I was much impressed by Birmingham&#39;s Civil Rights Institute, a study center and archive, as well as an excellent museum. I was impressed by &quot;the ham&quot; (Birmingham) over all, nice to be there for a few days.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Birmingham had some utopian aspirations and to some extent dreams came true, just we learn to take the future for granted, and what at one time might have been a stunning vision of a promised land, is just another day on Planet Earth:&amp;nbsp; great freeways sprawling every which way;&amp;nbsp; a proud university at the center of town; people from all walks of life expressing the human genome, without forced segregation;&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;TrimTab&lt;/i&gt; beer.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The American Experiment, so-called, was a bold one: to forge a civilization from all the world&#39;s peoples.&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;E Pluribus Unum&lt;/i&gt;:&amp;nbsp; from plurality, unity.&amp;nbsp; The whole world came to know of this experiment and now we&#39;re all American in some sense, indivisibly planetary in our affairs and outlook.&amp;nbsp; People understand the ideals, even if skeptical personally, about their attainability or worthiness.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Some commentators brand so-called &quot;globalism&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/03/of-globalism-and-macroscope.html&quot;&gt;as unAmerican&lt;/a&gt;, whereas &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2016/11/thinking-globally.html&quot;&gt;in my view&lt;/a&gt; America was always about accepting our manifest destiny, as work-study student-faculty within a spherical Global U.&amp;nbsp; Our promised land, our Israel, is ball-shaped.&amp;nbsp; Lets accept what&#39;s self-evident, shall we?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Speaking of student-faculty, the scholarly Sam Lanahan came by this morning and gifted me with a really robust, &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/FnyFNd&quot;&gt;top-ranked juicer&lt;/a&gt;, an appliance for turning fruits and vegetables into beverages.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m excited.&amp;nbsp; 2018 is about focusing on health.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s what we all need our freedom to focus upon.&amp;nbsp; Some of us don&#39;t have that privilege.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re asked to sacrifice health for the greater good sometimes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/24845201547/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Design Science Revolution&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Design Science Revolution&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4740/24845201547_b162c1ccef_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;238&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1584490840525433809'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1584490840525433809'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/01/mlk-day-2018.html' title='MLK Day (2018)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-475367505260986942</id><published>2018-01-12T20:49:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-11T11:37:48.526-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Curating Credits</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/elkHuRROPfk?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As a kid, one of my hobbies was using the parental tape recording unit to capture my favorite opening credit sequences on tape.&amp;nbsp; Cassette tape.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
By &quot;opening credit sequence&quot; I mean where they get you with imagery, theme music, names of actors, directors, producers... all that.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I recognized the talent that goes into establishing the atmospherics for a program in but seconds.&amp;nbsp; In computer terms, we&#39;re talking about a boot loader, or a context switch.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, along those lines, I&#39;d like to give my own award to &lt;i&gt;Westworld&lt;/i&gt; (HBO), for really fine stage setting.&amp;nbsp; The technology suggested is way higher than we have, and answers questions that might nag like:&amp;nbsp; can you do a human eye?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;We can&quot; say the credits, and so much more.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s the premise, however fantastic.&amp;nbsp; Science fiction is characterized by wild sets of premises, is it not?&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/475367505260986942'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/475367505260986942'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/01/curating-credits.html' title='Curating Credits'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/elkHuRROPfk/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5996373090874590240</id><published>2018-01-10T13:49:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-10T14:02:55.152-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Codes of Conduct (again)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
The memo put out by Liberals to wear black at the Golden Globes to protest sexual misconduct seems to have gotten lost in Liberal Logicville. They are soo clueless. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/tcot?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#tcot&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ccot?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#ccot&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/gop?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#gop&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/maga?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#maga&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/nJjYgz9kSA&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/nJjYgz9kSA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
— John K Stahl (@JohnKStahlUSA) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JohnKStahlUSA/status/951099289387716608?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
A lot of cultural misunderstanding persists, or shall we say culture clashes?
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How could these women be against sexual harassment when dressing in a &quot;provocative&quot; fashion, the skeptics want to know.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Pycon &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/12/codes-of-conduct.html&quot;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt; is specific about discouraging &quot;booth babes&quot; (of whatever gender) from mixing technology with erotica.&amp;nbsp; One is expected to dress in a more demure manner, which is what makes a &lt;i&gt;Pycon&lt;/i&gt; not a &lt;i&gt;Comicon&lt;/i&gt;, wherein cosplay is encouraged.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The same conversation goes on at work.&amp;nbsp; What dress style is appropriate?&amp;nbsp; Most of us have never really lived in a democracy as that question was never put to a vote.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re told, not asked.&amp;nbsp; The job comes with a uniform.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
College students may perceive an ideal world wherein dressing is not a &quot;code&quot; such that what one wears may not be construed as &quot;signalling&quot; or &quot;suggesting&quot; anything in particular.&amp;nbsp; Garb is not for signifying.&amp;nbsp; The Portland State campus has been &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/09/slutwalk-2014.html&quot;&gt;a site for &lt;i&gt;Slutwalk&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, wherein speakers eloquently sketch their utopia, then parade in costume.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A lot of the misunderstanding traces to English and the locution &quot;she made me feel...&quot; meaning we&#39;re able to use the &quot;victim tense&quot; rather easily.&amp;nbsp; If a guy feels consumed by lust, it&#39;s her fault.&amp;nbsp; We call it the blame game.&amp;nbsp; &quot;She made me do it&quot;.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/05/on-projection.html&quot;&gt;Projection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As a student of Peter Sloterdijk, I feel like saying the most we might hope for are spheres of agreement.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ll give up on &lt;i&gt;Pycon&lt;/i&gt; being like &lt;i&gt;Comicon&lt;/i&gt; as we&#39;re free as individuals to attend one or the other, both or neither.&amp;nbsp; Not every domain need abide by the same rules.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Humans hunger to establish villages, manageable communities, wherein their sense of taste gets expressed.&amp;nbsp; Vindication and satisfaction is in the realization, or at least it was a worthy experiment.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Design Science Revolution was about lowering barriers to entry such that more might afford their brand of theater.&amp;nbsp; Find your like-minded and try it out.&amp;nbsp; The technology is within range, even if the ideals turn out not to be.&amp;nbsp; Find that out.&amp;nbsp; Live your dream.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5996373090874590240'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5996373090874590240'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/01/codes-of-conduct-again.html' title='Codes of Conduct (again)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8217346927948147916</id><published>2018-01-06T09:00:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-09T10:46:17.301-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Geometry of Nature</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
So where were we, before I was so rudely interrupted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2018/01/health-plan.html&quot;&gt;the reality of my mortality&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What gets under the skin of many professionals is that Synergetics dares to be polemical about topics no one usually gets polemical about, prompting by turns defensiveness or simply dismissal.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How dare Bucky assert he&#39;s giving us a &quot;geometry of nature&quot; that (A) is not what we&#39;re used to in schools and (B) does make some modicum of sense, meaning it&#39;s hard to dismiss as &quot;simply crazy&quot;?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As someone trained to read philosophy, I&#39;m used to giving an author the floor and letting her or him construct a &quot;private language&quot; of sorts, meaning the author does some work to &quot;draw us in&quot; and make us privy to special meanings of this or that key term.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Synergetics started with a &quot;deliberately remote vocabulary&quot; but then, in Fuller&#39;s experience, over a lifetime, it seemed to be in a &quot;merging traffic pattern&quot; with what contemporaries were up to, in nearby namespaces.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
No one specifically claims that the XYZ coordinate system is &quot;the&quot; geometry of nature.&amp;nbsp; We have many coordinate systems.&amp;nbsp; I introduce &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quadray_coordinates&quot;&gt;Quadray coordinates&lt;/a&gt; the same way, as just one coordinate system among many, one that uses 4-tuples instead of 3-tuples vis-a-vis 4 instead of 3 &quot;basis vectors&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, our culture does take for granted, without ongoing debate, that &quot;space is three dimensional&quot; because &quot;height, width and depth&quot; are represented by three mutually orthogonal sticks (the &quot;jack&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Synergetics begins with the same &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/03/res-extensa.html&quot;&gt;res extensa&lt;/a&gt;&quot; -- a lump -- but doesn&#39;t claim to disintegrate it into conceptually separable aspects that could exist &quot;independently&quot;.&amp;nbsp; Instead, height-width-depth is a single mutually co-dependent phenomenon, and its avatar, if symbolized as a polyhedron, is more economically represented by the tetrahedron, not the cube.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That&#39;s a different beginning, outside our culture, a different set of language games.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re not accustomed to anyone &quot;questioning authority&quot; in quite this way.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Fuller had given up such lines of questioning and was doing his best to fit in, but tragedy and sorrow jarred him into reassessing whether he could afford to &quot;fit in&quot;.&amp;nbsp; His life plan of the day was not working out.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The rest of us tend to be grateful that he re-committed to his intuitions as, even if we don&#39;t buy into Synergetics, we credit his inventiveness and positive futurism as a boon to society.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/03/student-reading.html&quot;&gt;As a philosophy&lt;/a&gt;, Synergetics is committed to finding unity in complementary aspects, such as concavity versus convexity, tension versus compression, one could say two sides of the same coin.&amp;nbsp; Radiation and Gravity...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Again, with the Synergetics concept of Gravity, we&#39;re moving away from established usage patterns in the direction of logical coherence.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What holds a system together logically such that it continues to make sense to us?&amp;nbsp; A kind of connecting around in all directions.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s a sense of containment, but then we also sense when &quot;bubbles burst&quot; meaning systems fly apart thanks to internal and external forces.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Radiation is divergence from a common center.&amp;nbsp; Gravity is convergence thanks to everyone holding hands and pulling together. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/10/art-history.html&quot;&gt;the computer science notion of namespaces&lt;/a&gt;, we&#39;re able to relegate different usage patterns for such key terms, to their respective language games. There&#39;s not a requirement that we all be on the same page at all times.&amp;nbsp; Partially overlapping scenarios are both necessary and sufficient.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8217346927948147916'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8217346927948147916'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/01/geometry-of-nature.html' title='Geometry of Nature'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7265542681221968442</id><published>2017-12-30T00:32:00.003-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-03T17:15:36.608-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Hermit Chapter</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div a=&quot;&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/27606995599/in/dateposted-public/&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot; title=&quot;Morning Walk&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Morning Walk&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4692/27606995599_bbf085f656.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
This chapter, following Alabama Adventure, is soon to end, as I plot &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2018/01/new-years-day-2018.html&quot;&gt;a next trip&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, I&#39;m glad for this heated cave with WiFi.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m working on some new course-ware, written in Sphinx, and wrote an essay on &lt;i&gt;Medium&lt;/i&gt; about &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kirbyurner/whats-the-best-way-to-teach-python-675d4bfbdebd&quot;&gt;my latest thoughts&lt;/a&gt; on teaching Python.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I did get out this afternoon, to visit &lt;i&gt;The Good Bye Party&lt;/i&gt; family, out towards Gresham.&amp;nbsp; I took the Max. Great homemade pear wine!&amp;nbsp; I learned so much, hanging out with this younger bunch.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tonight I&#39;m listening to &lt;a href=&quot;http://amanofletters.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;A Man of Letters&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reading from &lt;i&gt;Undercover Mormon&lt;/i&gt; by Th. Metzger. I do this as I blog, upload pictures, and make a long overdue backup.
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7265542681221968442'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7265542681221968442'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/12/hermit-chapter.html' title='Hermit Chapter'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6271570546042504706</id><published>2017-12-27T19:06:00.003-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-27T19:06:29.491-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Got SQLite?</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/27566393149/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Screen Shot: Using Sphinx&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screen Shot: Using Sphinx&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4680/27566393149_1f4d0c1bb8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Does you office pass around .db files as a convenient way to share data?  
Of course many file extensions are overloaded, so yes, to be clear, I&#39;m talking about SQLite files, which require only the sqlite client, or many programming languages, to reveal their contents or accept new data.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In my courseware for IT workers, I tend to emphasize the efficacy with which SQLite might be used, as a simple way of keeping data organized.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A database much more difficult to either tamper with or change inadvertently than a database, plus the format preserves the structure of a relational database, meaning the query engine is at your fingertips, if you just remember enough of the language (SQL).&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6271570546042504706'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6271570546042504706'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/12/got-sqlite.html' title='Got SQLite?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1927296923885464308</id><published>2017-12-24T08:40:00.003-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-24T20:43:28.733-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Supply Chain Logistics</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/29643902771/in/album-72157673871844116/&quot; title=&quot;IVM FM&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;IVM FM&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8356/29643902771_0061d08cc7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
The world has lots of plastic junk already, and what with 3D printers now widely affordable, a different way to shape the plastic, we have a tsunami on our hands.&amp;nbsp; Recyclable plastic, actively reused in the space of an average human lifetime, might be a goal.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m back to those &lt;a href=&quot;http://grunch.net/synergetics/modules.html&quot;&gt;A &amp;amp; B modules again&lt;/a&gt;, so-named in &lt;i&gt;Synergetics&lt;/i&gt;, which aims to capitalize on a Unit Volume Tetrahedron (UVM) in a corner (remote) of Universe somewhere.&amp;nbsp; A rebel planet.&amp;nbsp; However in a Diverse Universe (DU), we can afford renegades and mavericks, some of which become tourist destinations.&amp;nbsp; Rebels needn&#39;t be averse to tourism as such voluntary traffic gives more vectors for disseminating a more sympathetic version of history throughout the galaxy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then we have the two flavors of E module.&amp;nbsp; I put it that way because whereas A &amp;amp; B are equi-volumed but differently shaped, the T &amp;amp; E have all the same angles and differ only in surface-to-volume ratio.&amp;nbsp; The E-mod is phi-down from E3, i.e. 1/120th of the RT3 (another name for &quot;SuperRT&quot;), the rhombic triacontahedron embedding the edge-2R (1D) icosa of volume ~18.51, and its edges crisscrossing dual Pentagonal Dodecahedron (the two five-fold symmetric Platonics).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
RT = Icosa + Icosa.dual(), where the dualing method sizes to cross edges by default, and the plus operation has been overloaded to mean combining two polyhedrons into one, a visually pleasing special effect.&amp;nbsp; Cube = Tetra + Tetra.dual().&amp;nbsp; RD = Octa + Octa.dual(), where RD is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2017/04/more-csn-esoterica.html&quot;&gt;Rhombic Dodecahedron&lt;/a&gt;, not a Platonic, but a space-filler nonetheless (and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.garritys.org/2017/02/keplers-rhombic-polyhedra.html&quot;&gt;a Kepler favorite&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;nbsp; Its dual is the CO (cuboctahedron).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Finally, bridging the volume 4 Octahedron (1D edges) and inscribed Icosahedron (two S-factor applications up from the relatively askew Cuboctahedron of volume 2.5, faces flush), are the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2015/06/math-avoidance.html&quot;&gt;24 S-modules&lt;/a&gt;, with a strong relationship to the E.&amp;nbsp; S:E :: VE:Icosa in volumetric terms, where VE labels the canonical CO of volume 20, edges 2R.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2017/11/hypertoons-2017.html&quot;&gt;the S-factor&lt;/a&gt; of about ~1.08.&amp;nbsp; We also have S3 (about ~1.066), the constant by which we do IVM:XYZ volume conversions, but also: VE * S3 = RT3 (in terms of volume).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Getting 3D printed, face-gluable A, B, T, E and S modules, and phi-sizes thereof, is a supply chain issue.&amp;nbsp; Just In Time principles apply, i.e. why generate more than we need just to build inventory?&amp;nbsp; Have the specific use case already planned for and scheduled.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m thinking of my Saturday Academy class.&amp;nbsp; Others have their other scenarios to plan for.&amp;nbsp; A lot of us have access to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/09/art-car.html&quot;&gt;workspaces like &lt;i&gt;Hedron&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which specialize in custom order manufacturing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Finally, AAB = Mite, or Minimum Tetrahedron.&amp;nbsp; I already have a &lt;i&gt;Pergamon Press&lt;/i&gt; bag full of these guys, a souvenir from a &lt;i&gt;First International Conference on Fullerenes&lt;/i&gt; in Santa Barbara (1993).&amp;nbsp; I met Harold Kroto there and corresponded with him &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2013/04/wanderers-201343.html&quot;&gt;a bit much later&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d rented a convertible.&amp;nbsp; Nick Consoletti rode south with me part of the way.&amp;nbsp; I drove a German guy around, his first time in North America as I recall.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll link to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/10/oil-water-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;another blog entry&lt;/a&gt; mentioning that adventure.&amp;nbsp; Ed Applewhite and Terry Bristol both had roles in helping me pull that one off.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/4674031264/in/album-72157630026830305/&quot; title=&quot;Nick Consoletti&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Nick Consoletti&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4011/4674031264_b90b3b041a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;:: Nick Consoletti with Sarah-dog ::
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1927296923885464308'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1927296923885464308'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/12/supply-chain-logistics.html' title='Supply Chain Logistics'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2112449566028987372</id><published>2017-12-19T10:02:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-21T19:30:25.589-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Codes of Conduct</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/38501489174/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Twilight in Birmingham&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Twilight in Birmingham&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4634/38501489174_4eb536f370.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Given my focus on Anthropology, the A in STEAM (not Art, as some falsely proclaim -- chuckle) I&#39;m keen to see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2014/09/slutwalk-2014.html&quot;&gt;Codes of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;&quot; become more of a focus.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re maybe done with tourism&#39;s first chapter, recreational travel post WW2.&amp;nbsp; That chapter was followed by &quot;tourism&quot; in the &quot;tour of duty&quot; sense, wherein adventurists donned camo and fanned out across the globe in some effort to &quot;fight terrorism&quot;.&amp;nbsp; A lot of these adventurists were of the scaredy-cat variety, only willing to venture forth if heavily armed.&amp;nbsp; The consequences of disobedience could be severe.&amp;nbsp; Lets not pretend their code was democratic in any way.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These days, in brainstorming a &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/04/projects-and-complications.html&quot;&gt;Trucker Exchange Program&lt;/a&gt;, I&#39;m thinking of the various briefings we&#39;d need.&amp;nbsp; You don&#39;t insert personnel into alien cultures with no preparation.&amp;nbsp; Tourists would do that of course, and complain of &quot;culture shock&quot; as a result.&amp;nbsp; What works better is to prep, to train, to do some homework.&amp;nbsp; Remember it&#39;s just a tour, and you get to come home.&amp;nbsp; You&#39;re not a missionary.&amp;nbsp; Your job is not to impose your code of conduct upon others, although you&#39;re certainly welcome to share about your ways, as tourism is a two-way street.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The right to drive a truck anywhere and everywhere, given suitable training, is not a recognized &quot;human right&quot; or anything.&amp;nbsp; Driving is a privilege.&amp;nbsp; Having a mentor, or mentors is key.&amp;nbsp; We all start out as apprentices, in one way or another.&amp;nbsp; Perhaps our driving skills are fantastic, but what about language skills?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Gender relations are especially touchy.&amp;nbsp; How are people to treat one another?&amp;nbsp; A lot of tourists have somewhat &lt;i&gt;Westworld&lt;/i&gt;-like expectations of their hosts.&amp;nbsp; &quot;If we pay you enough, you&#39;ll do what we say&quot; is their attitude.&amp;nbsp; Sex tourists, some wearing camo on duty, are &quot;looking for a good time&quot;.&amp;nbsp; Some aren&#39;t even expecting to pay, as they assume they have the privileges of a dominant culture.&amp;nbsp; This pattern goes way back, with &quot;rape and pillage&quot; but the tip of the iceberg.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2112449566028987372'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2112449566028987372'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/12/codes-of-conduct.html' title='Codes of Conduct'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>