<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211</id><updated>2025-02-27T06:25:58.543-08:00</updated><category term="clojure python REPL ide"/><title type='text'>BizMo Diaries</title><subtitle type='html'>On the road with Global Data</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=1826'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=1801&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=1851&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1905</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1826</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-113252023902256515</id><published>2005-11-20T13:06:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:47.539-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Another Outing</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/lifevirus.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/lifevirus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The above image is from inside a 1966 LIFE magazine (Feb 18, pg. 56). The virus model on the cover is far less sophisticated, but this one suggests a dawning awareness of &quot;the geometry of nature&quot; as Fuller called it, although carbon chemists had long known it as simply &quot;organic&quot; (lots of hexagons).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Scientific American&lt;/span&gt; popularized the new understanding, Fuller&#39;s name was cut from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/virus.html&quot;&gt;final writeup&lt;/a&gt;, in part because editors didn&#39;t think their readers were quite ready to grapple with Bucky&#39;s unsettling &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/modules.html&quot;&gt;A and B module&lt;/a&gt; talk. That was like forty years ago.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I purchased my copy of the aforementioned magazine from a local mom and pop books and periodicals store. I made an extra trip to get cash and spare them the surcharge (also to buy pie and walk Sarah).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recognize the plastic card system gives merchants a way to share the costs of making travel safer and more convenient, bringing more tourism to local establishments. But when shopping close to home, the locals may use a more traditional currency. That&#39;s certainly true here in the Hawthorne District.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113252023902256515'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113252023902256515'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/11/another-outing.html' title='Another Outing'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-113236069683642961</id><published>2005-11-18T16:38:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:47.473-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Parked in PDX</title><content type='html'>Mom got her nine packages today, sent UPS ground in some other blog post.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ulmer and I (likely to be confused by some misspellers) shot the breeze on Google Talk this afternoon (he&#39;s in a desert bizmo, I&#39;m somewhere in the Hawthorne matrix -- lots of wireless coffee shops).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yes, other Wanderers besides Dave and I use IM clients, blogs and so on.  This might help us recruit among a broader demographic, as young folk today seem born with IM skills and can&#39;t fathom why adults wouldn&#39;t have &#39;em.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113236069683642961'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113236069683642961'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/11/parked-in-pdx.html' title='Parked in PDX'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-113193426375143923</id><published>2005-11-13T17:57:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:47.407-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Sunday @ Meeting</title><content type='html'>Quakers of the past reputedly didn&#39;t say &quot;Sunday&quot; -- and in some cases this was true -- as &quot;Sun Day&quot; has a pagan sound, as if we really needed to name days for obvious &lt;span style=&quot;FONT-STYLE: italic&quot;&gt;Sesame Street&lt;/span&gt; figures or whatever. Let&#39;s just call it &quot;First Day&quot; and be done with it. That way, if we exit the solar system, and lose track of the sun... Anyway, it&#39;s not true. I say Sunday all the time, never think twice about it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyway, I was at Quaker Meeting today, wearing my Quaker hat (Paul Kaufman styled it, with a Chicago-style band). Actually, I flung the hat onto the raised platform on the north side of the room and worshipped hatless, as is our custom. I even shared from the heart, but didn&#39;t physically rise to my feet, as our group is still small enough to make standing optional. I told some stories from what I called my &quot;ecumenical weekend&quot; (Catholics and Unitarians, mostly -- I think of Wanderers as more Science than Religion, though it does phase into Philosophy on occasion).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Back at the ranch (not really -- no horses), we had guests over for homework. Our children are studying a combination of topics: coal, fossils, geological columns, layers of sediment. The local Max station under the Zoo has some amazing geological columns, tipped sideways, but going back in time in one direction. Long ago, this area was under a lot of water. A great flood happened, after some giant lake in Montana took off towards the ocean, leaving behind what we later called the Columbia River Gorge (a major feature of our landscape around here -- upriver was ground zero for the Manhatten Project, and OMSI teaches how important it is that we don&#39;t let groundwater fallout percolate out to our river (a lot of radioactive waste was just dumped or poorly contained, because there was a big war going on, and everyone was in a frenetic hurry -- no time for proper planning, and we&#39;re paying for that now)).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ways to mine coal (from the homework project): strip, surface, slope, shaft. Katrina and Rita hurt coal making they say. That explains the higher prices. Sounds reasonable. Coal types: anthracite, bituminous, lignite, sub-bituminous. &quot;Coal is a solid fossil fuel, it forms from decomposed swamp plants.&quot; Yep, that sounds believable.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113193426375143923'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113193426375143923'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/11/sunday-meeting.html' title='Sunday @ Meeting'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-113182222015381510</id><published>2005-11-12T11:01:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:47.345-08:00</updated><title type='text'></title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/chente.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/chente.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;font-size:85%;&quot; &gt;Chenté&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113182222015381510'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113182222015381510'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/11/chent.html' title=''/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-113173438526706629</id><published>2005-11-11T10:35:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:47.277-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Friday @ Matt&#39;s</title><content type='html'>I&#39;m at Matt&#39;s place checking Google videos. I enjoyed this &lt;a href=&quot;http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=-7154354738162008571&quot;&gt;quick tour&lt;/a&gt; of a newspaper production facility.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The IE interface to my control panel for blogging @ Google really sucks on this OS X box -- no editing controls. No wonder Nick is dead in the water (he&#39;s packing an iBook or something). I&#39;ll continue polishing this posting when I get access to a more usable interface. I don&#39;t know if Safari is any better... Nope, sucks as well (not user-friendly).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My own &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/11/google-gets-video.html&quot;&gt;video upload&lt;/a&gt; is still in verification.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why am I at Matt&#39;s place?  Time for the annual gutter cleaning, followed by the ritual meal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&#39;s Veterans&#39; Day today.  The flags are in place up and down Hawthorne.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113173438526706629'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113173438526706629'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/11/friday-matts.html' title='Friday @ Matt&#39;s'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-113156140660727946</id><published>2005-11-09T21:57:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-06-06T16:32:34.559-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wednesday @ Pauling House</title><content type='html'>Setting: two tapes filled, camera now rewinding (I was cameraman, made lots of mistakes); participants are right now discussing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.answers.com/funereal&amp;amp;r=67&quot;&gt;funereal&lt;/a&gt; customs, cemetery design and so on, having already covered transportation, economic and social rules, many other matters -- all this in the context of Guatemala, per Don&#39;s slide show.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On break, Dick Pugh offered to do similar travelogues (Trans-Siberian railroad for example). We&#39;re Wanderers, so yeah, this makes some sense. On the other hand, we&#39;ve typically integrated more science-minded analysis, dealt less in raw intelligence. What&#39;s the status of Guatemala&#39;s electrical grid I wonder. Or we could just lighten up and do more anthro -- more philo too while we&#39;re at it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Don was embedded with a former student and family, Don being retired faculty, Mt. Hood Community College. His student runs a restaurant serving USA-style dishes (pizza and such). Don learned a great deal on this three week sojourn, his first foray outside El Norte. He performed marvelously, and brought back a ton of interesting insights and information. Guatemala is definitely a happening place. I was especially taken with Chenté, a street smart dog in the family.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ve got a bid request in with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bullseyedisc.com/&quot;&gt;Bullseyedisc&lt;/a&gt; to see if our tape collection might be transcribed to DVD at an affordable cost. We&#39;ll recycle the Hi-8 tapes, minting 3 DVDs per talk to start: copy to the presenter(s) of a talk; copy to the in-house library; copy for off-site backup, Iron Mountain style. We may take up a collection, once the bid is in (likely the $80 or so in the coffee fund won&#39;t cover it -- I&#39;ve got a stash of like 25 tapes by this time, including the two of Doug Strain).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nancy joined Don and I for lunch on the boat where I got cell calls from France (school business) and from Mom in Washington, DC (I dropped her at the airport before Wanderers).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tonight I met up with Dick Pugh again, also Wanderers McCarty and McGown, at the Sigma Xi meeting at PSU (Brother Guy for the Vatican re Pluto et al (hey, I vote we name this new 10th planet, grain of sand thingy &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.google.com/images?hl=en&amp;amp;q=diana%20mythology&amp;amp;btnG=Google+Search&amp;amp;sa=N&amp;amp;tab=wi&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Diana&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; -- or maybe &lt;a href=&quot;http://images.google.com/images?svnum=10&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;q=coyote+mythology&amp;amp;btnG=Search&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Coyote&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; after some Native American)).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113156140660727946'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113156140660727946'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/11/wednesday-pauling-house.html' title='Wednesday @ Pauling House'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-113141043032821524</id><published>2005-11-07T17:06:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:47.145-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Monday @ Pauling House</title><content type='html'>Wardwell is burning CD-Rs with pictures taken in Guatemala on his Canon.  We just purchased those from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mmt.org/about_us/fredmeyer/&quot;&gt;Fred Meyer&#39;s&lt;/a&gt;, with a parking lot on the roof (Google Earth shows it clearly -- across from the red-roofed Jiffy Lube, 39th and Hawthorne). We also bought an extension cord (8&#39;) to go from the wall to the power strip (grounded outlet), into which strip are plugged: Don&#39;s iMac laptop, my Toshiba running WinXP, my Optoma small footprint projector. We&#39;re running routine tests to make sure we&#39;re ready for his presentations. Don and Patrick (works here) are chatting in another room. Outside: dusk, still pretty light, 4:39 PM.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113141043032821524'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113141043032821524'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/11/monday-pauling-house.html' title='Monday @ Pauling House'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-113112434154798608</id><published>2005-11-04T09:31:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:47.081-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Physics Emergent (ISEPP lecture)</title><content type='html'>Physicist and Nobel laureate Dr. Robert Laughlin delivered the kickoff ISEPP lecture at the Schnitz last night. He projected a series of hand drawings (he&#39;s pretty good -- plans to take up color in a next life if he gets one) and talked about The Frontier (archetype) in science: yes there is one, but a lot of times we look for it in the wrong direction.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The word &quot;law&quot; has two connotations in English: physical laws that set the stage, and social agreements that govern the acting. Laws of the first type get ascribed to God, at least in Judeo-Christian thinking, and so we get the picture that God supplies the foundations or fundamentals, and complex life forms such as ourselves build atop this set-in-stone framework.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;However, what&#39;s becoming more apparent in science is that physical laws may be emergent in the sense that their formulation and description only makes sense in the context of complex aggregates, assemblies or &quot;piles&quot; (Laughlin showed a pile of apples -- the picture had other plot elements I won&#39;t go into). The phenomena these rules describe simply vanish at more inward levels. So we get this hierarchy of &quot;grammars&quot; [my word choice].&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Later, after dinner at the Heathman, I stepped out from behind the camera to propose this analogy: say a novelist is bound to follow all the rules of grammar [I&#39;ll add proper spelling], but in order to sell books, knows to incorporate suspense, to follow other rules for strong plot development; nothing about the rules of grammar predict or force a novel to be any good (that&#39;s up to the writer) i.e. these higher order rules are emergent.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Laughlin found this a pretty good analogy with the following caveat: he doesn&#39;t see any need to complement the mindless automaticity of quantum mechanics with some new principle of Agency (the writer). He&#39;s OK having his Universe run on autopilot, with emergent/synergetic behaviors, yes, but still a machine in the final analysis (&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occam%27s_Razor&quot;&gt;Occam&#39;s Razor&lt;/a&gt; at work).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One practical consequence of emergent law (in physics, not just in biology and society) is we can&#39;t advance science through thought experiment alone. Measurement remains a primary source of new discoveries, and this feeds our appetite for new and better instruments (e.g. earth-focused satellites). Our sphere of scientific relevance, at any &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/omnihalo.html&quot;&gt;frequency&lt;/a&gt;, is bounded by our ability to measure.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For this reason, Laughlin sees string theory (about the very small) as only quasi-scientific, given it hasn&#39;t yet given us doable experiments that would make it falsifiable. A lot of cosmology (about the very large) is like that too. A chief purpose and benefit of such twilight zone science fiction is it helps us raise funds for new machinery so that the horizons of real science might be expanded to new frontiers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of Nobel laureates, we remember Dr. Richard Smalley, a co-discoverer of fullerene, who died recently. And speaking of scientists who have died recently, we remember Dr. George S. Hammond, chemist par excellance, and a Wanderer.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113112434154798608'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113112434154798608'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/11/physics-emergent-isepp-lecture.html' title='Physics Emergent (ISEPP lecture)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-113072232679938483</id><published>2005-10-30T21:00:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:47.002-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Good Night and Good Luck (movie review)</title><content type='html'>George Clooney, writer and director, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cpj.org/awards97/fred.html&quot;&gt;Fred Friendly&lt;/a&gt; in this film, takes us back to a world of monochrome TV, excessive smoking, and people trying to stay sane (which is why the film is timely, and why the packed audience applauded at the end). It&#39;s a film about courage and integrity. Mom loved it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A theme here is television might be used more effectively to wake people from their soaps and sitcoms and give them a bigger dose of reality. However, those trafficing in &quot;reality&quot; seem prone to paranoia and keep taking us into nightmarish episodes. Maybe more politicians should be watching &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Rome&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Extras&lt;/span&gt; on HBO, instead of inflicting their twisted brand of theater on the rest of us.  Maybe we need &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;more&lt;/span&gt; quality fiction, not less.  We could make it &quot;reality fiction&quot; -- like this film.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A couple years ago I rented the Ed Murrow vs. Joe McCarthy tapes from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moviemadnessvideo.com/&quot;&gt;Movie Madness&lt;/a&gt;, having been too young to appreciate these events at the time. Last night I took the new projector over to Larry&#39;s house, where he shared &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0146309/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Thirteen Days&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,  about the Cuban missile crisis, one of his favorite films (I shared &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120907/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;eXistenZ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, one of mine).  My reaction to these &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Great_Game&quot;&gt;great game&lt;/a&gt;&quot; scenarios (ongoing):  why should such a tiny cast get to arrogate so much power to script world events?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If an apocalyptic showdown between &quot;great powers&quot; is what turns you on, just rent the DVD. Either that, or think of some better role playing games, with more &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/bworks.html&quot;&gt;interesting and constructive props&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113072232679938483'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113072232679938483'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/10/good-night-and-good-luck-movie-review.html' title='Good Night and Good Luck (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-113038063124913437</id><published>2005-10-26T20:08:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:46.939-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Rambling On</title><content type='html'>I missed much of the Wanderers meeting today at the Linus Pauling house, as I had a routine doc appointment (my annual physical). I got back for the tail end of a rambling discussion of the Israel-Palestine situation, the Canadian health care system, the tax advantages of S- corporations and so on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We didn&#39;t have an organized presentation today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jim brought fresh-picked chantrelles again, $15/lb. at the local grocery store. I reported on Don&#39;s communications from Guatemala (so far so good). Patrick&#39;s wife might present on supercomputer applications in a few weeks (she used to work for Sandia).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In today&#39;s &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Oregonian&lt;/span&gt; (page D1): Google gives a $350K grant to PSU-OSU to for development of open source software (Google uses a lot of it, including Linux, Apache, Python and more).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This evening, I drove mom down to the AFSC-organized reading of soldier and civilian names, American and Iraqi war dead. I was glad to reconnect (however briefly) with local staff I&#39;ve worked with (Alice, Marco, Pam). I brought some decaf to the Metcalfs, MMM stalwarts, who were holding the Quaker sign. Bruce Huntwork sat next to me for awhile. A few hundred showed up, in the park between City Hall and the Federal Building. My camera fell out of its case onto the bricks, but didn&#39;t break (yay).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m making rather slow headway in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Quake 4&lt;/span&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2004-December/004187.html&quot;&gt;Les&lt;/a&gt;, recently back from China and Korea, would no doubt have finished it by now.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113038063124913437'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/113038063124913437'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/10/rambling-on.html' title='Rambling On'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-112996675278023322</id><published>2005-10-22T00:40:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:46.871-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Shopping Trip</title><content type='html'>Friend Andy Cross of MMM invited me to join him on a trip to Fry&#39;s Electronics this Friday morning, a big box vendor in Wilsonville that used to be named Incredible Universe when owned by Tandy (Radio Shack). I sometimes call it Mecca, given its importance in my reality, and how often I make the pilgrimage. That no doubt sounds &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.answers.com/sacrilegious&amp;r=67&quot;&gt;sacrilegious&lt;/a&gt; to some, but I figure electronics engineers have done God&#39;s will at least as effectively as priests (not that these are mutually exclusive occupations).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Andy was picking up a whole new system (a Sony desktop). I grabbed an internal DVD burner (16x +/- R, 4x DL, 5x DVD-RAM) for like $45 including mail-in rebate. My first backup was only 1x (very slow) but I don&#39;t think the new device was to blame (I was off having a beer -- next time I&#39;ll monitor more closely). I considered the more expensive Plextor, a brand with a loyal following, but unlike some Pentagoners I don&#39;t insist on gold plating.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also bought &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Quake 4&lt;/span&gt; for $37.99, a choice some Quakers will question. Like, what&#39;s a pacifist like me doing with an M-rated game (&quot;Blood and Gore, Intense Violence, Strong Language&quot;)? I&#39;m actually OK with mythical mayhem. I&#39;m this Marine fighting Strogg, with all humanity united behind me and my buddies depending on my prowess in battle. Thankfully it&#39;s only a simulation, as I die often.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112996675278023322'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112996675278023322'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/10/shopping-trip.html' title='Shopping Trip'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-112974850589922791</id><published>2005-10-19T00:16:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:46.793-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Back to Work</title><content type='html'>Following that fun vacation to McMinnville and environs, I needed to get back to various projects simmering on my metaphorical stove (my real electric one has 4 burners, only 3 usable, plus a working oven).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Front burner: Sam Lanahan would like to meet Ken Snelson, given Flextegrity is entering the patent literature in close proximity to Ken&#39;s and Bucky&#39;s work As a software engineer, I&#39;m suspicious patent abuse will gum up the works, but that doesn&#39;t mean I don&#39;t recognize good literature. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.python-in-business.org/ep2005/talk.chtml?talk=5769&amp;track=653&quot;&gt;Patent libraries&lt;/a&gt; are goldmines for historians of engineering.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/snelson/&quot;&gt;Ken&lt;/a&gt; phoned me re my recent email proposing Sam and I fly out for a visit, just as I was going into a meeting on another high priority project: keeping the flow of clinical data to my health mission client uninterrupted, as we transition from vendor A to vendor B in the cath labs over the next few months.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Project 3: &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/wittgenstein-dialognet/message/5442&quot;&gt;the RBF-LW bridge&lt;/a&gt;, a work in progress in philosophy world (I&#39;m a critical path manager on this one).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Project 4: wiring more synergetics into K-12 &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/thread.jspa?threadID=1268070&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot;&gt;CS-informed math&lt;/a&gt; (CS = computer science). I need more help from television on this front. Geometry lends itself to communication by that medium -- looking forward to more in high def TV and DVD. My work with Russ (he just sent some new EIG files) comes under this heading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And last but not least, Project 5:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2005-October/005413.html&quot;&gt;preparing to teach&lt;/a&gt; Python in a Portland Public School (a 9 week stint, not counting school holidays and vacations).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;... other projects, too numerous to mention, will need to go unlisted at this juncture (I read a lot of blogs, journalism and stuff, watch some TV, but that&#39;s more play than work, plus doesn&#39;t pay the bills).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Precessionally (tangentially, thinking more in terms of side effects), the above projects are also about putting 4D Solutions on wheels, in a bizmo, e.g. when I go on the road more, I&#39;ll still need to VPN into client networks, do source code editing and such (which reminds me, I need to stop writing in my blog and do some more POV-Ray renderings for Sam &#39;n LaJean).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112974850589922791'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112974850589922791'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/10/back-to-work.html' title='Back to Work'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-112939311569307829</id><published>2005-10-15T09:10:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:46.730-08:00</updated><title type='text'>From Evergreen&#39;s Airplane Collection</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/mig1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/mig1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;A MiG&lt;br /&gt;Photo by K. Urner&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Per our tour guide: the MiG&#39;s guns pointed upward 15 degrees for some reason, so the way to avoid being shot at was to fly very close to the ground. If you were shot at anyway, because the MiG was chasing you upside down, the pilot was probably Russian.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112939311569307829'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112939311569307829'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/10/from-evergreens-airplane-collection.html' title='From Evergreen&#39;s Airplane Collection'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-112939260442531130</id><published>2005-10-15T08:58:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:46.667-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Our Hotel&#39;s First Manager</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/tomwhite.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/tomwhite.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;font-size:85%;&quot; &gt;Portrait of Tom White&lt;br /&gt;photo by K. Urner w/ Olympus Stylus 500&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The inscription on the wall next to this painting reads:  &quot;Tom White gave life to the hotel in 1905 and guided it through its initial quarter century.  A bit of a Renaissance man, Tom was well-read, a devoted member of the Masons, and very active in community work.  He was an excellent cook, a skilled carpenter and loved working on his farm.&quot;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112939260442531130'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112939260442531130'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/10/our-hotels-first-manager.html' title='Our Hotel&#39;s First Manager'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-112924561539219714</id><published>2005-10-13T17:19:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-08-27T23:27:23.348-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Hotel Oregon</title><content type='html'>Dawn and I did a retreat at Hotel Oregon recently. That&#39;s in the small town of McMinnville, in the heart of some wider sprawl engineered by a freeway- and mall-minded culture. We stayed in the first manager&#39;s bedroom, Tom White&#39;s. Yes, another Mason, like many departed in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mcmenamins.com/&quot;&gt;McMenemin&#39;s world&lt;/a&gt;.  We learned of more Masons at the Grand Lodge in Forest Grove on another visit.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then we visited the Spruce Goose and friends, at &lt;a href=&quot;http://wweek.com/editorial/3315/8562/&quot;&gt;Evergreen Aviation&lt;/a&gt;. Our tour guide and former F4 pilot was none too pleased his bombing mission got canceled that day Hanoi Jane was in town. Fonda&#39;s visit recalls the early days after WWII, when the OSS thought Ho&#39;d be a fine leader of a Jeffersonian democracy (Ho thought so too) if only the French empire would pull back, which it eventually started doing (Japan&#39;s empire had already been pushed back, thanks in part to this new US-Vietnamese alliance).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then LAWCAP (e.g. Dulles &amp;amp; Dulles) decided to rebalance the powers by joining forces with former enemies Germany and Japan, now vanquished and ripe for rebuilding (see &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;JFK&lt;/span&gt; by Col. L. Fletcher Prouty). In Vietnam, the &quot;quiet Americans&quot; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=6182753&amp;amp;tstart=0#reply-tree&quot;&gt;Capitalism&#39;s Invisible Army&lt;/a&gt;) started taking over, to fight an Evil Empire. Thus began WWIII, or the Cold War as they called it, in which many more millions would die, especially in Southeast Asia. That was before the Grunch came along (e.g. Fuller &amp;amp; Co.) and another rebalancing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Evergreen also has an SR-71 Blackbird &lt;a href=&quot;http://wweek.com/editorial/3315/8562/&quot;&gt;spy plane&lt;/a&gt;, which could read license plates and sense where the bodies of migrant farm workers were buried in California. Very cool. Its competition, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/02/u2.html&quot;&gt;the U &quot;shot down&quot; 2&lt;/a&gt;, is still in service, exposing miles of film to targets of interest.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I especially recommend the Hotel Oregon&#39;s rooftop pub and restaurant (we took the stairs, but there&#39;s an elevator somewhere). Park in the 2-story garage opposite the police station on 5th. And be sure to check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macktheater.com/history/&quot;&gt;Mack Theater&lt;/a&gt; directly across 3rd street to see what&#39;s showing. Dawn and I saw &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0418773/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Junebug&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112924561539219714'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112924561539219714'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/10/hotel-oregon.html' title='Hotel Oregon'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-112882716217513375</id><published>2005-10-08T21:49:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2007-01-16T16:58:06.804-08:00</updated><title type='text'>The Corpse Bride (movie review)</title><content type='html'>Many critics declaim against this movie&#39;s supposedly shallow plot (my wife included), but I figure the secret to this fairy tale is to see but one bride and groom to be, and the projections they go through.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The girl thinks maybe a parasitical money-grubbing a-hole is out to get her, like the one that broke her heart before, but this new guy seems different.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The new guy, meantime, is your typical morbid poet, worried about death and decay, and how this gorgeous girl is also this amazing like dead thing, i.e. so absurdly physical.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So yeah, the marriage rehearsals leading up to the real deal are seemingly interminable. The projected parental marriages aren&#39;t very encouraging either. I can see where some young folks might pause for thought before tying the knot.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Like &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/04/robots-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Robots&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, this film is all about a &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;look&lt;/span&gt;, and that look ain&#39;t just window dressing or something irrelevant. No, that&#39;s a looking glass look, a fun house mirror, a lens -- an artifact storytellers have worked on and polished, and handed down across centuries. Many proud artists, many forgotten graves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The musical numbers:  also strictly by the book.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There&#39;re only so many ways to do macabre, and make a funny family flick at the same time  (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/find?q=addams%20family;s=all&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Addams Family&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is another).  This way works.  Please accept my gratitude.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112882716217513375'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112882716217513375'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/10/corpse-bride-movie-review.html' title='The Corpse Bride (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-112814193464013336</id><published>2005-09-30T21:39:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:46.450-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Talk Like A Pirate Day</title><content type='html'>&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/1600/pirateday.0.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1134/545/320/pirateday.0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;font-size:85%;&quot; &gt;Pirate ordering a cheeseburger&lt;br /&gt;at the Island Cafe, 19 Sept 2005&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;(by K. Urner, Olympus Stylus 500,&lt;br /&gt;brightness/contrast adjusted)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112814193464013336'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112814193464013336'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/talk-like-pirate-day.html' title='Talk Like A Pirate Day'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-112810993302781467</id><published>2005-09-30T13:06:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2009-07-13T14:04:57.587-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Rethinking the CyberBookMobile Concept</title><content type='html'>Based a lot on Ulmer&#39;s reality check, I&#39;m recognizing my state of the art bizmo fleet is going to need better infrastructure. I just don&#39;t have the skills necessary to operate a rig like Dave&#39;s -- would need a crew of grannies to keep it long haul operational.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Per my alternative model lifestyle, I&#39;d be less inclined to hold tightly to one bizmo of my own, and more thinking to check one out from a garage closer to a point of interest. After mission control uplinks my mission, I&#39;ll swoop into Town A and do some of the requested curriculum stuff, leaving behind a local school faculty thinking more about sphere packings, hypertoons, Pythonic mathematics. Lone Ranger type stuff (&quot;nicely done Kemosabe&quot; -- like when Don deftly parks his &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Meliptus&lt;/span&gt; alongside the Island Cafe).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is a healthy memepool for sure, but should be no one&#39;s exclusive diet, nor is it, even for me. However, my bizmo will run software uniquely customized for my brand of scholarship and teaching/outreach -- not because I&#39;m all that tied to a specific bizmo, but because the basic design is highly configurable through downlinking OS level stuff and/or special purpose applications.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the outside, different bizmos may have different decals (I&#39;m hoping we&#39;ll be seeing some from Google, whether I&#39;m a driver or not). Those with the same decals will likely be running a lot of software in common (reflective of whatever corporate cultures, e.g. Mentor Graphics).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The decals themselves may be swappable, in the same way a Tri-Met bus, though advertising its route with lit signage, is perfectly able to run a different route on another day. In my case, my decals (e.g. 4D Solutions logo) might follow me around, maybe in the form of a rear view mirror dongle or glove box credential. The same physical bizmo might return to the same electronic gate on consecutive evenings, and gain access the one night but not the other, because the decals, running code, crew and driver, could have all changed overnight, not a big deal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Basically, a geek checks the thing out of the garage, and then sucks down her favorite kernel (one of several), possibly similar to what wuz running in her last bizmo, or maybe in one she&#39;s nostalgic about (like running Win98 in 2020) but now the target points are different, so a different garage was accessed (same deal with the rental cars: return at the airport, like to PDX or whatever).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On another note (and speaking of The Island Cafe):  last September 19 was &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/09/talk-like-pirate.html&quot;&gt;Talk Like a Pirate Day&lt;/a&gt;, and by nightfall, we had a full cast of free spirits in properly piratical attire, right down to the plastic parrot this one guy had. A boat sailed to and fro in the channel, setting off a miniature ceremonial cannon, reminding me of the curious opening to &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Confusion&lt;/span&gt;, sequel to &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Quicksilver&lt;/span&gt; in the 3-part &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Baroque Cycle&lt;/span&gt; by Neal Stephenson (Jules, Don&#39;s grandson, Nirel&#39;s son, is another &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nealstephenson.com/&quot;&gt;Stephenson&lt;/a&gt; fan).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112810993302781467'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112810993302781467'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/rethinking-cyberbookmobile-concept.html' title='Rethinking the CyberBookMobile Concept'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-112792397713541581</id><published>2005-09-28T09:40:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:46.322-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Dave&#39;s Bizmo</title><content type='html'>Dave, age 59, is presenting &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Dave&#39;s Life&lt;/span&gt; this Wednesday morning, about his on-the-road lifestyle. His slides break it down into Motivation, Equipment, Infrastructure, Monthly Costs and so on. The lifestyle depends on having good telecommunications and maintenance skills.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Given the complexity of these rigs &quot;if you&#39;re not mechanically adept, you&#39;re dead meat&quot; -- even RV-driving grannies have to learn basic troubleshooting, often by consulting Internet user groups (there&#39;ll be one for every component). Schematics aren&#39;t necessarily available, and dealerships may have long waiting lists.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dave avoids RV parks like the plague, uses GIS/GPS to locate suitable public lands (BLM, state, national forest, military -- or maybe a Wal-Mart parking lot). This land is your land, this land is my land. He pulls a trailer containing a Yamaha Mountain Max snowmobile (used mostly in the spring) and Suzuki DRZ400 dual sport motorcycle. The bizmo itself is a 33&#39; Beaver Diesel Pusher motorhome. He&#39;s self-sufficient in terms of fuel, food, water, power, for weeks at a time. His utilities (fuel, satellite, insurance etc.) run about $825 a month, plus maybe $200 for food with an emphasis on fresh vegetables (Safeway a good source).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Before 2000, when GPS was deliberately inaccurate, Dave smashed his snowmobile on the side of Mount St. Helens, thinking he was on a trail he wasn&#39;t. Driving heavy equipment, alone, in desolate, erratic terrain, is highly dangerous. Dave rarely takes these unnecessary risks. He stores his camp sites, drive routes, other points of interest in GIS software. Given over two years of living this way full time, he&#39;s got a gold mine of information in his database. His photo diary, shared with a small group of subscribers, is likewise a valuable record of his adventures.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112792397713541581'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112792397713541581'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/daves-bizmo.html' title='Dave&#39;s Bizmo'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-112753669680411167</id><published>2005-09-25T12:20:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:46.183-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers Retreat</title><content type='html'>I showed up at the Blanchard Education Service Center today to make some brief remarks on behalf of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.koreducators.org/&quot;&gt;Koreducators&#39;&lt;/a&gt; charter school proposal.  Adam &amp; Co. certainly have their ducks in a row.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Retreat:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Day one (9/23):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We used &lt;a href=&quot;http://earth.google.com/&quot;&gt;earth.google.com&lt;/a&gt; software and projector to zoom in on the Pauling House, plus visit other points of interest (Gothenburg isn&#39;t highly resolved yet -- didn&#39;t find Chalmers). Jon Bunce grilled Dave Ulmer on his book (unpublished), having given it a close read. Nancy joined us enroute to another retreat at Mt. Angel with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salvationhistory.com/mission/staff/frdriscollCV.cfm&quot;&gt;Father Driscoll&lt;/a&gt;. We looked at slides I took of Julian&#39;s unveiling of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Heart of Steel&lt;/span&gt; in Lake Oswego, and slides of Dave&#39;s many bizmo adventures. The bizmo itself is parked out back, receiving satellite TV about hurricane Rita. Downloaded from iTunes and played:&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt; We Didn&#39;t Start the Fire&lt;/span&gt; (Billy Joel), played a bogus game of chess.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Day two (9/24):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Briefed by Dawn on &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Smallville&lt;/span&gt; developments (season 3), cartoons, Rita (weather news), breakfast on Hawthorne (Tabor Hill Cafe), helped Consoletti with inheritance fax, gave Ulmer my 9/14 letter (feedback on his book) while he projected the DVD &lt;a href=&quot;http://imdb.com/title/tt0087803/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;1984&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from his laptop (I didn&#39;t watch too closely this time, believe I&#39;ve seen it before -- like &lt;a href=&quot;http://imdb.com/title/tt0088846/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Brazil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Dave backed up the bizmo by 6&#39;, enough to see the HDTV satellite behind the tree. Jon &amp; Don off to check out a dishwasher (mechanical problem). Allen&#39;s here -- he and I went out for Thai (Rick joined us for Thai take-out last night). I did some &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2005-September/005225.html&quot;&gt;more messing about&lt;/a&gt; with &quot;math through programming.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Big summit on future of Wanderers in the evening. Terry Bristol, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.analyticanimations.com/&quot;&gt;David Feinstein&lt;/a&gt;, Steve Bergman, Audrey Lee, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.symmetrics.com/architects/people/people_barton.asp&quot;&gt;Pat Barton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://highmars.org/xpcup/xpcart01.html&quot;&gt;Gus Frederick&lt;/a&gt; joined our group. Lots of discussion, lots of web sites projected. What did we decide? Terry is working on getting us a server with a fat pipe. Doug Strain&#39;s interest in peace work helps define us.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Day three (9/25):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Woke up with Sarah in the bed (sorry Dawn, I know the rules), another &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Smallville&lt;/span&gt; briefing from Tara (still season 3). Drove mom to Quaker meetinghouse (former ESI building) in Razz (our razzberry-colored Subaru wagon). Joined Dave &amp; Don in the bizmo for long HDNet pans from a helicopter over New Orleans (some amazingly cool cemeteries). Even spookier would be HDNet over Chernobyl (saw that dare devil Russian chic&#39;s fast motorcyle diary -- likewise amazingly cool). Thanh Thao has been a source of most meals. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shatters.net/celestia/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Celestia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href=&quot;http://stellarium.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Stellarium&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; = an answer to my prayers. I missed the impromptu presentation by &lt;a href=&quot;http://portland.freeskool.org/&quot;&gt;portland.freeskool.org&lt;/a&gt;. Office Depot, printer madness. Guests from South Africa (the home scene). Julian came by with both children (I projected my slides from the unveiling). Jon solved the story problem (about a man and his dog).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112753669680411167'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112753669680411167'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/wanderers-retreat.html' title='Wanderers Retreat'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-112762547598876171</id><published>2005-09-24T23:19:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:46.246-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Retarded Design</title><content type='html'>At the other end of the spectrum: yes, the closed and systematic formal expression of Universe is incomplete, always tantalizingly improvable. But the balancing inexplicable complement, considered from an all too human point of view, is slow-like, not God-like. We&#39;re mortally, fatally stupid &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; (good news) the generalized principles are on our side -- was Fuller&#39;s view. The eternal works to save us from ourselves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Human intelligence, even at its best, is a form of retardation (a lagging), an abberation, which plunges us into the consequences of limited knowledge, limited speed. But that&#39;s not synonymous with any condemnation to hell. If we accept our limitations, yet continue to faithfully participate, knowing we&#39;re not the veritable impersonation of omniscience, we&#39;ll likely still do OK. Integrity matters.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What doesn&#39;t so much matter is whether you posit, in the sense of imagine, idolize, that superior intelligence. Either way, you/I ain&#39;t it. So believers, cut those who don&#39;t some slack. Non-believers, reciprocate. Either way, we&#39;re retarded, yet exercising what powers of intelligence we might. We shine as brightly as we&#39;re able, dim though we may be. Integrity matters.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112762547598876171'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112762547598876171'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/retarded-design.html' title='Retarded Design'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-112726109294989640</id><published>2005-09-20T17:02:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:46.115-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Happy Birthday Dawn Wicca</title><content type='html'>We&#39;re so fortunate to have you in our lives.  Here&#39;s to a kind and talented spouse, mother, daughter, friend, sibling -- also a fighter in more ways than one.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112726109294989640'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112726109294989640'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/happy-birthday-dawn-wicca.html' title='Happy Birthday Dawn Wicca'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-112658860306341848</id><published>2005-09-12T23:17:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:46.040-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Batman Begins (movie review)</title><content type='html'>This movie is now playing at the Bagdad in 2nd run (cheaper admission, profits made in beer &amp;amp; pizza), but I&#39;ve so far resisted the temptation to see it again. Dawn and I both enjoyed it quite a bit when we saw it in 1st run. Really the perfect batman film, plus the sequels have already been made, so the sequence feels complete. More could be done, sure, but this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0372784/&quot;&gt;particular one&lt;/a&gt; admirably captures Metropolis in high gothic style, within a dark story against an east-meets-west backdrop. Pretty sophisticated stuff, for a comic book movie about a fictional superhero. Plus I heard Terry Gross interview Christian Bale on NPR. Very informative.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112658860306341848'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112658860306341848'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/batman-begins-movie-review.html' title='Batman Begins (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-112648207370579016</id><published>2005-09-11T16:41:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:45.977-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Wedding Anniversary</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/img/254/1836/640/P9110066.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;border: 1px solid rgb(0, 0, 0); margin: 2px;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/img/254/1836/320/P9110066.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Photo by Brenna Nally&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Crystal Springs Rhododendron Garden&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dawn and I were married c/o Multnomah Monthly Meeting on September 11, 1993. We stopped by the wedding venue this afternoon, after enjoying a potluck with Friends at Laurelhurst Park.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112648207370579016'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112648207370579016'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/wedding-anniversary.html' title='Wedding Anniversary'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-112629449966427616</id><published>2005-09-09T12:34:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2006-11-15T11:43:45.913-08:00</updated><title type='text'>A Gothenburg Incredible</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/img/254/1836/640/P6300036.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;border: 1px solid rgb(0, 0, 0); margin: 2px;&quot; src=&quot;http://photos1.blogger.com/img/254/1836/320/P6300036.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center; font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&quot;A  boyfriend for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownlog.dreamhost.com/photooftheweek/2001/2001q1/20010318.htm&quot;&gt;Portlandia&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;br /&gt;(photo by Kirby)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112629449966427616'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/112629449966427616'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/gothenburg-incredible.html' title='A Gothenburg Incredible'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>