<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211</id><updated>2025-02-27T06:25:58.543-08:00</updated><category term="clojure python REPL ide"/><title type='text'>BizMo Diaries</title><subtitle type='html'>On the road with Global Data</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=1051'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=1026&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=1076&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1905</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1051</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5043519765896654898</id><published>2011-07-30T18:11:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2022-12-29T18:42:36.340-08:00</updated><title type='text'>BizMotica</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157627320573000&quot; title=&quot;LW36&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/6026/5993336260_679d102a0f_w.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;LW36&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;:: hb2u lw ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One of our staffers left her computer / bag aboard the Max from the airport (Red Line).  Honest Oregonians disturbed it not, and it joined a gated community facility, a forlorn kind of Toy Story place where many lonely toys are not found.  This bag was though:  I retrieved it in the &quot;escape pod&quot; Lindsey used to eject from the State of Georgia (her birthday today, having a small dinner party, Melody our cook).  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
My route was from &lt;a href=&quot;http://dir.groups.yahoo.com/group/WittrsEX/message/4576&quot;&gt;the marina&lt;/a&gt; adjacent PDX down Columbia Blvd to Lombard, into St. John&#39;s, over to Hwy. 30 past Sauvie Island to Cornelius Pass, up into Jenkins/158th area, near the &lt;i&gt;Costco&lt;/i&gt;. Same way back.  Quite a good drive.  The Nissan Maxima, performed well.  Lots of building going on.  Intel expanding etc.  Yet lots of rolling countryside, lots of farms.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
We saw them all off at the Max again this morning, bound for divergent destinations.  Staff is spread out.  Sebastopol was like a northern border with Russia in the early days, with Hispanic mission based culture coming up from the south.  The Bay Area was a center of contention.  Fun history to know, if you think of that Russian Imperial Museum in Minneapolis, housed in a mission-style building.  What does it all mean?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
I shared some some history too, learned from Les (&lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2010/11/happy-thanksgiving.html&quot;&gt;CIO&lt;/a&gt;) about those bad ass Haida, and the Hudson Bay Company&#39;s response:  to import lots of Hawaiian muscle to keep pushing a lucrative fur trade.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Those Euros couldn&#39;t get enough furs, having already managed their property unsustainably.  The &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/03/wanderers-2010316.html&quot;&gt;Doctrine of Discovery&lt;/a&gt; allowed for title transfer into church holdings, of vast tracts of valuable land.  Much of this was protected by a lay populace of faithful, willing to champion their ethnicity in a kind of zero sum game. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Anyway, Hawaiian names decorate the coastal areas, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/07/touring-facilities.html&quot;&gt;Camano Island&lt;/a&gt; for example.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Dignity Village&lt;/i&gt; was on the itinerary again, this time from the marina, not the airport. I refer to it as &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/01/metropolitan-talk.html&quot;&gt;Epcot West&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, America&#39;s best futuristic thinking on display.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Later, I played some &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/04/idiocracy-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Idiocracy&lt;/i&gt; again&lt;/a&gt;, while picking up the living room, dusting and so forth.  I even changed where I hung some of the pictures.  OSCON has clearly changed my mind in some ways.  That&#39;s what circuses do sometimes:  they expand one&#39;s idea of what&#39;s possible, by showing one freaks and geeks of various types, in a fun house of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2011-August/010410.html&quot;&gt;crazy-making mirrors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/61451741@N02/6149070419/&quot; title=&quot;vase09 by 生活童話, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;vase09&quot; height=&quot;118&quot; src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6155/6149070419_6087eb01db_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;click for author&#39;s photostream&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5043519765896654898'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5043519765896654898'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/07/bizmotica.html' title='BizMotica'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3320052848314138488</id><published>2011-07-27T10:57:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2013-03-14T17:16:14.875-07:00</updated><title type='text'>OSCON 2011 Continues</title><content type='html'>No bizmos at OSCON &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/08/oscon-day-2-wanderers.html&quot;&gt;this year&lt;/a&gt;.  Maybe someday we&#39;ll get one into the exhibit hall, a small version, but an open source one (open hardware, not just software).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
The keynotes today were somewhat ironic, with Microsoft seeing the cloud as another &quot;commercial software&quot; environment, with Windows Azure the latest back end.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
The announcement that it supports PHP, other open source, was perhaps underwhelming, somewhat like announcing a car with an &quot;ignition key&quot; as a feature.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
The next public splash came from Nebula, with the CEO whipping up enthusiasm for and industry-supported convergence of &lt;a href=&quot;http://openstack.org/&quot;&gt;OpenStack&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://opencompute.org/&quot;&gt;OpenCompute&lt;/a&gt;.  The goal:  generic cloud services built with open hardware and software at the core.  Was it a coincidence that Al Gore appeared in the promo, and a forklift was used as a prop to wheel out a rack?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
F151 was a deep silo discussion of CONNECT and Aurion, presented by the Alembic Foundation. CONNECT is a project to facilitate the exchange of medical information (HIE).  Hey, the guy said &quot;default&quot; -- that&#39;s the first time I&#39;ve heard anyone mention the WDC-based soap opera going on these days.  It&#39;s buzz word city in here.  Not clear to me Lower48 are where it&#39;s happening these days, where electronic medical data is concerned.  Too bureaucratized, even though we&#39;re talking big money. Count me a skeptic.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Chairman Steve gave awarded &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oscon.com/oscon2011/public/schedule/detail/21310&quot;&gt;the Frank Willison award&lt;/a&gt; to Georg Brandl.  I brought Naga, the PSF Snake, on the Max.  After the keynotes she went straight to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5987657253/in/set-72157627166240377&quot;&gt;the &lt;i&gt;DemocracyLab&lt;/i&gt; booth&lt;/a&gt;, remembering Deb Bryant (she&#39;s on Mark&#39;s board).  The Perl Foundation was immediately adjacent, so she next jumped over there and gave &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5988220546/in/set-72157627166240377/&quot;&gt;a ride to the camel&lt;/a&gt;.  Chairman Steve has &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/07/perl-world.html&quot;&gt;a debate later&lt;/a&gt; with one of the Perl avatars.  Both write curriculum for O&#39;Reilly School of Technology, so it&#39;s somewhat a punch and judy show.  We&#39;re all family here.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The talk on NORC&#39;s study, done for the US Congress, on open source EHR systems used in safety-net health-care clinics (so-called) was illuminating.  The clinics tend to get more deeply into using their systems as a function of both needing and wanting to customize them.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
R0ml took up the topic of internationalizing source code, one of my pets.  He conceded at the beginning, somewhat sarcastically, that &quot;everyone should learn English&quot;, satirizing the predominant Anglo imperialism (paradigm).  He used Portuguese as an example of another source code language for Python.  I already know from chatting with my Brazilian friends that top-level names, minus keywords, built-ins and standard library, are already in Portuguese in many a Python program.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
I introduced R0ml to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/03/pycon-2013.html&quot;&gt;Henrique&lt;/a&gt; in the Expo Hall later.  I also went back to the Perl booth where Michael of &lt;i&gt;Food Not Bombs&lt;/i&gt; was hanging out.  Mention of FNB brought up an interesting opportunity to compare notes, as the Perl guys were from Orlando.
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3320052848314138488'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3320052848314138488'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/07/oscon-2011-continues.html' title='OSCON 2011 Continues'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5912334799151023452</id><published>2011-07-19T01:41:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-07-21T22:22:26.584-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Rainbow Gathering (musings)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot; href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgxTQ_pqsb6RtR6DB3s8lOuzhURepaZXDCq05fnBLKM6zASPIuaaTMAE__Vw6IdW_grgonjyc3nudSf4U2pSw4acc1hOpjpfHpx6gzeAZKIXQKPTl9JiXq8cll6XJxJQBs12YWA/s1600/teslaturbine.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 320px; height: 190px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgxTQ_pqsb6RtR6DB3s8lOuzhURepaZXDCq05fnBLKM6zASPIuaaTMAE__Vw6IdW_grgonjyc3nudSf4U2pSw4acc1hOpjpfHpx6gzeAZKIXQKPTl9JiXq8cll6XJxJQBs12YWA/s320/teslaturbine.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5632042251532616818&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;:: bioneering project by jim murosako ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I didn&#39;t go to this Gathering, but many FnBers did, and I&#39;m pumping them for information.  Satya&#39;s group walked the whole way there.  The aftermath, involving cleanup, is a kind of Part 2.  I got reports about the trash, the detritus, from that many people camped in the forest for that long.  The reports make it sound a lot like the &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2007/06/more-meetings.html&quot;&gt;Gathering of Western Young Friends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; but on a much larger scale.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Expanding FnB as a way of training cooks, improving coordination and logistics, using food about to go to waste anyway, seems like a good idea.  I&#39;m surprised how below the radar it stays, given so many chapters.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I wonder about this Quaker network of safe houses or whatever it is.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/walking-with-walker.html&quot;&gt;LW&lt;/a&gt; and my friend, another chef, are thinking about scoping out more of Yamhill county.  I sent an email ahead, to one of the property owners.  There&#39;s no substitute for reality.  Dreams without substance accrue no inertia.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I was thinking back to my research into Unicode and OLPC today.  Sinhalese and Tamil were on my screen at CubeSpace, seems a long time ago by now.  I alluded to that chapter in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.python.org/pipermail/edu-sig/2011-July/010405.html&quot;&gt;my recent post to edu-sig&lt;/a&gt;.  The entire thread is interesting I think, relates to diversity (I have related threads going on both Diversity and PSF-members).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Should Global U students travel more?  Many of the more conscious and aware types, such as those in my current household, think a lot about peak oil. We mostly walk, bike, take the bus, though I gladly do chauffeur duty (company car) for the 82 year old.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Adding more electronics and doing more virtual meetups still seems like a realistic way to go.  But again, there&#39;s no substitute for reality. Sometimes one really needs to go to a place, to broaden one&#39;s perspective.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We should probably run these conveyor belts faster, get more turnover going.  But that takes software.  I&#39;ve imagined CSN as a supportive business, but one can&#39;t live on coffee shop fare, if that means your standard airport concourse coffee shop (which CSN shops are not -- some may require membership). &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; One needs to have substantive protein.  &lt;i&gt;Lyrik&lt;/i&gt; does a lot of its own baking.  Jody may have known about Calibri&#39;s operation but I was too new to CSA (community supported agriculture) to grok the background story.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The idea of a disaster relief corps is already well established with AFSC.  Of course the vast majority aren&#39;t Friends, but you may still find a lot of your own plans and dreams mirrored, just in a different namespace.  Happens all the time.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Should we take applications?  Who else wants to join our Global U project?  Metaphorically, it&#39;s what we&#39;re already involved in (Global U = Spaceship Earth), but on the ground you have all kinds of resource and personnel allocation strategies.  LW used to read resumes a lot, back in Savannah.  She might help select her own replacement for when the time comes to change the scenery (scene), not saying I&#39;m bound here either (turnover is a fact of life).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/03/wittgenstein-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Alex&lt;/a&gt;, newly a US citizen, said photography and cinematography were discouraged at the Gathering, so I may not find as much on Flickr as I&#39;d hoped.  &lt;i&gt;Burning Man&lt;/i&gt;, in contrast, is well covered by photography.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;As I was mentioning tonight, if the goal is community, then your designers need to know right away if you&#39;re accommodating the very young (newborns) and the elderly.  There&#39;s a tendency among the young to think in terms of their generation as the anchor.  However, many of these communities would likely happen more quickly if &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/07/seniors-musings.html&quot;&gt;the seniors&lt;/a&gt; saw them as a solution as well. Segregation by age has its consequences.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Lots of anthropology branches off from these rather scattered remarks.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5912334799151023452'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5912334799151023452'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/07/rainbow-gathering-musings.html' title='Rainbow Gathering (musings)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgxTQ_pqsb6RtR6DB3s8lOuzhURepaZXDCq05fnBLKM6zASPIuaaTMAE__Vw6IdW_grgonjyc3nudSf4U2pSw4acc1hOpjpfHpx6gzeAZKIXQKPTl9JiXq8cll6XJxJQBs12YWA/s72-c/teslaturbine.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6937852650940348563</id><published>2011-07-15T19:22:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2012-06-03T14:19:05.857-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Checking In</title><content type='html'>Once again from your business crew, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/07/bizmotica.html&quot;&gt;some Bizmotica&lt;/a&gt;...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Quakers convene for business yearly, in what&#39;s called &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/07/this-ones-for-you.html&quot;&gt;Annual Session&lt;/a&gt;, to have these plenary sessions.  There&#39;s an esoteric inner faction among Friends that&#39;s saying plen&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;ary&lt;/span&gt;, rhyming with can&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;ary&lt;/span&gt;, which of course is the wrong emphasis.  Fabik and Scholl went at it, first Lew with the Droid, then Dave with the iPhone, to find other rhymers, such as Harry.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Good segue:  in some Xtian sects, that &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/12/winter-traditions.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/span&gt; stuff&lt;/a&gt; is too distracting or &quot;of the devil&quot; or whatever, to be permitted a core focus of any official religious event.  Not so at Annual Session this year.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/12/driving-to-la.html&quot;&gt;Joe Snyder&lt;/a&gt; took a posse of some 39 ticket holders to opening night of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Part 2&lt;/span&gt; of the latest, with the whole group watching &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Part 1&lt;/span&gt; in the lounge at Pacific Lutheran University (PLU), where we stayed (wandering gypsies that we be).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Another highlight for me was watching that satirical look at the emerging &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/span&gt; culture through the eyes of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/12/team-america-world-police-movie-review_04.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;South Park Studios&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  We watched on his iPhone.  Google+ has just launched, around the time of this writing, so throwing people into circles (e.g. &quot;to the lions&quot;) has become a big part of the buzz.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The PSF snake, Ms. Naga, was a stowaway with the 3.1 computer speakers (with woofer).  She&#39;s the stuffed totem we cart around as another &quot;cult symbol&quot; (hacker speak) in Python World. In the comix, she&#39;s a good natured, adventuresome type.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
During &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Quaker Fair&lt;/span&gt;, when organizations paraded their stuff, like so many stationary floats, the anti cruelty to animals guy discovered he&#39;d forgotten the power cable for his speakers.  I was sitting right there, doing my day job &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/06/back-office.html&quot;&gt;teaching Python&lt;/a&gt; over wifi, and quickly volunteered that I had some back in the room.  Timothy Travis returned me by golf cart, forthwith.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Of course Naga came along in the bag and curled up at the exhibit, where the movie kept playing.  I got the soundtrack over and over as I continued my grading, hearing about the terrible things humans do to other animals.  This was a good position for &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/05/animal-rights.html&quot;&gt;a Quaker animist&lt;/a&gt; to take, and another score for FnB style cooking.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The two booths I spent most of my time at during this Fair:  AFSC and Western Friend.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/10/school-spirit-hillsboro-story.html&quot;&gt;Susan&lt;/a&gt; was showing some &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/04/future-of-image.html&quot;&gt;poster art&lt;/a&gt; reminiscent of Shepard Fairey&#39;s, prompting a quick visit to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.obeygiant.com/&quot;&gt;Obey Giant website&lt;/a&gt;.  Hyzy, WF editor in chief, was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/7200673656/in/photostream/&quot;&gt;like Lucy in her booth&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Peanuts&lt;/span&gt;.  Thinking of Linus, I remembered my security blanket (blue).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve also been reading and writing about &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/WittrsEX/message/4541&quot;&gt;Wittgensteinian philo&lt;/a&gt;, chatting with Nick, DK, wondering about my peeps, so spread out and around.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6937852650940348563'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6937852650940348563'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/07/checking-in.html' title='Checking In'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6985869641178460471</id><published>2011-07-13T00:45:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2011-07-13T02:17:36.426-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Diversity / Python Nation</title><content type='html'>Excerpt from one of my posts from earlier today (I added some hyperlinks for the blogged edition):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;A lot of people go by &quot;hurt feelings&quot; as their guide and naturally aim for&lt;br /&gt;a world, by whatever means necessary, wherein their feelings are&lt;br /&gt;better protected.  A kind of truce is trucked out:  &quot;I promise to not&lt;br /&gt;hurt your feelings if you promise not to hurt mine&quot;.  Those who apparently&lt;br /&gt;continue to hurt others feelings are in abrogation of this truce and are&lt;br /&gt;worthy of punishment to make them stop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There&#39;s an imperiousness to this however, in that you will look for&lt;br /&gt;and expect people to automatically change their behavior when&lt;br /&gt;they see you&#39;re offended.  The missionary shows up and is offended&lt;br /&gt;that people are not covered up, not modest, in the way God ordains.&lt;br /&gt;Will there be consequences if the locals refuse to modify their&lt;br /&gt;dress codes?  What if they continue to school their young in how&lt;br /&gt;to use various weapons?  Does it hurt your feelings that they won&#39;t&lt;br /&gt;accept the new edicts (e.g. the so-called &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/01/rebuilding-iraq.html&quot;&gt;Bremer Edicts&lt;/a&gt;&quot; in Iraq --&lt;br /&gt;which hardly anyone remembers anymore).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What offends people *a lot* is when they are not *obeyed*.  They&lt;br /&gt;may feel deeply hurt, quivering lip and everything, because the&lt;br /&gt;servant says &quot;no, I must take care of my sick child&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The flip side of &quot;you must not hurt my feelings&quot; is &quot;you must obey&lt;br /&gt;my will, within reason&quot; (but who defines &quot;reason&quot;?).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So, yeah, I&#39;m very suspicious of ethnicities that use &quot;hurt feelings&quot;&lt;br /&gt;as a guide.  Americans do this a lot, but they inherit so much from&lt;br /&gt;those Anglo-Euros when it comes to an imperial mindset.  Not a&lt;br /&gt;good guide for the future.  Behind those &quot;hurt feelings&quot; is a&lt;br /&gt;hypocritical willingness to use force.  They whine they&#39;re not&lt;br /&gt;getting enough health care, but are in no hurry to stop manufacturing&lt;br /&gt;drones and cruise missiles, and using those on others, because&lt;br /&gt;that means jobs jobs jobs.  I wonder how we might use Python to&lt;br /&gt;further reduce the influence of such people.&lt;span style=&quot;color:#888888;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#888888;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6985869641178460471'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6985869641178460471'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/07/diversity-python-nation.html' title='Diversity / Python Nation'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7405208087259875620</id><published>2011-07-07T22:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-07-08T00:30:34.997-07:00</updated><title type='text'>A Senior&#39;s Musings</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjP3httB2JXD7Cv-Shyphenhyphen2bbEOievE9xhagxJlv0ZbYm8LpUdYNEjh4lYXMooXRC8EEcCTajqAik5rn-MWPcVxmyA_wAW0v4dPyWxh6hwnskMG0QT7EtKVHkjC0yTCl1zaFeuIyGg/s1600/mangrove1.JPG&quot; onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 320px; height: 190px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjP3httB2JXD7Cv-Shyphenhyphen2bbEOievE9xhagxJlv0ZbYm8LpUdYNEjh4lYXMooXRC8EEcCTajqAik5rn-MWPcVxmyA_wAW0v4dPyWxh6hwnskMG0QT7EtKVHkjC0yTCl1zaFeuIyGg/s320/mangrove1.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5626842119278091538&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;:: bioneering project by jim murosako ::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I heard from &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/01/return-to-icu.html&quot;&gt;Nick&lt;/a&gt; this morning.  Looks like he&#39;ll be getting that apartment in Hillsboro.  He&#39;s been in Eugene.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today was the &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/03/open-source-photocopier.html&quot;&gt;Blue House&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; turn at bat with FNB, as usual. People were trickling back from the Rainbow Gathering.  I got my first reports.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The phrase &quot;check your privilege&quot; was a theme today.  I did some &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/Wittrs/message/6941&quot;&gt;cross-fertilizing&lt;/a&gt;, in typical Wanderers fashion.  Mandelbrot:&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &#39;Courier New&#39;, Courier, FreeMono, monospace; font-size: 13px; line-height: 18px; &quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &#39;Courier New&#39;, Courier, FreeMono, monospace; font-size: 13px; line-height: 18px; &quot;&gt;“Science would be ruined if it were to withdraw entirely into narrowly defined specialties. The rare scholars who are wanderers-by-choice are essential to the intellectual welfare of the settled disciplines.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;After the call from Nick, I did my 14 mile loop &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5914256995/in/photostream&quot;&gt;on EmoKid&lt;/a&gt;, the refurbished bike, successor to TinkerBell. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; I&#39;m officially a senior now, after last night.  The guy at &lt;i&gt;Burgerville&lt;/i&gt; gave me &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5914257659/in/photostream/&quot;&gt;a Senior Coffee&lt;/a&gt;.  I drank three cups, a kind of baptism.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As I was mentioning to Lindsey, in recounting this story in the meetinghouse kitchen, I take &quot;senior&quot; in that schoolish sense also, in the sense of &quot;senior privilege&quot;.  I get lots of power and control in this chapter.  Other connotations might be held at bay for a bit, while I manage these institutions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Could I be CMO from &lt;i&gt;Coffee Shops Network&lt;/i&gt;, and still be CTO for a government agency &lt;i&gt;at the same time&lt;/i&gt;?  It&#39;s a theoretical question, but as the former offers an open source business plan to funnel money to worthy causes, it&#39;s already doing more than many government agencies, not to mention NGOs (a &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2009/05/self-promotion.html&quot;&gt;self serving&lt;/a&gt; suggestion). &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; So in my own mind at least, the answer is yes.  One should have a minimum of two work identities.  We &lt;i&gt;want&lt;/i&gt; more than one job, for their &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/65932&quot;&gt;synergetic potential&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I was amused by &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2010/05/meeting-with-cso.html&quot;&gt;Glenn&#39;s stories&lt;/a&gt; of the BBC helping to shed more light on this Scientology business.  That was never my camp, though I&#39;ve done &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/07/interest-group.html&quot;&gt;some ethnography&lt;/a&gt;.  At least one of their security chiefs has defected, and that makes it easier to expose some of the inner workings.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7405208087259875620'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7405208087259875620'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/07/seniors-musings.html' title='A Senior&#39;s Musings'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjP3httB2JXD7Cv-Shyphenhyphen2bbEOievE9xhagxJlv0ZbYm8LpUdYNEjh4lYXMooXRC8EEcCTajqAik5rn-MWPcVxmyA_wAW0v4dPyWxh6hwnskMG0QT7EtKVHkjC0yTCl1zaFeuIyGg/s72-c/mangrove1.JPG" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-751696404638725273</id><published>2011-06-26T19:15:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-06-26T22:28:13.770-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Office Reflections</title><content type='html'>I&#39;m not too happy about &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Qwest&lt;/span&gt; changing its name to &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;CenturyLinks&lt;/span&gt;, a big faux pas in my book.  Anything &quot;century&quot; is too stale, unless grandfathered in.  Purposely reverting to such retro signage is just a pale retreat, an attempt at a new wrapping.  Anyway, not my problem.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I followed up on that PSF traffic regarding &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/08/pycon-tehran.html&quot;&gt;Python / Iran&lt;/a&gt;.  The for-credit &quot;truckology&quot; degree (not its real name) could be cause enough for a convergence, with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/06/solstice-wanderers.html&quot;&gt;GeoDjango&lt;/a&gt; a theme (like at &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/06/open-source-law.html&quot;&gt;OS Bridge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Holden and I discussed the new Hess album on Facebook, our having met at &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/11/goscon-2010.html&quot;&gt;GOSCON last year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Planning to see &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Source Code&lt;/span&gt; this evening.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have a &quot;commit bit&quot; for the Wittgenstein feed.  Hope Alex, Satya and company are doing well on their walk.  Lots of turnover at FNB.  LW enjoying Dostoevsky.  Did the 14 mile loop, like in the old days with &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/12/seeking-work.html&quot;&gt;SB&lt;/a&gt; and friends.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/751696404638725273'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/751696404638725273'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/06/office-reflections.html' title='Office Reflections'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-9039539032280547883</id><published>2011-06-25T09:45:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-06-26T19:38:55.434-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Simulating A School</title><content type='html'>I was back to my &quot;school for diplomats in the high desert&quot; topic again, in a recent meeting at the chairman&#39;s (some of the chairs were recently re-glued by Patrick).  Could we apply Henry George principles?&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/02/wanderers-20110209.html&quot;&gt;Henry George, an economist&lt;/a&gt;, proposed to keep government from being too greedy, by freeing people to add value to land through their own efforts, without having to pay tribute on the value added except in a most general way, relating to the appreciating value of the underlying shared infrastructure and ecosystem context.  &quot;Improvements&quot; wouldn&#39;t be penalized as a land tax is more about neighborhood value.  It&#39;s a way of &quot;raising all boats&quot; by boosting land values while allowing more of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/02/shovel-ready.html&quot;&gt;rewards of innovation&lt;/a&gt; to flow back to the innovators.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Economists are always interested in &quot;bootstrapping&quot; because development is a result of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/05/silicon-forest-origins.html&quot;&gt;cybernetic feedback&lt;/a&gt; that spirals one way or the other, or has both convergent (concentrating) and divergent (dissipating) tendencies.  A few domes in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2007/03/high-desert.html&quot;&gt;the desert&lt;/a&gt;, or near a stream bed, perhaps in an airspace zoned for air taxi service, do not by themselves constitute &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/04/school-spirit.html&quot;&gt;a school&lt;/a&gt;.  However, with a few product placements and signers on, sponsor decals, co-venturer insignia, one does have a basis for appreciating land values. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We already know some of the purposes of such a school, based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/12/countdown-to-zero-game.html&quot;&gt;the &lt;i&gt;Countdown to Zero&lt;/i&gt; literature&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/11/gasland-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Gasland&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and other classics.  Environmental monitoring, through the use of sensors, is in the public interest, as is the geographic display of the collected data.  It&#39;s not just a convenience, but a government responsibility to the people, the lack of which global data only goes towards delegitimizing those claiming to inherit high office.  If a citizen cannot dial up current data about Bull Run, the Portland metro area watershed, then do we really have a government?  The &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/06/open-source-law.html&quot;&gt;data collection centers&lt;/a&gt; will have a public service mission that&#39;s clear and obvious enough to attract the kind of volunteers we would most like to get:  idealistic and self motivated.  &quot;Idealistic&quot; does not mean &quot;pie in the sky&quot; so much as willing to project a personal narrative against the backdrop of &quot;the greater good&quot;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Beyond eco-monitoring and &quot;away team&quot; forays, the students are learning how to be mannerly in an ever-shifting global economy, one which brings ethnicities together in new ways.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Those tracking these blogs know that we&#39;ve created our &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/03/set-design.html&quot;&gt;Blue House&lt;/a&gt; as an urban based prototype of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/search?q=Earthala&quot;&gt;one of these schools&lt;/a&gt;, adopting a Free School model and providing economic support to self motivated individuals.  The &quot;time capsule&quot; houses much of the syllabus.  The back office is where sponsors put their mark.  Whether outreach to the movie industry succeeds sooner rather than later remains an open question.  Japanese anime companies have been courted.  Portland is on the map, diplomacy-wise.  Our track record has been established.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9039539032280547883'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9039539032280547883'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/06/simulating-school.html' title='Simulating A School'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6616619561313375721</id><published>2011-06-19T19:25:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-06-26T19:11:57.491-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Father&#39;s Day</title><content type='html'>I was grateful to be reunited with my daughter today, meeting Gonzo&#39;s party at carousel 4.  I also had Sir Steve in my company, his &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;JetBlue&lt;/span&gt; having landed but a few minutes earlier.  We all fit in the Kirby taxi no problem.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steve showed me some pix from Djangocon / Amsterdam.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Out to celebrate more.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6616619561313375721'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6616619561313375721'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/06/fathers-day.html' title='Father&#39;s Day'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7425294113245044425</id><published>2011-06-10T10:31:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-12-11T18:08:45.854-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Shanty Town USA</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/wnuXe6-m3WA&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; width=&quot;475&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You have &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/10/occupy-portland-event.html&quot;&gt;a lot of Americans&lt;/a&gt; pressuring to start the same sprawling shanty towns we find in many urban areas.  The city sidewalk and public thoroughfare is, not for the first time, &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/synergeo/message/65734&quot;&gt;the front line&lt;/a&gt; in a battle between public and private.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/osbridge/msg/0e3098b350afbe61&quot;&gt;The right to camp&lt;/a&gt; on public lands, if curtailed, is on some level a blow to sovereignty, especially as more citizens take to the camp grounds.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/03/stewart-brand-at-reed-college.html&quot;&gt;Stewart Brand&lt;/a&gt; was upbeat about all this youthful energy, the vast encampments spreading around great urban concentrations.  This might free up a lot more area for pure wilderness, a zoning he favors.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;His objections to solar /wind farms are mainly against the plow happy practices of tractor fanatics and their bulldozing cousins.  If flowers (sun tracking solar collectors) destroyed property the way those dozers do, we&#39;d have run out of wilderness in no time.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Nature seems to concentrate its stupidest memes in humans for some reason (guinea pigging?).  &lt;i&gt;Nature for Dummies&lt;/i&gt; is our constant reading, always going over the same lessons, again and again and again.  Tsk, I&#39;m sounding not philanthropic again.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Back to those tent city PeopleTowns:  here in North America, it might be &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3957147025/&quot;&gt;more senior-boomers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/3160978227/&quot;&gt;vets&lt;/a&gt;, mixed with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5095212133/&quot;&gt;young families&lt;/a&gt; just starting out, already foreclosed upon in our shark infested waters.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;America&#39;s people are among &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/big-foot-strikes.html&quot;&gt;the least defended&lt;/a&gt; against some brands of predator, the military conveniently looking the other way if it&#39;s an &quot;intelligence&quot; problem.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5818841255/&quot; title=&quot;P6100083 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5144/5818841255_e8ef6bb736_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;P6100083&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The military&#39;s ranks and budget actually swell when &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/07/independence-day-weekend.html&quot;&gt;civilians&lt;/a&gt; are driven from their precarious paycheck-to-paycheck perches.  Humans get herded into &lt;i&gt;I, Robot&lt;/i&gt; prisons and militias, once out of other options.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The schools have yet to catch up, making Food Services struggle without the benefit of much systems analysis or real time control room monitoring.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The Ivory Tower is still hellbent on obliging with killingry science it seems, pandering to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/04/roller-coaster-at-reed.html&quot;&gt;an Iron Mountain Economy&lt;/a&gt; while neglecting so many critically important student services, providing shelters for example, versus blowing them up.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We can&#39;t have strong ethics if we&#39;re busy selling out to the Forces of Darkness now can we?  &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/09/toontalk.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/i&gt; revisited&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/01/about-habitats.html&quot;&gt;I&#39;ve wondered&lt;/a&gt; if the aerospace sector, with lots of bright people, would be stepping up to the plate the way Bucky planned.  Weren&#39;t we expecting some experimental prototype community of tomorrow?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Then I realized I still like trains a lot, and maybe the global university extension campus should stretch across rail lines, for PhD programs in history, languages, signals, physics, geology -- you name it.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Not just PhD programs, but future Doctors of Philosophy especially stand to benefit from &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/10/oh-superman.html&quot;&gt;working on a railroad&lt;/a&gt; at some point in their lives.  Could be Russian Studies.  I&#39;m not saying I&#39;m confidant USAers are capable of self-organizing this creatively -- or they already would have by now, right?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Of course it&#39;s not either / or (trains versus planes) and &quot;working on a railroad&quot; easily becomes a metaphor for any dirty job involving a component of physical labor.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Young bodies are especially in need of exercise, aren&#39;t designed to just sit around in cube farms, rotting away around water coolers, eating too much meat, depending on air conditioning.  School is a travesty if it grooms only Eloi, channeling Morlock tendencies into either pointless athletics or outright predating on other humans (so-called blood sports, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/05/defending-homeland.html&quot;&gt;Roman circuses&lt;/a&gt;&quot;).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;You can see some TV stations wanting to move more in that direction, encouraging wars, inflaming both sides to boost ratings, with the producer-militants seeming to encounter little resistance from democracy&#39;s last bastions (this gives them encouragement).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Hey, I&#39;m starting to sound like Micheal Sunanda, my hippy co-interviewee in Internet Radioland, on one of those Coast to Coast type twisted alien shows, like those underground comics.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So why is Planet Earth still such a nasty place, why so much misery?  The pat answers of the past don&#39;t ring so true anymore.  The sermons have gone hollow in so many churches (at least Subgenius rants still have some punch).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The poignancy is still there, but its nature has changed, the surrounding storytelling.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It&#39;s getting harder to think in terms of pure physical insufficiency anymore (the &quot;too many people&quot; cop out) ever since the Renaissance in Italy, and especially since the 1970s with its Apollo Program and so forth.  Humans have the ability to ferry themselves to the moon using small well-insulated capsules. Amazing.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;m meeting about &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/01/metropolitan-talk.html&quot;&gt;EPCOT West&lt;/a&gt;&quot; tonight, among other projects (&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/05/architect.html&quot;&gt;Earthala etc.&lt;/a&gt;).  You could think of it as a book club for retired science fiction writers if that sounded comforting.  Other Tomorrows Network?  See you next Esozone maybe?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7425294113245044425'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7425294113245044425'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/06/shanty-town-usa.html' title='Shanty Town USA'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/wnuXe6-m3WA/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1040055985428275308</id><published>2011-06-01T14:20:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-08-31T21:32:32.132-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Hatless in Portland</title><content type='html'>I took some time out today, to label recent photographs, to hunt for my hat.  I&#39;ve misplaced it again, perhaps this time for good.  Said hat hogged the limelight in &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/Wittrs/message/6823&quot;&gt;my autobiographical post&lt;/a&gt; to the Wittgenstein list.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Trisha (at Wanderers this morning) was off to help load a donkey into a pickup truck and that got us all talking and Googling. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;What&#39;s a mule anyway?  Jim Buxton had more experience with donkeys.  The dad is always the donkey it seems.  If the mule is fertile, it&#39;s because she might get pregnant.  Guy mules have no track record of fathering. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Mules bond well with horses, especially mother figures.  Many attractive features.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A non-sterile male mule with a horse father and donkey mother would likely be too oxymoronic to call a mule.  It&#39;d deserve its own label.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Donkeys usually are a help around the farm, especially when it comes to looking after other animals.  However, one donkey Glenn knew was credited with teaching the horses in its care to step over cow guards.  It showed them over and over until they got it.  The horses and donkey would take off and go exploring, much to the consternation of their human proprietor.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1040055985428275308'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1040055985428275308'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/06/hatless-in-portland.html' title='Hatless in Portland'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-823359920049415696</id><published>2011-05-26T18:01:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-06-01T14:18:43.754-07:00</updated><title type='text'>FNB Gossip</title><content type='html'>Walker&#39;s switch to raw vegan leads her less into chiefing the cheffing show, which she and I have been casting, and pulling off weekly since September, sometimes one or another of us taking the full load (Lindsey more than I, given my trips to Philly and Sonoma County).&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;My version has FNB scaling, changing branding if disowned, yet always respectful of its &quot;parent&quot; organization, even while incarnating as its weirder spawn (&quot;Make Portland Weirder&quot;).  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/11/made-for-tv.html&quot;&gt;We publish DIY (&quot;how to&quot;) cooking shows&lt;/a&gt;, showing few-for-many styles, not just nuclear family me-for-myself or me-for-hubby-n-kids.  Other shows do that, with which we don&#39;t compete.  Crew cooking in a well equipped kitchen and serving by bicycle in public structures.  We&#39;re looking at public schools maybe taking this on, bringing back the day when bike riding was a for credit learning experience, as important (another part of) drivers&#39; ed.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I was using funny accents today and talking about ToonTown, as I&#39;m wont to do.  &quot;Every day is cartoon day&quot; I intoned, in &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/09/more-about-quakers.html&quot;&gt;a Quaker meetinghouse&lt;/a&gt;, sounding like some weighty Friend in a Disney cartoon, some Subgenius.  Lindsey&#39;s energy adds to the lunacy of it all, as do others in this roly-poly cast.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We&#39;re talking about shutting down the Thursday program as is and reconfiguring.  Too early to see the shape of what&#39;s to come.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/823359920049415696'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/823359920049415696'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/05/fnb-gossip.html' title='FNB Gossip'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7321088123668401733</id><published>2011-05-17T13:44:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2011-05-17T14:03:06.753-07:00</updated><title type='text'>HB2Me</title><content type='html'>Yes, another &quot;coming of age&quot; date on the calendar, a prime number this year.  Carol, my mother, now age 82, took me to lunch &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/04/night-shot.html&quot;&gt;at &lt;i&gt;The Bagdad&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  I had a Dungeon Burger, curry chic pea soup, and two &lt;i&gt;Workingman&#39;s Reds&lt;/i&gt;.  Mom had turkey sandwich, same soup, and coffee with cream.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;She had plenty of stories from the Philippines, of lowlanders coming into a &quot;zip code area&quot; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/05/yakking-on-facebook.html&quot;&gt;forging documents&lt;/a&gt;, making a kind of &quot;mockumentary&quot; wherein ancestral lands could be sold to USA imperial corporations, like Dole, for nominal prices.  When westerners mean &quot;land reform&quot; that&#39;s often it:  set up a game wherein we make the rules, so we can buy you out for cheap (as in swindle).  Easterners would fall for that, time and again.  Or do we call them &quot;easterners&quot; any more.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I haven&#39;t had time to read &lt;i&gt;The Mercury&lt;/i&gt; yet but the cover story title makes no sense.  How could indoor digital put Indie Theaters out of business? A lot of them use the same technology.  It&#39;s about distribution, not what kind of light bulb you&#39;re using.  If the coffee shops have first dibs on the work of this or that studio, by longstanding agreement, then you&#39;ll expect a loyal base, interested in that studio&#39;s latest releases.  Home theaters will catch it later, unless in the loop in some way (there&#39;s no rule against staff house parties).  Wineries have a similar economy:  some taste it before others.  Film culture has always been osmosis-based.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgFyujmhRMVVPpqWHj_rjeYbLDbzPysDdBhNw_9I0JSI0lRrJ0Jl6phq6bgRW66woyRtv0eZMnFP3MLU2NUlamIULVUAWkBJvtOpMQgfiKAE_nJRKe3uqd-_WXmeAUFhnKe_YX1/s1600/ronpaul.png&quot; onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 400px; height: 95px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgFyujmhRMVVPpqWHj_rjeYbLDbzPysDdBhNw_9I0JSI0lRrJ0Jl6phq6bgRW66woyRtv0eZMnFP3MLU2NUlamIULVUAWkBJvtOpMQgfiKAE_nJRKe3uqd-_WXmeAUFhnKe_YX1/s400/ronpaul.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5607790741954016514&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/drug-wars.html&quot;&gt;re Prohibition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7321088123668401733'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7321088123668401733'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/05/hb2me.html' title='HB2Me'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgFyujmhRMVVPpqWHj_rjeYbLDbzPysDdBhNw_9I0JSI0lRrJ0Jl6phq6bgRW66woyRtv0eZMnFP3MLU2NUlamIULVUAWkBJvtOpMQgfiKAE_nJRKe3uqd-_WXmeAUFhnKe_YX1/s72-c/ronpaul.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7712223619327990238</id><published>2011-05-08T18:33:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-05-08T18:39:55.987-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Per the BBC</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;349&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/1LNTsle7UtM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;349&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/p6Dq9Togf6w&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/WittrsAMR/message/4360?var=0&amp;amp;l=1&quot;&gt;some comments (apologies for typos)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7712223619327990238'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7712223619327990238'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/05/per-bbc.html' title='Per the BBC'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/1LNTsle7UtM/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1847897130494650590</id><published>2011-05-02T22:41:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2011-05-04T12:40:25.989-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Lesson Planning</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjlEw91bmaunW_CIXpLcCyO7SwFr4EMlzMwrKfEMLggK0DQkkxQiaAI6hh6-63PKdgieu-wDYa8L98q_6ANSaIon6TVy43z71UghhBxtlS1nMw3tnYSVGK3NfCnXTKCZMqFd1NL/s1600/psf_ad.png&quot; onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 400px; height: 326px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjlEw91bmaunW_CIXpLcCyO7SwFr4EMlzMwrKfEMLggK0DQkkxQiaAI6hh6-63PKdgieu-wDYa8L98q_6ANSaIon6TVy43z71UghhBxtlS1nMw3tnYSVGK3NfCnXTKCZMqFd1NL/s400/psf_ad.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5602366234061304626&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgLnIA-Zhb4dPvuzyOJW6PtsIdg1SEfoqsdNnQ9MedvabZzukHmc_rw5UIhcMwAYE8Uz0ekqtxeA-0609KLf3dJzlFVMDmBGrcLMkM_Nglqm3w2bwq2Xdu6DmFhdZ8_h4xI0jq4/s1600/py433project.png&quot; onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 400px; height: 384px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgLnIA-Zhb4dPvuzyOJW6PtsIdg1SEfoqsdNnQ9MedvabZzukHmc_rw5UIhcMwAYE8Uz0ekqtxeA-0609KLf3dJzlFVMDmBGrcLMkM_Nglqm3w2bwq2Xdu6DmFhdZ8_h4xI0jq4/s400/py433project.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5602361572859816770&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh8mNSlwGnwqTWu4WU8Kfr5HMlisVddP5CIzSOjgqLWKPOUCJVKLbL_qTme73e06ED3TMkEpnQzsUO1ymeyb13AFEUfpkda8R4Kjfgp7eQIiDDyfE-sVZw4f7ygdebECt26oqfx/s1600/lesson4_4.png&quot; onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 400px; height: 177px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh8mNSlwGnwqTWu4WU8Kfr5HMlisVddP5CIzSOjgqLWKPOUCJVKLbL_qTme73e06ED3TMkEpnQzsUO1ymeyb13AFEUfpkda8R4Kjfgp7eQIiDDyfE-sVZw4f7ygdebECt26oqfx/s400/lesson4_4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5602361197625860706&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Some programmers new to Python do not understand how a two dimensional array might be implemented simply as nested lists.  The &quot;outer list&quot; forms your rows and the members of that list, themselves lists, define the columns.  I used to go back and forth &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2004/12/view-from-middle-earth.html&quot;&gt;with Bernie Gunn&lt;/a&gt; on that one, the 70+ year old geochemist who flew his own plane in New Zealand, had cut his teeth on Pascal.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Whereas years of grade-school drill in this biases, such as to put (0,0) either in the middle or lower right, the way printers and typewriters work, by typing against an advancing scroll, suggests the first row will end up at the top of the page.  Ding, carriage return.  Old typewriter noises.  So (0,0) tends to mean &quot;upper left) and (1,0) is one row down, far left margin if you read left to right, possibly far right margin if you read right to left.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjUGNbpNyBRKZDdCEhs-468Z8QTgagfPLd0_CquLc7aGursfb-K5T7xGkZ6UOkQUIOUcAyE2lPH3iv15beT-8Xxj-FcZUaB14CZSk2Apl2ILkfzUSZ6v9axWvpEzpOaDbEBDo9M/s1600/beachwork.png&quot; onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 400px; height: 350px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjUGNbpNyBRKZDdCEhs-468Z8QTgagfPLd0_CquLc7aGursfb-K5T7xGkZ6UOkQUIOUcAyE2lPH3iv15beT-8Xxj-FcZUaB14CZSk2Apl2ILkfzUSZ6v9axWvpEzpOaDbEBDo9M/s400/beachwork.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5602372601188950354&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;The Tractor is similar enough to a Turtle to be imported as such, but the field it plows is simply a two-dimensional array with a simple ASCII representation.  Mentally, students are starting to think in terms of a GUI canvas, but in terms of working the server, we&#39;re keeping the processes fairly lightweight.  The REPL buffer stays reasonable unless students create vast fields (of soybeans), &lt;a href=&quot;http://chicagoboyz.net/archives/1908.html&quot;&gt;like in Brazil&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1847897130494650590'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1847897130494650590'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/05/lesson-planning.html' title='Lesson Planning'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjlEw91bmaunW_CIXpLcCyO7SwFr4EMlzMwrKfEMLggK0DQkkxQiaAI6hh6-63PKdgieu-wDYa8L98q_6ANSaIon6TVy43z71UghhBxtlS1nMw3tnYSVGK3NfCnXTKCZMqFd1NL/s72-c/psf_ad.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1113788883885541445</id><published>2011-04-24T09:17:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-05-02T22:41:35.100-07:00</updated><title type='text'>More Bizmotica</title><content type='html'>A BizMo, some may remember, is a &quot;business mobile&quot;, and that has various connotations, one of which is you&#39;re making some kind of positive contribution to an economy in that &quot;not yet retired&quot; sense.  &quot;Still performing a service&quot; -- that&#39;s the connotation of &quot;in business&quot; or &quot;working&quot; today, though &quot;going to school&quot; is acknowledged as a kind of work, hence work / study (i.e. the &quot;GU scenario&quot; -- GU = &quot;global university&quot;).&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Wanderer NA and I checked out &lt;i&gt;Movie Madness &lt;/i&gt;(she&#39;d never been there) where I exchanged &lt;i&gt;Fantastic Planet&lt;/i&gt; (animation) and &lt;i&gt;Hitler&#39;s Last 10 Days&lt;/i&gt; (Alec Guinness), for another of Alec&#39;s, &lt;i&gt;Horses Mouth&lt;/i&gt;.  You might call these homework assignments.  Right next to MM is a BizMo Food Court, with each bizmo a restaurant, with shared outdoor seating.  &lt;i&gt;Willamette Week&lt;/i&gt; just did a cover story on these businesses, which are not really a new idea, and which have sprung up all over town, in food courts everywhere.  NA and I both had the chicken horseradish sandwich at &lt;i&gt;EuroTrash&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Food caravan bizmos come in various shapes and sizes, many still on the drawing board.  Were we to serve the schools with these festivals on wheels, we could add &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/08/escaping-light-pollution.html&quot;&gt;the planetarium truck&lt;/a&gt; and some of the other education mobiles (lots of STEM and/or STEAM), tipping the scales in favor of study.  The military recruiters would want to join our circus, along with various gangland front ends, as humans tend to polarize into warring bands in some regions, which pass on their traditions.  We could have a traveling anthropology bus with some exhibits about that, as if it were news to anyone.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Rather than emphasize the competitive aspect so much, I tend to think of bizmos in fleets, with control room dispatchers responding to request maps.  You tend to go where you&#39;re wanted and invited.  Like I felt welcomed in those venues last night, as another guest of a family.  I hadn&#39;t expected to find James.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/04/earthy-day.html&quot;&gt;The Earth Day festival&lt;/a&gt; had its food booth aspects as well, and a carnival atmosphere.  The fair and circus come into play as motifs anytime you caravan these things, which conjures gypsies.  There&#39;s the romance of the road, the idea of sometimes sharing a journey.  However it&#39;s not like I&#39;m inventing this life style in science fiction:  we already have the RVs and their RV parks.  Dave Ulmer has been tooling around with his version.  NA is on his mailing list and has been getting those pictures.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1113788883885541445'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1113788883885541445'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/04/more-bizmotica.html' title='More Bizmotica'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7247390263939126675</id><published>2011-04-13T20:44:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2011-04-13T20:55:40.982-07:00</updated><title type='text'>From the Chronofile</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhMiC3nGY-ZpqBpQsq2ux-Rq_tyPOITVVKoSrjUJFrIV8V3gDiAHh6a4Z8h-CMFkjI8U8NoaRQ-LzXOT-QCtznXUO_ISoOOWRs05wFIQTOkqwKppHLmShhxt0SfZwmN9anmvgM-/s1600/ezra_pound_in_venice.png&quot; onblur=&quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 400px; height: 323px;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhMiC3nGY-ZpqBpQsq2ux-Rq_tyPOITVVKoSrjUJFrIV8V3gDiAHh6a4Z8h-CMFkjI8U8NoaRQ-LzXOT-QCtznXUO_ISoOOWRs05wFIQTOkqwKppHLmShhxt0SfZwmN9anmvgM-/s400/ezra_pound_in_venice.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5595280445793186770&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;[ &lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.com/books?id=iTKLOUiqHMMC&amp;amp;lpg=PA37&amp;amp;ots=T8tLBeR-tw&amp;amp;dq=%22ezra%20pound%22%20buckminster%20venice&amp;amp;pg=PA37#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; style=&quot;border:0px&quot; src=&quot;http://books.google.com/books?id=iTKLOUiqHMMC&amp;amp;lpg=PA37&amp;amp;ots=T8tLBeR-tw&amp;amp;dq=%22ezra%20pound%22%20buckminster%20venice&amp;amp;pg=PP1&amp;amp;output=embed&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7247390263939126675'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7247390263939126675'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/04/from-chronofile.html' title='From the Chronofile'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhMiC3nGY-ZpqBpQsq2ux-Rq_tyPOITVVKoSrjUJFrIV8V3gDiAHh6a4Z8h-CMFkjI8U8NoaRQ-LzXOT-QCtznXUO_ISoOOWRs05wFIQTOkqwKppHLmShhxt0SfZwmN9anmvgM-/s72-c/ezra_pound_in_venice.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3209471824768136684</id><published>2011-04-07T09:07:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-10-18T14:01:56.375-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Meetup in Woodstock</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Mom reminded me on the phone that she and Jack had visited the remnants of a Georgist colony in Louisiana.  Most had gone to Costa Rica a generation before.  Quakers mostly: not eager to play out their lives against the backdrop of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/more-about-narnia.html&quot;&gt;Machine World&lt;/a&gt; in El Norte.  My sister Julie joined the Costa Rican branch off community as a school teacher.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/03/inside-job-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;My review of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Inside Job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; had attracted some attention, but we didn&#39;t talk about that film.  Tom Gihring, already a good friend of the Boltons (whom I&#39;ll lunch with today), was one of the gang.  He seemed comfortable with Georgist lingo.  I consider myself more of a novice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Indeed, my purpose in being there was more to recruit another school of Economics to Systems Science.  PSU is like that last university in El Norte to offer a degree in it.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5583591181/in/set-72157625646071793&quot;&gt;Melanie Mitchell&lt;/a&gt; is on the faculty.  Students from around the world come here to learn this stuff, but there&#39;s talk of being swallowed by another department.  From my side, Systems is doing some swallowing of its own, the better to compete with Economics, while seeking defectors willing to jump ship.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Plans to phase in energy management simulations (micro and macro), as a part of the curriculum, link here.  I&#39;m not sure if Stanford is into being this practical.  California is taking the lead in other respects.  I was expressing admiration about that at Wanderers today, saying Reed College could learn a thing or two from the competition (not that I&#39;m with Reed College, any more than with PSU -- just close with some alums, current and ex faculty, a few students).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;The Systems / GST camp is staking turf in the &quot;smart house / smart grid&quot; namespace, prying it loose from Economics, at least of the fuddy dud sort.  Software engineers will have more of a future with &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2006/09/toontalk.html&quot;&gt;CEOs&lt;/a&gt; who studied Systems over some withering branch of Econ out of Chicago or whatever.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3209471824768136684'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3209471824768136684'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/04/meetup-in-woodstock.html' title='Meetup in Woodstock'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4377778350563930463</id><published>2011-04-01T19:27:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-12-20T12:18:36.860-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Ecumenical Ministries</title><content type='html'>I&#39;m feeling like the chief clerk of EMO these days, not that they have such a position.  That&#39;s Ecumenical Ministries of Oregon, my old boss, and sponsor of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2009/05/time-for-reconciliation.html&quot;&gt;Bishop Tutu&#39;s visit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Today, I was in somewhat &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/02/methodist-morning.html&quot;&gt;Methodist circles&lt;/a&gt;, explaining &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/04/first-person-physics.html&quot;&gt;to Bob (Fuller) &lt;/a&gt;that I&#39;d met Alex through this esoteric Buddhist cult called FNB, which of course is a stretch.  It&#39;s a national organization.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Our lunch as at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5584181036/in/photostream/&quot;&gt;the Cuban place&lt;/a&gt; on 28th and Glisan, a first for all three of us.  Mom left voice mail from her airplane seat:  off to WDC again.  We&#39;d all been to Burma (me just for a couple days as I recall, on home leave), two of us to Bhutan. I wore a sharks &amp;amp; dolphins T-shirt under a free pile &lt;i&gt;Nike&lt;/i&gt; jacket, which become too hot as the weather brightened and warmed.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
After lunch I dropped a trailer with cooking gear w/ Jay @ SDW (Episcopalian) before visiting the &lt;i&gt;Daime House&lt;/i&gt; (which &lt;i&gt;WW&lt;/i&gt; had unceremoniously dubbed the &lt;i&gt;Voodoo House&lt;/i&gt;, in a rather parochial snub piece).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Lets be fair though, I really was learning about some esoteric Buddhist stuff in the park, like from a computerist guitarist who&#39;d been sharing the other night (and not someone ordained).  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
This was an important API, this part of &quot;the matrix&quot; (rDzogs-chen).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
That&#39;s when I wrote to Quakers (Los Amigos):&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot; style=&quot;border-collapse: collapse; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot; style=&quot;border-collapse: collapse; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;That&#39;s one reason I think an FNB binder might be cool:  we get such exotic people coming through all the time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot; style=&quot;border-collapse: collapse; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot; style=&quot;border-collapse: collapse; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;I enjoy the ecumenical opportunities that this work fosters.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot; style=&quot;border-collapse: collapse; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot; style=&quot;border-collapse: collapse; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;Learned more about Newar Buddhism and Palden Lhamo today, at the serving.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I borrowed &lt;i&gt;Forest of Visions: Ayahuasca, Amazonian Spirituality, and the Santo Daime Tradition&lt;/i&gt;, by Alex Polari De Alverga (translated from Portuguese by Rosana Workman).  I think I&#39;ll &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/11/smiley-guy.html&quot;&gt;take it by &lt;i&gt;Lyrik&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for conversational value.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
Speaking of which, I had &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2011/03/more-qm-in-portlandia.html&quot;&gt;a meetup with Jody&lt;/a&gt;, the former owner.  I named &lt;i&gt;Fine Grind Productions&lt;/i&gt; after her coffee shop, now &lt;i&gt;Lyrik&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
I&#39;ve also borrowed &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5583591181/in/set-72157625646071793&quot;&gt;Complexity: A Guided Tour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, by Melanie Mitchell.  Melanie is teaching at PSU this semester.  She harkens back to SFI (Santa Fe Institute) and is part of the dynamical systems clique, along with her mentors, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/06/scholars-in-summer.html&quot;&gt;Douglas Hofstadter&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/04/reinventing-sacred.html&quot;&gt;Stu Kauffman&lt;/a&gt;, the latter one of our ISEPP lecturers.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4377778350563930463'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4377778350563930463'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/04/ecumenical-ministries.html' title='Ecumenical Ministries'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1055966068327551365</id><published>2011-03-30T13:49:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-03-30T14:15:44.503-07:00</updated><title type='text'>More Comedy</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;311&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/TvQbkPS8zCA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;311&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/9QS0q3mGPGg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Current household faves, when taking a break from being serious.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/12/some-youtube-r.html&quot;&gt;Earlier favorites&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1055966068327551365'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1055966068327551365'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/03/more-comedy.html' title='More Comedy'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/TvQbkPS8zCA/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7011780100611292592</id><published>2011-03-27T10:52:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-04-17T00:14:33.687-07:00</updated><title type='text'>The Magic Christian (movie review)</title><content type='html'>I tried grabbing a screen shot of Yul Brynner in drag.  Easier said than done with bitmaps.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;d not been aware of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0064622/&quot;&gt;this interesting spoof&lt;/a&gt;, starring Peter Sellers and Ringo Starr.  Early (1969) foreshadowing of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/06/bruno-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Bruno&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, especially in the boxing ring scene.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The film is about the all-corrupting power of money, and the thin veneer of polity (polite company) over fear and longing, with all kinds of cracks and fissures manifest.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But is also a who&#39;s who of sorts, an allusion to the ship of fools that is &lt;i&gt;The Magic Christian&lt;/i&gt; (an opulent cruise ship).  Raquel Welch, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0061391/&quot;&gt;of &lt;i&gt;Bedazzled&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, makes an appearance.  The future &lt;i&gt;Monty Python&lt;/i&gt; cast is picking up the baton of British comedy.  Then there&#39;s Ringo himself, with a sound track by Paul.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Sellers is preternaturally good at affecting lots of inane mannerisms and accents.  American accents (and attitudes) get spoofed as well.  Ringo Starr is the privileged son who gets the view from back stage as it were, with a front row seat on &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2011/03/inside-job-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Vice Street&lt;/a&gt; goings on (board meetings etc.).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;When the practical jokes are as benign as these, having lots of money starts to look like fun.  Too bad so many jokers are &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/08/dark-knight-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;more like The Joker&lt;/a&gt; than like our &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/01/being-there-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Being There&lt;/i&gt; guy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7011780100611292592'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7011780100611292592'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/03/magic-christian-movie-review.html' title='The Magic Christian (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1214955611208718225</id><published>2011-03-24T14:33:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2011-03-27T10:21:58.780-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Citizen Diplomats</title><content type='html'>Tara and I met with Betsey today, in Vancouver, Washington (McMenamins).  On the agenda:  a delegation to Nicaragua.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Later we found out that the SE side Passport Office is not where Google says it is.  The guy behind the desk assured us they&#39;d contacted everyone they could think of about the misinformation. Welcome to government, where record keeping is hard to keep up with, even if working at the speed of light.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Good to catch up with Betsey, one of Tara&#39;s &quot;Quaker aunts&quot;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Welcome to Portland, Colin.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;m finally getting &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/12/onward-fnb.html&quot;&gt;back in the saddle&lt;/a&gt; with FNB and the Multnomah Friends Meetinghouse.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1214955611208718225'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1214955611208718225'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/03/citizen-diplomats.html' title='Citizen Diplomats'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2396310836456316321</id><published>2011-03-17T14:01:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2011-05-07T12:30:20.163-07:00</updated><title type='text'>SPD (sponsored)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;311&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/9w0cEESCuDA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The above is what my friend Andrew Frank has been into, as a dedicated worker for the Infinia company.  He swooped in from Kennewick that time, to show me innovations in pedagogy.  He&#39;d always been talented.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This week:  the Sonnenfeld family came through, minus Candy and Teddy, but we included Candy vicariously (she&#39;d grown up in Portland some) by going to the &lt;i&gt;Crab Bowl&lt;/i&gt; (in name only, but a dear place nonetheless).  Ergo, I didn&#39;t get to the well-attended Quantum Mechanics lecture at ISEPP, starring Julian and George, other friends (hello Allen Taylor... Jon Bunce).  Dinner at the &lt;i&gt;Portland Fish House&lt;/i&gt; was a better use of my time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today:  SPD (St. Patrick&#39;s Day) is also when Dawn left our company, though not in spirit.  I&#39;ve been invited to a Labyrinth ceremony this evening.  Tara is in debate camp (nat quals), while Alexia celebrates her eldest daughter relationship.  My mom phoned me, to yak about death and taxes.  She&#39;s using her Google phone, which she likes a lot.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rick got to meet Alex.  The Wittgenstein Study Group lives on.  Before that:  OMSI.  We all road the simulator, which appears to substitute acceleration with motion, but can&#39;t really do the roller coaster willies the way a real roller coaster would.  But then it&#39;s only $5.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Speaking of which, I&#39;m reviewing the ways in which Bangladeshis are called &quot;poor&quot; in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sundance.org/videos/gates/small-changebig-idea/&quot;&gt;this excellent video&lt;/a&gt; by my good friend Glenn Baker.  In light of &lt;i&gt;The Economics of Happiness&lt;/i&gt;, I&#39;d suggest that be revised.  Bhutanese have a high living standard, because they&#39;re free and under the thumb of nary a superpower.  Superpowers are sorrowful, cuz they suck.  Mad Magazine never wuz one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;LW is off to FNB.  Marian Rhys phoned to say she&#39;d be there.  I have no idea about Jezebel.  When the Sonnenfelds were around, I made sure to play up the Google Earth reality of some of these structures, such as the Pauling House and Lew&#39;s rendition of the Stark Street meetinghouse.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I notice Trump is on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newsmax.com/InsideCover/TrumpRaisesBirtherQuestions/2011/03/17/id/389792&quot;&gt;bandwagon of sickos&lt;/a&gt; already in questioning the president&#39;s credibility and veracity on the matter of his own place of birth. President Obama has done a fine job in my book: no kooky generals bombing Iran already, like ran amok in Iraq.  LAWCAP&#39;s &quot;spaz attacks&quot; were /are killing our planet (hence the straitjacketing, continued auditing).&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2396310836456316321'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2396310836456316321'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/03/spd-sponsored.html' title='SPD (sponsored)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/9w0cEESCuDA/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1429091933560966593</id><published>2011-03-10T13:40:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T09:16:39.092-08:00</updated><title type='text'>PPUG 2011.3.8</title><content type='html'>I got good and winded running to the bus for this one, almost door-to-door.  I&#39;d forgotten where the door was though, which added time.  &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I barely had time to swig a beer and grab a piece of Fat Tuesday pastry at &lt;i&gt;Urban Airship&lt;/i&gt; before the charming Michelle hassled me to grab a nametag.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;My name was spelled backwards (ala Leonardo), leading one geek to joke about his mirror iPod app (for when you need to fix your lipstick or whatever).&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The main talks were by Lindsey Smith regarding feedparser, &quot;Shmichael&quot; about PEPs 380 &amp;amp; 3152, Adam Lowry about some ingenious thread tracker he&#39;d written, and Eric Holscher on a way he could track server activity with this nifty graphic web stuff he&#39;d put together.  These were definitely &quot;makers&quot;, creative bar none.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Will I have time to propose an OS Bridge talk this year?  I don&#39;t yet have the video clips I&#39;m looking for.  We&#39;re in a holding pattern, waiting for the dominant paradigm to admit it could use some stabilizing influences.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We went to Bailey&#39;s for the after-party again.  As usual, I talked with the gmpy guy from Mentor Graphics, plus someone else who wanted to talk about OpenEMR, other open source medical records initiatives.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Remember:  open source doesn&#39;t mean open data.  You can have all the source code published and in the clear, and still be as tight as Fort Knox in what you do with it.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Some of us are going to Pycon this weekend.  Not me though, gotta work and stop traveling for awhile.  I&#39;ll miss the whiskey BOF.  Jason Kirtland had some cool glasses made.  One is depicted below.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5516563954/&quot; title=&quot;P3080164 by thekirbster, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5258/5516563954_98dab6732f_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;180&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; alt=&quot;P3080164&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1429091933560966593'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1429091933560966593'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/03/ppug-201138.html' title='PPUG 2011.3.8'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5258/5516563954_98dab6732f_t.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-514155820278171139</id><published>2011-03-05T07:21:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2011-03-27T10:31:32.407-07:00</updated><title type='text'>War as Sport</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/03/corporation-meeting.html&quot;&gt;Our corporation meeting&lt;/a&gt; continues... Treasurer&#39;s report in progress.  Friends really appreciate JimFletcher.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;ve been reading some of the literature around Friends Center, reminding myself that many enjoy participating in outward wars, find meaning in it, and would feel lost without these kinds of challenges.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/11/hurt-locker-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;War is addictive&lt;/a&gt; and many depend on it for their livelihoods, not just soldiers.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Friends engage in somewhat parallel activities in extolling &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5497828579/in/set-72157626076057099/&quot;&gt;the &quot;Lamb&#39;s War&quot;&lt;/a&gt; as something positive. This is an inward war, a jihad, waged with psychological instruments.  Many enjoy this work and take sustenance from it.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Legitimizing large scale violence is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gPJU0dbrOXI&quot;&gt;a core function&lt;/a&gt; of many states and religions.  The business of making war depends on inspiring ideologies, cheer leading, drumming up passions.  The star &quot;athletes&quot; in this sport become anxious when no war seems to be looming.  How will the next generation learn the ropes?  The cigarette industry has a similar ongoing challenge:  recruiting new smokers.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Fortunately for the violence-prone, the human condition remains dire, with resources distributed highly inequitably and injustice the norm.  Betting on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R9wgjxO7JtY&quot;&gt;the war machine&lt;/a&gt; seems like a secure investment and many pensions depend on its thriving (or used to -- some have escaped the vortex to morally higher ground).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;LAWCAP long ago figured out how to institutionalize weapons production across many congressional districts (CDs).  Since WW2, the actual needs of professional militarists has taken a back seat to &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/12/iron-mountain-revisted.html&quot;&gt;the economic needs&lt;/a&gt; of the war machine.  Outward war is &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/06/recruiting-commercial.html&quot;&gt;an economic necessity&lt;/a&gt; for this creature, regardless of consequences.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The proliferation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/12/countdown-to-zero-game.html&quot;&gt;nuclear WMDs&lt;/a&gt; of little strategic or tactical value is symptomatic of this form of mental illness (the so-called &quot;military industrial complex&quot;).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Yeah, these are somewhat cliche thoughts for a Quaker to be having, I admit.  Decrying the &quot;war machine&quot; is an ancient literature by this time.  If people really thought a better lifestyle were possible without it, that&#39;d shift the balance perhaps, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theendofpoverty.com/&quot;&gt;such &quot;utopianism&quot;&lt;/a&gt; is routinely dismissed by the outward warmongers.  Those with the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/08/some-analysis.html&quot;&gt;most toys&lt;/a&gt;&quot; are given to believe that &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2008/05/carrier-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;their living standards&lt;/a&gt; would plummet were there to be something called &quot;world peace&quot;, a nasty and undesirable outcome &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2010/01/revisting-malthus.html&quot;&gt;by many accounts&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;To really move beyond &quot;outward war&quot; (which&#39;d require more effectively countering sociopathic behavior around the world), we&#39;d need to go with something more &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/gst1.html&quot;&gt;like general systems theory&lt;/a&gt; (ala &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/17157315@N00/5497829057/in/set-72157626076057099/&quot;&gt;Kenneth Boulding&lt;/a&gt;) over traditional economics.  We&#39;d need to take a more &lt;a href=&quot;http://grunch.net/archives/41&quot;&gt;Project Renaissance approach&lt;/a&gt;, wherein longing would trump fear.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/514155820278171139'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/514155820278171139'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/03/war-as-sport.html' title='War as Sport'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>