<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211</id><updated>2025-02-27T06:25:58.543-08:00</updated><category term="clojure python REPL ide"/><title type='text'>BizMo Diaries</title><subtitle type='html'>On the road with Global Data</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=501'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=476&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=526&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1905</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>501</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1245300852179704369</id><published>2017-12-15T12:22:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-15T12:36:18.427-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Launch Pad</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
The house next door held an album release party last night. I believe &lt;i&gt;Peach Pit&lt;/i&gt; is the name of the band. One of our regulars found a wallet on the sidewalk and mentioned to several partiers we had it. Stopping the band for a sec to make an announcement proved impractical.&amp;nbsp; She came and collected it later. I never saw the lass as I was engulfed in the Steve Holden Chair of Computer Science, now with a large log in the back to compensate for lost screws.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These were the days, at the conclusion of 2017, when DC was relinquishing relevance left and right, butting out of businesses it no longer has the capacity to either regulate or understand.&amp;nbsp; Like the military, DC depends entirely on the private sector for any remaining smarts.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not saying the public sector can&#39;t or won&#39;t make &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2011/05/cowardly-capitalism.html&quot;&gt;a comeback&lt;/a&gt;, however that needn&#39;t happen in DC in particular.&amp;nbsp; OSCON is &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenewstack.io/oscon-coming-back-portland-show-wrap-co-chair-kelsey-hightower/&quot;&gt;returning to Portland&lt;/a&gt; after all.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Melody and Alexia each took a guest room as we switch tracks through this hub.&amp;nbsp; Blue House experiences turnover.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve finished my most recent cycle of ten meetups, netting more LinkedIn connections.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s an over-the-wire closed circuit TV show, built atop Internet technologies (or should we write &quot;internet&quot; -- the &lt;i&gt;Buzzfeed&lt;/i&gt; copy editor shared some views on that at Powell&#39;s recently).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The idea of a global oligarchy / kleptocracy is not new and the concentration of capitalism in fewer hands, amidst a rising financial literacy index, has helped it once again gain foreground status. The notion of a &quot;grunch&quot; of giants pulling the strings is ingrained in the folklore, as expressed in various narratives.&amp;nbsp; The demise of nation-state politics, or shall we call it an eclipse, was never an overnight phenomenon.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ll have true believers clinging to their true beliefs long into some future.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Tom&#39;s&lt;/i&gt;, a favorite breakfast nook, was not quite up to snuff this morning; too busy? The PSU student I was with required one fried egg over hard, but got two, soupy.&amp;nbsp; For a hard egg person, soupy is not appetizing.&amp;nbsp; Have you notice the &quot;hard over&quot; types also trend towards crispy bacon?&amp;nbsp; Lets see a scatter plot right?&amp;nbsp; Big Data where are you?&amp;nbsp; I posted a semi-favorable review on &lt;i&gt;Yelp!&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; No place is perfect.&amp;nbsp; They recooked the egg part then still billed for two (neither eaten), a sixty cent difference, but the bookkeeper trainee stood on principle, bless her heart.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Coming back to Blue House we encountered a small murder of crows, nothing like what we see (and hear!) in the PSU park blocks.&amp;nbsp; I mention that &quot;group word&quot; for crows in explication of my &quot;grunch&quot; (of giants) above.&amp;nbsp; Haim and I used to joke on &lt;i&gt;math-teach&lt;/i&gt; about how I got it wrong in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/grunch.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Desovereignization&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (a web page):&amp;nbsp; I said &quot;gander&quot; instead of &quot;gaggle&quot; (of geese). I still get those two confused.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
Please don&#39;t ask that question. I think we have seen there is no bottom to stupidity.😝😝😝 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/Z9QjaaCitN&quot;&gt;https://t.co/Z9QjaaCitN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
— Dorthea Kemp (@dkempdesigns) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dkempdesigns/status/941376612263710720?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 14, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1245300852179704369'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1245300852179704369'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/12/launch-pad.html' title='Launch Pad'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5405685941757104875</id><published>2017-12-09T22:08:00.005-08:00</published><updated>2023-05-07T16:10:39.962-07:00</updated><title type='text'>School Planning On Facebook</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; gesture=&quot;media&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8_R55Z0OWQU&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On Facebook, we&#39;re looking at the XQ Super Schools Project, a priority of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emersoncollective.com/&quot;&gt;Emerson Collective&lt;/a&gt;. This was after I brought up the generic idea of charter networks latching on to at least some of the New England / New Scotland (Nova Scotia) stuff, transcendentalism if you will.&amp;nbsp; Alexander Graham Bell and family were the New Scotland residents. His interests had turned to aeronautics after the big invention for which he was most known: the telephone.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You may have seen me on Youtube in my obscure (esoteric) channel, telling the story of Bell and his kites, based on this book I&#39;m reading, having mined it for pictures.&amp;nbsp; Bucky Fuller is mentioned throughout, as another genius who came upon the same discovery by a different route.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m talking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/4dsolutions/Python5/blob/master/STEM%20Mathematics.ipynb&quot;&gt;the octet-truss &lt;/a&gt;of course.&amp;nbsp; What charters teach that?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not that one needs a charter or that you have no right to experiment even if you&#39;ve been stereotyped as a &quot;traditional&quot; school.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Friday, I was out of my usual ruts in North Portland, finally visiting the latest digs used by Saturday Academy, by now the thirty five year old institution.&amp;nbsp; You&#39;ll find &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/search?q=%22Saturday+Academy%22&quot;&gt;I go way back&lt;/a&gt; regarding Saturday Academy in these blogs.&amp;nbsp; We talked about Martian Math some more.&amp;nbsp; I showed up with what&#39;s left of those cardboard polyhedrons made by Russell Chu and Trevor Blake and myself.&amp;nbsp; Some of those didn&#39;t survive to the end of 2017. Plus I took some C6XTY to the meeting.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/5436831548/in/photolist-wWKQmk-bdBsk4-a3doND-9mY873-9hrbAY-8awzCS-7Fw23Z-7dcs4X-6BY6va-6oqjem-6i5oRw-5SXuYP-5PjRWV-5AA1JF-5xe2b6-5sHnxN-5rFY8v-2yoZR2&quot; title=&quot;Bell&#39;s Octet Truss&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bell&#39;s Octet Truss&quot; height=&quot;387&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4112/5436831548_feefdbb9a0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Where we stand today in Python World, is Visual Python, a flagship spatial geometry add-on, is starting to work well with Jupyter Notebooks, a core technology in my virtual classroom.&amp;nbsp; We might be able to give high and middle school age students some experience with these tools.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.4dsolutions.net/satacad/martianmath/toc.html&quot;&gt;The Martian Math stuff&lt;/a&gt; is very polyhedron focused.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
C6XTY consists of plastic soccer-ball like spheres held in a semi-rigid lattice per the octet-truss arrangement, ditto Alexander Graham Bell&#39;s design for kites, towers, other structures.&amp;nbsp; Is it that he didn&#39;t patent the thing?&amp;nbsp; One might think that Fuller&#39;s gaining a patent on it later might have necessitated bringing their contributions together, and making Bell&#39;s work known to Fuller.&amp;nbsp; Apparently these connections got made only later.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Will a &quot;super school&quot; teach me anything about A, B, T, E and S modules?&amp;nbsp; In this flavor of spatial geometry, we employ the octet-truss as our home base conceptual scaffolding, not the XYZ all-cubes lattice of Descartes and Fermat.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not like we can&#39;t use both.&amp;nbsp; Indeed, in converting between the unit volume of the &quot;IVM&quot; (the octet-truss skeleton) and the unit volume of the XYZ coordinate system, we encounter S3, a specific scale factor, or &quot;currency converter&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Quakers (Friends) have their history as school makers.&amp;nbsp; Schools have to be more than brick and mortar buildings, a physical campus, to survive the exigencies of time.&amp;nbsp; They need &quot;schools of thought&quot; to inhabit them, give them life.&amp;nbsp; What ghosts might we attract over time?&amp;nbsp; What frequencies?&amp;nbsp; Obviously, I&#39;m reaching back to reach forward.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/38925811861/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Vpython in Jupyter&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Vpython in Jupyter&quot; height=&quot;327&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4524/38925811861_7b5a21877a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5405685941757104875'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5405685941757104875'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/12/school-planning-on-facebook.html' title='School Planning On Facebook'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/8_R55Z0OWQU/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7868273055921260753</id><published>2017-12-02T10:44:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-02T11:09:29.814-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Work / Study</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
The plan in the &quot;US&quot; Congress, to gut grad schools by making tuition waivers taxable, targeting those with the least income yet still with hope, is motivating changes in bookkeeping.&amp;nbsp; Work/study is what they do in Congress too.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When I get a job at IBM or Google, and work my butt off to learn a lot of in-house procedures, you could say I&#39;m in a kind of grad school, except I never see the $95K income the government would tax, that represents the worth of my training.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Likewise, a freshman legislator, still learning House rules, is getting a tuition waiver on like a $200K privilege, as she or he gets an education in the arcane functioning of government organs.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s a lot like going to med school.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Given this concept of &quot;tuition waiver&quot; is so flexible, and doesn&#39;t apply in the case of IBM or Congress, it looks like schools will be changing their rules as well, to operate more like corporations, the only structure the &quot;US&quot; looks upon favorably, having been hollowed out by same.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We say &quot;US&quot; Congress with scare quotes at times, as the will of the people is no longer expressed through democratic institutions in the District of Columbia.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s propaganda, or fake news, and rather weak.&amp;nbsp; We know bankruptcy when we see it.&amp;nbsp; The attack against grad students is proof positive that we have a dangerous parasite in our midst.&amp;nbsp; Let&#39;s hope the antibodies go into overdrive.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You&#39;ll notice the so-called &quot;public schools&quot; no longer teach civics nor provide much insight into the workings of government.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ve degenerated into clashing mobs and their media.&amp;nbsp; I suppose that&#39;s what they mean by &quot;populism&quot;.&amp;nbsp; Whatever it is, it&#39;s not recognizably what&#39;s spelled out in the US Constitution. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
That the USA is dead and gone, undefended by those sworn to uphold its Constitution, is &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=7bzPDQAAQBAJ&amp;amp;lpg=PA74&amp;amp;ots=Z6iD06JwCh&amp;amp;dq=grunch%20bankrupt%20extinct&amp;amp;pg=PA74#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;not really news&lt;/a&gt; though.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ve lived with mob rule since the 1980s at least.&amp;nbsp; Imperialism spelled the death of a once proud democracy.&amp;nbsp; We live amidst its ruins and remnants, waiting to see what springs from the ashes.&amp;nbsp; In the meantime, it&#39;s all &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/12/reality-tv.html&quot;&gt;Reality TV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7868273055921260753'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7868273055921260753'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/12/work-study.html' title='Work / Study'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6569300784530069861</id><published>2017-11-23T21:17:00.004-08:00</published><updated>2021-07-27T16:24:45.534-07:00</updated><title type='text'>TG 2017</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157691081244906&quot; title=&quot;TG 2017&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/4538/37722923845_e5b12483c5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;TG 2017&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Carol and I were grateful for an invitation from the Bartons to share their Thanksgiving. Tara used to babysit for their kids.&amp;nbsp; Patrick and I were co-workers with O&#39;Reilly School.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Now I&#39;m back in my personal workspace (PWS) plowing through some &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/5ThZst_U4HA&quot;&gt;instruction videos&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; I did about two hours researching wars in the former Yugoslavia first.&amp;nbsp; That came up during dinner, as the war crimes trials in The Hague are just coming to a conclusion around now.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m thinking my next Python course should &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/SMEOKDVXlUo&quot;&gt;look at Bitcoin more&lt;/a&gt;, as an example of (a) applied cryptography and (b) using a complex API.&amp;nbsp; If you&#39;ve followed me on math-teach at all, I&#39;ve been pushed for more crypto along &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathforum.org/kb/message.jspa?messageID=10283328&quot;&gt;a high school DM (digital math) track&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Bartons have a new adult dog named Quinn.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve been getting time with Quinn when Patrick brings him to Mt. Tabor, a popular walk for a lot of us.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tomorrow I&#39;m up early, for travel out of state.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I didn&#39;t know that bokeh in photography meant peripheral blur, i.e. there&#39;s a contrasting focus on &quot;what&#39;s relevant&quot;.&amp;nbsp; That gets me thinking of the Synergetics &quot;sphere of relevance&quot; meme, a system attuned to a frequency that dismisses a bokeh of twilight zone data.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Systems, in Synergetics, have a visual representation as spherical objects.&amp;nbsp; If you read &lt;a href=&quot;https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/bubbles&quot;&gt;Peter Sloterdijk&#39;s stuff&lt;/a&gt;, you&#39;ll get a workout thinking with this metaphor.&amp;nbsp; That could help make Synergetics useful, as a tool.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6569300784530069861'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6569300784530069861'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/11/tg-2017.html' title='TG 2017'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8512134285758073180</id><published>2017-11-17T00:04:00.003-08:00</published><updated>2017-11-17T00:04:47.126-08:00</updated><title type='text'>UFOs</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/37762339284/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Python Lab&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Python Lab&quot; height=&quot;291&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4581/37762339284_f7cec7bc86.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I needn&#39;t have conclusions regarding UFOs in order to pay attention to reports.  In this Python lab, I use a UFO reports database as a means of introducing the DB API i.e. &quot;this is how we talk to a SQL engine&quot;.  I&#39;m not aiming to settle any disputes.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8512134285758073180'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8512134285758073180'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/11/ufos.html' title='UFOs'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7468392565659718304</id><published>2017-11-10T01:04:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2017-11-10T01:15:36.265-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Old Feuds</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Buried in some distant past already, the prehistoric origins of Scientology, in science fiction writings by the same author.&amp;nbsp; A shift of gear, a change in tenor (or tense), and a new religion pitched a big tent, its founder a legend in his own time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As cultural historians have shown, the culture was hungry for healing, having been through some bruising battles, literally as well as metaphysically.&amp;nbsp; Civil Rights were hard won, as we feel more acutely when the clock starts running backward.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A core tenant of Scientology goes back to P.D. Ouspensky and others:&amp;nbsp; taking the negative charge off of memories takes Work.&amp;nbsp; Maurice Nicoll, a Jungian Scots following in O&#39;s footsteps, capitalized Work the same way.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then &lt;i&gt;est&lt;/i&gt; came along and reiterated various practices, though certainly not auditing and e-meters and without the business model of a religion.&amp;nbsp; Many in the Scientology camp felt compelled to think in terms of a turf battle.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s one of the old feuds.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A hit piece against Erhard by mainstream media, somewhat baseless, showed that money and politics were hard at work, seeking to keep some trends in check.&amp;nbsp; Bucky was fighting alongside Erhard around then.&amp;nbsp; You might wanna dig into that story sometime, if curious. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Another feud is between the reverent and irreverent more generally.&amp;nbsp; As one who grew up reading &lt;i&gt;MAD Magazine&lt;/i&gt; as an alternative to Meeting for Worship (I&#39;d go both ways), the irreverence of the &lt;i&gt;Church of the Subgenius&lt;/i&gt; was sure to resonate.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m glad the Kickstarter project, to get the documentary out there, got funded.&amp;nbsp; I pledged my $30.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As these blogs disclose, I did volunteer work for the Centers Network around the time I enrolled in &lt;i&gt;est&lt;/i&gt;, in my Princeton through St. Dominic years.&amp;nbsp; My friend Ray Simon was a big fan of Hubbard and Erhard both.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve told that story.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Not just the struggle for Civil Rights across &quot;races&quot; but across generations.&amp;nbsp; Did these adults who thought a certain way have the right to derail young lives by sending kids to fight in the jungles of Southeast Asia against their will?&amp;nbsp; What was the rationale?&amp;nbsp; To fight for freedom? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Muhammad Ali shows up, along with Malcolm X and Father Divine, as a bridge figure, taking us closer to MLK&#39;s dream of a post-apartheid America. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Jungians have their own leading towards pacifist strategies.&amp;nbsp; Unlike Quakerism, the Jungian tradition is more a profession than a religion.&amp;nbsp; These two strands intertwine nonetheless.&amp;nbsp; When I&#39;m tempted to feed into religion, I&#39;m reminded of my existing outlets.&amp;nbsp; Praise Bob.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7468392565659718304'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7468392565659718304'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/11/old-feuds.html' title='Old Feuds'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1967061821294714552</id><published>2017-11-06T12:51:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2017-11-07T11:16:37.888-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Another HP4E Story</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/btPqKAGyajM&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Welcome to another episode of &lt;i&gt;Hexapents for Everybody&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; What&#39;s a hexapent?&amp;nbsp; Most simply, the Adidas soccer ball pattern, also found in Carbon-60, the buckminsterfullerene molecule.&amp;nbsp; FIFA appears to have moved on to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.soccerballworld.com/HistoryWCBalls.htm&quot;&gt;a new pattern&lt;/a&gt;, but that&#39;s neither here nor there.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/08/hp4e.html&quot;&gt;The topology at work&lt;/a&gt; is such that those twelve pentagons, evenly distributed on the classic soccer ball, might be more randomly distributed, even as the number of hexagons is allowed to proliferate (&quot;higher frequency&quot;).&amp;nbsp; Nor are we limited to twelve pentagons if straying from a purely hexapent pattern. Why not allow squares too?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Adrian Rossiter &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/08/code-school-evening.html&quot;&gt;of Antiprism fame&lt;/a&gt; has shared such a construction in the window below.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s fortuitous for &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/08/hp4e-continued.html&quot;&gt;our HP4E campaign&lt;/a&gt; is we don&#39;t need the petitioned bureaucracy behind public road signage to cave, and show pentagons going forward.&amp;nbsp; We use the discrepancy, now enshrined, to suggest a productive thought process, a new thoroughfare.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Keep those signs exactly as they are, along with any number of similar exhibits suggesting unfamiliarity with basic principles of Synergetics, and leverage that circumstance to promote the missing ingredient.&amp;nbsp; The lack begets its antibody, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kirbyurner/thinking-globally-in-2016-f01cd34466a6&quot;&gt;the corresponding knowledge&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sketchfab-embed-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowvr=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; onmousewheel=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://sketchfab.com/models/29ce6292101f4fa88a978d4f239b9422/embed&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: #4a4a4a; font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal; margin: 5px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://sketchfab.com/models/29ce6292101f4fa88a978d4f239b9422?utm_medium=embed&amp;amp;utm_source=website&amp;amp;utm_campain=share-popup&quot; style=&quot;color: #1caad9; font-weight: bold;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UK Government Standard Hex Football&lt;/a&gt;
    by &lt;a href=&quot;https://sketchfab.com/antiprism?utm_medium=embed&amp;amp;utm_source=website&amp;amp;utm_campain=share-popup&quot; style=&quot;color: #1caad9; font-weight: bold;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Adrian Rossiter&lt;/a&gt;
    on &lt;a href=&quot;https://sketchfab.com/?utm_medium=embed&amp;amp;utm_source=website&amp;amp;utm_campain=share-popup&quot; style=&quot;color: #1caad9; font-weight: bold;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sketchfab&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1967061821294714552'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1967061821294714552'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/11/another-hp4e-story.html' title='Another HP4E Story'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/btPqKAGyajM/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1021706478312169122</id><published>2017-11-02T19:25:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2017-11-05T09:55:02.252-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Another Kirby</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/p4dLVRWUgdk&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m not saying I don&#39;t see similarities, in that we&#39;re both pink and round, and I can be something of a demon in the kitchen, occasionally breaking things (Selma could tell you).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, we should allow that&#39;s Kirby&#39;s strategy, above, of unifying opposites, is the time-tested remedy of alchemists.  Maybe he stayed a little on the too hyper side, but then it&#39;s easy to second guess from the sidelines.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi1j5F-nz0bunugmAHhmZDOJR0uPpXh4km0Gpjko56JCY4K27VEQ14fErMkSMSSo-o5Eg0qq_Id7Mondhm6UQK7yFPT_MvkzB7WDu_MnXt6Itt3-DoAc700NsTjkEISW50eivUc/s1600/kirby_sucks.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;960&quot; data-original-width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi1j5F-nz0bunugmAHhmZDOJR0uPpXh4km0Gpjko56JCY4K27VEQ14fErMkSMSSo-o5Eg0qq_Id7Mondhm6UQK7yFPT_MvkzB7WDu_MnXt6Itt3-DoAc700NsTjkEISW50eivUc/s320/kirby_sucks.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1021706478312169122'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1021706478312169122'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/11/another-kirby.html' title='Another Kirby'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/p4dLVRWUgdk/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1272466295472200616</id><published>2017-10-27T12:44:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-27T12:44:01.906-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Synergetics for Kids</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;680&quot; seamless=&quot;seamless&quot; src=&quot;https://www.codesters.com/embed/preview/b595f462122e44c88c617664c11f0162/&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;680&quot; seamless=&quot;seamless&quot; src=&quot;https://www.codesters.com/embed/preview/bea551486b384cbe8d49c87a94216dbb/&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1272466295472200616'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1272466295472200616'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/10/synergetics-for-kids.html' title='Synergetics for Kids'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6802219485076815812</id><published>2017-10-22T18:29:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-26T11:11:04.004-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Catching Up</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/37160167834/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Brochure at Hop House&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Brochure at Hop House&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4451/37160167834_3ac6a433c1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I claim to enjoy browsing a lot, since well before web browsers, but when do I get the time?&amp;nbsp; Well, today for example, I left my Stetson at &lt;i&gt;Hop House&lt;/i&gt; and used that as an excuse to wander on to &lt;i&gt;Common Ground&lt;/i&gt;, the coffee shop with the most magazines on upper Hawthorne.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I ordered a whole pot of coffee, to counteract the beers, and read up on Sleep Science, VP Pence, and former US president Hoover, not necessarily in that order.&amp;nbsp; This was all in the one issue of &lt;i&gt;New Yorker&lt;/i&gt;, October 23, 2017.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
At the &lt;i&gt;Hop House&lt;/i&gt;, with Glenn, I picked up a pamphlet on Falun Dafa. I&#39;ve been looking at this practice through a framework of comparisons with Hizmet.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Both religious movements were at first embraced by their respective governments, Turk and Chinese, then demonized.&amp;nbsp; Turkey holds US citizens hostage hoping to extradite Gulen in exchange.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I was unaware that Hoover had been a mining engineer.&amp;nbsp; His determination to feed Belgium at the height of the blockade jibed with &lt;i&gt;Human Smoke&lt;/i&gt; and his Quaker values.&amp;nbsp; He seemed happiest and/or most fulfilled when serving as some kind of chief of logistics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ll need to cycle back through his bio again soon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mike Pence, per this &lt;i&gt;New Yorker&lt;/i&gt; analysis, has always been interested in serving as a US president.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;s a heartbeat away at this moment, but at a time when said high office is waning in power?&amp;nbsp; The west coast has escaped Prohibition (the later chapter) and no longer supports the Drug Wars unless that means against McKesson etc.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I don&#39;t just browse print media however.&amp;nbsp; Last night I was half comatose letting Youtube keep picking the next one.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d surface from my somnolent state from time to time, curious what I&#39;d been brainwashing myself with.&amp;nbsp; Louis Farrakhan?&amp;nbsp; Just his fans?&amp;nbsp; Back to dream land.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I have a big screen facing me, while I recline on the futon couch.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m also active on my Kindle these days reading a Hoover Institution fellow&#39;s book from the 1990s, &lt;i&gt;Inside American Education&lt;/i&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tsowell.com/&quot;&gt;Thomas Sowell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He seems respectful of Bayard Rustin, who had Freedom House connections.&amp;nbsp; Freedom House is quoted in that Falun Gong brochure, attesting to the reality of organ harvesting.&amp;nbsp; That calls to mind &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/a6-eo6bh87g&quot;&gt;another Youtube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I visited Indiana around the time Pence made himself more enemies in the alt-gender community.&amp;nbsp; I guess it&#39;s OK with him to do that.&amp;nbsp; He defines himself as rigidly parochial Christian, not a cosmopolitan.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Glenn and I watched &lt;i&gt;Portland Timbers&lt;/i&gt; win the &lt;i&gt;Cascadia Cup&lt;/i&gt; from &lt;i&gt;Back Stage / Bagdad&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dinner with mom at &lt;i&gt;Thanh Thao&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Need sleep.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/37870183541/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Timbers win Cascadia Cup&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Timbers win Cascadia Cup&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4489/37870183541_8e1c8aa6d0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6802219485076815812'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6802219485076815812'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/10/catching-up.html' title='Catching Up'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3208660683492581258</id><published>2017-10-18T16:36:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2017-11-10T10:31:21.274-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Social Contracts</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
A lot of journalists are reporting that, given the Equifax data breach, banks are now off the hook if they mistake you for me, and open an account for the wrong person.&amp;nbsp; Who can really tell these days right?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I say &quot;nice try&quot; but the rules have changed, given now we know what they told us was secret no longer is.&amp;nbsp; So issue new credentials?&amp;nbsp; Think of new ways to establish trust?&amp;nbsp; The bitcoin people do this all the time, and yet only get flak for it from the supposedly security-minded banks.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Now that we all know an identity is easy to forge, that currency, trafficked in by Equifax, has been thoroughly debased.&amp;nbsp; Don&#39;t believe lawyers who say banks are protected from complicity in fraud if they do not exercise due diligence.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What due diligence meant then, and what it means now, given the balls that&#39;ve been dropped, is a whole new ball game.&amp;nbsp; Many conventional / routine transactions may no longer have that flavor.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not just &quot;the masses&quot; who&#39;ve realized the credit game has turned some corner.
&lt;br /&gt;
Glenn and I watched the Timbers win the Cascadia Cup.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/37870183541/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Timbers win Cascadia Cup&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Timbers win Cascadia Cup&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4489/37870183541_8e1c8aa6d0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3208660683492581258'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3208660683492581258'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/10/social-contracts.html' title='Social Contracts'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6534976583268657075</id><published>2017-10-17T16:00:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-17T16:00:38.379-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Raining Cats &amp; Tacos</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;402&quot; src=&quot;//scratch.mit.edu/projects/embed/170790360/?autostart=false&quot; width=&quot;485&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6534976583268657075'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6534976583268657075'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/10/raining-cats-tacos.html' title='Raining Cats &amp; Tacos'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-696888559714593698</id><published>2017-10-13T19:59:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-13T20:11:48.569-07:00</updated><title type='text'>October 13</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/37425325120/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;jackbhutan&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;jackbhutan&quot; height=&quot;215&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4514/37425325120_a2500d7a51.jpg&quot; width=&quot;362&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
In the year 2000 on this day, on one of many trips to nearby Bloemfontein, my parents, in their Kia SUV, encountered a pickup coming the other way in their lane.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I flew to South Africa.&amp;nbsp; Mom had survived.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We remember Jack on this day.&amp;nbsp; I arranged for his memorial service in Maseru and was graciously hosted and helped by many who knew him.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
My sister came after about a month and took over, helping Carol get back to the Pacific coast, where she lives today.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dad had a pacemaker and low blood pressure, so chances are he wouldn&#39;t have made it to today. Women outlive their men for the most part.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Here&#39;s a link to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/4dsolutions/jackbio.html&quot;&gt;an on-line bio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/696888559714593698'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/696888559714593698'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/10/october-13.html' title='October 13'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3369660122722856616</id><published>2017-10-07T13:03:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-07T16:02:20.704-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Nobel Peace Prize</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
The Nobel Peace Prize went to I-CAN this year, an organization with which my mom has worked, given the abolition of nuclear weapons is core to the WILPF agenda as well.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The award was well-timed to help focus international attention on the UN treaty to ban nuclear&amp;nbsp; weapons.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Organized crime rules the planet, often in the guise of religion.&amp;nbsp; However the rule of law has made some gains in certain pockets or niches.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The old USA was a champion of the rule of law, and democracy in many minds, until it got taken over by oligarchs and plutocrats.&amp;nbsp; Organized crime is in control again, hiding behind the veneer of legality, an increasingly thin disguise.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Absent much moral authority, the imposter government continues in a farcical manner, a scary clown.&amp;nbsp; People still interested in advancing democratic values have had to reorganize, to get out from under a failed nation-state system.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The icons and symbols, such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2017/09/flag-waving.html&quot;&gt;the Stars &amp;amp; Stripes&lt;/a&gt;, remain important.&amp;nbsp; Their meanings continue to shift, as global humanity seeks a new equilibrium.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The illegal war of aggression against Iraq, into which the American people were railroaded, pretty much broke what remained of a working democracy.&amp;nbsp; The descent into despotism has been ugly, to say the least.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3369660122722856616'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3369660122722856616'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/10/nobel-peace-prize.html' title='Nobel Peace Prize'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4992761918380102802</id><published>2017-09-26T21:23:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-02T23:28:26.220-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Five Dimensions of Python</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Understand that I&#39;m using the term &quot;dimension&quot; loosely, perhaps to structure a TED Talk, or TEDx or something similar.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Roman orator, Cicero a role model, learned to break it down into chunks.&amp;nbsp; If the chunks were too fine:&amp;nbsp; a host of problems.&amp;nbsp; Too big:&amp;nbsp; problems there too.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The goal of the accomplished orator was to get the chunk size &quot;just right&quot; for the intended audience.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The first dimension is like your utility belt, so close to home base you consider its content basic, and full of &quot;built-ins&quot; as these tools are called.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Here is your basic vocabulary for bootstrapping all the rest.&amp;nbsp; Any classic Python shell provides them natively.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In __builtins__ you get your &quot;import&quot; (for expanding the vocabulary) and your &quot;open&quot; (for streaming), your several workhorse &lt;i&gt;types&lt;/i&gt;: list and range (sequences), some number types (int, float, bool), the string type (str, another sequence), the dictionary (dict) and the set (the not-sequences or mappings).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Functions such as &quot;iter&quot; &quot;next&quot; and &quot;divmod&quot; grace the builtins, with &quot;property&quot; a built-in class (used as a decorator when the time comes).&amp;nbsp; The large number of built-in exceptions are not &quot;junk DNA&quot; but rather the signalling system used to recover gracefully from inevitable glitches.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Before dimension one though, is dimension zero: the keywords. Forgive me for going out of sequence.&amp;nbsp; The builtins are actually somewhat easier to grasp, as objects, than these more ephemeral tokens of the Python grammar.&amp;nbsp; Words like &quot;if&quot; &quot;else&quot; and &quot;lambda&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In any case, I propose we should number our dimensions from zero like Python does.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dimension Zero are the keywords and related punctuation, such as colon, square brackets, quote marks (single and double, then triple of either).&amp;nbsp; Dimension Zero provides the original syntax you&#39;ll need to structure your programs, to tell a story of what happens among its several players (the objects). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Only three of the keywords are uppercase: True, False and None.&amp;nbsp; About 35 in all, for looping, branching, making functions and classes (callables).&amp;nbsp; No keyword is a callable.&amp;nbsp; In prehistoric Python, before the great leap, &quot;print&quot; was a keyword, yet today is a built-in function.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
By dimension two, we&#39;re looking at &quot;special names&quot; (or call them __ribs__), provided by the language, meaning new ones get added from version to version, but they&#39;re not for the Python coder to create.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Like the keywords and builtins, we accept them as given.&amp;nbsp; They have that funny look:&amp;nbsp; __getitem__, __getattr__, __setitem__, __setattr__ ... __add__, __mul__ and __call__.&amp;nbsp; With these &quot;puppet strings&quot; we&#39;re able to control the behavior of our objects down to the syntactical level.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What should be the effect of using square brackets right up against my objects?&amp;nbsp; What should it do when &quot;called&quot; with curved parentheses?&amp;nbsp; How should two objects of my own devising interpret the addition or multiplication operator?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m empowered to devise alternative languages, or to approximate existing ones more closely. M1 @ M2 might result in matrix multiplication, while (f * g)(x) might be massaged to mean the same as f(g(x)).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Such sinewy flexibility, built right in to the language, could easily become a justification for the snake motif.&amp;nbsp; A snake is a subtype of dragon.&amp;nbsp; Perhaps Python has the connotation of &quot;dragon language&quot; in a more Chinese take on computer science.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dimension three: the Standard Library.&amp;nbsp; Here, with &quot;batteries included&quot; we reach a frontier.&amp;nbsp; Any Python distribution is likely to come with all of the above, after which we reach dimension four.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Dimension four includes anything from simple one-module libraries, to frameworks and distributions.&amp;nbsp; One might further differentiate between these levels, however keeping it all zero to four has its advantages.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When I teach Python to others, I&#39;ll be specific about these dimensions and then begin spiraling in all five over time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In a given lesson, we&#39;ll add a couple more keywords here, a special name there, a built-in, and then a module.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
By &quot;add&quot; I mean &quot;add to the student&#39;s knowledge base&quot; i.e. to the student&#39;s awareness of a complete ecosystem, still evolving. Python is a moving target, but it&#39;s never too late to catch up.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Even core Python is evolving, both as a language specification and in terms of its implementations.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Python has been implemented in C, C#, Java (Jython) and in a more simplified version of itself (PyPy).&amp;nbsp; Python has likely been implemented in languages I don&#39;t know about.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then we have Cython, a superset of Python with more compile time goodness.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We should expect people not that conversant with this variegated geography (territory) to get somewhat lost in it sometimes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Partly why I offer these simplifying schematics and &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/4dsolutions/Python5/blob/master/Dimensions%20of%20Python.ipynb&quot;&gt;dimension talk&lt;/a&gt;&quot; is to tame the wilderness or wildness (entropy) and bring some order out of chaos.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4992761918380102802'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4992761918380102802'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/09/five-dimensions-of-python.html' title='Five Dimensions of Python'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-325170547782242246</id><published>2017-09-25T10:38:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2017-09-26T13:42:51.263-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Curriculum Segments</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;344&quot; width=&quot;425&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/v/6qlj_AZqpto&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;embed src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/v/6qlj_AZqpto&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Above:&amp;nbsp; Discussing issues of scope, comparing and contrasting the block-based MIT Scratch with Python in Codesters.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Below:&amp;nbsp; giving a sense of where it goes after Codesters.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;344&quot; width=&quot;425&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/v/Iptjjxrvyhk&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;embed src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/v/Iptjjxrvyhk&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
Then I continue demonstrating what object oriented programming looks like, comparing the Spyder and Codester IDEs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/09/newest-youtubes.html&quot;&gt;This sequence continues&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Control Room&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;344&quot; width=&quot;425&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/v/yK0LrfQFdQY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;embed src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/v/yK0LrfQFdQY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/325170547782242246'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/325170547782242246'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/09/curriculum-segments.html' title='Curriculum Segments'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7777665061925493669</id><published>2017-09-17T10:32:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2017-09-17T10:37:27.426-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Business Meeting</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I don&#39;t think P&amp;amp;SC has had enough time to address the Chelsea Manning affair at Harvard, in which somehow Morell got mixed up. We do have a minute asking Friends Everywhere to consider the newly minted UN treaty banning (criminalizing) nuke WMDs.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;d be a step beyond banning bio and chemo, except for authorized doctor use in the war on cancer, other diseases.&amp;nbsp; Nuclear medicine is still OK.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m planning to bring Deviled Eggs to potluck, there being no prohibition against same, the name notwithstanding. We&#39;re considered Liberal Friends, meaning eggs &quot;of the Devil&quot; have not been banned, and indeed they usually go quickly, either alone or as an ingredient with potato salad, like Sonya does.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I once had a long conversation with Christine, not a big believer, thinking the kitchen conversation she&#39;d recounted was with Sonya, not Sonja -- we have both.&amp;nbsp; Silly me for getting the whole scene wrong in my head.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;ve all gotta watch that.&amp;nbsp; Constructing one&#39;s own reality (liberals believe in constructivism usually, per Piaget), is a weighty responsibility, as any weighty Friend worth her salt will attest.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I did my walking meditation up the mountain this morning, which sounds so dramatic. Mt. Tabor is the neighborhood hill, full of decorative lakes, a tribute to Portland&#39;s former glory when, like ancient Rome, it enjoyed an entirely gravity fed water system.&amp;nbsp; Engineers may be forgiven for not having the training and background to keep that up into the 21st century.&amp;nbsp; We switched over to pump-driven because that&#39;s what engineers today can understand.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The new sandals from &lt;i&gt;Bi-Mart&lt;/i&gt; are on a maiden voyage this morning, as boats for my feet.&amp;nbsp; Time to visit &lt;i&gt;Fred Meyer&lt;/i&gt;, a &lt;i&gt;Kroger&lt;/i&gt; brand shopping center, for the requisite deli offering.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Carol is here with complete versions of the UN Nuke Weapons Ban Treaty, ready for distribution at Business Meeting after potluck.&amp;nbsp; Quakers know nation-states thrive in war mode, like a drug, and have no ability to go cold turkey where WMDs are concerned.&amp;nbsp; However, we&#39;ve been able to orchestrate a gradually introduced safety and security program wherein we safeguard future generations from our radio-toxic stockpiles.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Containing fires in the heavy element sphere has not been our forte.&amp;nbsp; Chernobyl, Fukushima, Three Mile Island... how many others don&#39;t we know about?&amp;nbsp; The tick tick ticking of the time bomb nuclei, nano-hazards, have been released and the genii won&#39;t go back in the bottle.&amp;nbsp; Yes they occur naturally in some cases.&amp;nbsp; In other cases, you need a freak of nature, like hominid species of a self-destructive bent.&amp;nbsp; Then there&#39;s the depleted uranium issue.&amp;nbsp; Lots to study at OSU.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Multnomah Friends Meeting&lt;/i&gt; is based in Portland, Oregon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lastly, for today, a brought a free sample of C6XTY for the kid programs, letting them know there&#39;s more where that came from if there&#39;s interest.&amp;nbsp; I have exhibits I could bring in.&amp;nbsp; Friday was &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/09/gala-gathering.html&quot;&gt;a gala event&lt;/a&gt; wherein we got the super bowl commercials in the can.&amp;nbsp; Just kidding.&amp;nbsp; This stuff is a tad esoteric for the NFL.&amp;nbsp; When it comes to soccer clubs on the other hand...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m literally in the meetinghouse on Stark Street as I write this.&amp;nbsp; This used to be Doug Strain&#39;s electronics factory (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/planting-seeds-in-silicon-forest.html&quot;&gt;his company&#39;s&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jantzen&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Jantzen&#39;s&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; before that (swimwear factory). &lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7777665061925493669'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7777665061925493669'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/09/business-meeting.html' title='Business Meeting'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5367129623390698785</id><published>2017-09-13T21:57:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2017-09-13T22:04:20.094-07:00</updated><title type='text'>FrackNation (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
This documentary is a direct response to the award winning &lt;a href=&quot;http://controlroom.blogspot.com/2010/11/gasland-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Gasland&lt;/i&gt; by Josh Fox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I recommend viewing it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span itemprop=&quot;director&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/name/nm2697567?ref_=tt_ov_dr&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;itemprop&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Phelim McAleer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;did a lot of homework, starting with Kickstarter.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The director engages in a point by point refutation of the Josh Fox documentary.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I notice there&#39;s a &lt;i&gt;Gasland 2&lt;/i&gt; out by now.&amp;nbsp; I haven&#39;t seen it yet.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m all for public debate about public policy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The MSM comes in for some severe criticism in this film as well, especially the NYT.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5367129623390698785'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5367129623390698785'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/09/fracknation-movie-review.html' title='FrackNation (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6487912434173111809</id><published>2017-09-05T22:02:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2017-09-05T23:20:05.759-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Task Management</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.melconway.com/Home/Conways_Law.html&quot;&gt;Conway&#39;s Law&lt;/a&gt; says organizations reflect outwardly how they communicate inwardly, and that gets me thinking about task management both individually and at more collective levels.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How we write computer programs may have an impact on how we conceptualize about multi-tasking more generally. That&#39;s something I sometimes talk about with &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/08/concurrency-again.html&quot;&gt;Dr. David DiNucci&lt;/a&gt;. He was at Wanderers this evening, which adjourned early on account of &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2017/09/vacation-time.html&quot;&gt;unhealthy air quality&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the Python asynchronous model, a Task is like an egg working towards hatching, with an event loop scheduler checking each egg, almost round robin, until any one of them cracks.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The syntax expresses putting a wind-up toy into the mix, but how fast it unwinds depends on many environmental factors, such as the slowness, or speed, of the network.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tick tick tick go the eggs, somewhat like time bombs but we want and expect them to go off eventually, and each one is enveloped in a waiting handler, less a callback function than a surrounding context, the enveloping Task.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, Python&#39;s means of maximizing or optimizing a single thread is only the beginning.&amp;nbsp; Spawning threads and processes is likewise possible, using tools from the same &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/4dsolutions/Python5/blob/master/py_async_get_chemicals.py&quot;&gt;asyncio library&lt;/a&gt; or other places.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A procrastinator will often beat himself or herself up for delaying an important task just thought of, however queuing up stuff to do later is likewise a signature activity of the self-organized.&amp;nbsp; Putting things off is not a dodge, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/03/silicon-forest-curriculum.html&quot;&gt;intelligent scheduling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Let tasks come to you and don&#39;t feel compelled to jump up and immediately attend to them in the order dreamed. Acting immediately is what we call &quot;impulsive&quot; and many seemingly important tasks will appear &quot;half baked&quot; looking back.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Doing jobs in the same order you think of them may be a higher risk lifestyle than you need indulge in, is the mantra here. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Go ahead and stay in &lt;a href=&quot;http://grunch.net/synergetics/gst1.html&quot;&gt;the lotus position&lt;/a&gt;, even if your jobs queue grows in the meantime. You&#39;ll need downtime to optimize.&amp;nbsp; Seeing how to kill many virtual birds, with no real birds harmed in the process, with one stone, will be your saving grace in many cases.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, sometimes we need fast reflexes to take over.&amp;nbsp; Things do happen too fast for a lot of, or any, conscious consideration sometimes.&amp;nbsp; However don&#39;t treat your whole life like a twitch game.&amp;nbsp; Practice the art of creative delay i.e. scheduling.&amp;nbsp; Computers do it.&amp;nbsp; Multitasking is a science and an art.&amp;nbsp; Learn to both divide, and undivide, your attention.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6487912434173111809'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6487912434173111809'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/09/task-management.html' title='Task Management'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5916076908520151809</id><published>2017-08-30T15:32:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2017-08-30T15:51:43.844-07:00</updated><title type='text'>The Jupyter Community</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wdmf1msbtVs&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9by46AAqz70&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5916076908520151809'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5916076908520151809'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/08/the-jupyter-community.html' title='The Jupyter Community'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/wdmf1msbtVs/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1958646203829387795</id><published>2017-08-23T13:35:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2017-08-23T13:38:13.441-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Abducted!</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;344&quot; width=&quot;425&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/FH65gd6HwQw&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;
&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/FH65gd6HwQw&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;stage.set_background(&quot;summer&quot;)

nyc_girl = codesters.Sprite(&quot;person10&quot;, -100, -100)
girl2 = codesters.Sprite(&quot;person7&quot;, 50, -100)

ufo = codesters.Sprite(&quot;ufo&quot;)
ufo.glide_to(100, 200)

nyc_girl.say(&quot;OMG! What&#39;s that???&quot;)
stage.wait(2)
girl2.say(&quot;I think it&#39;s a flying saucer!!!&quot;)
stage.wait(2)

nyc_girl.say(&quot;&quot;)
girl2.say(&quot;&quot;)

ufo.glide_to(-400, 200)

def click():
    x = stage.click_x()
    y = stage.click_y()
    ufo.glide_to(x, y)
    # add other actions...
    
stage.event_click(click)

def space_bar():
    nyc_girl.jump(1)
    # add other actions...
    
stage.event_key(&quot;space&quot;, space_bar)


def enter_key():
    nyc_girl.hide()
    # add other actions...
    
stage.event_key(&quot;enter&quot;, enter_key)

def up_key():
    girl2.jump(1)
  
    
stage.event_key(&quot;up&quot;, up_key)

def down_key():
    girl2.hide()
    # add other actions...
    
stage.event_key(&quot;down&quot;, down_key)

def a_key():
    # add other actions...
    stage.set_background(&quot;moon&quot;)
    ufo.glide_to(0,0)
    ufo.glide_to(0,100)
    girl2.show()
    nyc_girl.show()
    nyc_girl.glide_to(-100, -100)
    girl2.glide_to(50, -100)
    nyc_girl.say(&quot;OK, so now what?&quot;)
    
stage.event_key(&quot;n&quot;, a_key)

&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1958646203829387795'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1958646203829387795'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/08/abducted.html' title='Abducted!'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8511270310427283764</id><published>2017-08-22T19:13:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2017-08-22T19:30:10.408-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Amish Mafia</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
I&#39;m not calling this a movie review because we&#39;re talking about a made-for-TV series, meaning we bypassed the old-timey big screen theater distribution networks (e.g. Miramax) and went straight to cable (which includes satellite and optical fiber).&amp;nbsp; Netflix tends to pick it up from there (just kidding, we have lots of subnets, very diverse).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In any case, I&#39;m finding myself pleasantly entertained by this pseudo-documentary genre, many faces blurred to protect the innocent.&amp;nbsp; Amish maybe get some protection from English viewers, and we the English get to see our Mafia turf wars transposed into an innocent key, with buggy races not allowed in Levi&#39;s court. Merlin, an Ohio rival, another Mafia boss, muscles in.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I rented this first season alongside season two of &lt;i&gt;Fear the Walking Dead&lt;/i&gt;, picking up at the coastline, now that our families have escaped the LA zone.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However it&#39;s not like I have oodles of hours to watch soap operas.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m doing full time work with a rush hour on both ends, ala the North American fossil-fueled nightmare (not complaining). Amish Mafia + Mennonite helps this old bones Quaker unwind a bit before midnight or whatever Zs time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What stretches credibility is that a documentary film crew would get just this angle, with intimate relationship scenes on the Sarasota beach (no worries, everyone stays fully clothed). Why would Levi allow cameras?&amp;nbsp; Actually that makes plenty of sense: he covers his butt as Amish special operations, given he&#39;s never really alone with her. They&#39;re all using the film crew to tell their side of it.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re the ET observers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
John the malcontent-in-trouble is hilarious, as is the Mennonite intense. I know these people, have met them many times.&amp;nbsp; The eternal vibe in this transposition is what makes it both Biblical and high comedy all in an anthropological bundle.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I love it when they speak Dutch, so Afrikaner in some ways, said the Englishman, right?&amp;nbsp; Actually the Afrikaners don&#39;t equate USAers with UKers, remembering some earlier conflict I suppose.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve written on that topic more elsewhere.&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8511270310427283764'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8511270310427283764'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/08/amish-mafia.html' title='Amish Mafia'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1453748872893412479</id><published>2017-08-15T19:43:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2017-09-05T15:55:06.574-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Skin Color</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/36621251195/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Struggle&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Struggle&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4419/36621251195_74b8fab133.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
When I was little, I&#39;d hear my maternal grandmother sometimes refer to &quot;colored people&quot; which to her ears was not a slur.&amp;nbsp; America, in those days, consisted of &quot;whites&quot; and &quot;coloreds&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However my generation was already being schooled that &quot;colored people&quot; was not acceptable.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Skin colored&quot; in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thehindu.com/news/national/student-sues-company-over-racist-crayon/article4792263.ece&quot;&gt;a box of crayons&lt;/a&gt; was also biased, obviously, because off-pink (not white really) is only the color of a sampling.&amp;nbsp; Lots of skin colors out there.&amp;nbsp; That much, at least, is clear.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What&#39;s not clear is whether &quot;white&quot; is really not a color, given few people are actually that.&amp;nbsp; Off-white is a paint color, a whole variety of them.&amp;nbsp; Singling out &quot;white&quot; as a one non-color seems a similar form of discrimination.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If &quot;people of color&quot; (POC) is OK to say, is it OK if off-whites and even true albinos, be considered people of color as well?&amp;nbsp; That would seem the more uniform basket we&#39;re looking for, where any skin tone has its associated RGB value.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A problem though, is we use appearances for a kind of code, as in dress code, but also as in &quot;code of veiled meanings&quot;.&amp;nbsp; Choice of font might be part of a code, or a flag, or other symbol.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Perhaps the better word is &quot;brand&quot; as in &quot;look and feel&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Like when we go to high school or later college, we might have these various stereotypes, these templates, that people follow, more or less consciously.&amp;nbsp; Out of such raw material, identities get carved and tested, torn down and recast.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Is obsession with nuanced codes the way we operate as egos?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A lot of meanings can&#39;t or won&#39;t survive a bright light, but as implication and innuendo, they have a shadowy persistence.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The need to have or be a &quot;personality&quot; might have a lot to do with our color coding.&amp;nbsp; We get to play roles then, even pick up the mantle of this or that group and become as though mouthpieces of historical lineages, simply on the basis of a few genes in charge of skin, melanin content etc.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As we grow older, and closer to death, some of us become the disembodied voices of these imagined &quot;races&quot; or &quot;ethnic groups&quot;.&amp;nbsp; We might get our DNA tested, and build an identity based on what Ancestry.com has to say.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lots of theories and superstitions, or call them &quot;day dreams&quot; help the ego glue it all together.&amp;nbsp; Everyone needs to be somebody, right?&amp;nbsp; Why not start with skin color, daft as that may sound?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Might there be a way to champion humans, or even more than that, humanity itself?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We have this word humane, and use it with respect to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/01/recruiting-new-wanderer.html&quot;&gt;other animals&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; In what ways might we train to be humane?&amp;nbsp; Would we need to identify as a person of any specific color to be humane?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Perhaps these code languages, not of our own choosing, nor making, could be left by the roadside?&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m tempted to disrupt them.&amp;nbsp; I frequently question the reality of &quot;races&quot; and the relevance of DNA to one&#39;s mental makeup.&amp;nbsp; The power of stereotypes, templates, role models is real though.&amp;nbsp; I admit &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2017/05/telerama.html&quot;&gt;there&#39;s theater&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I suppose if &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldgame.blogspot.com/2017/08/consciousness.html&quot;&gt;your daydream&lt;/a&gt; is working well for you, adding insights and happiness, productivity, then it might be worth keeping.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve been inventive regarding my own persona, crafting some &lt;a href=&quot;http://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2011/09/my-character.html&quot;&gt;specific guy&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Realizing one&#39;s ability to be inventive is perhaps the most one might hope for.&amp;nbsp; Doesn&#39;t &quot;human&quot; mean &quot;made from clay&quot;?&amp;nbsp; I read that somewhere.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1453748872893412479'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1453748872893412479'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/08/skin-color.html' title='Skin Color'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2908440228727747963</id><published>2017-08-14T18:03:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2017-08-14T18:03:59.654-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Foam</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/36407041582/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Balls in Backyard&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Balls in Backyard&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4442/36407041582_92c7c9e890.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/36407062022/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;C6XTY&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;C6XTY&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4394/36407062022_6bdd846ab1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2908440228727747963'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2908440228727747963'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/08/foam.html' title='Foam'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8923071779207042484</id><published>2017-08-09T15:19:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2017-08-09T15:34:43.680-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Summer Camp Fun</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1-IiLbSwuBM&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Summer Camp is primarily focussed on MIT Scratch.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The &quot;block language&quot; projects have continued to evolve though.  Today we took a look at Blockly and Berkeley Snap.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/35634930074/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Snap in Arabic&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Snap in Arabic&quot; height=&quot;326&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4413/35634930074_92d238c2f3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8923071779207042484'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8923071779207042484'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2017/08/summer-camp-fun.html' title='Summer Camp Fun'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/1-IiLbSwuBM/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry></feed>