<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211</id><updated>2025-02-27T06:25:58.543-08:00</updated><category term="clojure python REPL ide"/><title type='text'>BizMo Diaries</title><subtitle type='html'>On the road with Global Data</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=151'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=126&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=176&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1905</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>151</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-552854481296094839</id><published>2023-01-11T19:25:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-14T22:18:29.534-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Random Gossip</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/2992608615/in/photolist-5yrUhg-75tSeE&quot; title=&quot;Bob Dobbs&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bob Dobbs&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/3144/2992608615_cd005c1bc8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;From some Facebook timeline somewhere:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m still trying to figure out the IRA game (Internet Research Agency) as 
research seemed what it was up to:  stage events, gain followers, sell 
stuff, promote memes... but to what end?  Twas Bannon of Cambridge 
Analytica who overtly copped to trying to win 
elections, with that whole scary backstory about the secret Facebook 
quiz.  Facebook took the heat and learned to kowtow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I bet IRA was more &quot;oligarchs playing with the west&#39;s new toys&quot; trying to
get in on the ground floor playing the new social media capitalist 
game.  Swinging the election was likely not a motive, not at all.  My 
hypothesis.  Facebook and Google are global goliaths and the Russians assume (as I do) that they&#39;re just as entitled to their troll farms as any lobby 
group.  IRA actually stood up to Mueller saying it had every right to 
play the game and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/justice-department/why-did-justice-department-drop-its-prosecution-2-firms-linked-n1161886&quot;&gt;Mueller backed down&lt;/a&gt;, seeing this as a footnote in 
history he&#39;d like us to forget.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On the other hand, the whole &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2020/01/geek-lore.html&quot;&gt;Guccifer 2 business&lt;/a&gt; and Crowdstrike is a 
separate narrative and there we&#39;re told the GRU itself has its hands in 
everything, and working on Trump&#39;s behalf was definitely the goal in 
that case.  The Mueller report goes into great detail, showing the 
Russians snapping to attention when Trump called for them to find those 
missing Hill-Billary emails.  The only weakness in the narrative there  
is CrowdStrike wrote it under contract, with the FBI in no position to 
audit, only coach and cajole to get the narrative it wanted.  It&#39;s not 
what I&#39;d call highly credible, even if it&#39;s in the Congressional Record 
(so is a lot of other garbage).&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/552854481296094839'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/552854481296094839'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2023/01/random-gossip.html' title='Random Gossip'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2961991561930011109</id><published>2023-01-03T17:37:00.009-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-03T17:47:53.933-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Making Sockets More Secure</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;An issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/12/one-of-angels.html&quot;&gt;CJ and I&lt;/a&gt; would argue about, was whether browsers were amiss in relegating unencrypted websites to second class status.&amp;nbsp; Chrome seemed especially heavy-handed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d taken up the position that sticking with HTTP was no sin, any more than not wearing a mask, or wearing one.&amp;nbsp; In principle, we don&#39;t have enough info to talk about who&#39;s being &quot;too unforgiving&quot;.&amp;nbsp; The bare fact of using HTTP does not warrant any kind of moral or aesthetic judgement.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had a dog in the fight: through 2022, my Grunch.net, host of &lt;a href=&quot;https://grunch.net/synergetics&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Synergetics on the Web&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and hosted at GoDaddy, was serving plain old HTTP, with no encryption, no security certificate.&amp;nbsp; Perhaps for this reason, although I&#39;m not clear on the mechanics, my ability to connect to my own website was degrading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I cannot quite imagine what whitelist or blacklist would be frustrating traffic through my two routers, one behind the other, when neither registered any explicit blocking.&amp;nbsp; Was CenturyLink getting involved up line from me?&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d reboot the routers, and at least temporarily regain access to the site -- or not (even that stopped fixing the issue).&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We could still ping and traceroute the grunch.net domain, just not get through to the server, netting a timeout instead.&amp;nbsp; Yet that very same website, viewed through Verizon, on a phone, was still quite responsive.&amp;nbsp; &quot;What&#39;s up with that?&quot; was the thinking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, in the midst of all this confusion I decided it was time to bite the bullet and tackle the HTTP issue more directly, by upgrading Grunch.net to an HTTPS site.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;GoDaddy had a solution waiting.&amp;nbsp; I was able to follow the steps myself, although not without some confusing chat sessions (by voice and by text) with disgruntled tech support humans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d point out to CJ that many of our treasured websites no longer had active administrators behind them.&amp;nbsp; Webmasters pass away.&amp;nbsp; Getting them converted over to HTTPS would require someone taking active measures and assuming administrative responsibility.&amp;nbsp; Is that even possible in all cases?&amp;nbsp; Given our rough and tumble Global U reality, we have no right to assume such faculty will be available.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2961991561930011109'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2961991561930011109'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2023/01/making-sockets-more-secure.html' title='Making Sockets More Secure'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5782696759937880864</id><published>2022-12-28T08:44:00.011-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-28T18:07:46.313-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Avatar 2 (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/3773478351/in/photolist-wGiKZb-QHZSHL-Surfvj-VGJT71-7rM19m-2dfwRjZ-2jD8BCL-2jY3yrP-2o8p3Q4-9EQgiS-ah9iqm-axmKBd-azRZ9u-bwVuKq-bDLGJv-bGH9H4-bKQdbV-ccPN8d-ck1haY-cZpcTG-fxi1Ru-81tpTE-95uMMM-95uN48-95xQL5-6CCVc9-5r4ez5-5shrrT-5smNfC-5u8MwA-5B524e-5GBYVM-6cWsX2-6smLEE-6smNUw-6Ks4Dz-6WgwAE&quot; title=&quot;Bagdad at Dusk&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bagdad at Dusk&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/2537/3773478351_0371ae92fa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Bagdad Theater, 2009&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rumor I heard, on the lengthy delay between movies, is the director, James Cameron, was waiting for technology to catch up.&amp;nbsp; The first movie, a 3D as well as 2D work, constructed a state of the art, highly intricate world that would have to be topped.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a visual feast (I saw it in 2D this time), Avatar 2 certainly delivers.&amp;nbsp; I hadn&#39;t gone back to watch &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/12/avatar-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;the earlier one&lt;/a&gt;, so was maybe a little confused on who&#39;d descended from whom, but blue people hybridized with sky people have only four fingers and a thumb, which singles them out for ridicule by kids in the other tribe (the water people, more green than blue).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main plot element to get is: the main villain (a sky person, white) has arranged to reincarnate, and/or have his memories transferred, to one of &quot;them&quot; (a blue) if his current avatar (piece on the board, US Marine type) gets destroyed, and that apparently happened, as he wakes up in a blue body, but with the same gung-ho personality.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bad guy&#39;s white son, in the meantime, left behind because they can&#39;t freeze babies for cryogenic travel, grew up native, as a blue.&amp;nbsp; The blues are the Native Americans if you haven&#39;t figured it out yet, albeit mythically portrayed through Hollywood movie tropes.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re also all-American and highly relatable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The film is a lot about the &quot;strong father&quot; archetype.&amp;nbsp; The dads keep expressing disappointment in their kids, especially the boys, for their foolish misjudgements, and the boys hate being dissed by the man they most admire and aspire to be like.&amp;nbsp; They just want to be brave. The greens have a strong father chief too, with offspring.&amp;nbsp; The whites have their reincarnated guy with his left-behind &quot;monkey boy&quot; son.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The blue family seems very like &lt;i&gt;The Incredibles&lt;/i&gt; family (also Disney), especially the teen girl, who feels marginalized as a four finger, and who is developing psychic powers beyond her peers (see &lt;i&gt;Beetlejuice&lt;/i&gt; for another take on this character).&amp;nbsp; She saves the day on numerous occasions.&amp;nbsp; The younger boy does too, in bonding with the four eyed whale, the outcast one who had tried to fight the sky people earlier.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The plot is complicated but basically goes like this:&amp;nbsp; the bad guy Marine and his ilk (the sky people) have returned in their spaceships (buckyballs!) with a special grudge against the blue family dad.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The blue family, to protect their own people, decide to hide out amongst the greens, which is controversial as the blues are forest people with underdeveloped lung power for undersea activities.&amp;nbsp; The greens agree to take in these Incredibles and teach them their watery ways, but it isn&#39;t long before the whites figure out where they are, and a fight ensues.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cameron did both &lt;i&gt;Aliens&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Titanic&lt;/i&gt; and really knows how to put together a believable &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/more-about-narnia.html&quot;&gt;Machine World&lt;/a&gt;, an extrapolation of our own.&amp;nbsp; He also knows how to tilt the decks, as the ship is sinking, making the&amp;nbsp; passengers slide and/or climb what had been horizontal surfaces.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sigourney Weaver plays her cameo role, as the human mother of the blue teen with psychic abilities.&amp;nbsp; This mother and daughter don&#39;t meet directly in person, but on a psychic plane, in a dream state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the whole, I was glad to revisit this world and continue processing the machine versus natural technology rift.&amp;nbsp; The technology of the Native Americans is higher in many ways, if we include nature herself as a kind of Mech &#39;n Tech (which she is).&amp;nbsp; Whales are higher tech than any aircraft carrier, and so on.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The brutish sky people are the Euro whites, the neo-Romans, the US Army more specifically.&amp;nbsp; A lot of what this subculture is most proud of comes in for criticism, in part simply for being so hackneyed, but also in the tradition of great westerns such as &lt;i&gt;Little Big Man&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;Dances with Wolves&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Europe is the dying world.&amp;nbsp; America, already inhabited, is the new world.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I saw the film by myself at &lt;i&gt;The Bagdad&lt;/i&gt; and although the film was long, I didn&#39;t take any pee breaks.&amp;nbsp; Nor did I have my customary IPA or other drink (which probably helped) as I&#39;ve given up beer (but not wine or gin).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5782696759937880864'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5782696759937880864'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/12/avatar-2-movie-review.html' title='Avatar 2 (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1966599571067678549</id><published>2022-12-27T12:01:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2023-08-31T00:25:40.196-07:00</updated><title type='text'>After Princeton</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/52525632600/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;284 Magnolia&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;284 Magnolia&quot; height=&quot;286&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52525632600_1a3dc0e60b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
These were my digs in Jersey City, &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/06/machine-world.html&quot;&gt;post Princeton&lt;/a&gt;, a shared group house, more Platonic than polyamorous, though we certainly loved each other as schoolmates do.&amp;nbsp; We somewhat continued our lifestyle from &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/05/princeton-25th-reunion.html&quot;&gt;2 Dickinson Street&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My cohort was mostly using JCNJ as a springboard, to promising careers in the Big Apple, and they&#39;d find a new place pretty soon.  I found work within walking distance, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2018/04/positive-futurism.html&quot;&gt;a high school teacher&lt;/a&gt;, and continued on in this space, renting from Mr. Chang, through other chapters of housemates.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Which house again? Immediately adjacent to the apartment building.&amp;nbsp; No solar panels.&amp;nbsp; Two cars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/52524629342/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;The Alleyway&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Alleyway&quot; height=&quot;286&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52524629342_75de6a2799.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Above, you&#39;ll see that same apartment building with the house behind it (red balloon).  You&#39;re looking at Loews Theater on Journal Square, courtesy of Google Earth.  The alley to the left of Loews, connecting JSQ to Magnolia, our old street, was used for &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/0wagyhpw7Y0&quot;&gt;a scene in &lt;i&gt;The Joker&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  Newark was also used for &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2019/10/the-joker-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;that movie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearby: &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/05/flash-back.html&quot;&gt;The Stanley&lt;/a&gt;, used in a movie directed by Woody Allen. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This all happened in the early 1980s.&amp;nbsp; By 1984, I was living on the opposite side of Manhattan, in Queens, sharing digs with &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/01/wanderers-200818.html&quot;&gt;Ray Simon&lt;/a&gt;, along with a job at McGraw-Hill courtesy of Nola Hague.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By then, I was also on the other side of a gig with Project VOTE!, aka Americans for Civic Participation, headed by Sandy Newman.&amp;nbsp; That was a rooming situation in Washington, DC (thanks Brenda), during the Reagan versus Mondale presidential contest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Below:&amp;nbsp; Journal Square, across from Loews, back in the day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;  
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/2560252510/in/album-72157605485853546/&quot; title=&quot;JSQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;JSQ&quot; height=&quot;355&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/3184/2560252510_5dd8aabbba.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1966599571067678549'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1966599571067678549'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/12/after-princeton.html' title='After Princeton'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6806551778443456460</id><published>2022-12-24T23:10:00.007-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-30T22:00:37.812-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Some Psycho Analysis</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh2oDODJm9xRthRrBeYzxf5kCarNPvf3zVY8v9DoQENpZMkmO4ODUNXVjCwXNfONuZcZix--RO-OYoQBiwKcIU6g3h7IOMmeng0KKr2omvZnNacI1t6kWZETPa7ttF7H3Ga2VSxDTXjoJup_zXNeVbNR9CYfrTvvwQahwZEpGGFoZk6rtEpOA/s584/dump_nato.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;584&quot; data-original-width=&quot;526&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh2oDODJm9xRthRrBeYzxf5kCarNPvf3zVY8v9DoQENpZMkmO4ODUNXVjCwXNfONuZcZix--RO-OYoQBiwKcIU6g3h7IOMmeng0KKr2omvZnNacI1t6kWZETPa7ttF7H3Ga2VSxDTXjoJup_zXNeVbNR9CYfrTvvwQahwZEpGGFoZk6rtEpOA/w360-h400/dump_nato.jpg&quot; width=&quot;360&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;I
 don&#39;t see &quot;the USA&quot; as fighting Russia so much as an arrogant 
self-aggrandizing group we call neocons, which rose to power under 
Reagan during the Contra War against Nicaragua, and sees itself as being
 in charge.  Many Americans have no beef with the 
Russians and are in fact of Russian heritage.  Washington DC may see 
itself as representing &quot;the USA&quot; but some of us just see a silly &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2013/08/city-of-morons.html&quot;&gt;City of Morons&lt;/a&gt; (one of my blog posts).  Clearly I have my own deviant rhetoric.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;I
 also tend to shy away from historical accounts that make &quot;nations&quot; the 
principal actors.  I don&#39;t have any great belief in nations except as 
ideological / psychological constructs we use to organize our human 
affairs, akin to a corporation or religious bodies
 / institutions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;The English language allows us to construct stories 
wherein Europe does this and London does that and Nicaragua does 
something else.  I know how to talk this way too, and do (when in 
Rome...), but under the hood I&#39;m a skeptic.  Only humans have agency.  
These inanimate actors are at best a kind of journalistic shorthand.&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;A
 faction of Ukrainian ideology wants &quot;Ukraine for Ukrainians&quot; and has a very definite idea of what that means.  Ethnic Russians fall 
outside the definition.  It&#39;s like if we had a faction here saying &quot;real
 USAers&quot; have to be white and of &lt;a tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;European heritage,
 anyone else is tolerated but is not as real.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Given my upbringing as a 
liberal, I was taught that &quot;ethnic uniformity&quot; was a primitive older 
idea of &quot;a nation&quot; that had been superseded by the modern conception, 
one which accommodates a mix of cultures and religions and doesn&#39;t put 
any one of them in charge.  I call that &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/11/about-secularism.html&quot;&gt;secularism&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Secular nations 
(which accommodate religions) are the ones &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2022/12/advice-column.html&quot;&gt;I&#39;m snobby about&lt;/a&gt; and think 
more highly of.  &quot;Ukraine for Ukrainians&quot; sounds old fashioned and 
immature to my ears.  I&#39;m sorry this faction has gained an upper hand in
 Ukrainian politics and that they have their proud boy types to enforce 
their racist views.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;x193iq5w xeuugli x13faqbe x1vvkbs xlh3980 xvmahel x1n0sxbx x1lliihq x1s928wv xhkezso x1gmr53x x1cpjm7i x1fgarty x1943h6x xudqn12 x3x7a5m x6prxxf xvq8zen xo1l8bm xzsf02u&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Translating
 to Americanese I might say that in my view 2014 was a January 6 moment, 
except the Trumpies won, the ultra nationalist Bandero Ukraine for 
Ukrainian proud boy types forcefully took charge.  The decent 
Ukrainians, especially out east, were shocked by 
this violent uprising and wanted out of this nascent nation-gone-bad.  
Russia is blue, fighting Maga Reds in Kiev.  NATO is fascist to the 
core, we know from what it did to Libya, where &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/whats-urner.html&quot;&gt;my family&lt;/a&gt; worked for six 
years.&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6806551778443456460'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6806551778443456460'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/12/some-psycho-analysis.html' title='Some Psycho Analysis'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh2oDODJm9xRthRrBeYzxf5kCarNPvf3zVY8v9DoQENpZMkmO4ODUNXVjCwXNfONuZcZix--RO-OYoQBiwKcIU6g3h7IOMmeng0KKr2omvZnNacI1t6kWZETPa7ttF7H3Ga2VSxDTXjoJup_zXNeVbNR9CYfrTvvwQahwZEpGGFoZk6rtEpOA/s72-w360-h400-c/dump_nato.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2730624937309744395</id><published>2022-12-16T14:52:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-16T14:56:34.656-08:00</updated><title type='text'>One of the Angels</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/5508345645/in/photolist-9oKHfD&quot; title=&quot;CJ @ Play&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/5255/5508345645_61cd3597dd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;CJ @ Play&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;On Thursday, December 8, 2022 at 10:37 PM EST, Christopher John “CJ” 
Fearnley, passed away from a very aggressive, still undiagnosed cancer. 
CJ was 55 years young. He is survived by his partner Jeannie, two 
sister’s Michele and Brenda, his mother Marilyn, father Jack and 
stepmother Edyta, and two nephews Ryan and Nick. CJ was born in NY. CJ 
was a Comprehensivist and Explorer in Universe.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;In my own experience, CJ was a great inspiration and collaborator, whether it was a deep exploration
 into Bucky Fuller, synergetic geometry,  philosophy, Dante, Dostoevsky,
 Saramago or Mary Shelley&#39;s FRANKENSTEIN, our last deep read. He had a 
reading plan that extended years into the future.  In recent months, as 
he refined his ideas about the need for comprehensivity, he encouraged 
all to be macro-comprehensive and micro-incisive.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;CJ was one of the angles. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;-- D.W. Jacobs&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2730624937309744395'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2730624937309744395'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/12/one-of-angels.html' title='One of the Angels'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8438902571998316748</id><published>2022-11-26T11:31:00.009-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-30T22:07:14.906-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Adventures in Quakerism</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/BrGCHYRN3ME&quot; style=&quot;background-image: url(https://i.ytimg.com/vi/BrGCHYRN3ME/hqdefault.jpg);&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Everyone has a different experience (of life) of &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2014/10/a-quaker-arc.html&quot;&gt;Quakerism&lt;/a&gt;, in terms of vantage points assumed and/or achieved. I did a lot of the small meetup stuff, in part because my parents found sitting in silence a great way to get to know strangers, who then become Friends in one&#39;s own eyes.&amp;nbsp; The proverbial beholder&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The above YouTube continues &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/AmJjUNHAGWA&quot;&gt;an earlier one&lt;/a&gt; that should just was well be entitled &quot;experiments in&quot; (versus &quot;adventures in&quot;) Quakerism, which is not meant to sound cynical, as if Quakers were my guinea pigs.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m the guinea pig, and I&#39;m encouraged to explore my religion &quot;experimentally&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s &quot;my religion&quot;?&amp;nbsp; Again, that&#39;s whatever pass for priors in terms of one&#39;s own dogmatism.&amp;nbsp; Not all beliefs can be under the microscope at every moment.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One has to believe Google Maps or just trust intuition, unless one knows one&#39;s way about.&amp;nbsp; My friend Steve had a cul-de-sac dead end loop for an address, but the mapping software showed the street went through.&amp;nbsp; The procession of lost vehicles was endless.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s critical is your religion have an update or upgrade process, whereby &quot;waste beliefs&quot; get dealt with and excreted. Nostalgically curating &quot;bad beliefs&quot; (as in &quot;no longer useful&quot;) results in a level of metaphysical constipation that may become uncomfortable, not only personally, but institutionally, depending on one&#39;s role in society.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quakerism, in focusing on silent worship, interrupted with ministry (aka ranting), does not get hung up on a bunch of &quot;credos&quot; wherein people give themselves the self indulgent benefit of being able to debate the trivial stuff quasi-endlessly.&amp;nbsp; You know you&#39;re dealing with the over-entitled when their predilection is to fiddle as Rome burns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My hope for Quakerism, in a nutshell, is silent worship, as a central practice, as a catalyst, akin to various forms of meditation, will keep some of the least beneficial viral memeplexes from taking root.&amp;nbsp; Too many religions prove vulnerable to satanic &quot;mind thetans&quot; or whatever we wanna call &#39;em.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8438902571998316748'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8438902571998316748'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/11/adventures-in-quakerism.html' title='Adventures in Quakerism'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/BrGCHYRN3ME/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2476587194112421684</id><published>2022-11-25T09:00:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-30T22:14:26.220-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Elevator Pitch</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;The elevator pitch for the giant dome is survivalist, which immediately gets funny, because of &lt;i&gt;Yes Men&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/n71DUBRuUo8&quot;&gt;their Survivaball&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Not that domes are the equivalent of space suits.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But when it comes to heating and cooling a big volume, the logistics of powering a single space comes with an economy of scale, at least in theory.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inside, you have your sound stage and audience,&amp;nbsp; a perimeter of concessions.&amp;nbsp; In neighboring domes, people pitch their tents.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In some, you stage a quaint village, Medievalish but &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/11/asylum-city-project.html&quot;&gt;with amenities&lt;/a&gt;, built more with movie set theater prop technology, than with old fashioned brick and mortar, as you&#39;re more in a studio than protecting against the elements.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The dome or other universal studio building is already taking care of wind, rain, cold and heat.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Benefits of rapidly deployed and emergency assembled and disassembled heating and cooling domes include practicing the world game disciplines we&#39;ve come to take for granted.&amp;nbsp; People have to choreograph and to some extent improvise.&amp;nbsp; The moves become smooth to the extent practiced.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Movie-making comes closest, as a design science, with military logistics providing a complementary theater.&amp;nbsp; Both center around simulation and planning with models and maps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The domes in Cornwall provide a good example of what we all expect from the UK.&amp;nbsp; If British Aerospace can&#39;t deploy emergency heating domes, who can?&amp;nbsp; Raytheon?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The engineering sector is shifting our attention from &quot;Big Tech&quot; and/or &quot;Big Pharma&quot; in the sense of social media and biochemistry advertisers respectively, as these are small fry compared to the aerospace sector.&amp;nbsp; We have conventionally allocated aerospace to civilian versus military but there&#39;s little to keep this namespace anchored.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides, it&#39;s not either / or.&amp;nbsp; Health care is just as big a consumer of computer science warez as the military and weapons vendors.&amp;nbsp; The arrival of mass casualties during wartime, begot triage and triage tents and all manner of medical practice I know more about from watching movies than from nursing school.&amp;nbsp; WW1 saw the beginning of many new kinds of war science.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of nursing, I do appreciate the cram course YouTubes I&#39;ve been plowing through.&amp;nbsp; As we all get older, we encounter more issues in health care, for ourselves and for others.&amp;nbsp; In my case, I also had a professional track running through heart procedure territory, being a chief data harvester for a research hospital system.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was not in patient care, unless we count long term outcomes research, a kind of feedback doctors treasure.&amp;nbsp; I knew heart anatomy pretty well.&amp;nbsp; Lately I&#39;ve focused more on lungs and liver.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Could a giant dome be an emergency hospital, like a MASH unit?&amp;nbsp; People may spontaneously associate such setups with war zones, but disaster scenes more generally feature both the wounded and the infected.&amp;nbsp; Lately, the world has been dealing with infection and overdose.&amp;nbsp; That was until they decided to plug and play this retro Euro-war.&amp;nbsp; Now war wounds are what&#39;s climbing again, along with thermal issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So we&#39;re back to MIT having done its homework, and private firms having their catalog of emergency shelters at the ready, whether or not they&#39;e actually free span.&amp;nbsp; The more likely shape of anything American is a box, with sliding doors, more like a giant garage, farmhouse or big box shopping center store, like a Costco or Home Depot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The floor plan of a &quot;camp in&quot; dome is more suburban street mode, with curvilinear walkways (synthetic pavements) and marked out camping sites, like when car camping.&amp;nbsp; A few golf cart type vehicles offer fixed route services whereas delivery forklifts carry palettes to and fro, complete with kitchen units and entertainment (education) modules.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some properties have tents, but a lot of those are outside.&amp;nbsp; Property holders stack the various units, which need not be equipped with individual heating or cooling units, given the context, of a larger system.&amp;nbsp; You may have personal devices, such as fans or baseboard units.&amp;nbsp; There might be a sauna and/or hot tub module, depending on amps available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Cornwall Domes use like a Tefzel pillow, I&#39;ve never toured the place.&amp;nbsp; J. Baldwin was my source of pillow dome savvy.&amp;nbsp; I got to &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/01/about-habitats.html&quot;&gt;interview the guy&lt;/a&gt; on camera even, when staying with Rick and company in San Jose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What do the power stations look like?&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s another whole side of the business.&amp;nbsp; No doubt NATO, like FEMA, has a large number of plans for such units, with other regional bodies likewise sharing blueprints.&amp;nbsp; Given the dire needs of the populace, and funding already allocated, it&#39;s time to spring into action, right?&amp;nbsp; Right!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2476587194112421684'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2476587194112421684'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/11/elevator-pitch.html' title='Elevator Pitch'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6355618026453967077</id><published>2022-11-14T13:41:00.008-08:00</published><updated>2022-11-15T09:22:45.643-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Soap Operas</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;I just got off the phone with &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/02/methodist-morning.html&quot;&gt;Maureen of Lake Oswego&lt;/a&gt;, having gotten all melodramatic, getting stentorian, while telling her melodrama was not my style, enough with the goodies and baddies already!&amp;nbsp; My impatience comes in waves, as I think is true with many of us, nor am I saying impatience is always a bad thing, on the contrary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of soap operas, Don Wardwell was by today, in the wake of &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2022/10/comedy-and-social-commentary.html&quot;&gt;Glenn&#39;s stuff&lt;/a&gt; reshuffling in an orderly fashion (hi Barbara), and he told me the story of a guy he knew who was hoping to get a friend of his to move in with him.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;d stormed out of the Pauling House when Don suggested his desire to discuss this move publicly might be inappropriate.&amp;nbsp; That guy was supposedly me.&amp;nbsp; You say she&#39;d been a Jehovah&#39;s Witness, that I was smitten somehow?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One reason I doubt the story is it so closely matches what actually did happen:&amp;nbsp; at the height of my Food Not Bombs activity, &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2022/10/food-not-bombs-story.html&quot;&gt;around Occupy,&lt;/a&gt; I shared my house with three women (how I think of them, fairly), all of whom I still know and keep track of.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;re blog characters, you can go back and look.&amp;nbsp; We were in synergy in some ways, and no, it wasn&#39;t a harem situation, gosh darn.&amp;nbsp; More &lt;i&gt;Charlie&#39;s Angels&lt;/i&gt;?&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re talking soaps after all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&#39;ll go back and check the timeline.&amp;nbsp; A don&#39;t doubt this new angel actually existed, I just don&#39;t remember Glenn talking me out of it, or the Pauling House episode (back to Don&#39;s recollection).&amp;nbsp; Apparently my erratic behavior had no consequences this time, as no such creature moved in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s what I think:&amp;nbsp; especially older people, but really young people too, are prone to develop &quot;like I was there&quot; memories, vivid, sharp, of contrary-to-fact scenarios.&amp;nbsp; Day care centers get shut down over this kind of stuff, and probably nursing homes too for that matter (I&#39;m in neither business).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sorry everyone, if I&#39;m the one turning into a leaky bucket, letting important memories fade away.&amp;nbsp; I pride myself on having a good memory, as Suzanne might remember.&amp;nbsp; These blogs (Quaker journals) help a lot.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6355618026453967077'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6355618026453967077'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/11/soap-operas.html' title='Soap Operas'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-492619862084894844</id><published>2022-11-03T08:51:00.005-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-16T08:27:28.410-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Asylum City Project</title><content type='html'>
Sanitation has to be at the heart of any human settlement design.&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;This includes dealing with waste of all types, including sewage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bucky Fuller was one of the pioneers in this arena. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prototyping is key.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/492619862084894844'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/492619862084894844'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/11/asylum-city-project.html' title='Asylum City Project'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2809663137717084407</id><published>2022-11-02T15:33:00.010-07:00</published><updated>2022-11-04T12:08:59.544-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Looney Tunes</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll say up front I&#39;m skeptical of those who assert the &quot;US + UK + EU = The West&quot; in some way.&amp;nbsp; Like I know that&#39;s a common trope among storytellers, I just don&#39;t consider it a stable memeplex.&amp;nbsp; &quot;The West&quot; is the western hemisphere (North, South, Central America) and &quot;The East = Eurasia + Africa + Australia&quot; to just focus on the continents.&amp;nbsp; Greenland could go either way.&amp;nbsp; In sum, shop talks that map to the realities of geography likely have more staying power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, geopolitically speaking, I think too many Anglo-Saxons (to use the Kremlin term) fail to appreciate how different the Americans are, from the whites who stayed home in the various homelands, if we might call them that.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many Anglo-Euros right here in the Americas may not appreciate that either.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m talking about the influence of original peoples, their thought patterns.&amp;nbsp; As &lt;i&gt;The Dawn of Everything&lt;/i&gt; makes clear: the anthropology and psychoanalysis was a two way street, and still is.&amp;nbsp; It was never a question of which were the savages:&amp;nbsp; those would be the Brits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward and we get those Halloween images of a horror film Truss, still wiping blood off her lips after biting hard into Germany&#39;s jugular.&amp;nbsp; Now the latter has fallen to the floor, shivering, with few prospects.&amp;nbsp; &quot;It is done my lord&quot; she whispers on her phone, to a vamped up Darth Vader type.&amp;nbsp; Very cinematic you have to admit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All joking aside, I think &quot;US + UK = Looney Tunes&quot; is what we&#39;re seeing today, with John Bolton as Yosemite Sam, minus the charm.&amp;nbsp; I would not think it possible for Anglo-Saxons to be genetically berserk, so it boils down to something in the water maybe?&amp;nbsp; The District = Flint = Jackson, Mississippi?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I&#39;ve recently been to &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2022/10/comedy-and-social-commentary.html&quot;&gt;a comedy club&lt;/a&gt; (actually, a main line theater, that happens to feature comedy from time to time).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So given I&#39;m so remote with my vocabulary to begin with, even &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/yesterday.html&quot;&gt;questioning the Louisiana Purchase&lt;/a&gt; as a truly done deal, you can see where I&#39;m not making the rounds as an interviewee.&amp;nbsp; No, I&#39;m just a deeply buried Quaker blogger with some political views.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From another point of view, I see the US Congress and the old USSR (the ghost of) on the same side, collaborating to extinguish a kind of ethnic nationalism that doesn&#39;t rise to the level of nation state.&amp;nbsp; These political bodies cannot effectively turn away from &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2022/07/rebuilding-ukraine.html&quot;&gt;their own destinies&lt;/a&gt;, as two sides of the same coin.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You could say I&#39;m being cynical but I think that would require positing a high level of conscious awareness on the part of &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2022/07/antsy-engineers.html&quot;&gt;the perpetrators&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m suggesting we&#39;re running on automatic, as bots.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s not a new phenomenon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2809663137717084407'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2809663137717084407'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/11/looney-tunes.html' title='Looney Tunes'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3459903894680004470</id><published>2022-10-29T15:18:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2023-01-30T22:21:10.386-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Camera Story</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/52466464639/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Lumix Takes Picture of Lumix&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Lumix Takes Picture of Lumix&quot; height=&quot;334&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52466464639_8c6b72380f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been hobbling around a bit, and actually took a cane, no, almost did, to that comedy show at The Aladdin.&amp;nbsp; The reason is I swerved out into the street, as a pedestrian, out of social distancing habits, but forgot, when re-merging with the sidewalk, that I&#39;d be walking over rough terrain, some decorative boulders.&amp;nbsp; I went sprawling, but was proud how I landed and didn&#39;t bang my head or anything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The upshot of all that, was I immediately forgot about it and continued onward to the supermarket, getting some provisions for a friend.&amp;nbsp; Only later, walking home, did I pat myself, my hoodie pouch especially, and realize I was cameraless.&amp;nbsp; Walking out the door, I was sure I&#39;d had it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To make a long story short, I woke up at 5 AM the next morning with lots of leg pains, which jogged my memory, and I thought &quot;Ah, I bet the camera fell out when I took a spill&quot;.&amp;nbsp; It had been getting dark, which is partly why I&#39;d missed seeing the boulders I now believe.&amp;nbsp; I hobbled out into the darkness of the early morning, iPhone flashlight in hand, to look for it.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d been to the supermarket Lost &amp;amp; Found the night before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given how much I loved that Lumix L-7, a point and shooter that starts to crossover into higher end, very fast, very trusty, I went on the internet and used all my skills to find a good deal on a used one.&amp;nbsp; I could afford it.&amp;nbsp; I took the plunge.&amp;nbsp; We&#39;re talking $250.&amp;nbsp; That includes a spiffy case, another charger plus battery, and a protective pouch, along with the second camera.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, second camera, because in the meantime, I found the first, not smashed on the sidewalk, but safely next to my hat and McMenamins face mask (which I consider stylish, pandemic or no pandemic), at my friends house.&amp;nbsp; Starting with the fall itself, and on through some hours after, I was at a low point in my awareness of my devices and peripherals (accessories).&amp;nbsp; I get this way sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m glad to have two copies of the same camera and do not regret the purchase.&amp;nbsp; The main consequence of all this action is I&#39;m still working on renormalizing around that knee.&amp;nbsp; The day after, I&#39;d gone on a test walk with Dr. D., to make sure I could still do a few miles.&amp;nbsp; That was probably not the best therapy however, and I&#39;ve been paying the price ever since.&amp;nbsp; Derek has confirmed my propensity to keep stretching and claiming my range of motion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of claiming, I claimed by first Urbit planet today.&amp;nbsp; You might have thought, judging from writings, that I&#39;d already invested in such a ship, but in fact, I&#39;ve been practicing on comets and more recently a moon.&amp;nbsp; Stepping up to a real planet is somewhat a rite of passage in this universe (semantic space) and I was sure to mark it accordingly, both privately and publicly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3459903894680004470'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3459903894680004470'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/10/camera-story.html' title='Camera Story'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1583356821914865260</id><published>2022-10-28T21:49:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-31T11:43:08.576-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Urbit Food Pod</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/49485473676/in/photolist-pvEZhR-ySFa4G-A3tDJP-XZoVVL-6YZAVg-245rckJ-29tRj9n-8teEv6-2ifaZP7-2ioRZh1-2jj93by-2kYEM9B-2mn49FK-2mJvGBu-2mXuMe4-2nFwbsD-2nV2FCV-94mRQq-95xQkb-a9gn49-6Kwbqo&quot; title=&quot;Hawthorne Asylum Food Pod&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Hawthorne Asylum Food Pod&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/49485473676_17ccee1091.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;:: asylum food pod ::&lt;/i&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One could do the prototype simulation without any hardware, so to speak, meaning no real food need be cooked for real animals.&amp;nbsp; Maybe there&#39;s a Planet &quot;bank&quot; (a conversion point, intra-currency), and each &quot;cart&quot; or &quot;truck&quot; is but a Moon of that Planet.&amp;nbsp; Good design?&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m still learning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting that shopping cart app up and running in Urbit may be a solved problem.&amp;nbsp; What&#39;s more interesting is not the app per se, but the task of educating the public, and what more could a Food Pod be?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those following my blogs know I tried to interest the Methodists in converting an abandoned church into a community center focused on experimenting with exactly such simulations, with a microwave tower aligned to OMSI&#39;s.&amp;nbsp; That was &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/06/ghost-church.html&quot;&gt;Project Ghost Church&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Like a lot of my projects, it&#39;s more science fiction than real science at this point, more like Dark Matter or one of those.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re probably thinking I must be backed by a bunch of wild and crazy libertarians, the Web 3.0 crypto warriors and so on.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m aware too that Swiss cantons were hoping to cash in on &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2022/12/crypto.html&quot;&gt;the crypto craze&lt;/a&gt; by leveraging their pre-existing savvy around financial services.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have to confess I&#39;m not really up to date on what either of these groups is up to.&amp;nbsp; All I know is I&#39;m still looking forward to visiting one of these newfangled Food Pods some day.&amp;nbsp; It wouldn&#39;t have to be implemented in Urbit, although that seems like a natural fit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When testing, players need some &quot;funny money&quot; like in Monopoly, a currency accepted within the game. Spend funny money to get your virtual burritos.&amp;nbsp; Playing the &quot;board game&quot; (pun intended) is how one develops expertise in advance of actually implementing such a facility.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Simulate with software and players before you build&quot; as a way to &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/08/food-pod-simulators.html&quot;&gt;work out some kinks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1583356821914865260'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1583356821914865260'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/10/urbit-food-pod.html' title='Urbit Food Pod'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8476008463796209995</id><published>2022-10-26T11:17:00.005-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-26T11:32:23.679-07:00</updated><title type='text'>What is Work?</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;One of the memeplexes I revisit, and seek to untangle, at least in my own mind, is where a Protestant idea of &quot;work&quot; meets a Physics one.&amp;nbsp; We have the work ethic, versus the idea of wasted energy, i.e. leakage away from the real work getting done.&amp;nbsp; But to what extent is &quot;work&quot; in the eye of the beholder observer?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example they say a steam engine leaks energy away in the form of heat and noise, but what if your main purpose, as a steam engine, is to entertain with your noises, while heating the room?&amp;nbsp; As a side benefit, you also power the whole museum.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s not your paid work though; you do that for free.&amp;nbsp; Yes, I&#39;m addressing a steam engine here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe there&#39;s nothing deep here.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m drowning in the shallows, where many drownings happen.&amp;nbsp; Yet it seems the idea of a work vector, along which no waste is happening, is really in a multi-dimensional space higher than the eye can see.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Invisible means complicated.&amp;nbsp; Side effects may be main effects.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was the charm of the honey-maker moneymaker bumblebee concept:&amp;nbsp; that cross-pollination is precessional to what the &quot;bees&quot; (moneymakers) are about.&amp;nbsp; The flowers use them to exchange genetic information (get the real work done).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I find it hard to get away from the idea of a taskmaster, the Protestant, very puritanical about what &quot;work&quot; means and quick to call anything &quot;entropy&quot; that is not strictly to his liking.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fragility of his mindset in the face of even minimal chaos, as he sees it, is not a mental condition we would welcome or wish to nurture in ourselves.&amp;nbsp; We want our physics meaning of &quot;work&quot; to stay pure of such an influence, unaffected by the religious mores of some random republican farmer, newly emigrated to North America from some homestead in Eurasia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I take comfort in how many humans are in retirement or &quot;at the ready&quot; but not really doing anything in terms of directly constructing infrastructure.&amp;nbsp; We already have a huge carrying capacity with respect to people needing food, shelter and healthcare, and from whom little is asked.&amp;nbsp; They&#39;ve performed their service already.&amp;nbsp; We either call them &quot;veterans&quot; or &quot;retired&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We only need so much infrastructure.&amp;nbsp; Cities for the sake of cities are not really a social good.&amp;nbsp; From a movie-making point of view, we need a balance between plot-advancing box office action, and locating sites to build sets.&amp;nbsp; Sometimes the movie is about the making of the movie, which is what we think of as real life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Choreography, script writing, is the name of the game i.e. what will the lifestyles be like?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Saying they contain &quot;a lot of leisure time&quot; might be a moral judgment, like when the honest work of a homemaker, caring for kids, is somehow really &quot;leisure time&quot; because &quot;unpaid&quot;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The guy with the job, the breadwinner, was the only &quot;worker&quot; in the family, whereas caring for other animals only counted as work where animal husbandry was concerned, as when raising sheep or other livestock.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then both parents &quot;got jobs&quot; in the nuclear family model, leaving the suburban home mostly empty during the day (the kids were in daycare), with the urban office space mostly empty at night, and jammed freeways in between.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And then all these ideas about &quot;net worth&quot; seem rather morally perverse, as if dropped from the sky by some giant egg laying monster.&amp;nbsp; The moneymaker game seems to casually assume ownership of the public&#39;s good words, as if entitled.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the physics world, just breathing is work.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s work to pump air in and out of the lungs.&amp;nbsp; It takes joules, and a minimum amount of muscle power.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given breathing is necessary to life, no puritan is in a position to argue that no useful work is being done.&amp;nbsp; Ergo, why not pay this person on a per breath basis?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That proposition takes the breath away, in some circles, because isn&#39;t the whole point to make life support hard to afford?&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s an old school belief with its hands on the steering wheel to this day, according to lore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The gymnast does a &quot;workout&quot; which we call &quot;work&quot; whether or not she or he is paid as a professional gymnast.&amp;nbsp; Many professions put a premium on looking one&#39;s best.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So that&#39;s spending energy to better one&#39;s physique.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sure, much energy is lost to heat and sometimes noises, but a gym wouldn&#39;t be a gym without all those vibes.&amp;nbsp; In that sense, nothing is wasted, as entropy is factored in as a necessary feature, not as a cosmic defect or original sin.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8476008463796209995'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8476008463796209995'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/10/what-is-work.html' title='What is Work?'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6738788050910508779</id><published>2022-10-24T17:26:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-28T21:52:30.162-07:00</updated><title type='text'>The Asylum Project</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/52452287409/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;asylum_pod&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;asylum_pod&quot; height=&quot;328&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52452287409_14e3f158a3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I tell people regarding Bitcoin is that I&#39;ll never be interested in having any myself unless it&#39;s easy to charge my wallet, from my bank account say, and spend the bits on burritos and other sundries, at a Food Pod that makes that easy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Food Pod is like a Food Court, made more international by the World&#39;s Fair franchise.&amp;nbsp; However the Pod consists of carts or trucks, which may be trundled away, leaving spots for new mobile restaurant kitchens.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of Portland&#39;s more famous Pods is Hawthorne Asylum Food Truck Pod, at the intersection of SE Madison and SE 11th.&amp;nbsp; Hawthorne Asylum is named in honor of the mental asylum, run by one Dr. Hawthorne, for whom the nearby Hawthorne Boulevard is named.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, the trucks are not equipped to accept Bitcoin easily.&amp;nbsp; I think the business model should be an experimental Pod &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/10/urbit-food-pod.html&quot;&gt;that only takes crypto&lt;/a&gt;, but with an easy way to pay for some with your phone, much as Club Med used to exclusively take plastic beads for its optional purchases internally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know that refugee camps have been experimenting with crypto currencies, which brings me to the refugee camps the State of Oregon is considering.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not saying my Vortex 1 + Country Fair + Rainbow Gathering + Occupy template has been accepted.&amp;nbsp; Calling it &quot;a template&quot; is a bit of a stretch, but we do know the State of Oregon has experience with at least a one of those models.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reason &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2022/10/asylum-city_23.html&quot;&gt;life in a refugee camp&lt;/a&gt; might be interesting is it&#39;s a place to test prototypes, as well as therapies. Journalists are always welcome, and many will take cheap shots, as the faculty learns the ropes.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much needs to be invented.&amp;nbsp; Experimental community building (aka &quot;nation building&quot; on a smaller scale) is a job for social engineers with a secular background, not just for religious wonks.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6738788050910508779'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6738788050910508779'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/10/the-asylum-project.html' title='The Asylum Project'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6477443517583755394</id><published>2022-10-11T13:27:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-11T13:27:00.152-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Car Talk</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/52419849133/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Reunion&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Reunion&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52419849133_22eb8c312c_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There she was, waiting for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One develops attachments to things, not just people.&amp;nbsp; Sometimes the things are stand-ins for people.&amp;nbsp; Other times, they&#39;re just favorite objects, and/or, in the case of a car, something needed to get around, to enjoy a specific lifestyle.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;K&amp;amp;M Auto Service knew exactly what to do, as I did (&lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/10/small-time-stuff.html&quot;&gt;see previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;nbsp; But I didn&#39;t have the right size, shape or skills.&amp;nbsp; Only $118, with a full diagnostic.&amp;nbsp; They say I should replace the brake fluid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/52417446112/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Dropping off Maxi Taxi&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Dropping off Maxi Taxi&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52417446112_6a786aed18.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6477443517583755394'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6477443517583755394'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/10/car-talk.html' title='Car Talk'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3237468666392836627</id><published>2022-10-05T21:03:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2023-01-30T22:33:32.546-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Small Time Stuff</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/15624212726/in/photolist-2kZEHtL-pNEb73-bPvict-bPvi5p-b89Pev-aBUhaj-9Jw4Wb-9Jw4Eb-9oKJ3p-76jj94-6V6uqW-6bigru-2kmBeEs-UNpxir-UqCsa8-bWZhni-7iN1QW-6US1xd-6TzsJT&quot; title=&quot;Maxi Taxi&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Maxi Taxi&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/5612/15624212726_07bf06bba6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dunno if it was Synchronicity or what, but that guy in the junkyard, on YouTube, had my exact car, same color and everything.&amp;nbsp; A Nissan Maxima.&amp;nbsp; The brake pedal, when relaxed, does not hold the circuit closed, such that charge leaks out of the battery through the brake lights.&amp;nbsp; They won&#39;t go off, even with no key in the ignition, in park.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So that YouTube showed precisely the problem and the fix.&amp;nbsp; However a big guy like me isn&#39;t cut out to be up under the steering wheel.&amp;nbsp; Dave got some paper in there, to save charge, but that won&#39;t last.&amp;nbsp; I emailed my mechanic this morning, but I have no idea how busy they are.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll have them look for other problems.&amp;nbsp; Yes she&#39;s a junker but I don&#39;t believe in throwing away serviceable equipment unnecessarily.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I bought a new phone-based HOP card recently, so I can hop a bus any time.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m likely going to refrain from driving for awhile, until I get a clear lane so to speak.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3237468666392836627'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3237468666392836627'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/10/small-time-stuff.html' title='Small Time Stuff'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-878265799345002284</id><published>2022-09-29T08:44:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2022-09-30T01:05:13.151-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Wanderers:  Fall Equinox Gathering</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72177720302486362&quot; title=&quot;Equinox Gathering 2022&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Equinox Gathering 2022&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52389463664_14efb675ef.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We were small in number, yet with interesting new people, invited guests.  I took fewer pictures than I usually do, if present, at one of these Equinox or Solstice get-togethers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We often meet at the boyhood home of Linus Pauling, where we used to hold weekly meetings, however sometimes we meet elsewhere, in retreat mode.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had an iPad going for those wishing to drop in by house WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/878265799345002284'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/878265799345002284'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/09/wanderers-fall-equinox-gathering.html' title='Wanderers:  Fall Equinox Gathering'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6353458443577907464</id><published>2022-09-12T11:02:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2022-09-21T17:35:01.273-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Making Tensegrity</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhrFywarOL68CIYtbVN1dRFq1unUJN6LcSII3nmGluek_EtEoziRWlz9a36dTSH3PKZUdqOavFeUOBfL3wCR606Dph4OsMvxzFHLh0PwY_05aw_sut7hYASm5tPlzLtd7w3eE6CzEJ2RQaOVSbw7gSilxvlizAqSY06gmzMQ3LGhlrAECzcyA/s2048/triped2020.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;2048&quot; data-original-width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhrFywarOL68CIYtbVN1dRFq1unUJN6LcSII3nmGluek_EtEoziRWlz9a36dTSH3PKZUdqOavFeUOBfL3wCR606Dph4OsMvxzFHLh0PwY_05aw_sut7hYASm5tPlzLtd7w3eE6CzEJ2RQaOVSbw7gSilxvlizAqSY06gmzMQ3LGhlrAECzcyA/w400-h400/triped2020.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;[cutting and pasting a Facebook comment]&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FB friend: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There seems to have been a dearth of beautiful and innovative tensegrity artwork for decades. Between his new biotensegrity models and these lighting models, Gerald has single handedly advanced tensegrity artwork into the 21st Century. [&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/betsyann.baron/posts/pfbid02wJjtJThKMMAjAmn9rKhisvZUpPxzjRBHESszLaXLgwWLHFZbuAtfohM58PgRovQ2l?notif_id=1662775528508688&amp;amp;notif_t=comment_mention&amp;amp;ref=notif&quot;&gt;Facebook link&lt;/a&gt;] are photos from the first in-person rehearsal for a dance presentation at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/fasciaresearchcongress/?__cft__[0]=AZVt88hEJM4YomPqzvr7pA52nf1-coRwrkUHbO975KzaOsvWNll98IYEo7FZWgcnT7cya8fk9wsoffnz7b-BJSV0reLfCHNqIGZbfbKel5bUSfi2BAdagQznKS58p_9XU9tLXzQuwt4cJZ1g4M4Ih8cuke0_51Pbbl3Zzy4MeVkYAwWX9SD50W_cT0NCfLzJkiY&amp;amp;__tn__=R]-R&quot;&gt;Fascia Research Congress&lt;/a&gt;. Gerald shipped all those models in a single piece of checked luggage. I call his design architecture &quot;turnbuckle tensegrity&quot; -- except that all the threads in those struts are right-handed. Turnbuckles would be more elegant, but nobody makes cheap hardware with turnbuckle threading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kirby, do you know any good candidates for pitching a feature for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/makemagazine/?__cft__[0]=AZVt88hEJM4YomPqzvr7pA52nf1-coRwrkUHbO975KzaOsvWNll98IYEo7FZWgcnT7cya8fk9wsoffnz7b-BJSV0reLfCHNqIGZbfbKel5bUSfi2BAdagQznKS58p_9XU9tLXzQuwt4cJZ1g4M4Ih8cuke0_51Pbbl3Zzy4MeVkYAwWX9SD50W_cT0NCfLzJkiY&amp;amp;__tn__=R]-R&quot;&gt;Make: Magazine&lt;/a&gt; on how to design a geometry, acquire the parts, and assemble &quot;tough tensegrity&quot; models? This would really light the fuse to a massive number of load-bearing tensegrity models in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Me: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When
 I joined O&#39;Reilly, Make: Magazine was still sharing the same Sebastopol
 building (we got the tour) but was morphing into its own standalone 
business.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The
 principal there at Maker had purchased a startup named Useractive of 
Champaign-Urbana (run by Trish and Scott Gray (Making Math), University 
of Illinois and Wolfram connections) when still a part of O&#39;Reilly 
management. However by the time the merger happened, and Useractive 
became O&#39;Reilly School of Technology (which is where I came in, as 
faculty), he&#39;d opted out of the chain of command.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I
 therefore interfaced through OST to O&#39;Reilly bosses without ever 
getting to make solid connections with Make: Magazine and its team.  
I&#39;ve gone to Maker Fairs here in Portland, hosted by OMSI (industrial 
science museum) and friends, and finally got to 3D print an S module and
 a phi-down version, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/-O0XLGGIn8o&quot;&gt;at a public library&lt;/a&gt;, with help from Sam Lanahan&#39;s 
chief CAD designer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regarding Tensegrity, I don&#39;t know if Maker Mag does write-ups or profiles of individual makers, but if it does, an article on &lt;a class=&quot;qi72231t nu7423ey n3hqoq4p r86q59rh b3qcqh3k fq87ekyn bdao358l fsf7x5fv rse6dlih s5oniofx m8h3af8h l7ghb35v kjdc1dyq kmwttqpk srn514ro oxkhqvkx rl78xhln nch0832m cr00lzj9 rn8ck1ys s3jn8y49 icdlwmnq cxfqmxzd pbevjfx6 innypi6y&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/gerald.dejong?__cft__[0]=AZVt88hEJM4YomPqzvr7pA52nf1-coRwrkUHbO975KzaOsvWNll98IYEo7FZWgcnT7cya8fk9wsoffnz7b-BJSV0reLfCHNqIGZbfbKel5bUSfi2BAdagQznKS58p_9XU9tLXzQuwt4cJZ1g4M4Ih8cuke0_51Pbbl3Zzy4MeVkYAwWX9SD50W_cT0NCfLzJkiY&amp;amp;__tn__=R]-R&quot; role=&quot;link&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;rse6dlih&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Gerald De Jong&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
 which includes his software contributions (critical to EIG), would most
 definitely be in order.  Let Gerald share his process with readers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Postscript:
 O&#39;Reilly wanted to turn OST from a dot com into a dot edu, but that 
meant getting certified as an academic institution, which process is 
replete with bureaucracy ($$). The uphill battle to become a legit 
university in California proved a budget breaker and we dissolved, after
 a rather fun / wild ride.  I met and stay in touch with some astounding
 people.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6353458443577907464'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6353458443577907464'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/09/making-tensegrity.html' title='Making Tensegrity'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhrFywarOL68CIYtbVN1dRFq1unUJN6LcSII3nmGluek_EtEoziRWlz9a36dTSH3PKZUdqOavFeUOBfL3wCR606Dph4OsMvxzFHLh0PwY_05aw_sut7hYASm5tPlzLtd7w3eE6CzEJ2RQaOVSbw7gSilxvlizAqSY06gmzMQ3LGhlrAECzcyA/s72-w400-h400-c/triped2020.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1274521382308380635</id><published>2022-09-02T08:50:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2022-09-07T07:47:02.383-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Social Darwinism</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/jMjcDbYxS3M&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My impression is the meme of &quot;races&quot; (how many again?) is a top drawer tool for recruiters working to swell the ranks of the Social Darwinists.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One may be a fan of Darwin and his theorizing, without switching into &quot;genetic Calvinism&quot; i.e. some doctrine of preordained &quot;fitness&quot; based in having the better DNA.&amp;nbsp; That ideology worked well for Royals too, as it perpetuated the myth of &quot;blood&quot; i.e. some coveted genetic plasma, divinely conferring special rights and special powers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The race theory depends heavily on their being a &quot;mixed race&quot; category.&amp;nbsp; People must be allowed to fall through the cracks so to speak.&amp;nbsp; Without cracks, the categorization system would be too brittle and break down.&amp;nbsp; One&#39;s racial makeup is allowed to be &quot;fuzzy&quot; and the prospect of entirely new races emerging is not actively contemplated in most racist science fiction (&quot;super race&quot; mythologies usually revolve around refining some prior race, even while pushing for its &quot;world dominance&quot; or &quot;supremacy&quot;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Were a race detectable in pure form, even in a mixed race person (thinking of superstitions around blood again, and powers-of-2 subdivision e.g. 1/32nd race X), we would have found it by now, but there&#39;s no reduction of &quot;race&quot; to canonical strings of chromosomal encoding.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rather, we find ourselves defining &quot;ancestry&quot; which relates to &quot;geography&quot; based on the presence (or absence) of &quot;genetic markers&quot;.&amp;nbsp; Tracing a family tree means following world lines against the backdrop of Planet Earth, with its partially overlapping scenarios.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Animal husbandry has the same degree of precision (imprecision).&amp;nbsp; In animal husbandry, one speaks of breeds, which one may consciously design and refine over the generations.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Darwinist is able to see &quot;breeds&quot; within in the human family in that sense, a kind of family resemblance, but maybe through several filters, as there&#39;s no universal agreement on what any of these breeds really are.&amp;nbsp; We just know we keep re-encountering the same types.&amp;nbsp; Supermodels?&amp;nbsp; Midgets?&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://metro.co.uk/2015/10/03/dwarf-fashion-show-hits-paris-to-show-that-its-not-height-that-makes-you-a-model-5419258/&quot;&gt;Midget supermodels&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Men and women create this first idea of a divide, orthogonal to Darwinistic evolution through speciation.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Homo Sapien is the current species, a Cro-Magnon with some Neanderthal mixed in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An alternative view is of a very expressive human genome, able to manifest features in various ways, without distilling into an essential palette of racial archetypes.&amp;nbsp; We don&#39;t need to discern &quot;races&quot; as the compass points for categorization, even if we&#39;re tracking ancestry.&amp;nbsp; The ideology of racial purity and of a genetic competition amongst genetic &quot;teams&quot; (the races) is a layer of dogma that doesn&#39;t logically follow from biology.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s more an extended metaphor, with memes replacing genes in ways that pander to a sense of tribe and belonging.&amp;nbsp; We like to rally around genetic features sometimes, e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Redhead_Day&quot;&gt;a convention for gingers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1274521382308380635'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1274521382308380635'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/09/social-darwinism.html' title='Social Darwinism'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/jMjcDbYxS3M/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4441675574397670360</id><published>2022-08-14T10:16:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2022-08-14T10:16:44.247-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Burger Week</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/52284167355/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Burger Week is Here&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Burger Week is Here&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52284167355_dfbd676201.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&#39;t been that big of a meat eater, by western standards.&amp;nbsp; Yes I eat meat, including bison or buffalo on occasion, but I&#39;m not like a steak every month or week guy.&amp;nbsp; My diet isn&#39;t paleo.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve spent probably thousands on McMenamins Dungeon Burgers over the years.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s the one with mushrooms and Swiss cheese.&amp;nbsp; I wonder if their database would show that.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;select count(item), sum(item_price) where customer = [me] and item = &quot;dungeon_burger&quot;;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those would be aggregating columns. That&#39;s in pseudo-sql against a database I&#39;ve never met in person. A mind game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Originally I&#39;d titled this post &quot;Summer BBQ&quot; because I had this metaphor in mind:&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve stoked the briquettes with all the newspaper needed, and lit the pyre (if I might call it that); lets see if the briquettes catch, which means they&#39;ll generate their own heat, long after all the newspaper is consumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/52283684666/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Abduction&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Abduction&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52283684666_4438189883.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That metaphor in turn was about my approach to andragogy.&amp;nbsp; If I keep fawning over the flames, fanning them, I won&#39;t know if they would go out without me.&amp;nbsp; Given I could use such feedback, I&#39;ll aim to stand back.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve worked on the ignition phase plenty, it seems to me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m still being rather abstract, but that&#39;s OK.&amp;nbsp; Lets get back to burgers.&amp;nbsp; Portland has a whole week celebrating the genre and recommends retailers offer an $8 burger week special, their choice of what to try.&amp;nbsp; At least that&#39;s my understanding of the challenge.&amp;nbsp; I don&#39;t know what syndicate is behind it exactly, only that this is not a new institution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Almost in anticipation of said burger week, Glenn and I sampled the offerings at the &lt;i&gt;Yes Please Smashburger&lt;/i&gt; shack, a certified food cart right across from the Linus Pauling House.&amp;nbsp; I took quite a few pictures and have left them interspersed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/52282704052/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Yes Please food cart&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Yes Please food cart&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52282704052_5508c40642.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4441675574397670360'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4441675574397670360'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/08/burger-week.html' title='Burger Week'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1342918597277943557</id><published>2022-08-07T10:05:00.006-07:00</published><updated>2022-09-28T13:47:33.450-07:00</updated><title type='text'>New Bucky Bio</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/52269737248/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;New Bio&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;New Bio&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52269737248_c0089c52cb_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just got the book yesterday and have been doing my nonlinear Evelyn Wood Reading Dynamics thing, i.e. I&#39;ve been browsing it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_quote&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;I&#39;ve
 always contended studying Bucky&#39;s bio is worthwhile because he was so, 
shall we say, gregarious.&amp;nbsp; He got around.&amp;nbsp; He was &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2008/06/poor-slob-bucky-psb.html&quot;&gt;a mover-shaker type&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;He
 also lived a long time and was a compulsive self chronicler, by 
design.&amp;nbsp; Guinea Pig B wanted to be studied.&amp;nbsp; Alec is paying him that 
courtesy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Alec&#39;s
 bio also proves my point.&amp;nbsp; Every page is connecting us to a 
recognizable vista of big name architects, poets, professors and so on.&amp;nbsp;
 Military types...&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Great
 story.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s like a Michelin guide to the 1900s, of course to specific 
circles, an intelligentsia that still persists in some form.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Given how thick it is, I understand Alec&#39;s not trying to be another Amy Edmondson and recap Synergetics.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;He gives readers enough to whet their appetites, and then it&#39;s all online.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;I didn&#39;t participate in creating this book.&amp;nbsp; I see Trevor mentioned, and CJ.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;That means I still have my stories to tell, as &lt;a href=&quot;http://grunch.net/snelson/&quot;&gt;Kenneth Snelson&#39;s first webmaster&lt;/a&gt; (BFI&#39;s too) and so on.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;&gt;[first posted to TrimTab BookClub GoogleGroup]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1342918597277943557'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1342918597277943557'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/08/new-bucky-bio.html' title='New Bucky Bio'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-633733535328765920</id><published>2022-07-29T21:16:00.007-07:00</published><updated>2022-07-29T21:21:28.192-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Uncle Bill Stranded</title><content type='html'>&lt;div href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/52250344041/in/dateposted-public/&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot; title=&quot;Portland on Google Earth&quot; true=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Portland on Google Earth&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52250344041_f9c79b283c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; I&#39;m pretty sure Uncle Bill, age 97, is still stuck at Union Station.&amp;nbsp; I got a surprise call from the guy at 4:15, right before I was to start teaching class.&amp;nbsp; He was in Portland, here for the day, to see a different relative.&amp;nbsp; The only thing was:&amp;nbsp; he hadn&#39;t been able to reach said relative on the phone, yet he came anyway.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I couldn&#39;t help.&amp;nbsp; My Python for High School was to start in 15 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The good news was that even if he was missing his 4 PM train, he&#39;d get the next one back to Seattle around 6 PM.&amp;nbsp; He&#39;d make it to Union Station by taxi.&amp;nbsp; Good plan.&amp;nbsp; I encouraged him to high tail it down there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As it turned out, however, the Steel Bridge was &quot;having issues&quot; (due to the heat we think) and Amtrak trains were stranded on both sides, going nowhere.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or was the one in Tacoma having other issues?&amp;nbsp; Bill&#39;s ticket was (is) for the Coast Starlight, coming north.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m watching for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AmtrakAlerts/status/1553220098344853504?s=20&amp;amp;t=O4W6WPJqqfmZET4K7jxLVw&quot;&gt;updates on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As for me, I need to get up early (alarm set for 5 AM) and start a next teaching gig.&amp;nbsp; I have a pretty full calendar this coming month.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re in the middle of a heat wave in Portland.&amp;nbsp; Fortunately, I&#39;ll have completed my first session before it really heats up.&amp;nbsp; The course is mapped to the New York clock.&amp;nbsp; The headquarters are in Turkey.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/52208250265/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Union Station&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Union Station&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52208250265_fca8228bed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

 </content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/633733535328765920'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/633733535328765920'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/07/uncle-bill-stranded.html' title='Uncle Bill Stranded'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7130736889873564612</id><published>2022-07-24T17:20:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2022-07-24T17:25:39.980-07:00</updated><title type='text'>High School in the Silicon Forest</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/xaXXIpXx-lU&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7130736889873564612'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7130736889873564612'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/07/high-school-in-silicon-forest.html' title='High School in the Silicon Forest'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/xaXXIpXx-lU/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3665842629529883482</id><published>2022-07-22T20:49:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2022-07-26T22:17:10.333-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Campus Recruiting and Logistics</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/52234356720/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;welcome_newcomers&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;welcome_newcomers&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/52234356720_9f4411847f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve got my fishing pole in this lake, but don&#39;t expect many nibbles.&amp;nbsp; I consider it free advertising for my company, which has a footprint in education.&amp;nbsp; What about American Transcendentalism as a literary tradition?&amp;nbsp; How about as a philosophical one?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transcendentalism is not usually acknowledged within any taxonomy of philosophies, although some of its leading lights get a tacit nod, in the case of Emerson, from Nietzsche.&amp;nbsp; As a literary phase, it fits between Romantic / Dark Romantic (Gothic) and Realistic, on the way to Modernist and Postmodernist.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m looking to do business with education institutions.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps we&#39;ll devise a standard practice, based around bizmo fleets, where they travel from campus to campus, because they&#39;re outfitted to perform scholarly research.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some do bug counts (insect populations), some focus on testing soils.&amp;nbsp; The universities and other bases need both the data, and the science trained personnel.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An active bizmo fleet keeps ideas in circulation, literally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For those just joining us, I&#39;ve been planning around truck stops and the lifestyle of truckers, both long and short distance haulers.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not an expert.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not a trucker.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m interested in these truck stop hubs for various reasons.&amp;nbsp; I have prototype dwelling machine villages in mind, designed for transport by shipping container, meaning trucks along the way, trains also.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some truckers are in like PhD programs where they stay awhile in these remote lands, allowing the payloads to go on without them.&amp;nbsp; Learn the history, some of the language, become more familiar with the local ways.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Live in some yurt-like pod on a utility pole, surrounded by yak herds or peacocks.&amp;nbsp; Then move on.&amp;nbsp; In this global university model, students and faculty are not necessarily shy about operating heavy equipment, including long haul rigs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A bizmo (business mobile) is a smaller more agile vehicle that scouts the routes and tends to business, without hauling a big load.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One might say these bizmos gather and relay intelligence about an area, but that sounds like a suspect activity, unwelcome spying perhaps.&amp;nbsp; However your average bizmo is most welcome in most cases, wherever it goes, because there&#39;s nothing especially clandestine about how or why it operates.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s nothing necessarily wrong with monitoring local conditions, especially by locals themselves, perhaps as mentors with apprentices, themselves on tour.&amp;nbsp; Keep the databases up to date.&amp;nbsp; Think of Google Street View or one of those.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think of tour guides too.&amp;nbsp; We want and expect them to guide us through, especially in tricky situations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The work comes under the heading of citizen diplomacy in many ways.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3665842629529883482'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3665842629529883482'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/07/campus-recruiting-and-logistics.html' title='Campus Recruiting and Logistics'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>