<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211</id><updated>2025-02-27T06:25:58.543-08:00</updated><category term="clojure python REPL ide"/><title type='text'>BizMo Diaries</title><subtitle type='html'>On the road with Global Data</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1905</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4570471174054723904</id><published>2025-02-25T12:34:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-02-25T12:52:36.740-08:00</updated><title type='text'>No Bears (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157621793762675&quot; title=&quot;Iranian Festival&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Iranian Festival&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/2672/3779629934_448b486a33.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rented &lt;i&gt;No Bears&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2025/02/border-cafe-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;Border Café&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; together, from &lt;i&gt;Movie Madness&lt;/i&gt;, and have a plan to continue drawing DVDs from the Iranian shelf. That section of the video rental store is indeed sorted by nationality, and alphabetically within that. Other sections of the store sort by Hollywood Director, or categorize into Horror vs. British vs. legacy television.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re lucky to have such a facility, with over 80K titles, as a part of our neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;i&gt;No Bears&lt;/i&gt; second, and didn&#39;t realize until viewing the special features that the director was also the protagonist, and his predicament in the film is similar to his predicament in real life: he&#39;s in trouble with the government and not supposed to escape to a foreign country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The film has an ingenious twist, which I&#39;m suggesting you can know about without spoiling the viewing experience, as the paradox, if we might call it that, never fully resolves. The split between reality and filmed reality is the issue. When we posit what we&#39;re viewing is reality, as if the camera wasn&#39;t there, then by that very same token it&#39;s not reality, because we&#39;re viewing it, so there&#39;s a camera.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The documentary genre will sometimes up the honesty by bringing the crew and camera into the filming, whereas those feature films suggesting we suspend disbelief will offer a &quot;making of&quot; as a feature, acknowledging the artistry behind the projected illusion. A &quot;making of&quot; is akin to going backstage to meet with actors out of character, resuming their native personae.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What this film does is lull the viewer into thinking we&#39;re in &quot;omniscient camera&quot; mode, only to have that assumption pushed aside when the opening scene turns out to be a take in a movie, which our protagonist is attempting to direct remotely, from the other side of the Iran-Turkey border.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But then in another twist we find out the acting couple is indeed attempting to obtain black market passports for a one way trip to Europe, but that going together is problematic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point, with the camera&#39;s loss of omniscience and invisibility, our sense of the director&#39;s innocence decreases as his participation in his own film&#39;s drama brings out the manipulative character of film directing. He might be getting people in trouble, making their lives worse?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a man from the city, educated, with money, and with a fancy car, he is treated with respect and politeness. He gets people to do things on his behalf that might be more in his self interest than theirs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The director is addicted to making movies, even if that means turning his own life into film. Is this passion constructive or destructive? Would we in the audience have such a useful and penetrating view of traditional Iranian village life, without his guidance?&amp;nbsp; We know the film is ultimately fictional and therefore harmless. Why would the Iranian government persecute a guy who is making Iranian filmmaking famous? A deep question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I see why the movie won awards and plan to see some others by this same director, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/name/nm0070159/bio/?ref_=nm_ov_bio_sm&quot;&gt;Jafa Panahi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4570471174054723904'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4570471174054723904'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2025/02/no-bears-movie-review.html' title='No Bears (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7994735805143398701</id><published>2025-02-22T11:01:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-02-22T17:02:39.328-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Border Café (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54344008133/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Truck and Bus Stop&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Truck and Bus Stop&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54344008133_b12e6f8b04.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;
:: visitor center; Asylum City ::  
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;I just saw &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0477585/&quot;&gt;Border Café&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, originally &lt;i&gt;Cafe Transit&lt;/i&gt;, you can see why I&#39;d be into it: &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2022/08/trucker-exchange-program-promotional.html&quot;&gt;Trucker Exchange Program&lt;/a&gt;. The movie is set around a little roadside cafe in the hinterlands bordering Turkey, Syria and Iran. We have a Russian homeless teen hoping to reach Italy, and a lonely Greek seeking his missing wife.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I could see screening this for the elite early birds wanting to get those initial anthropology requirements out of the way. The movie is all aboard borders and social customs and the ethics around women working, but with few compunctions about child labor.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We should remember that not long before &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/11/roaring-20s.html&quot;&gt;the Roaring 20s,&lt;/a&gt; women in the North American states had few opportunities outside the home. Jealous men kept them &quot;protected&quot; as prize possessions, as trophies. Then came the two world wars and an ongoing labor shortage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Not only did women come into the office, they started operating heavy equipment, more like Sigourney Weaver in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Aliens &lt;/i&gt;movies&lt;i&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The Trucker Exchange Program is not about &quot;in your face&quot; challenging everyone&#39;s cultural norms in a disruptive manner.&amp;nbsp; That&#39;s happening anyway, through TV, radio, and streaming.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Some parts of the globe are already comfortable with female drivers. Others might accept a long hauler married couple.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The movie is about the thermodynamics of gossip, and what spreads. If there&#39;s nothing scandalous happening, how is it clickbait?&amp;nbsp; Ordinary news tends to be relatively dry, an acquired taste.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The movie is also about cuisine.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The female principal is obviously a genius cook and what brings in the truckers in droves is her excellent homemade food. She has a profession, a calling. The males around her have a hard time handling the idea that a woman could have any profession outside of homemaker. Somehow someone&#39;s honor is at stake.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;My point is: it wasn&#39;t that long ago before only &quot;loose women&quot; (of the kind you&#39;d meet in bars) could have any profession and then they all seemed to have the same one. Margaret Fuller helped women break into journalism, starting with cultural columns, then branching out into hard news.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Traveling to far off lands may be like going back in time, which in turn means that, coming the other way, is like going forward in time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But let&#39;s not forget about going sideways.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Sometimes culture shock doesn&#39;t come in the form of a time shift, as what alters is not the time but the space, the vibe, the atmospherics. Said vibes tend to be timeless a lot of the time, archetypal.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7994735805143398701'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7994735805143398701'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2025/02/border-cafe-movie-review.html' title='Border Café (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5881795421631380192</id><published>2025-02-19T06:28:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-02-25T12:06:36.364-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Speculative Prehistory: the Naga Story</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54337782321/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Naga Story&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Naga Story&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54337782321_a34a42bbed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand how a reader might pick up &lt;i&gt;Critical Path&lt;/i&gt; and experience some disillusionment upon encountering the Naga Story. Even if the Genesis Story has little basis in science, perhaps with the exception of the flood (talking about the Black Sea filling up suddenly), how are we to take a migration story that begins in the South Pacific and comes westward to Europe and beyond? Why replace one incredible story with &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2025/02/playing-with-dsr1.html&quot;&gt;another one&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot depends on how we define “humanity” as one could say we’re still on a Planet of the Apes with simple reclassification. The “homo” branch of the ape family exemplifies tool use, and we already have ape and monkey branches that don’t and/or can’t interbreed, so let’s make the so-called sapiens more of those, another breed of ape, why not? It seems like a demotion of sorts as we&#39;re saying &quot;humanity is yet to come&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then comes the paradisiacal Eden-like experience of growing up in Polynesia, with just the right mix of stimuli, and at last, true humanity is upon the scene. A new ideal is achieved. Where this new spirit comes from is only tunable metaphorically: from the stars, as a transmission. That&#39;s in keeping with intelligence being metaphysical (weightless).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This humanity is spread by both land- and sea-based branching vectors, and provides actual human (pueblo) status to the sapien branch of the apes. We get the rice paddy economies following river beds towards higher mountains. We get the discovering of metals and their alloys. We get our planetary species civilization, spreading from Southeast Asia to India, Africa, Europe, the Americas, or directly to the Americas going around the other way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, we imbue the circumnavigating Polynesians with our identity as actual humans, in the process of becoming even more humane, while mixing it up with other animal stock in some cases, harnessing and riding them and/or domesticating and husbanding them. A third class of human took to the sea, depending on wind power more than animal power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With industrialization came more “energy slaves” per capita, meaning humans were served by more and more horsepower not expressed through living animals but through mechanical devices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A hint about this reading comes from those passages wherein Bucky warns us about boxing and/or overspecialization. When we bash one another in brutish fashion, de-geniusing ourselves, we regress (revert) to our more ape-like substrate. Our humanity evaporates from the Zeitgeist when we march towards oblivion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This may all sound well and good but what about Polynesians having affinity with dolphins and whales more than apes? Why say humanity has more in common with these indigenous ocean goers than with the landlubber tool users? And yes, some apes are more aquatic than others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First of all, that’s not actually the claim. Interest in dolphins and whales was developing over Fuller’s lifetime, with a strong emphasis on their safekeeping and preservation. Dr. Lilly even tried to open a communication channel with the dolphins, with a little help from his three-letter friend LSD.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Critical Path&lt;/i&gt; was reflective of its own period in history in speculating about a humanity-dolphin hybrid (so-called mermaids). This might have happened on other worlds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seeing a shared humanity in these ocean-going mammals is probably more predictive of the future than a key to past evolutionary biology on Spaceship Earth.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Humans have the capacity to build out under water, as well as over water. Given the percent of the planetary surface that’s oceanic, humans will likely colonize a lot more of the oceanic ecosystem before they ever get to Mars, perhaps modifying themselves genetically in the process.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5881795421631380192'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5881795421631380192'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2025/02/speculative-prehistory.html' title='Speculative Prehistory: the Naga Story'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7426220762175641294</id><published>2025-02-17T17:28:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-02-18T08:06:36.202-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Detachment</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjmuMsqRQaGSjoB3nN7T1VJwUyV3EcruVXK0FFWe5o_l9lPW5xmmh4aY9WcU4NjUFOPkojS37XrCOL1uoYzMaZmioBwPIkxRcmjE2EmZ-gaKI5HjJLMUaFHSBEEfM7dvDuXLQFpQnib0ZO3YLDH-m55wKCN69qmhMHtjc3KToZDD3gsGG_zLgsa/s1536/buddha_in_gym.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1536&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1536&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjmuMsqRQaGSjoB3nN7T1VJwUyV3EcruVXK0FFWe5o_l9lPW5xmmh4aY9WcU4NjUFOPkojS37XrCOL1uoYzMaZmioBwPIkxRcmjE2EmZ-gaKI5HjJLMUaFHSBEEfM7dvDuXLQFpQnib0ZO3YLDH-m55wKCN69qmhMHtjc3KToZDD3gsGG_zLgsa/w400-h400/buddha_in_gym.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you prompt me to talk about Buddhism vs Christianity, I might bring up that much misunderstood word, used by translators, &quot;detachment&quot;, and link it that to that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Does-God-love-or-hate-the-world-Are-John-3-16-and-1-John-2-15-opposed-Does-it-seem-as-if-God-loves-the-world-but-asks-us-not-to-do-so&quot;&gt;troublesome Jesus meme&lt;/a&gt; &quot;hate the world&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The depth psychology here is &quot;the world&quot; is indistinguishable from one&#39;s experience of it, except that &quot;one&#39;s experience&quot; is objectively subject to change more adeptly (&quot;on a dime&quot;) than &quot;the world&quot; is, given the latter is macrocosmic and therefore suffers from more inertia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Hate the world&quot; means leaning to cultivate dispassion and what in science we call &quot;a sense of objectivity&quot; to where you&#39;re less invested in your current ego beliefs. You&#39;re potentially more open minded, which is where God&#39;s grace comes in, with the epiphanies and revelations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The anthropologist, plunked down in some setting, is a trained observer, including of her or his own thoughts and reactions. We learn about cultures from their interactions. But the observer is not so in love with her or his own culture to want to step in and intervene, as some kind of missionary. The anthropologist is there to live and learn, not to judge, not to be a jerk (as in &quot;knee-jerk reflex machine&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To cultivate dispassion, to become more open, is to become less bot-like, less programmed, less predictable in one&#39;s reactions. Which doesn&#39;t mean a personality is morphing on every front. On the contrary, as Bucky would put it (paraphrase): the metaphysical aspect settles down, even as one&#39;s appreciation for the complexity of it all continues to skyrocket.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7426220762175641294'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7426220762175641294'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2025/02/detachment.html' title='Detachment'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjmuMsqRQaGSjoB3nN7T1VJwUyV3EcruVXK0FFWe5o_l9lPW5xmmh4aY9WcU4NjUFOPkojS37XrCOL1uoYzMaZmioBwPIkxRcmjE2EmZ-gaKI5HjJLMUaFHSBEEfM7dvDuXLQFpQnib0ZO3YLDH-m55wKCN69qmhMHtjc3KToZDD3gsGG_zLgsa/s72-w400-h400-c/buddha_in_gym.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6377862567431770173</id><published>2025-02-14T15:19:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-02-27T06:25:58.458-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Planet Palestine</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54326834622/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;NPU&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;NPU&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54326834622_7d17b836d6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;415&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

I&#39;ve been &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2025/02/free-range-humans.html&quot;&gt;pretty consistent&lt;/a&gt; in coming down on the side of freedom of movement, probably because &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.io/g/synergeo/message/2961&quot;&gt;my school of thought&lt;/a&gt; sees the individual-to-planet relationship as initially, by default, open, in the sense of unconstrained.&amp;nbsp;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Institutions may clamp down on &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/08/colluding-on-confinement.html&quot;&gt;your freedoms&lt;/a&gt; as a tourist and/or planetary explorer, however we struggle to keep tourism a reality, without depending so much on the militaries for this purpose.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;As a USA citizen with a passport, I&#39;ve enjoyed relatively unfettered access to many parts of the globe, a freedom I&#39;m well aware not so many enjoy, because they&#39;re not carrying the right travel credentials and have no clear path towards getting such credentials.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54328205678/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;New Palestine University&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;New Palestine University&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54328205678_3dcc480da8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;465&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6377862567431770173'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6377862567431770173'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2025/02/planet-palestine.html' title='Planet Palestine'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1942874177056708187</id><published>2025-02-04T05:48:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-02-04T05:48:11.361-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Cascadian Synergetics</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54306757794/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Cascadian Synergetics&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54306757794_ee6877d7dd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Cascadian Synergetics&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;            
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54306757804/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Forest Altar&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54306757804_e91438ddc7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Forest Altar&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;       
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54306517286/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Campus Building&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54306517286_f42eeab073.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Campus Building&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;         
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54306770593/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Cascadian Art&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54306770593_2a1c7b9431.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Cascadian Art&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;        
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1942874177056708187'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1942874177056708187'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2025/02/cascadian-synergetics.html' title='Cascadian Synergetics'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-380496169612407622</id><published>2025-02-01T03:36:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-02-01T03:50:49.982-08:00</updated><title type='text'>ChatBot Chatting</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/53973447428/in/photolist-2qes2vN&quot; title=&quot;King Hilbert (or N-dim-eus)&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;King Hilbert (or N-dim-eus)&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53973447428_2db042582f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;King N-dimeus of Hilbert Space&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Prompt&lt;/i&gt;: &amp;nbsp;Explain AI image generation in terms of moving through Hilbert space to a particular position.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Answer&lt;/i&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explaining AI image generation in terms of moving through Hilbert space involves understanding how these models navigate complex mathematical spaces to create images. Here&#39;s a simplified explanation:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Introduction to Hilbert Space&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;b&gt;Hilbert space&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a mathematical concept that extends the idea of Euclidean space to infinite dimensions, allowing for the representation of complex data structures like images. It is equipped with an inner product operation, enabling the definition of lengths and angles, which is crucial for analyzing and manipulating data within this space[8].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;AI Image Generation Basics&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;AI image generators, such as those using **diffusion models**, create images by iteratively refining a noise signal until it converges to a desired image. This process involves moving through a &lt;b&gt;latent space&lt;/b&gt;, which can be thought of as a subset of a Hilbert space, where each point corresponds to a specific image representation[1][4].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Moving Through Hilbert Space&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the context of AI image generation, moving through Hilbert space can be metaphorically understood as navigating through this vast, multidimensional space to reach a specific point that corresponds to the desired image. Here’s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;b&gt;Initialization&lt;/b&gt;: The process starts with a random noise vector in the latent space, which is analogous to a point in Hilbert space. This noise vector represents the initial state of the image generation process[1].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;b&gt;Guidance Signal&lt;/b&gt;: A guidance signal, such as a text prompt, is used to condition the generation process. This signal acts as a direction or a target in the Hilbert space, guiding the model towards the desired image characteristics[1].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. &lt;b&gt;Diffusion Process&lt;/b&gt;: The model iteratively refines the noise vector through a diffusion process, which involves a series of transformations that progressively move the vector closer to the target point in the latent space. Each step in the diffusion process can be seen as a movement in the Hilbert space towards the desired image representation[1][3].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. &lt;b&gt;Convergence&lt;/b&gt;: As the diffusion process continues, the vector converges to a specific point in the latent space, which corresponds to the final generated image. This point represents the culmination of the journey through Hilbert space, where the model has successfully mapped the input prompt to a visual representation[1].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Challenges and Opportunities&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Navigating Hilbert space for image generation poses challenges such as managing high-dimensional data and ensuring interpretability of the learned representations. However, it also offers opportunities for creating diverse and realistic images by leveraging the vast potential of these mathematical spaces[5][9].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In summary, AI image generation can be viewed as a process of moving through a complex Hilbert space to reach a specific point that represents the desired image. This involves navigating through a multidimensional space guided by a conditioning signal until convergence to the target image representation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Citations:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&quot;https://sii.pl/blog/en/a-brief-history-of-ai-powered-image-generation/&quot;&gt;https://sii.pl/blog/en/a-brief-history-of-ai-powered-image-generation/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/faster-image-classification-generation-using-hilbert-curves-n-&quot;&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/faster-image-classification-generation-using-hilbert-curves-n-&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sFztPP9qPRc&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sFztPP9qPRc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[4] &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/aiwars/comments/1ae55p0/technical_ai_image_generators_draw_from_an/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/aiwars/comments/1ae55p0/technical_ai_image_generators_draw_from_an/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[5] &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.easiio.com/neural-network-hilbert-space/&quot;&gt;https://www.easiio.com/neural-network-hilbert-space/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[6] &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2666675821001041&quot;&gt;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2666675821001041&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[7] &lt;a href=&quot;https://proceedings.neurips.cc/paper_files/paper/2023/file/76c6f9f2475b275b92d03a83ea270af4-Paper-Conference.pdf&quot;&gt;https://proceedings.neurips.cc/paper_files/paper/2023/file/76c6f9f2475b275b92d03a83ea270af4-Paper-Conference.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[8] &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hilbert_space&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hilbert_space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[9] &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.altexsoft.com/blog/ai-image-generation/&quot;&gt;https://www.altexsoft.com/blog/ai-image-generation/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/380496169612407622'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/380496169612407622'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2025/02/chatbot-chatting.html' title='ChatBot Chatting'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7900759831996073138</id><published>2025-01-31T20:06:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-01-31T20:06:18.290-08:00</updated><title type='text'>A Canadian Connection</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhZKxsy3bZqhH51mwRLX2Uip4_TEaB4Zh_6A4LzcDbcC4c4trgKfyYwPA6lNAEs0_cuQXIhYF0ifgKZ5W2hhdAZI389jbxaLh-9NlWOlPZW5K0yA7r3mj31_dmAhJPpbxmUh3yk3j80wGoeVHWps25irOXIC1NikCQ4RkOiCkZyIFNNn1PLlgQh/s1232/IMG_1933.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;928&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1232&quot; height=&quot;301&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhZKxsy3bZqhH51mwRLX2Uip4_TEaB4Zh_6A4LzcDbcC4c4trgKfyYwPA6lNAEs0_cuQXIhYF0ifgKZ5W2hhdAZI389jbxaLh-9NlWOlPZW5K0yA7r3mj31_dmAhJPpbxmUh3yk3j80wGoeVHWps25irOXIC1NikCQ4RkOiCkZyIFNNn1PLlgQh/w400-h301/IMG_1933.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael Accera of Lux Blox sent me this “geometer guy”, AI generated, awhile back in a DM. We were talking C9 (Cloud Nine) as I recall, one of our tribal memes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In retrospect I have to say the image kinda reminds me of Joe Truss, now that we’ve finally &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.io/g/synergeo/message/2934&quot;&gt;met on Zoom&lt;/a&gt;. I say “finally” because Joe is a contemporary who worked with Stafford Beer, the Team Syntegrity guy. I’d been aware of their work but only to a strictly limited degree.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7900759831996073138'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7900759831996073138'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2025/01/a-canadian-connection.html' title='A Canadian Connection'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhZKxsy3bZqhH51mwRLX2Uip4_TEaB4Zh_6A4LzcDbcC4c4trgKfyYwPA6lNAEs0_cuQXIhYF0ifgKZ5W2hhdAZI389jbxaLh-9NlWOlPZW5K0yA7r3mj31_dmAhJPpbxmUh3yk3j80wGoeVHWps25irOXIC1NikCQ4RkOiCkZyIFNNn1PLlgQh/s72-w400-h301-c/IMG_1933.jpeg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5902861133077318805</id><published>2025-01-25T10:58:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-01-25T11:12:40.040-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Asylum City</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjqoBUhmxoyoXP0gc0EgwsIVsWzv3KP8zot_Pl87ISRLhOJRxum0GYz1K8osvizCwhxZBFIMgkjFT4ggKONkRMiCpOwWz7DqMWLNuNK6x33WXwd7R4YJBNVaSvyy5lJc_pLEW8aybFIT5KOyuWEq-QPxJIESiZRiQ-QMu94FxqesuAemAhidicI/s1244/Screen%20Shot%202025-01-22%20at%209.06.59%20AM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;828&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1244&quot; height=&quot;266&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjqoBUhmxoyoXP0gc0EgwsIVsWzv3KP8zot_Pl87ISRLhOJRxum0GYz1K8osvizCwhxZBFIMgkjFT4ggKONkRMiCpOwWz7DqMWLNuNK6x33WXwd7R4YJBNVaSvyy5lJc_pLEW8aybFIT5KOyuWEq-QPxJIESiZRiQ-QMu94FxqesuAemAhidicI/w400-h266/Screen%20Shot%202025-01-22%20at%209.06.59%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;:: from my dad&#39;s archive: layout plan for Hoon, Libya ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When&#39;d I&#39;d tell folks what I was into at Princeton, like if sitting next to a stranger on Amtrak, and getting to talking, they&#39;d say &quot;what ya gonna do with that?&quot; meaning my background reading Philosophy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the tone was dismissive, other times more pensive, as the culture sends a mixed message. We&#39;re told it&#39;s (philosophy is) great prep for CS (computer science) and a career in IT (information technology), which is more or less what happened to me, but also for future CEOs and startup founders.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although &quot;a founder&quot; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/4dsolutions/&quot;&gt;per LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;), I&#39;ve been in the ball game too long to call my sole proprietorship, previously a partnership, a &quot;startup&quot;. I&#39;ve been DBA 4D Solutions and before that InfoTech, for a long time. DIADEM Center for Creative Networking before that (&lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/12/after-princeton.html&quot;&gt;starting in JCNJ&lt;/a&gt; -- Jersey City, near where Bruce Wayne&#39;s parents got shot), after I quit my fun and challenging high school teaching job (private academy), believing I heard Destiny calling (or Fate as the case may be and depending on the namespace / vocab).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what I&#39;ve discovered, in retrospect, is sticking to a philosophy track, even if a worker bee, entitles one to some Brit aristocracy airs, in the sense that one is allowed, even expected, to be &quot;eccentric&quot;. That quality flies brilliantly here in Portland, aka Weirdo City. To top it all off, I like in Asylum District, truly named for a mental hospital (pastoral setting) that used to take up quite a bit of space here on the east side.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an &quot;out there&quot; type person, I&#39;m allowed to be more like those comedians, those jokers, who push the envelope as we say, regarding what&#39;s OK to have a sense of humor about, and what&#39;s not. Philosophers as a class sometimes go over the line, are beyond the pale, get lost in some twilight zone, and yet society may nevertheless reward them, as this is their role. It all depends. The devil, as they say, is in the details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my case, I look to my American heritage and see refugees as far as the eye can see, coming from all manner of other places, but mainly from the Atlantic side, only to meet up with the peoples already here and to close circuits with Asia.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My dad was a city planner, with many branching specialties. Had he stayed in Portland, he&#39;d probably have ended up with Metro, as he had a more regional perspective. Reading over his shoulder, I encountered Doxiadis (Ekistics), Solari (Arcosanti),&amp;nbsp; and other luminaries. On my out, out of Princeton, I dove into the Buckminster Fuller corpus, fresh from reading Nietzsche under Walter Kaufmann, Wittgenstein under Richard Rorty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dad didn&#39;t stay in Portland though, as his dream since boyhood was to see the world and find a line of work, other than military (he decided around college), that would take him places (literally). He might&#39;ve been a travel agent if people decided they didn&#39;t need planners anymore. But it turned out they needed planners, so that&#39;s what he did, for several governments and ministries over the decades.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given all those data points, you could say it&#39;s predictable that I&#39;d take in the stadium shaped city meme and picture it as one of many dotting the globe, forming a high tech, well run &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/09/refugee-channel.html&quot;&gt;Refugee Cities Network&lt;/a&gt;. To an extent, it&#39;s a juxtaposition over the realities of today. Cities take in refugees a lot. Some cities were built pretty much entirely by immigrants, new to the New World.&amp;nbsp; Old Man River City, for Bucky, was for East Saint Louis. But he wasn&#39;t about to waste his career on it, meaning he knew he was working for future generations and needed to time capsule as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a philosophy track choo choo, I&#39;m allowed to chugga chugga through this science fiction vista, visiting these giant stadium cities of the mind, picturing the movies, the backdrops, the decades that might fly by as humans contemplated their various options. Decades have already flown by. The passage of time is not &quot;theoretical&quot;. &quot;Time is the only dimension&quot; says Synergetics, I forget where. We meet up with counterweights on that word (&quot;dimension&quot;) given Synergetics is richly textured with the &quot;4D&quot; meme. That&#39;s where my 4D Solutions is coming from, in my own mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also predictable was I&#39;d be enamored with One Laptop Per Child and the XO line of computers stemming from that project. The internet more generally was a big source of hope, especially with open source, and the police agreed with me. I&#39;m referring to that Hillsboro West Precinct story. The cops were tired of being used by schools to scare the kids about &quot;software piracy&quot; (music and games mostly) whereas here was this free and open world, with copyleft and unbridled sharing, that the schools were refusing to teach about, given corporate capture. West Precinct even set up a Linux school at the station, which me and another guy staffed that one summer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My activism in the area of education reform matched Guido&#39;s to some level (Python&#39;s inventor) and I was recruited to join that Mark Shuttleworth summit in Kensington, Greater London. Seymour Papert had sent his regrets, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2006/04/at-summit.html&quot;&gt;Alan Kay&lt;/a&gt;, a friend of Seymour&#39;s, made the meeting. We&#39;re talking about Logo and Smalltalk respectively. The Scheme community was represented.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How could South Africa leverage open source to better serve its schools? How might students of all ethnic backgrounds avail of these metaphysical (informational) goodies? Mark set up his Freedom Toasters, these kiosks that burned CDs on demand, complete with Linux, Python, and whatever else (music and games) of the copyleft variety.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having retired from applications development, mostly for nonprofits, including some big ones (especially if governments count), I&#39;m devoting a lot of hours to curriculum development and teaching gigs, while also doing various kinds of homework, availing myself of all that hypertext I used to pray for, in the lineage of Vannevar Bush (MEMEX) and Ted Nelson (Project Xanadu). The World Wide Web came along, thanks to Tim at CERN, and the global U has taken off. U as in University.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of hypertext, I&#39;m still focused on hypertoons, doing keyframing, imagining the inbetweening a lot of the time. My topics: the scenarios in Synergetics involving polyhedrons and their transformations, but not only those. I&#39;m seeing hypertoons, the concept, as informing my YouTube channel and how I weave YouTube scenarios together, about Couplers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/13QLfgKo6kyX0j0K0RJ7W0uisB0ZyeBiK-_qbzytipck/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;about BASKET&lt;/a&gt;, about Asylum City, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5902861133077318805'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5902861133077318805'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2025/01/asylum-city.html' title='Asylum City'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjqoBUhmxoyoXP0gc0EgwsIVsWzv3KP8zot_Pl87ISRLhOJRxum0GYz1K8osvizCwhxZBFIMgkjFT4ggKONkRMiCpOwWz7DqMWLNuNK6x33WXwd7R4YJBNVaSvyy5lJc_pLEW8aybFIT5KOyuWEq-QPxJIESiZRiQ-QMu94FxqesuAemAhidicI/s72-w400-h266-c/Screen%20Shot%202025-01-22%20at%209.06.59%20AM.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7524774358219383600</id><published>2025-01-22T06:55:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-01-22T06:55:27.794-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Pacwest</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEj2q5CBsjOxPg_0sLZoYpoUs1eBlZrxaEfP2O1o66yTHK1BNYyqz257HeMiklvv3gyXBpc0a9MKE5aMj2kfSbt39OqE7BDHJ-HCgFf_t1Fzbw3mvPA3Aj-5vgaeDjNQT7V9AtIHlckDJkinfyRvUQjKCffupV5UT9wX1NyDR0I9PTB1v6QcG21S/s1024/pacwest.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEj2q5CBsjOxPg_0sLZoYpoUs1eBlZrxaEfP2O1o66yTHK1BNYyqz257HeMiklvv3gyXBpc0a9MKE5aMj2kfSbt39OqE7BDHJ-HCgFf_t1Fzbw3mvPA3Aj-5vgaeDjNQT7V9AtIHlckDJkinfyRvUQjKCffupV5UT9wX1NyDR0I9PTB1v6QcG21S/w400-h400/pacwest.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7524774358219383600'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7524774358219383600'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2025/01/pacwest.html' title='Pacwest'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEj2q5CBsjOxPg_0sLZoYpoUs1eBlZrxaEfP2O1o66yTHK1BNYyqz257HeMiklvv3gyXBpc0a9MKE5aMj2kfSbt39OqE7BDHJ-HCgFf_t1Fzbw3mvPA3Aj-5vgaeDjNQT7V9AtIHlckDJkinfyRvUQjKCffupV5UT9wX1NyDR0I9PTB1v6QcG21S/s72-w400-h400-c/pacwest.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4864848016482763025</id><published>2025-01-16T06:26:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T11:28:23.696-08:00</updated><title type='text'>TikTok Goes the Clock</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/AUSJ3ZozLMQ?si=gPODkWZuAZIWuhND&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
I had my comment on this vid:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;blockquote&gt;I’m glad Linus went public with his sentiments. Not all Finns are sucking up to NATO so contrary to his statement, it’s far from obvious what his attitude would be based simply on nationality. Part of open source is getting these dirty secrets out in the open.&lt;/blockquote&gt;He&#39;d likely take exception to my phrasing, however &lt;a href=&quot;https://epjdatascience.springeropen.com/articles/10.1140/epjds/s13688-023-00441-2&quot;&gt;we do have Finns&lt;/a&gt; who take a skeptical attitude towards that state&#39;s recent suckering for specific genres of propaganda.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2025/01/oregon-fever.html&quot;&gt;As an Oregonian&lt;/a&gt;, I feel I should say this Linus guy isn&#39;t speaking for all of us, those of us proudly of &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/12/merry-xmas-2024.html&quot;&gt;Russian heritage included&lt;/a&gt; (I&#39;m &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2005/12/whats-urner.html&quot;&gt;more Swiss&lt;/a&gt; if we go by memes, &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/07/july-4-2015.html&quot;&gt;Swedish&lt;/a&gt; if by genes).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Many Russian Oregonians with sympathy for those caught up in WW2 era reflexing (i.e. knee-jerk dino thought patterns) were nevertheless hoping the software engineering world was on a plane above such politicized robotics.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;That was an element in the early idealism of free software more generally, if not of Linux in particular.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Linux certainly benefited from the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/08/digital-islam.html&quot;&gt;cyberpunk&lt;/a&gt;&quot; movement, bringing us PGP (Pretty Good Privacy) and the like. RSA is built in to the HTTPS protocol, since even before Elliptic Curve crypto.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But that was then and &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/12/zeitgeist-cartoons.html&quot;&gt;this is now&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Linux is by now the new Microsoft, the behemoth, more button-down and corporate than ever, and more at home simply running things, as the ubiquitous operating system, versus going back to playing the role of youthful idealistic outsider.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;My own preference is these sanctions (including the Magnitsky ones) be rescinded amidst a return to sanity, such that politicians stop doing harm to &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2022/07/antsy-engineers.html&quot;&gt;our shared infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;, around which they have very little management competence. Their schools are to blame.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Wait, wasn&#39;t this supposed to be a post &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2021/06/tiktok-meets-gst.html&quot;&gt;about TikTok&lt;/a&gt;?&amp;nbsp; As of this posting, a nationwide ban is about to occur.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Like I said, politicians are poking their knuckles into machinery they were not the ones to either plan or design. They bring their own set of unbalanced biases to the table. I don&#39;t wonder that they wipeout often, or that their plans frequently backfire.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4864848016482763025'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4864848016482763025'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2025/01/tiktoc-goes-clock.html' title='TikTok Goes the Clock'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/AUSJ3ZozLMQ/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6361381088298123204</id><published>2025-01-11T16:50:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-01-11T16:50:01.514-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Surely You&#39;re Joking Mr. Fuller</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157658107022875&quot; title=&quot;Two Ways of Looking&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Two Ways of Looking&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/5764/20454481123_47c4b56a3b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In culty backwaters, or call it a swamp, where the sausage gets made, we have our little niche controversies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps goaded by Braingate, the controversy swirling around the two elderly gangsta presidents (were their faculties still intact? Not really, at least in Biden&#39;s case), and the subsequent coverup, some latecomers to our party have decided to retell the story around Bucky.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to them, our guy was too Alzheimery by the 1970s to really know what he meant in Synergetics, which means the rest of us have been engaged in a coverup, trying to make Synergetics seem more coherent than it really is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This new &quot;Bucky was senile&quot; faction wants to purge S3 (an important constant) from the future curriculum, to spare people the need to understand what it&#39;s all about.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They say because Bucky was close to senile by the time those two volumes were published, he was able to confuse himself about this nonsensical number (~1.06066... or 2nd root of 9/8).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But was he really that confused? We&#39;re talking about two conceptions of unit volume and comparing them. Both the cube and the tetrahedron will need to be sized, when the other is unit. We&#39;ll need a conversion constant in other words, like a currency conversion constant, between Tetrahedron Dollars and Cube Dollars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a tetrahedron&#39;s six edges are all twice that of a cube, then that difference in volume, one of proportion between them, is S3. The difference is only about 6%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think what makes readers doubt the sense of Synergetics is that what it does to the cube seems too drastic: a cube of edges 1 no longer has a whole number volume of 1, but of 1.06066... &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That can&#39;t seem right to anyone already brainwashed to think &quot;right angles rule&quot; and &quot;cube is king&quot;, the predominant orthodoxy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Surely you&#39;re joking Mr. Fuller!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6361381088298123204'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6361381088298123204'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2025/01/surely-youre-joking-mr-fuller.html' title='Surely You&#39;re Joking Mr. Fuller'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6837710610519997498</id><published>2025-01-10T15:49:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-01-11T16:11:19.567-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Quick Response</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/6kgq-iXQDT4?si=HNIaWo9wUW8tqGM5&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
It&#39;s but minutes before class, me the teacher, however I thought I&#39;d update with this vlog from Natasha. You&#39;ll find others of hers scattered through my journals.&amp;nbsp;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;ve watched her editing skills evolve, in tandem with her many adventures.

My comment on this one (I don&#39;t usually comment):&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: georgia;&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;@kirbyurner
53 minutes ago&amp;nbsp;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;I’ve watched a lot of Lex interviews over the years. I know this one was a major achievement for him. Congrats Lex. Some DC think tanks have for many decades promoted Ukraine-involving designs to challenge Russian influence in the region. British too. I don’t believe Putin could have prompted this war simply as a self-serving popularity stunt. He needed to tap into the deeply engrained paranoia of the populace. His opponents made that easy. There’s lots of momentum behind these unfortunate developments going back to WW2.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6837710610519997498'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6837710610519997498'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2025/01/quick-response.html' title='Quick Response'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/6kgq-iXQDT4/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7820649868475127884</id><published>2025-01-06T06:27:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-01-06T06:37:00.008-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Back to Work</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjUthfdnwgDaTvP5cSPa1k4Pb5k9ZWf-4OiY0nMb00XZuOKA5vLXdK4_ztH2nHkM-nwXz5Llzar4DKGLCRnv9NYjsiPINzioWcBNwUt74Y-h6Yqr8cmGJ7rOwiXwQAEcAjW4ujR32WY1HFFBco9JAeuh_0UXNVlV0YvH8-SA1gK4Yohyphenhyphenz3HGZa1/s2078/IMG_0605.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1912&quot; data-original-width=&quot;2078&quot; height=&quot;368&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjUthfdnwgDaTvP5cSPa1k4Pb5k9ZWf-4OiY0nMb00XZuOKA5vLXdK4_ztH2nHkM-nwXz5Llzar4DKGLCRnv9NYjsiPINzioWcBNwUt74Y-h6Yqr8cmGJ7rOwiXwQAEcAjW4ujR32WY1HFFBco9JAeuh_0UXNVlV0YvH8-SA1gK4Yohyphenhyphenz3HGZa1/w400-h368/IMG_0605.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve enjoyed the break in the workflow and didn’t travel anywhere further than Eugene, and that for a day trip only, at the beginning. Today the break is over and we pick up where we left off. Not wanting to get out of shape in the interim, as the instructor, I did some workouts with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/4dsolutions/School_of_Tomorrow/blob/master/Tabulations.ipynb&quot;&gt;tabulations and multi-indexing&lt;/a&gt; in my School of Tomorrow PWS (personal workspace in GST).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the comics and in myths, we encounter those endowed with superpowers, by dint of ingenuity or by inheritance, and the literature gets into lots of detail regarding these awesome capabilities. Some become invisible, whereas others fly. Many have multiple abilities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But let’s bring it back to the mundane. Just being able to read and write is something of a miracle, as is the ability to drive safely. A lot of our skills are collective, but get rusty if we don’t rehearse them. More people are shopping in pajamas, losing the ability of keep up a full spectrum wardrobe. A lot of powers are mental. Simply pondering and coming up with results of contemplation is as close to supernatural or paranormal as it gets, without being either, because these are such normal, everyday, taken for granted abilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another highlight: visiting faculty from out of town dropped by for an evening. They introduced me to the Sri Lankan place on Belmont. After which we elected not to see &lt;i&gt;Nosferatu&lt;/i&gt; at Bagdad, choosing to yak some more &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/02/network-nations.html&quot;&gt;in NPU mode&lt;/a&gt; (comparing notes). I caught Nosferatu later, assuming Lexi and I will be able to find another fun movie, perhaps the new fictional rendering of Bob Dylan.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7820649868475127884'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7820649868475127884'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2025/01/back-to-work.html' title='Back to Work'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjUthfdnwgDaTvP5cSPa1k4Pb5k9ZWf-4OiY0nMb00XZuOKA5vLXdK4_ztH2nHkM-nwXz5Llzar4DKGLCRnv9NYjsiPINzioWcBNwUt74Y-h6Yqr8cmGJ7rOwiXwQAEcAjW4ujR32WY1HFFBco9JAeuh_0UXNVlV0YvH8-SA1gK4Yohyphenhyphenz3HGZa1/s72-w400-h368-c/IMG_0605.jpeg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1038161655690271186</id><published>2024-12-31T15:07:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-01-01T10:20:07.914-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Happy New Year from Crow Town</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjFxRXSx7-gwJDksWJAp7XWZkOJyNIfNSVubYXUi1mfNrRR2heQkrEFfI4FPH5_e9Lh3ucui1SyERWZ4SaaVsjIYdnMfbg5d_AB-SfLxwYrvT4CvHkv5By5XrDUogcUkxf8RrclFX5bjW_XoJjcg3rZMiQ8BUkpVOagCpnt5-ekhZaFai-pxTMu/s1605/IMG_0563.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1605&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1590&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjFxRXSx7-gwJDksWJAp7XWZkOJyNIfNSVubYXUi1mfNrRR2heQkrEFfI4FPH5_e9Lh3ucui1SyERWZ4SaaVsjIYdnMfbg5d_AB-SfLxwYrvT4CvHkv5By5XrDUogcUkxf8RrclFX5bjW_XoJjcg3rZMiQ8BUkpVOagCpnt5-ekhZaFai-pxTMu/w396-h400/IMG_0563.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;396&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1038161655690271186'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1038161655690271186'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/12/happy-new-year-from-crow-town.html' title='Happy New Year from Crow Town'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjFxRXSx7-gwJDksWJAp7XWZkOJyNIfNSVubYXUi1mfNrRR2heQkrEFfI4FPH5_e9Lh3ucui1SyERWZ4SaaVsjIYdnMfbg5d_AB-SfLxwYrvT4CvHkv5By5XrDUogcUkxf8RrclFX5bjW_XoJjcg3rZMiQ8BUkpVOagCpnt5-ekhZaFai-pxTMu/s72-w396-h400-c/IMG_0563.jpeg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4040010384054714359</id><published>2024-12-27T17:45:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-27T21:51:34.616-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Data Science for All</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/eTDH7m4vEiM?si=FjryVYhDwcm1U6tJ&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was listening to one of Starmer&#39;s StatsQuests again, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/YtebGVx-Fxw?si=khdH8y3Z29eFS7KA&quot;&gt;this one on Entropy&lt;/a&gt;, and it really hit me why I&#39;m glad for data science having taken off, not leaving statistics in the dust so much as giving it a much needed makeover. That was my old lingo in the 1990s: math was overdue for a makeover, by which of course I included the need to phase in &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2017/03/pedagogical-artifacts.html&quot;&gt;more Synergetics&lt;/a&gt;. That much hasn&#39;t changed. &quot;More than Cosmetic&quot; was a slogan, to counter the stereotypes &quot;makeover&quot; comes with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my high school, statistics was, like trig, one of those semester courses one could take towards filling a math credits requirement, even while opting to get off the main track: pre-calc + calc. The latter was considered the more stringently &quot;college prep&quot; path, whereas if one already knew the goal was a business degree and not to shoot for a &quot;next Einstein&quot; award, then why not take statistics, a kind of knucklehead math that&#39;d be useful in Economics, a knucklehead science?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was happy to take stats and trig, but I took pre-calc + calc also, and was good in them. I placed straight into honors calc at Princeton, with Dr. Thurston as my prof. Then I went on to study linear programming (featuring its simplex algorithm) with one of the leaders in the field, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.informs.org/Announcements/Harold-W.-Kuhn&quot;&gt;Dr. Harold Kuhn&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;d circle back to linear algebra much later, when getting into the geometry of rotating polyhedra (we use matrices for that, &lt;a href=&quot;http://4dsolutions.net/ocn/oopalgebra.html&quot;&gt;if not quaternions&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My point here is I no longer have that old prep school mindset. I&#39;m happy to see calc (Newtonian delta calculus) postponed until college, and have it feature inside a major, such as physics, or why not more stats?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Slicing and dicing into infinitesimals is at the limit of discrete math (where we meet the so-called manifold), which math (discrete) became the focus of my lobbying at the state level. Let kids take a discrete maths approach all the way through high school if they like, with less focus on calc (by definition) and increasing focus on number and group theory, say, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/12/another-math-summit.html&quot;&gt;with computer programming&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data science is providing the glue though, in bringing it back to everyday coping, like people do, with words like expectation and surprise, entropy and probability. Likelihood. These are the everyday words of common experience, and to see them treated mathematically, with notation, with symbols, is a kind of music to my ears in the sense of providing segues to what many find a turn-off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey, I hadn&#39;t realized that Edward Teller and his wife, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Martians-Science-Physicists-Changed-Twentieth/dp/0195365569&quot;&gt;more Martians&lt;/a&gt; (Hungarian heritage), had contributed to Markov Chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) taking off, as later abetted (translated to stats language) by Hastings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kirbyurner.medium.com/somewhere-in-one-of-our-bootcamp-slide-decks-we-define-a-data-scientist-as-someone-who-knows-more-344e74bf0d2a?sk=8303332378cee747848e9d51764b5fa7&quot;&gt;Data Science&lt;/a&gt; connects us to Information Theory, signal versus noise, entropy and cryptography, but by anchoring some of our everyday bread and butter notions as agentic humans in Universe. Bayesian thinking connects to machine learning, which is also the kind we do when push comes to shove.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4040010384054714359'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4040010384054714359'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/12/data-science-for-all.html' title='Data Science for All'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/eTDH7m4vEiM/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-312970776252633406</id><published>2024-12-25T10:59:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-25T11:00:27.008-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Merry Xmas 2024</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgJbLg54DuUgyeeAC6_kQoCSzi18qVNbsKNPKOQ_-B8V8LdOnZVW4YP0Zh-gG1HfcWLApmp7Lzi53ODjzp5ub92JA8NrdFvJpdnt-PIttpUW0s9pubo1gFOGPlYbfRk8WRsZQlhcecRFwSgflbFt9mCZHcmkkXA95gdx62RgUQlUu0_djEPoLMA/s1024/merry_xmas.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgJbLg54DuUgyeeAC6_kQoCSzi18qVNbsKNPKOQ_-B8V8LdOnZVW4YP0Zh-gG1HfcWLApmp7Lzi53ODjzp5ub92JA8NrdFvJpdnt-PIttpUW0s9pubo1gFOGPlYbfRk8WRsZQlhcecRFwSgflbFt9mCZHcmkkXA95gdx62RgUQlUu0_djEPoLMA/w400-h400/merry_xmas.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiFvMlGzRMMRa_yD137Nkn7JEq94A_4MX7XfmyPCEL6tUbFOvfhSEgAGysoQin_vTQioXIhuNWRvdO5ije2ayaM0a9clwiNvRjnG9nkLTSeTfzhWjTRzG28yKCV_q82AWZcvLHydkpcbAWArvVh-W_RYGZBN7_OmaH4xd-di2rDVOrYJ15-zsFC/s1024/homeland_security.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiFvMlGzRMMRa_yD137Nkn7JEq94A_4MX7XfmyPCEL6tUbFOvfhSEgAGysoQin_vTQioXIhuNWRvdO5ije2ayaM0a9clwiNvRjnG9nkLTSeTfzhWjTRzG28yKCV_q82AWZcvLHydkpcbAWArvVh-W_RYGZBN7_OmaH4xd-di2rDVOrYJ15-zsFC/w400-h400/homeland_security.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjQqEbziroV1VZ8nynSsCXZvk7s62NtLu016dSD1rx9bwJ5tTHyFehyphenhyphenfvK_XLF_VJLz03IE00tuirKmbg6cdqzQ3uYY5fomRsEujkmT59P5REif7-2gCVYVpnLOi7gZ-XDKKvQ1eavk0gnCNS2CMR9LyP1y-vEuyob9cibhtI5kepGhX_e-v2WR/s1024/cascadia2024.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjQqEbziroV1VZ8nynSsCXZvk7s62NtLu016dSD1rx9bwJ5tTHyFehyphenhyphenfvK_XLF_VJLz03IE00tuirKmbg6cdqzQ3uYY5fomRsEujkmT59P5REif7-2gCVYVpnLOi7gZ-XDKKvQ1eavk0gnCNS2CMR9LyP1y-vEuyob9cibhtI5kepGhX_e-v2WR/w400-h400/cascadia2024.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: xx-small;&quot;&gt;by DAF w/ AI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/312970776252633406'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/312970776252633406'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/12/merry-xmas-2024.html' title='Merry Xmas 2024'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgJbLg54DuUgyeeAC6_kQoCSzi18qVNbsKNPKOQ_-B8V8LdOnZVW4YP0Zh-gG1HfcWLApmp7Lzi53ODjzp5ub92JA8NrdFvJpdnt-PIttpUW0s9pubo1gFOGPlYbfRk8WRsZQlhcecRFwSgflbFt9mCZHcmkkXA95gdx62RgUQlUu0_djEPoLMA/s72-w400-h400-c/merry_xmas.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6739701308263995878</id><published>2024-12-19T13:25:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2025-01-01T10:19:10.993-08:00</updated><title type='text'>A Synopsis</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Europe was headed in the direction of relative utopia with &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2022/03/world-game-planning.html&quot;&gt;Nord Stream 2&lt;/a&gt; about to come online, but Social Darwinists in The District wouldn&#39;t have it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if the French working class were actually able to stabilize around that much vacation time, with Club Med level leisure class facilities, and what if socialized health care actually worked over the long haul?&amp;nbsp; The American public would become dissatisfied with their lot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Condoleezza Rice could see the writing on the wall. The rapacious license to exploit, called the American Way, would fall into disfavor and the accompanying grotesque lifestyles might become a thing of the past.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So Europe&#39;s ruling cast quislings consented to have&amp;nbsp;their own workers&#39; jugular sliced so they could more effectively concentrate power in the hands of the few with less of a threat to their &quot;system&quot;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Military Socialism (e.g. NATO) would continue to rule, with its veneer of Cowardly Capitalism.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Their consent would be in exchange for making Russia weak again, so that their future energy imports might be controlled by Wall Streeters and post WW2 financial institutions created by the military-entertainment complex.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Europe would share in the glory of the American Empire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fuller predicted in the 1980s in &lt;i&gt;Critical Path&lt;/i&gt;, that LAWCAP&#39;s greed would eventually lead it to attack the Russians.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the honesty of his financially and engineeringly informed poetics helped open a window of optimism that such a scenario might be avoided, and giving the USSR a chance to reform.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, in the aftermath of &lt;i&gt;Grunch of Giants&lt;/i&gt; we got the message: LAWCAP would not morph into something spanking new without a fight.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fuller&#39;s writings would be relegated to the &quot;subversive&quot; pile (his reputation would be smeared) and good doobie apprentice capitalists would be insulated from such futurism going forward. That was the plan anyway. I&#39;m not suggesting it was ever realistic.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6739701308263995878'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6739701308263995878'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/12/a-synopsis.html' title='A Synopsis'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3550378940714051817</id><published>2024-12-17T11:23:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-26T09:25:40.719-08:00</updated><title type='text'>The Business Plot</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54163860067/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;OMR&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;OMR&quot; height=&quot;438&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54163860067_81a797e476.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it’s not a no brainer, it’s almost that, to recognize Major General Smedley “Fighting Quaker” Butler for his bravery not only in the company of his men, but later in life, as more of a loner, when he published &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/war_is_a_racket_1903_librivox/warisaracket_01_butler_128kb.mp3&quot;&gt;War is a Racket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; and had to expose the creeping private sector, anxious to keep devouring the public space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What public space? In some ideologies there’s no such thing. The world inherently belongs to this or that people, championed by this or that cult, and if not the whole world, then at least a part of it, with the intention to expand. That’s to claim the land on behalf of a people as private to them, which becomes the rallying cry of citizens once they have it. But do they have it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We know about public spaces and public services, which happen when private interests collaborate to achieve something no one could afford to undertake solo. That would be the space program for example, in its more writ large aspects, and certainly that would be war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However these days the wars are privatized, not declared, and run irrespective of any meaningful oversight. Weapons and funding is easy to come by. All one needs are ideologues with a willingness to die for some cause. If not that, at least they can eat, presuming the militia is able to support itself logistically, which is not always the case.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do we have any public space left in education? I would say some. Without authorization from some private company, or better, with the authorization of only my own company, I have the right and ability to purchase public facing screen estate. Prospectors are able to scroll through my material.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Smedley Butler was approached with a scheme to finally privatize the remaining public institutions that had survived thanks to FDR. The ruling elite wanted their country back. Smedley would have nothing of it and blew the whistle. After all he’d done to be loyal, he wasn’t about to go down in history as a traitor. Probably the business perps who tried to persuade him said they were doing it for the peoples’ benefit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward and the push to privatize would reach an apex under president Reagan, coincident with a similar high water mark under Margaret Thatcher in England. The private sector would attempt to establish control without its takeover destroying the underlying legitimacy of their platform. One might call this Business Plot 2.0 and without a Smedley in the picture, it mostly worked, except that people were sensitive to the hollowness and lack of statesmen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward some more and we have a eugenics-minded Social Darwinist private sector acting like we’re in the early 1900s again. The public sector is all but gone and a private mercenary army supports the highest bidders with WMDs. The USA to some extent still fights back, in part by keeping Smedley Butler relevant to the narrative.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3550378940714051817'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3550378940714051817'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/12/the-business-plot.html' title='The Business Plot'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4200169124987327811</id><published>2024-12-16T05:54:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-19T05:28:12.048-08:00</updated><title type='text'>More Curriculum Notes</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54204134943/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;TetraBook in Balls Format&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;TetraBook in Balls Format&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54204134943_55d0fab737.jpg&quot; width=&quot;445&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;:: photo by DBK ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have an army of geeks with M4 Mac Minis this Xmas, extrapolating from YouTubes, and a goodly number of them are running Blender. Some would like to break into Python teaching. I have some recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re a new kid on the block and want a ground floor entrance to an express freight elevator to the top, figuratively speaking, you might want to visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://kirbyurner.substack.com/p/a-portal-for-silicon-foresters&quot;&gt;my latest Lesson Plan&lt;/a&gt; featuring S3, a number I was &lt;a href=&quot;https://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2024/11/verboten-math.html&quot;&gt;promoting to Epistemologists&lt;/a&gt; recently, at least to their admins.&amp;nbsp; S3 = 1.06066...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Polyhedrons may be related to one another versus studied only as individuals. For example, how the cube (3) and its dual (4) both nest, as short and long diagonals respectively, within the twelve diamond faces of the rhombic dodecahedron (6), should not come across as ungraspable mumbo-jumbo known only to esoteric clerics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/48904575438/in/photolist-q8vyLo-GNshah-QrfReH-231UJ5S-2csiBa8-2hvwJt9-2ifuQn8-2msgpP9-2mVNrUK-2mZv5LL-2nahrpx-2narEqo-2nas2eN-2ngptRX-2nsq3WJ-2pwyGXW-2qhdxrK-fwsARu-fwsE89-fwsLq7&quot; title=&quot;whole_number_volumes&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;whole_number_volumes&quot; height=&quot;444&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/48904575438_a350c6b183.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;V + F == E + 2&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re talking common knowledge on the level of ABCs. The dual of the cube being the octahedron.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However just reading such stuff isn&#39;t to get the visualization necessarily and for that we could use Blender. I date myself with &lt;a href=&quot;http://4dsolutions.net/ocn/numeracy0.html&quot;&gt;my POV-Ray based approach&lt;/a&gt;, but the final rendering step isn&#39;t as critical as the guts, which is where S3 comes in, in our computations of volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/49962483976/in/photolist-2j81MPw-2jDrsZn-2jDsfpX-2qqtfLs-9M9MUk&quot; title=&quot;Dabbling in Blender&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Dabbling in Blender&quot; height=&quot;304&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/49962483976_a99348b4b3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;1, 12, 42, 92, 162...&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Piero della Francesca at least, in the 1400s, we&#39;ve had a way to derive a tetrahedron&#39;s volume from its edges. Other such algorithms, starting from the six edges, have come along since.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These formulae need to make a come back, as short computer programs, as we present an alternative to the XYZ approach vs-a-vs the tetrahedron&#39;s volume in our new paradigm, the one with the unit edge D, the unit volume tetrahedron.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We may use the &quot;from edges&quot; approach instead, with S3 as a modifier, and/or use Gerald de Jong&#39;s method, which had no XYZ version in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/39391693474/in/photolist-q8vyLo-GNshah-QrfReH-231UJ5S-2csiBa8-2hvwJt9-2ifuQn8-2msgpP9-2mVNrUK-2mZv5LL-2nahrpx-2narEqo-2nas2eN-2ngptRX-2nsq3WJ-2pwyGXW-2qhdxrK-fwsARu-fwsE89-fwsLq7&quot; title=&quot;Computer Volume&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Computer Volume&quot; height=&quot;463&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/4672/39391693474_c6c54f3d22.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have two principal targets after establishing the new volumes table: great circle networks and sphere packing. Of course the two interrelate and of course both have multiplicitous applications within geography, computer games, and crystallography, even psychology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We spin our cuboctahedron and icosahedron, for example, to net great circle networks of 25 and 31 great circle networks respectively, and we juxtapose them.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sphere packing starts with our D-edged tetrahedron itself (D = ball diameter). The CCP, with D-edged tetrahedral and octahedral voids, is our Matrix home base.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How we got here though, was over the S3 bridge, and in Silicon Forest Martian Math, in the context of Sapiens coming to better understand an ET intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/51804664503/in/photolist-q8vyLo-GNshah-QrfReH-231UJ5S-2csiBa8-2hvwJt9-8tm3iL-2ifuQn8-8xp1nN-2msgpP9-2mVNrUK-2mZv5LL-2nahrpx-2narEqo-2nas2eN-2ngptRX-2nsq3WJ-2pwyGXW-2qhdxrK-bH5gvP-c5RPLS-fwdt8t-fwsARu-fwsE89-fwsLq7-5QyKe7-5QyKsS-6n24Ja-7cXk2G-7jZLhp-8batec-8pNQou-8ryyt2-8ryEix-8ryECF-8teDJ4-8teEm2-8thDyL-8thDHW-8thE4q&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia Volumes Table&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wikipedia Volumes Table&quot; height=&quot;308&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/51804664503_63e3407cba.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mac Mini army has the compute to bring this literature into the foreground, perhaps in the form of anime.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sapiens and ETs meet on some Mesa and learn to collaborate on hydropower projects. The relationship is non-adversarial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lesson here is for those succumbing to phobias.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Humans have a track record of working together, and the global grids are what we&#39;re working on now, much to the chagrin of the phobia-ridden politicians who can&#39;t envision a world they don&#39;t control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2023/03/version-control.html&quot;&gt;attack on Nord Stream&lt;/a&gt; was an expression of the fearful reflex-conditioning of the more robotic lower half of the Bell Curve (less mindful), pampered juveniles groomed to feel entitled to management positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54201030604/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;TetraBook Toy&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;TetraBook Toy&quot; height=&quot;252&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54201030604_cf75ced6da.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4200169124987327811'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4200169124987327811'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/12/more-curriculum-notes.html' title='More Curriculum Notes'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-372485187005331661</id><published>2024-12-12T16:46:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-12T16:46:16.011-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Tooting My Own Horn</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54200807933/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Tooting Horn&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tooting Horn&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54200807933_6fe15cbf97.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I corrected myself later in a follow-up message. Margaret Fuller died at sea, with her new baby and Roman soldier husband (he&#39;d fought for Roman independence against the Vatican), so clearly Fuller was not a physical descendent. She was his great aunt. Intellectually speaking, however, he was shaped by her writings and she was among the three women to whom he dedicated his &lt;i&gt;Grunch of Giants&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;  
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54200716258/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Floppy Cube Types&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Floppy Cube Types&quot; height=&quot;486&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54200716258_e363bb7068.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54200777263/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Philosophy Background&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Philosophy Background&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54200777263_3b1fef209a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54200740463/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Leverage…&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Leverage…&quot; height=&quot;344&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54200740463_cf3b165d1a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;  
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/372485187005331661'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/372485187005331661'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/12/tooting-my-own-horn.html' title='Tooting My Own Horn'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-760048938172743430</id><published>2024-12-03T17:26:00.010-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-03T17:29:24.294-08:00</updated><title type='text'>T4P Caravan</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgrvktzycyRz31UbVuXOsb_WaObdXjG8YOd2NvVQplCLwgrueJcZtHsfED-Ovu19NvMzwM1FU4rVWRUAu3amq5uvrHHv5gd02KKu7cFYteDfyGEKLS38antIcKKy_6mxVTJlQoIpYO2oBpC0_52jFmwhavIrjX5BWtIV4xXmf6F3MwMEmxe79i8/s1024/truckers_for_peace_6.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgrvktzycyRz31UbVuXOsb_WaObdXjG8YOd2NvVQplCLwgrueJcZtHsfED-Ovu19NvMzwM1FU4rVWRUAu3amq5uvrHHv5gd02KKu7cFYteDfyGEKLS38antIcKKy_6mxVTJlQoIpYO2oBpC0_52jFmwhavIrjX5BWtIV4xXmf6F3MwMEmxe79i8/w400-h400/truckers_for_peace_6.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgcuAemmFtVghR15n0bDJBBYN1jC26ISKUohfQp6Ft9EyA-XOQmE1qeNHrt0wJqrIKFT21GMzn4SEb3wTfRWBoYB8S_fZ1u2v1R8N3v3UMPeBQk5PKzU1pzMnAqXg_XSpH-cG8uYM6Wiej9zXJqnUn4JO1jK2H1SP8u5C3jAXM9v4z5b-nXRVNX/s1024/truckers_for_peace_3.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgcuAemmFtVghR15n0bDJBBYN1jC26ISKUohfQp6Ft9EyA-XOQmE1qeNHrt0wJqrIKFT21GMzn4SEb3wTfRWBoYB8S_fZ1u2v1R8N3v3UMPeBQk5PKzU1pzMnAqXg_XSpH-cG8uYM6Wiej9zXJqnUn4JO1jK2H1SP8u5C3jAXM9v4z5b-nXRVNX/w400-h400/truckers_for_peace_3.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhbcYr82qmX-aQAYJAbGV2zeUSfaHVuam8SyiS285fqoHfJrK-lS7KhKftRySqcSn1gkJRLoYqyDfX0qyuaEqUpqGCZHk-YCjvOlkjQiSmGilNWxqE3eyUB7Pma28sI3L5duSYReTGZXWFz5NDmrO_jdBdb_YRySS7CuI3iG4QRuupPVkdoZJob/s1024/truckers_for_peace_4.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhbcYr82qmX-aQAYJAbGV2zeUSfaHVuam8SyiS285fqoHfJrK-lS7KhKftRySqcSn1gkJRLoYqyDfX0qyuaEqUpqGCZHk-YCjvOlkjQiSmGilNWxqE3eyUB7Pma28sI3L5duSYReTGZXWFz5NDmrO_jdBdb_YRySS7CuI3iG4QRuupPVkdoZJob/w400-h400/truckers_for_peace_4.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/search?q=t4p&quot;&gt;search: t4p&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;conjured from Hilbert Space&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/760048938172743430'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/760048938172743430'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/12/t4p-caravan.html' title='T4P Caravan'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgrvktzycyRz31UbVuXOsb_WaObdXjG8YOd2NvVQplCLwgrueJcZtHsfED-Ovu19NvMzwM1FU4rVWRUAu3amq5uvrHHv5gd02KKu7cFYteDfyGEKLS38antIcKKy_6mxVTJlQoIpYO2oBpC0_52jFmwhavIrjX5BWtIV4xXmf6F3MwMEmxe79i8/s72-w400-h400-c/truckers_for_peace_6.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-9174002984970862523</id><published>2024-12-01T12:12:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-01T12:12:20.886-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Python Teaching Ideas</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/9sMawhe6glU?si=meiKF4iGLv6ydO7J&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9174002984970862523'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/9174002984970862523'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/12/python-teaching-ideas.html' title='Python Teaching Ideas'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/9sMawhe6glU/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8131662962333775467</id><published>2024-11-25T06:34:00.005-08:00</published><updated>2024-11-27T13:47:34.311-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Friendly Art</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi42uke2s3sycwvBsRYR-CnDgXhA8fxdzu7e8pIzh7WUussuyJ0hJV9EKqeXz8TEwnpNdWsashj-OBI5AA5KnIJRpba4SIFxQxpEEJFWlUUtIg5rZBJ5p4g7UBnnfdOp8lHZIUbMFndNoHRwtTIhdFjIhlOxEDlvGPrHSXrthxTbzqnbTDm3g04/s1024/black_hat.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi42uke2s3sycwvBsRYR-CnDgXhA8fxdzu7e8pIzh7WUussuyJ0hJV9EKqeXz8TEwnpNdWsashj-OBI5AA5KnIJRpba4SIFxQxpEEJFWlUUtIg5rZBJ5p4g7UBnnfdOp8lHZIUbMFndNoHRwtTIhdFjIhlOxEDlvGPrHSXrthxTbzqnbTDm3g04/s320/black_hat.png&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiJdKlbICOAAB8Fkb_H2l4yeKl86tvV0faYSk2Vewg-ZXo0VIdRTdtOAVSAG9bVkVvl1tpxpX-UFnsd2CwatJlpGS2lNqR7DzifL3C4K9Pzoeq1N44uVTpZX_9XpwI_1mHrsqxlNi5qHW_ysXkCTBYc6wIulPaCBmvT3Z-AHKOm_UhhyphenhyphenedzlUtR/s1024/burning_bush.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiJdKlbICOAAB8Fkb_H2l4yeKl86tvV0faYSk2Vewg-ZXo0VIdRTdtOAVSAG9bVkVvl1tpxpX-UFnsd2CwatJlpGS2lNqR7DzifL3C4K9Pzoeq1N44uVTpZX_9XpwI_1mHrsqxlNi5qHW_ysXkCTBYc6wIulPaCBmvT3Z-AHKOm_UhhyphenhyphenedzlUtR/s320/burning_bush.png&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjXl8fqV8_y33BORiDqsfg5rnHt8iYbOEIweF3yiVqqcRzFNZyLc6-pIbgutyOwAtodhauleRf1NL6gmimOoqIqNw9jOuctIhteKxnhh9srIj3BeHyA9GFaFRTZ2m96rnLf7mtEe502lZiyMu8E63n1rhI2DEK-vakLAJVbLKR41E77HIzkxqYt/s1024/mason_maslow.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjXl8fqV8_y33BORiDqsfg5rnHt8iYbOEIweF3yiVqqcRzFNZyLc6-pIbgutyOwAtodhauleRf1NL6gmimOoqIqNw9jOuctIhteKxnhh9srIj3BeHyA9GFaFRTZ2m96rnLf7mtEe502lZiyMu8E63n1rhI2DEK-vakLAJVbLKR41E77HIzkxqYt/s320/mason_maslow.png&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgrt-4IZjypCFzdwZ03DbzXtQCJo99tpstsl6VtGQQJzqOOfl2QYxAqvqi3QzNLqfMaHLGC0LiZggIKDvCMgSQn_TqJC5n4qtZT6iDhwZLPSNMToiFQpaxU7tQtHHO5_FpY62RcSyFqQe5Brloah-xkraNwPoatApsgdNygH0icBClrX7YVRbPw/s1024/maslow_masonic.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgrt-4IZjypCFzdwZ03DbzXtQCJo99tpstsl6VtGQQJzqOOfl2QYxAqvqi3QzNLqfMaHLGC0LiZggIKDvCMgSQn_TqJC5n4qtZT6iDhwZLPSNMToiFQpaxU7tQtHHO5_FpY62RcSyFqQe5Brloah-xkraNwPoatApsgdNygH0icBClrX7YVRbPw/s320/maslow_masonic.png&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;prompted from Hilbert Space, praise the King&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8131662962333775467'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8131662962333775467'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/11/friendly-art.html' title='Friendly Art'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi42uke2s3sycwvBsRYR-CnDgXhA8fxdzu7e8pIzh7WUussuyJ0hJV9EKqeXz8TEwnpNdWsashj-OBI5AA5KnIJRpba4SIFxQxpEEJFWlUUtIg5rZBJ5p4g7UBnnfdOp8lHZIUbMFndNoHRwtTIhdFjIhlOxEDlvGPrHSXrthxTbzqnbTDm3g04/s72-c/black_hat.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1282399331646573393</id><published>2024-11-20T12:47:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2024-11-27T13:52:44.825-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Church and State</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54154430878/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;USA OS Iconography&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;USA OS Iconography&quot; height=&quot;495&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54154430878_8a9cdaa6c8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;:: six fingers jammin Sam ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have seen in the movies where certain underground cults have gone ga ga for an iconography, such as that of a nation. In torch-lit ceremonies, whatever logo gets used, some motivational symbol, such as the Olympic Games deploys, or Nike. Not that either of these are “cults” in popular parlance. The spin on key terms here is colored by its ballpark.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My own bias is to think of n8v tribes that went bigly for the Stars and Stripes as a motif in their beadwork. I also think of Grateful Dead, the band, on the road, and its merging with Uncle Sam imagery. That’s a goldmine we’ve been mining to this day, exploring what the new AI dream machines might do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From a more legal code angle, the picture is not one of a government foisting itself upon others, so much as a subculture partaking of the same mythic sources. The same George Washington under the same elm tree waves the new flag, but some of the troops complain about the miniature Union Jack in the upper left, and Betsy Ross makes sure it’s replaced. That’s straight outta &lt;i&gt;Critical Path&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;(St. Martins Press) check archive dot org.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So say a subculture, like the Masons, is into a lot of the same pyramid eye stuff as the Union of States, the Federation. Good icons are hard to find, let alone great ones. Some of these cults predate the USA obviously. So it’s not so much like government encroaching on the church as the church asserting its intellectual property rights in the realm of the Zeitgeist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The story need not be adversarial at all, as in the case of George Washington, who had no problem with Masonic rituals. The Quakers might be cast as synergyzing with n8vs per the early days in Sylvania (William Penn’s), comparing notes on governance and community building, only to bring their newly won insights to their new circuit designs, the ones that started up in Philadelphia but eventually moved to that former swamp called DC (District of Columbia).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I live in “DC West” meaning the Columbia River has its watershed, a district. I’m in that district, near the confluence of said great river and one of its tribs, known as the Willamette.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So lets say here in DC West, a tribe of Quakers get very into Uncle Sam iconography, along with some brewpub already promoting the Grateful Dead. Would George Washington seem out of place? Certainly the Masons have been embraced (by the McMenamins brewpubs, talking about Oregon and Washington). I’d say “Deja vu”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/515466638/in/photolist-2yq37Z-2yutzw-531ujy-531uqd-GTbP9h-5qMUa5-5w7Pmh-5xiocW-5y2HWL-5DAYvD-5DFgpG-6qSmPp-6uVDKs-6xA8jQ-7h9iyC-2jY3ytN-2ms9iKH-MxUih-My38n-My3ak-My3ax-2pvZRNV-2q8yKms-a1caHB-aCZS1a-MxUdy-MxUeb-MxUfC-MxUgf-MxUgQ&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot; title=&quot;At the End of the Universe...&quot; true=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;At the End of the Universe...&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/195/515466638_b55faf2954.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1282399331646573393'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1282399331646573393'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/11/church-and-state.html' title='Church and State'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>