<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211</id><updated>2025-02-27T06:25:58.543-08:00</updated><category term="clojure python REPL ide"/><title type='text'>BizMo Diaries</title><subtitle type='html'>On the road with Global Data</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=26'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=1&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=51&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1905</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>26</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3201479557390473078</id><published>2024-11-18T05:43:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2024-11-19T22:14:02.580-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Headless Nations</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh8XQSMhm25Kh0efS5XZEbaLhCaPNIesEXxiMISZjoOxoVXYY7otDp64_yukGRXssUPKjgCzyaDKqtdryjvZuf6STZHpeMLWbVMlE_AaN-oxxig4xPMMr-lNdi15OV3oS1uAozSaHxeTHEt3fqXd-0ltLyOtEw-4881Q5SuT4oTZBfUYasPGXaX/s1607/IMG_0358.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1607&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1281&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh8XQSMhm25Kh0efS5XZEbaLhCaPNIesEXxiMISZjoOxoVXYY7otDp64_yukGRXssUPKjgCzyaDKqtdryjvZuf6STZHpeMLWbVMlE_AaN-oxxig4xPMMr-lNdi15OV3oS1uAozSaHxeTHEt3fqXd-0ltLyOtEw-4881Q5SuT4oTZBfUYasPGXaX/w319-h400/IMG_0358.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;319&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Excuse me? Who are you calling “headless” in this picture&lt;/i&gt;?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today’s YouTube thumbnails are saying “Joe Biden” and or “the US” is giving the green light to this or that, through the &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt;. Clearly someone is feeling authorized to make stuff happen, as the Davos crowd seems to be surging in a particular direction.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet public attention has been elsewhere, possibly making this feel like a window of opportunity to these political actors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How all this lashing out is supposed to advance US interests is hard to decipher. One presumes some last grasper is hoping to express manhood or otherwise address a perceived failing. Everyone knows there’s no “commander in chief” at the helm and that we’re running on reflexes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re back to the usual fun game of headless chicken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How is the world to deal with zombie juggernauts?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My Silicon Forest is far away from The District and has its own circuitry. We do microchip fab a lot, with Intel here, in Hanoi, in New Mexico. We’re not “Atlanticists” here on the Pacific Rim, somewhat by definition.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We haven’t green lighted anything from here.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Empire attacked us with storm troopers ala &lt;i&gt;Star Wars&lt;/i&gt; not that long ago. We continue to flaunt federal restrictions on controlled substances and sometimes break the human trafficking laws, by providing asylum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, there’s no danger of me saying “we” when it comes to whoever is doing the signaling with those green lights. We’ve known since Reagan that the deep state is all about working around Congress and carrying out business plots regardless of whatever “oversight” the so-called government attempts to exercise. Evidence: the Nord Stream extrajudicial special military operation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;People still talk about the Constitution a lot and brand themselves as defenders thereof, but I don’t see where Congress gets to seriously debate anything anymore. We see orchestrated symbolic votes but not actual discussion. The whole debate process has been privatized.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The executive branch simply executes, disconnected from any legislative controls. And yet they claim we have a system governed by laws, not egos. In these circumstances, some see it as their duty to disobey.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3201479557390473078'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3201479557390473078'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/11/headless-nations.html' title='Headless Nations'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh8XQSMhm25Kh0efS5XZEbaLhCaPNIesEXxiMISZjoOxoVXYY7otDp64_yukGRXssUPKjgCzyaDKqtdryjvZuf6STZHpeMLWbVMlE_AaN-oxxig4xPMMr-lNdi15OV3oS1uAozSaHxeTHEt3fqXd-0ltLyOtEw-4881Q5SuT4oTZBfUYasPGXaX/s72-w319-h400-c/IMG_0358.jpeg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4803688410419864232</id><published>2024-11-10T14:09:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2024-11-15T05:36:16.279-08:00</updated><title type='text'>The Science of Infinity</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54131096335/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Philo Book&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Philo Book&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54131096335_b0fc7287e9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;395&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend is leaving Portland, and is letting me get some mileage out of his book collection until he arranges for them to join a library. He’ll likely outlive me so he imagines this will be his karma. I’ve already been enjoying earlier portions of his collection, including the extensive set of titles about or by Ludwig Wittgenstein, a corpus we’ve both studied.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I spent much of yesterday extracting two bookcases that had been squeezed between the wall and Carol’s bed, to give them more breathing room in what used to be the back office. Now I have the 2nd floor office to claim if H&amp;amp;R Block suggests filling out such a schedule: &amp;nbsp;a home office may not double as sleeping quarters, a tough rule for folks in those tiny apartments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Lots of these books are about maths, Such as &lt;i&gt;Philosophical Introduction to Set Theory&lt;/i&gt; by Stephen Pollard, the 2015 Dover edition of the original 1990 Notre Dame Press copy. Back in the day, I’d debate math ideas with other math heads, such as Dr. Wayne Bishop at California University. The National Council of Teachers of Mathematics eradicated this archive however. The Math Forum, as we called it, started at Swarthmore, then moved to Drexel.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The book starts out drawing attention to the proliferation of mutually unintelligible subspecialties within maths, and the dangers this poses to a unificationist agenda. Pollard argues that only Set Theory has what it takes to keep Humpty Dumpty recognizably an egg (a whole), whereas Category Theory, an upstart grand unifier, hasn&#39;t yet proved itself more effective, in part because, as a relative new kid on the block, it&#39;s less established. But let&#39;s remember these words were penned in the 1980s sometime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A core idea in Cantorian set theory is this idea that you cannot pair natural numbers with the reals because too many reals fall through the cracks as it were, per the &quot;diagonal argument&quot; and so on (pages 8-9).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The targeted reals are allowed to have infinitely many digits after the decimal point whereas that way is barred to the left side: natural numbers with infinity digits are not actually natural numbers, by definition.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suppose one assigns a random number to any real number produced. Does the pairing process ever fail in that case? A rule to not break is that of uniqueness: one does not get to assign the same natural number to more than one real, for an operation to count as perpetual pairing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once a natural number is spoken for, it retires.&amp;nbsp; So what’s the problem?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is the pool of eligible brides thereby diminished such that I’ll run out of Ns for my grooms in R? If I need more digits (given how many Rs you give me) I’ll add them. I’ll never repeat. Pairing works no?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reason you can’t pair N and R simply by removing the decimal point is precisely because members of N are not allowed to have infinitely many digits. We wouldn’t be able to sequence them all if they did, even if subsets could still be ordered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even if N were to include infinity-digit members, like the reals do, we could still use them for counting sheep, as the finite digit Ns would still be in the N set as well. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But then allowing &lt;a href=&quot;https://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2016/04/nonsense-numbers.html&quot;&gt;infinity-digit Ns&lt;/a&gt; into contemporary maths would turn it into a wasteland (teenage or otherwise) set theoretically speaking, so lets us just keep things the way they are shall we?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The computer science mindset has made long digit sequences into strings, meaning we don&#39;t suffer headaches or vertigo in thinking &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/2quin6k&quot;&gt;how divergent&lt;/a&gt; (vs convergent) a number like ...3804951234... (random forever in both directions) must be. Digits are digits, with or without a decimal point. What impossibility are we talking about?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Random infinite strings of digits needn&#39;t &quot;stand for&quot; anything, e.g. we&#39;re not forced into picturing astronomically huge collections corresponding to the output of these noisy, chaotic, digit generators. Whereas these same random digits to the right of a decimal connotes ever more microscopic fine tuning and precision (convergence), which seems a lot more &quot;believable&quot; (the mental picture is more obvious).&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4803688410419864232'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4803688410419864232'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/11/the-science-of-infinity.html' title='The Science of Infinity'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1370015985542815197</id><published>2024-11-02T12:23:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-11T04:57:00.996-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Raining Pumpkins</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEitwZObgFonzsguvCTb8THPusb1IQgTQHtwvqVZOewwbY_BK5s7B_7ZbyKiEP59_4zTYMuMW_jUHzhQw9b-pVTJyunpD2Ygy95gA5Ms2kzbWzfOWGCnJh5QO53SiFhbhwfp77F_boiJJSsLfyY98DOWivRG4hIBgVxQeEYVwHPeZVZOEOiGEQP4/s611/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-29%20at%208.39.51%20AM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;523&quot; data-original-width=&quot;611&quot; height=&quot;343&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEitwZObgFonzsguvCTb8THPusb1IQgTQHtwvqVZOewwbY_BK5s7B_7ZbyKiEP59_4zTYMuMW_jUHzhQw9b-pVTJyunpD2Ygy95gA5Ms2kzbWzfOWGCnJh5QO53SiFhbhwfp77F_boiJJSsLfyY98DOWivRG4hIBgVxQeEYVwHPeZVZOEOiGEQP4/w400-h343/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-29%20at%208.39.51%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In line with my keeping my curriculum &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/10/keeping-it-quirky.html&quot;&gt;quirky and idiosyncratic&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(weird), words used by detractors as well as friends, I&#39;m allowing more autobiography, which is to personalize, to &quot;icosahedronize&quot; (add to dictionary). There&#39;s nothing amiss in being special case unique and indeed any other way is missing something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Allowing more autobiography&quot; where? In this specific case I was thinking of my Github repo, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/4dsolutions/School_of_Tomorrow/blob/master/School_of_Tomorrow.ipynb&quot;&gt;School of Tomorrow&lt;/a&gt;, where I engage students with a variety of topics, from Python to Occupy Portland (&lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/11/occupy-university.html&quot;&gt;OPDX&lt;/a&gt;) to our Mazeway of Polyhedrons. I just coined that here: &quot;mazeway&quot; thumbs up, sounds theme parky.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I link &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2022/11/prospectus.html&quot;&gt;Occupy to Dr. Graeber&lt;/a&gt; and the N8V critique of Anglo-Euro-speak: that it&#39;s way too unimaginative when it comes to (a) pictureing lifestyles and (b) assuming one size (&quot;way of life&quot;) must eventually fit all. Is the Earth a backdrop for some epic Capitalism versus Socialism extravaganza? Not exclusively. Live that melodrama if you like but don&#39;t pretend the rest of us don&#39;t have other core concerns. Like, we don&#39;t see the world in those terms, so sorry,&amp;nbsp; did you think we should?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We might wanna bring back Ancient Egypt with contemporary characteristics. In Egypt. Who is &quot;we&quot;? Not me specifically as my Sands of Time clock is running low and we haven&#39;t even done &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2018/01/curating-credits.html&quot;&gt;a &lt;i&gt;WestWorld&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; yet, except on TV.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also link OPDX and the Elk Statue (undergoing renovation) specifically to the Bonus Army demonstration between the wars. Penny pinchers in Congress wanted the budget for pet projects whereas no one saw a way to deal with bitter veterans. Smedley &quot;fighting Quaker&quot; Butler was one of them, looking back on a life as a war racketeer, and realizing,&amp;nbsp; as Eisenhower warned us later, that war is an end in itself, not a merely a means, to supply chainers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Smedley was in DC to see the Bonus Army, camped out in Hoovervilles, getting smacked down by General MacArthur, of whom he took a dim view. The war mad Manifest Destiny types ruined the American Dream for most of us, while trashing the smashing their way through the Philippines, Indochina, Central America, Eastern Europe, the Middle East.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pressure to spray out weapons is intense, with shareholder-backed pensions depending on it. Some boomer doomers fear dying off in droves if they&#39;re any less grim with their Genocide R Us grim reaper policies. Not that they won&#39;t die off in droves anyway, as it&#39;s getting to be That Time for them, given the Bell Curve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the Bell Curve, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nbviewer.org/github/4dsolutions/clarusway_data_analysis/blob/main/basic_python/sandbox_week_03.ipynb&quot;&gt;last night I demonstrated&lt;/a&gt; a basic Galton Board to my data science students, along with a simple Python program for simulating balls falling left or right, through rows of pegs. Most random falls will end up in the middle, but randomness allows for outliers and the pseudorandom integer generator I was using is certified to be that normal kind of random.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjCMhnhzvGkgi3LQFWhpcTaM-OqRdkInelxOHII-i4HM3rB0H9HxM1Zp9Z_WoV9BYsshmEgfmYQ6v5qy-HAKkTkO4mPe6VvpbnOEPFC1BifyPRk19jem87eg1OyQWO_tyamOhrdsag7CvhOnF2r11HXMypwjcOJq0yMIjLUwl0emLIlO4CQgXf5/s578/Screen%20Shot%202024-11-02%20at%2012.21.17%20PM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;450&quot; data-original-width=&quot;578&quot; height=&quot;311&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjCMhnhzvGkgi3LQFWhpcTaM-OqRdkInelxOHII-i4HM3rB0H9HxM1Zp9Z_WoV9BYsshmEgfmYQ6v5qy-HAKkTkO4mPe6VvpbnOEPFC1BifyPRk19jem87eg1OyQWO_tyamOhrdsag7CvhOnF2r11HXMypwjcOJq0yMIjLUwl0emLIlO4CQgXf5/w400-h311/Screen%20Shot%202024-11-02%20at%2012.21.17%20PM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgs_-a262bEayXsL1XtuNeAUVk3VDm_oc3fCUMxhyNHLej14QUWT8uEyiwlKJDjR0ZjqYmkJDZyxFJ_RZ0IeP-OWhg4jJ7VYj4RTu0I99FNJ2ywbWZahItzjNNvu3usNxK72dA8x7LPCHt4lbfpV-Ppx4pKzMLOTQ8FIo9T2ytmVKVKnwz0drMH/s578/Screen%20Shot%202024-11-02%20at%2012.21.47%20PM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;450&quot; data-original-width=&quot;578&quot; height=&quot;311&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgs_-a262bEayXsL1XtuNeAUVk3VDm_oc3fCUMxhyNHLej14QUWT8uEyiwlKJDjR0ZjqYmkJDZyxFJ_RZ0IeP-OWhg4jJ7VYj4RTu0I99FNJ2ywbWZahItzjNNvu3usNxK72dA8x7LPCHt4lbfpV-Ppx4pKzMLOTQ8FIo9T2ytmVKVKnwz0drMH/w400-h311/Screen%20Shot%202024-11-02%20at%2012.21.47%20PM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Bell Curve Dynamics&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
So what&#39;s up with the bacteriophage? That&#39;s our icosahedral and cuboctahedral numbers &lt;a href=&quot;https://oeis.org/A005901&quot;&gt;entry point&lt;/a&gt;, talking nucleocapsid and Jitterbug, as well as our &lt;i&gt;War of the Worlds&lt;/i&gt; and Wells meets Welles, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/nUdghSMTXsU&quot;&gt;YouTube link&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/04/catacombs.html&quot;&gt;the Codacombs&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1370015985542815197'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1370015985542815197'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/11/raining-pumpkins.html' title='Raining Pumpkins'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEitwZObgFonzsguvCTb8THPusb1IQgTQHtwvqVZOewwbY_BK5s7B_7ZbyKiEP59_4zTYMuMW_jUHzhQw9b-pVTJyunpD2Ygy95gA5Ms2kzbWzfOWGCnJh5QO53SiFhbhwfp77F_boiJJSsLfyY98DOWivRG4hIBgVxQeEYVwHPeZVZOEOiGEQP4/s72-w400-h343-c/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-29%20at%208.39.51%20AM.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-129020681170995698</id><published>2024-10-30T12:30:00.005-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-30T12:33:20.591-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Keeping it Quirky</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEie3nDoflWAEL1WbloopcZjnfL9zOLwfUr9OSGsZ_kG2_nMYx0CopXdgw4vAYSYtQnwEpdvJVtXpVpmrR-jlaYTUvSt7_mnsQd6s9S6G3wY8WqbToHVfyN3sKg311fGmke35yzxrFzARXxMyALOw8j0XLAV5j8cEaxiduNNAvfNLhhhzPvxbL_1/s1024/art_deco_1.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEie3nDoflWAEL1WbloopcZjnfL9zOLwfUr9OSGsZ_kG2_nMYx0CopXdgw4vAYSYtQnwEpdvJVtXpVpmrR-jlaYTUvSt7_mnsQd6s9S6G3wY8WqbToHVfyN3sKg311fGmke35yzxrFzARXxMyALOw8j0XLAV5j8cEaxiduNNAvfNLhhhzPvxbL_1/w400-h400/art_deco_1.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What&#39;s becoming more clear to me is I&#39;m not on the hook to author some veridical textbook standard that nails it. Nails what?&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of nails, cosmetics, Max Factor, I am welcoming the view that polymathy, a commitment to comprehensivity, does not entail a commitment to omniscience. The &quot;know it all&quot; as a personality type is already off-putting vs-a-vs my type, whatever that is (I&#39;ve not done Myers-Briggs, or if I have, for joining with temp agencies, they didn&#39;t tell me my sign).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Insofar as School of Tomorrow is concerned, this means I&#39;m free to continue exploring off the ends of the roads I&#39;ve already achieved. That&#39;ll lead to new connections, such as I discovered yesterday, H.G. Wells and Orson Welles in the same room with a journalist, on radio methinks.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They discussed the similarity in their names, as I&#39;ve pointed out, and Wells asks Orson about the upcoming movie (Orson: thanks for the plug, citizen Kane).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wells has an especially kind spin on the Halloween Panic, when Orson persuaded some listeners there&#39;d been an attack of the UAPs. Wells: oh we knew from across the pond how you Americans like to dress up in a bed sheet on Halloween and pretend you&#39;ve seen a ghost and start screaming, hah hah. Orson: you&#39;re very kind -- he was up to his neck in hot water after that stunt -- which he knew better than to ever live down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I free to stay with Mark Fisher and his nostalgia for pre-Thatcher English brutalism in architecture, echoing Sovietism, because it reflected a for-the-ages commitment to public works. So Tucker was impressed by those subway stations, why fight it?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Privatization has come at a cost, and it makes sense for a Portland-based open source freelancer type guy to say that, if not for Pearson to make a textbook out of it. Not that I thoroughly understand the British Ingsoc. What&#39;s the BBC again? A private company you say? Not really?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m able to stay with David Graeber and fellow travelers, who to my mind were pointing out that it&#39;s not a grand struggle between two or three mega-designs, where we all end up on the same page at the end of the day. Why? Why even make that a goal. I&#39;m fine that you and your campuses look and feel different and feature different course offerings. That&#39;s how I succeed in recruiting, by emphasizing how we&#39;re different.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think of all the board games there are. I&#39;ve been to houses where every shelf was pile high with game boxes, because that&#39;s what this household chose to specialize in and there we certainly enough offerings out there, to fill a house worth. No problemo.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that&#39;s how to think of human communities and their internal arrangements: highly variegated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graeber likes to recount how one tribe he came across was all hippie dippie loosey goosey communal anarchist in the summer, but went for hierarchical fascism with lockstep minions in the winter (I paraphrase). Phase changes: a single substance will have gas, liquid and solid phases, quite different. Now multiply by a lot of substances and divide by 137 (just kidding, I mean 42).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/129020681170995698'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/129020681170995698'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/10/keeping-it-quirky.html' title='Keeping it Quirky'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEie3nDoflWAEL1WbloopcZjnfL9zOLwfUr9OSGsZ_kG2_nMYx0CopXdgw4vAYSYtQnwEpdvJVtXpVpmrR-jlaYTUvSt7_mnsQd6s9S6G3wY8WqbToHVfyN3sKg311fGmke35yzxrFzARXxMyALOw8j0XLAV5j8cEaxiduNNAvfNLhhhzPvxbL_1/s72-w400-h400-c/art_deco_1.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5192030193711139148</id><published>2024-10-25T14:51:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-25T15:13:18.138-07:00</updated><title type='text'>A BFI Event</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhJkqexve0yDQCvrJ2vUvim7ZEj9uvlW8Z2o6c2Nc9a-9jCrUtFyW9fx9MeVGHbw07H7U4WVLwp4eLfiYOdWxdg76UxwALgmlFyiNhfWKaDxwphOlHPb4a4SECYFO5QGk46n1smMfY4iNAxxZzu7hCdRmW5TTtLNGKj5pTWJLeka8JLwCohC3nC/s1144/princeton_philosophy.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1144&quot; data-original-width=&quot;912&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhJkqexve0yDQCvrJ2vUvim7ZEj9uvlW8Z2o6c2Nc9a-9jCrUtFyW9fx9MeVGHbw07H7U4WVLwp4eLfiYOdWxdg76UxwALgmlFyiNhfWKaDxwphOlHPb4a4SECYFO5QGk46n1smMfY4iNAxxZzu7hCdRmW5TTtLNGKj5pTWJLeka8JLwCohC3nC/w319-h400/princeton_philosophy.png&quot; width=&quot;319&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;A PATH-STEM Meetup&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;(after the C.P. Snow Bridge)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today was a special event in the BFI (bfi.org) network, as we gathered around the figurative campfire to both hear and tell stories. D.W. Jacobs is a playwright but also director, which means he&#39;s by definition a skilled acting coach, as what a director does, more than run cameras or wrangle lighting, is give the cast guidance with regard to their roles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doug structured our Zoom meetup like a workshop in that everyone was given an opportunity to construct a story, like a fairytale, meaning following a formula but not too mechanically. Keep it from the heart, tell an authentic story of what brings you to this campfire, here in the shadow of one Buckminster Fuller.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A story has a beginning, middle and end.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s an event, a skeletal plot.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The story itself has mnemonic value in that it self coheres by dint of its own protein-folding chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That in itself was a great beginning, but Doug backed it up by (a) enforcing a time limit, albeit in a friendly manner and by (b) offering criticisms, as one would after a performance, by an actor on stage, trying out for (auditioning) or maybe learning the nuances of (already cast) an important role.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I notice you used a whole minute introducing and explaining why you were telling the story, when a context had already been handed to you&quot; (I&#39;m paraphrasing). &quot;That&#39;s a great billboard or advertisement for your being about Bucky, but what&#39;s the micro event you hope we will remember?&quot; and &quot;Those doing this later are going to benefit from the feedback I&#39;m giving the first few&quot;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Towards the end, he&#39;d stopped coaching. He figured we&#39;d gotten the exercise by then and everyone said their piece. I was glad to catch Chad&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autobiography lends itself to scene construction and plot design so I&#39;d say everyone followed the instruction insofar as they recounted a first person narrative i.e. with one&#39;s self the protagonist. I think we all did that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My story featured Fred Craden, my middle school sociology teacher (amazing, right?) at the Overseas School of Rome, and how he&#39;d had my dad address our class during &quot;what&#39;s your parent&#39;s job day?&quot; and Dr. Urner, the city planner, unrolled some impressive maps of some city (probably in Libya but I don&#39;t remember that detail).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dad directed our attention to a color code, a shade of green, appearing all around this city map, although not right in the downtown or CBD (not in this one) and asked if we could decipher the color&#39;s meaning. &quot;Parks?&quot; Nope. &quot;Zoos?&quot; Nope. &quot;Golf courses?&quot; Nope. Turns out they were cemeteries. Forehead slap. Of course, those are ubiquitous.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, the story goes, Fred Craden and fellow teachers all came back from some off-camera event, and were jabbering excitedly in some cultish jargon, about how squares were unstable and tetrahedra were where it&#39;s at.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I only figured out later what had happened: they&#39;d been to some Bucky talk obviously. I still haven&#39;t figured out which one exactly. Late 1960s or very early 1970s -- by 1972 we&#39;d left Rome behind and were in the Philippines, where Bucky would also appear (I&#39;d only find out later).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My other story (these were short): when Doug and I first met, and he was doing the play in Portland, in 2008, the Scrooge play (&lt;i&gt;Christmas Story&lt;/i&gt;) had to closed, for election day. They wouldn&#39;t sell nearly enough tickets to make it profitable, with everyone home glued to the TV, watching Obama&#39;s triumph.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Doug&#39;s play was in &quot;the crypt&quot; in the Portland Armory (by now remodeled into theaters), and the company hatched a brilliant plan: entice engineers and their families from &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2007/08/ieee-picnic.html&quot;&gt;the IEEE mailing list&lt;/a&gt;, give them a special free lecture, before the play, by Kirby Urner. Just in general be solicitous and kowtowing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It worked: the place was packed, and during half times we could double check how the election was going. A fun evening. I enjoyed the play too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OK, then Doug did something brilliant (again). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He asked us to speak up if anything in another&#39;s story had in turn sparked our storytelling impulses. Like when that one guy talked about Barbara Marx Hubbard as inspirational, I was taken back, in my thinking, to dad&#39;s volunteering for her campaign. I got to join him, in her house, and hear her speak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She was running for Vice President, as a free standing candidate available to whatever president would have her. I think she was hoping John Glenn given they were both spacey space buffs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In going around the figurative Zoom room, it become clear that our stories were branching and interweaving and in no time, it seems, would encompass the world. A collective &quot;scenarios basket&quot; would be hugely encompassing, in any case, not that we had time to weave it then. Doug still had his main presentation to give.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another of the guys present (Bonnie was there too -- not all the guys were guys) was in fact a descendent of a Great Pirate, literally. Bucky&#39;s prose poetry was redolent with pirate imagery, in connection with his maritime-anchored historical narrative, stretching back to Venetian times and before.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I mention Venetian in part to justify including my AI graphic above, from my Project Renaissance collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54092978981/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;D.W. Jacobs Presents…&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;D.W. Jacobs Presents…&quot; height=&quot;341&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54092978981_534940b47f_w.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Urner Connects&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5192030193711139148'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5192030193711139148'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/10/a-bfi-event.html' title='A BFI Event'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhJkqexve0yDQCvrJ2vUvim7ZEj9uvlW8Z2o6c2Nc9a-9jCrUtFyW9fx9MeVGHbw07H7U4WVLwp4eLfiYOdWxdg76UxwALgmlFyiNhfWKaDxwphOlHPb4a4SECYFO5QGk46n1smMfY4iNAxxZzu7hCdRmW5TTtLNGKj5pTWJLeka8JLwCohC3nC/s72-w319-h400-c/princeton_philosophy.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1258843671468815010</id><published>2024-10-20T17:07:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-25T10:42:18.026-07:00</updated><title type='text'>The Apprentice (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/Y3jeNId-b48?si=Wklz27bzWYS1YA98&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just to set the stage, I took the bus (one transfer) on a beautiful fall day, to a 1 pm matinee at Eastport Plaza, out on SE 82nd, a major thoroughfare and home to big Asian supermarkets. Such a store was my first destination: Hong Phat, a remodeled WalMart, to eat some no-frills salad rolls and a little sushi, while chatting with my distant daughter on the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I texted some other friends on the way, as bus riding is conducive to phone chatting. My peer group is quite anti Trump and they worried this was maybe a propaganda movie.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what if it was, right? I&#39;m a big consumer of propaganda, a primary or raw material for the kind of anthropology I&#39;m into. I study cults, left and right. Plus I&#39;m in one, one could say, producing propaganda of my own (or call it advertising).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But it wasn&#39;t really a propaganda film, or at least not of the shallow type, all hype and puffery. I already knew from the NPR interview with the director that I caught in the car, coming back from the Seattle area recently, that this would be an empathetic view without constituting an endorsement. I would assess the film will have approximately zero impact on the final outcome of the 2024 presidential race. Most people will catch it later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr. D. (PhD) joined me, arriving by EV, just as the previews got going. The smallish theater had only two others besides ourselves. This 1 pm matinee was the latest showtime available, on a Sunday anyway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These were lounge style seats. I don&#39;t usually make it to this particular theater and didn&#39;t figure out how to operate the recliner controls until after the movie was over, although the seat did seem to kick back a bit on its own (I must&#39;ve rubbed up against the button).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, those details out of the way, what &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; this?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A fictionalized not-documentary that reminds us of the timeline. When Donald was doing this, Nixon was doing that. When DT was onto building Trump Tower, we were up to Mayor Koch already.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mayor Koch... so I would&#39;ve been in Jersey City, close to penniless, a Catholic school teacher, but writing to Koch anyway (not that often), about various city plans I had: train to plane; &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2014/11/wanderers-2014114.html&quot;&gt;high def illuminated billboard&lt;/a&gt; near Journal Square; IMAX in &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2009/05/flash-back.html&quot;&gt;the Stanley&lt;/a&gt;; something about navy submarines (for tourists).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But I had no Roy Cohn to take me under his wing. I had Ray and Bonnie Simon, who took me under theirs, and I learned a lot from them, not to mention a small income for taking care of their baby daughter. Ray and Bonnie both had work in the Big Apple. We&#39;d sit around their living room table after hours, getting deep in to philosophy and pop culture.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ray and Bonnie were both closer to the show biz world and that whole chapter in my life was about tuning in show business (its centrality).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, after Trump Tower, came the Atlantic City chapter, and then Trump buys Mar-a-lago, and the movie draws to a close. He&#39;s still married to Ivana. His mentor Roy has died. &lt;i&gt;The Art of the Deal&lt;/i&gt;, the book, is just getting underway.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No &lt;i&gt;Miss Universe&lt;/i&gt;, no &lt;i&gt;Apprentice&lt;/i&gt; on TV, no running for president, except for foreshadowing. It&#39;s all about his family matrix (mom and dad, brother Frank) right when he&#39;s becoming a &quot;self made&quot; man. It&#39;s a coming of age story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found the Roy Cohn character captivating, a star performance, which in the movie, Trump did too (he found Roy fascinating).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So as the director says: it&#39;s a movie with empathy for its protagonist. The camera rarely gets far from the Donald. We&#39;re always finding stuff out when he does. The camera never drifts off to follow others, making us privy to what they&#39;re saying about Trump behind his back. We simply don&#39;t go behind Trump&#39;s back. He&#39;s the center around which the world turns, an entirely valid point of view obviously, for either a novel or a fictional film.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trump character doesn&#39;t seem that much like him at first, but it&#39;s a good performance and he seems to gradually adopt the mannerisms, gestures and phraseology we&#39;ve come to expect. I don&#39;t have any strong issue with anyone&#39;s acting. Or the directing. The script paints in broad, bold brush strokes, serving a didactic function, educating its audience about the thermodynamics of it all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Roy is tough, a &quot;killer&quot; (he doesn&#39;t shoot anyone), some say vicious, but the movie wants to humanize him as well, and in my book succeeds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He considers himself a true American patriot, and regards his winning the death penalty for the Rosenbergs one of his greatest achievements. He admires Trump because he&#39;s a privileged golden boy aristocrat who has chosen an uphill battle. Roy perceives that Trump needs a true bully in his corner, to fight the bullies. His friendship is authentic, but becomes strained in the end.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whatever the real Roy was like, this one was believable, and consistently rendered. Bravo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last time I was at this theater, I forget which movie, I emerged to find then president Trump had approved the martyring of Iranian general Qasem Soleimani, thereby adding to the lawless mayhem that is otherwise described as the rules based order.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Friends (Quakers) don&#39;t celebrate outward violence, nor do I recall a lot of flag-waving at the time. More just worry and concern. Portland is not as into Murder Inc. as some cities I could name. Trump had by then become another swamp creature, a kind of political dinosaur, a living fossil. We still have quite a few of those around, still thrashing about, making waves while going under.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh6A_22rbBhV8Fv3nhxvjcIudHShxkV7MeqZWmciKyKF42sqVE2zwNMIn0pu-HiWreIuqxtKuwE9eAoWesJLlRlsjO-Vkt9grJXrDeFT1qMI6hf137tWhyaj6RwjCfWVy3GKIDGSGRO8DptD0tWakZNhHo7JWIcLHsvfTKrvQe88d5QbGkqkR5_/s1536/jp_needs_prez.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1536&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1536&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh6A_22rbBhV8Fv3nhxvjcIudHShxkV7MeqZWmciKyKF42sqVE2zwNMIn0pu-HiWreIuqxtKuwE9eAoWesJLlRlsjO-Vkt9grJXrDeFT1qMI6hf137tWhyaj6RwjCfWVy3GKIDGSGRO8DptD0tWakZNhHo7JWIcLHsvfTKrvQe88d5QbGkqkR5_/s320/jp_needs_prez.png&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1258843671468815010'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1258843671468815010'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/10/the-apprentice-movie-review.html' title='The Apprentice (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/Y3jeNId-b48/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1154353646703203628</id><published>2024-10-17T10:06:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-17T10:07:41.531-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Trucking Algorithms</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhGRmj7ccK5sue_ESDd4Aqloy55cSZFuEqhdD-VLAOQwQb6iISBK2sMWdbS2c1CxUgxpzo2Vu-9noRyWUw4Ym_ebO-ojSWNlwVnhZlVvdHKUABskR8BfUVo2BbqswQKNPSuh1aJAVoiLtUvZCmAEyWbmy2wG8Y37G-xVFrR4fUPq8nUf0ba1YhI/s1194/Screen%20Shot%202024-09-22%20at%208.39.33%20AM.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;900&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1194&quot; height=&quot;301&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhGRmj7ccK5sue_ESDd4Aqloy55cSZFuEqhdD-VLAOQwQb6iISBK2sMWdbS2c1CxUgxpzo2Vu-9noRyWUw4Ym_ebO-ojSWNlwVnhZlVvdHKUABskR8BfUVo2BbqswQKNPSuh1aJAVoiLtUvZCmAEyWbmy2wG8Y37G-xVFrR4fUPq8nUf0ba1YhI/w400-h301/Screen%20Shot%202024-09-22%20at%208.39.33%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;I don&#39;t think long haul truckers have much to fear from AI in the short term, in terms of job loss. However that doesn&#39;t mean that lifestyle is immune from overhaul in other dimensions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;EV trucking might be a thing (Tesla testing) but probably only if cabs decouple from payloads more, i.e. it&#39;s super easy to drop a trailer and head to charging, while another cab takes the payload onward with very little downtime.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Cabs queue and charge at a slower rate but there&#39;s always enough of them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Trucking companies might choose a &quot;driver stays with the payload&quot; policy and have the driver hop from cab to cab, or the driver could stay with the cab and get hitched to different trailers going from A to B all day, not much rhyme or reason from the driver viewpoint but expertly routed by Mother (the company computers).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1154353646703203628'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1154353646703203628'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/10/trucking-algorithms.html' title='Trucking Algorithms'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhGRmj7ccK5sue_ESDd4Aqloy55cSZFuEqhdD-VLAOQwQb6iISBK2sMWdbS2c1CxUgxpzo2Vu-9noRyWUw4Ym_ebO-ojSWNlwVnhZlVvdHKUABskR8BfUVo2BbqswQKNPSuh1aJAVoiLtUvZCmAEyWbmy2wG8Y37G-xVFrR4fUPq8nUf0ba1YhI/s72-w400-h301-c/Screen%20Shot%202024-09-22%20at%208.39.33%20AM.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4727808501521005042</id><published>2024-10-15T21:48:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-16T04:02:26.722-07:00</updated><title type='text'>DS US</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54045808780/in/album-72177720296706479&quot; title=&quot;From Intro to Python slides&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;From Intro to Python slides&quot; height=&quot;329&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54045808780_649f84fb85.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;US track, Data Science&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tonight I was engaged in torch passing. No, not PyTorch (you know of it?) but moving in that direction. I told my students they were on like the Trans-Siberian railroad, from London to Beijing. I would be their tour guide from London to Berlin. Then I’d hand them off to a next instructor. They’re wending their way towards ML (Machine Learning) the domain of PyTorch, although from the slides I see it’s TensorFlow they get into, which makes sense too. Keras…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The part of the ML pipeline I have them look at is analogous to what I did in outcomes research, when David Lansky and company (MDRC to be precise) were harvesting data from heart procedures, diagnostic and interventional, and getting it statistically analyzed. David and Gary knew statistics. I was the computer guy who knew how to harvest on the front end, design a GUI for data entry and cleaning, while feeding a growing repository on the backend, what would, over time, become Big Data — provided PATS could handle the load.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harvesting, merging and cleaning data: that was my bread and butter in that this hospital system became my biggest client. That I wasn’t an employee was to their advantage but also put limits on how long this particular configuration could last. Microsoft would end up pulling the plug on Visual FoxPro in 2015. Bigger players would be moving in, replacing my applications. We managed to launch a few careers. Outcomes research took off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Merging is often overlooked but that’s where pandas in a Jupyter Notebook may prove its metal, pure gold for some company. Do you know about pandas? That’s like Excel in terms of providing tabular frameworks. Tabular data has to be as old as data gets. Rows and columns. Arrays. In the Python world, we have a stack for that, a suite of 3rd party packages. Download and import and you’re in business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’d get data from here and there (scannable forms played a role — forms I got to design) and it all needed to get neatly shuffled and interpolated, and placed in relational tables. You only want a specific patient detailed once, but then with multiple episodes, admits and discharges, with procedures in between. That’s one to many.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every patient has their own arteries (one to many), but they each have the same coronary suite, so many to one. Which of these arteries have become occluded if any? What cath and what stent were used, or was this a graft, a bypass?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had CLAIR for the cath labs and CORIS for the ORs. The doctor practice supporting my efforts, in addition to the hospital system itself, thought my applications were prototypical enough to be worth sharing with bigger companies. &quot;See this stuff Kirby is doing? That&#39;s what we need. Why not learn something?&quot; They learned, to a degree anyway. I was in a position to assess.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But I wasn’t using pandas or Jupyter Notebooks or any of that stuff back then. We were a Microsoft shop and I was using FoxPro for the intermediary holding tanks and the GUI.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’d learned to parse through cath lab text files coming from time-stamped chronologs made by Quintons, the cath lab machines, where techs chronicled all the details of a procedure. Patient goes under, doctor arrives… procedure over, another success (the success rate was high). Parse the logs, populate tables, let a data pro audit and revise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another workflow that gets overlooked, in addition to merging, is anonymizing. Creating these amazing data sets is only allowed if there’s HIPAA compliance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were eager to amass heart procedure and long term outcomes data and to pool it with other hospitals, but not in such a way as to violate confidentiality in medical record keeping.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My institution (a client) was pretty meticulous along those lines and a big part of my job was to help my coworkers keep all the sensitive identifying fields behind a security wall within the hospital. We suffered no data breaches on my watch, that I know of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I make it sound like I was doing all this by myself, however the final repository of all this data was PATS, owned by a different company. Once the data my systems harvested was merged and cleaned through my FoxPro GUIs, it got batch imported into PATS, by people trained in that work especially, along with their other tasks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I was telling students tonight over Zoom, I had a long career before Python popped up on my radar and even then, it wasn’t as a replacement for the FoxPro applications development toolset. All seems more clear with hindsight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What drew me to Python was computer graphics and my curriculum development work, more an outgrowth of the McGraw-Hill chapter, which had come before my moving back to Portland and diving in with the FoxPro.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graphics and animation. VPython. Hypertoons.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But then I could backfill by leveraging the data science work just described, and become a guru of data pipelining the way that’s taught now. FoxPro was very SQL-savvy. Learning the Python DB API was not that big a deal. I could use SQL for my Polyhedrons.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4727808501521005042'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4727808501521005042'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/10/ds-us.html' title='DS US'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2950208107124962966</id><published>2024-10-14T15:14:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-14T15:14:57.483-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Sculpting with Marble</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiLbln0LquEBPARhqkQpcB-kJHe97-OGekkJyep2rN6dBCaEQLBiI1jblyMKuOp2-FJkPN7YaWDFr1ZbAns9LjRo0vSZzQ62Vbsj-SR0DxEwco-qZ2vzYL-te72wB7QNjRAXrisBczzUcwKYgG1aGNiKeJ6u84fZrwRqos_sJKuxo18tvULsJAk/s800/marble_polys.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiLbln0LquEBPARhqkQpcB-kJHe97-OGekkJyep2rN6dBCaEQLBiI1jblyMKuOp2-FJkPN7YaWDFr1ZbAns9LjRo0vSZzQ62Vbsj-SR0DxEwco-qZ2vzYL-te72wB7QNjRAXrisBczzUcwKYgG1aGNiKeJ6u84fZrwRqos_sJKuxo18tvULsJAk/w400-h300/marble_polys.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjJ3JwpA3WRoo-gQymTXyCNq1BOuaQ4ABm3wvL8Yx1ddwLX2MknmUGBKv5qmtfMY8FMWr04f-rus_vGvnlEoCsf9NzCduYem0EIyrHvsoiHtcWpdh6HSnABsW_30mt2Ec5PQmsn0i8VivbbamjqnGvvmbD9-6IKmPMOoVD1QCjQto9D6yRBuNdv/s711/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-14%20at%208.42.33%20AM.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;353&quot; data-original-width=&quot;711&quot; height=&quot;199&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjJ3JwpA3WRoo-gQymTXyCNq1BOuaQ4ABm3wvL8Yx1ddwLX2MknmUGBKv5qmtfMY8FMWr04f-rus_vGvnlEoCsf9NzCduYem0EIyrHvsoiHtcWpdh6HSnABsW_30mt2Ec5PQmsn0i8VivbbamjqnGvvmbD9-6IKmPMOoVD1QCjQto9D6yRBuNdv/w400-h199/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-14%20at%208.42.33%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2950208107124962966'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2950208107124962966'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/10/sculpting-with-marble.html' title='Sculpting with Marble'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiLbln0LquEBPARhqkQpcB-kJHe97-OGekkJyep2rN6dBCaEQLBiI1jblyMKuOp2-FJkPN7YaWDFr1ZbAns9LjRo0vSZzQ62Vbsj-SR0DxEwco-qZ2vzYL-te72wB7QNjRAXrisBczzUcwKYgG1aGNiKeJ6u84fZrwRqos_sJKuxo18tvULsJAk/s72-w400-h300-c/marble_polys.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-241159898293785635</id><published>2024-10-07T17:29:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-07T17:29:05.002-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Indian Gaming</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54051274259/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;world_game_room_2&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;world_game_room_2&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54051274259_b55c4b384e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;399&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;i&gt;

Prompt:&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A Quaker who looks like the Quaker Oats guy is strolling through a huge room where native Americans in traditional dress are hunched over gaming consoles in an Indian Gaming context. Casino decor. War room. Psyops? Troll farm? Kind of mysterious.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;X-REF:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2008/07/touring-facilities.html&quot;&gt;Touring Facilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/241159898293785635'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/241159898293785635'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/10/indian-gaming.html' title='Indian Gaming'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2553407898668018968</id><published>2024-10-04T08:35:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-04T08:41:09.322-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Let Us Debate</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/5236864896/in/album-72157625538952986&quot; title=&quot;Reporting for Duty&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Reporting for Duty&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/5168/5236864896_26bae9242a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Posting to the Facebook Epistemology group:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
It’s not “factually true” in any epistemological sense that political ideologies span a one dimensional spectrum from far right to far left.&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;These directions (relative to whom?) are arbitrary to begin with, and come with a built in bias. “Right” also means “correct” whereas “Left” inherits the historical stigma of “sinister”, from the Latin “sinistra”. So there’s a thumb on the scale right from the outset. Bad design from the get go.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tangential aside: It’s like “positive” and “negative” in mathematics, hardly neutral terms. Only the positive three vectors in the XYZ system get to be “basis vectors” whereas the negatives are always secondary, even if you can’t tell them apart in terms of the work that they do.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Biased labeling aside, the idea that a simple linear spectrum is adequate for modeling political ideologies should be met with well-founded suspicion, especially in this golden age of data science (apparently). Who knew statistics would be overnight transformed into the sexiest of professions by the brilliant success machine learning?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In data science we have something called Principal Component Analysis (PCA) which adjudges, by mathematical techniques, what we might call the “rgb colors” or “fundamental properties” of any space. To each component corresponds a dimension, in some n-dimensional Hilbert Space.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;PCA involves not necessarily knowing in advance how many dimensions we might really need. To specify in advance: only one dimension, is to prevent the PCA algorithm from optimizing.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;In other words, “left versus right” is not only poor terminology (because biased), it’s bad science (data science). Too few dimensions to not a cogent model make. Even astrology had more dimensions, not forgetting the superseding Myers-Briggs.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And yet political scientists put up with it, do not fight back. That’s akin to the situation in anthropology, where the pros know we don’t have “five races of man” (black, white, red, yellow, brown), that’s so much bogus BS, and yet corporate sponsored pop culture is allowed to stay uncorrected. A great dumbing down is allowed to persist.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So what’s my ultimate conclusion, in light of this rant?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;Resolved: that English, without major modifications, is a garbage language, not suited to logical or rational thought. Let’s debate.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So many of core English concepts are so obviously poorly conceived and corrupt (computer science: buggy). Should “good philosophy in English” be considered an oxymoron then?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;I wouldn’t go that far. I think English in the right hands is still capable, as a language.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;But by default, English left to its own devices, is not suitable for scientific communications. That’s why education in professional grade English is so important, right?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjbQ4t8uuSJqNKy6cOoWfosSzmhF5wihQ6NeESm1B5IDKAakY94T4NLV72r4NQwoK4HBS-gDulcQNeqoy89wk3mmSDDHJMFItWQ0BWXFZgHe72jYrFbiamF_3b-1SAciY0q5C51otGmvg2UJBUfbUGIYhI2D3pb14RufAgiiBOeuGwUzmJFF-38/s931/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-04%20at%208.39.47%20AM.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;590&quot; data-original-width=&quot;931&quot; height=&quot;254&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjbQ4t8uuSJqNKy6cOoWfosSzmhF5wihQ6NeESm1B5IDKAakY94T4NLV72r4NQwoK4HBS-gDulcQNeqoy89wk3mmSDDHJMFItWQ0BWXFZgHe72jYrFbiamF_3b-1SAciY0q5C51otGmvg2UJBUfbUGIYhI2D3pb14RufAgiiBOeuGwUzmJFF-38/w400-h254/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-04%20at%208.39.47%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2553407898668018968'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2553407898668018968'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/10/let-us-debate.html' title='Let Us Debate'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjbQ4t8uuSJqNKy6cOoWfosSzmhF5wihQ6NeESm1B5IDKAakY94T4NLV72r4NQwoK4HBS-gDulcQNeqoy89wk3mmSDDHJMFItWQ0BWXFZgHe72jYrFbiamF_3b-1SAciY0q5C51otGmvg2UJBUfbUGIYhI2D3pb14RufAgiiBOeuGwUzmJFF-38/s72-w400-h254-c/Screen%20Shot%202024-10-04%20at%208.39.47%20AM.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8862667313244467926</id><published>2024-09-29T19:04:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-29T19:04:18.945-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Looking Back</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;A popular exercise in high school history could be to have students write a narrative they imagine in a future history book, about the recent past. Try to emulate the style of academic writing to some extent, but with an audience of people at their same reading level, which is high school to adult.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But of course that’s a broad assignment, which is part of the challenge. How does one pitch it at the right level of overview. The main thing is to emulate hindsight and tell the story differently, to signify the future perspective. What does the current time look like, from after the Singularity? We’re writing science fiction in that case. Martian Math.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drawing from my own recent corpus and generating from that, a lot of us geeks were turned on by the global electrification trend, which president Johnson made his name in connection with, being a point man when it came to electrifying Texas, still with its own grid. We picked up on the HVDC trend and bought into the World Game plan to link up the hemispheres. On the other hand, a slower business-minded mindset could not conceive of such infrastructure minus its own ownership and control of it, and these delinquents sidetracked the project in order to prove who was calling the shots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Something about “taking credit” is amiss in today’s cybersphere, where a lot of the content creeping in is recycled bot talk, but not flagged as such. Teen zeens, fan literature, vehicles for advertising, have found ways to amp up content using only half human-authored texts. Text generators abetted by editors, allowed to editorialize, compete with naked thinkers to using AI. The more phony stuff tends to come with telltale signs if one knows what to look for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Martian Math opted for hydropower in conjoining the physics of power generation with synergetic volumetric accounting, a minor wrinkle, experimental, and a door-opener for curriculum developers, as now we’d have a stronger geometric vocabulary and concept set. Students from our academies would rocket ahead, not being burdened with the kinds of ethnocentrism that lead others to spin out of control, sometimes right out of the gate.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8862667313244467926'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8862667313244467926'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/09/looking-back.html' title='Looking Back'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1173447271941228283</id><published>2024-09-26T10:15:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-27T21:33:42.012-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Am I a Racist? (movie review)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54022594677/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Fox Tower Regal Theaters&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fox Tower Regal Theaters&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54022594677_f9afe858a4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As y&#39;all might know, I&#39;m a YouTube junkie. I&#39;ve got it playing from when I feed the dog breakfast, before sunup, until sundown, off and on.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And as YouTubers know, to tug on a video is to yank on a long chain of recommendations. &quot;If you liked that one, what about this one?&quot; And so on. I don&#39;t resent said algorithms; I use them as mirrors. I&#39;m able to see how my interests change over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, a lot of my peeps have started reviewing that Matt Walsh movie, which broadcasts from the right on the political spectrum, which in snapshot, in today&#39;s lingo, means it&#39;s prone to pick on a lot of the more juvenile elements within the professoriate (e.g. the ones who haven&#39;t gone back, in later life, for those high school refresher courses per my &lt;a href=&quot;https://nbviewer.org/github/4dsolutions/School_of_Tomorrow/blob/master/School_of_Tomorrow.ipynb&quot;&gt;School of Tomorrow&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The meme of &quot;race&quot; (not genetically based really, and yes, we all have a skin color, what&#39;s your rgb?) still besets American discourse, whereas most of the time what they really want to talk about is &quot;ethnicity&quot; but that word is hardly made available to them, given the weakness of the anthropology department.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Teasing apart &quot;race&quot; from &quot;ethnicity&quot; is more where my training would go. There&#39;s not color blindness, but there might be some acknowledgment that &quot;race&quot; is more important in apartheid cultures than others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I prefer the word &quot;apartheid&quot; to &quot;systemic racism&quot; and think it&#39;s useful, even essential, to speak freely about the US apartheid system that we succeeded in stamping out for the most part, starting with the anti-slavery movement and leading through a civil war to the civil rights movement.&amp;nbsp; People are still working hard on their phobias. Islamophobia and Russophobia are still prevalent as mental illnesses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those human rights gains were all hard won and we should thank our lucky stars we&#39;re not in the pit of hell like Israel is, for choosing apartheid as its moral compass (nothing to do with Judaism in my view, which is here to stay, by &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/04/satori-states.html&quot;&gt;continuing to morph&lt;/a&gt;, as they all do, these world religions). Too bad women never got an Equal Rights Amendment though. Patriarchy triumphed, at least in the lagging political sphere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anthropology, the discipline, always had a hard time escaping ethnocentrism, but it least it had a name for it, and could therefore set up a program whereby individual students of anthropology could start to deprogram, to whatever extent they wished or could.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/09/another-journal-entry.html&quot;&gt;Deprogramming&lt;/a&gt; means discovering one&#39;s own birth culture to be sufficiently alien as to no longer come across as the one obvious choice, even for oneself or one&#39;s family, going forward. Roll your own, from the wealth of great lineages made available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You have to work on transcending your own ethnicity to have empathy and understanding of the others, and that work eventually becomes more about solo psycho-philosophy or &quot;soulmaking&quot; in the James Hillman tradition. You don&#39;t necessarily die with the ethnicity you&#39;re born with. That&#39;s partly what makes it less attractive to bureaucrats, who want to check a box that never changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The racists, on the other hand, that dwindling number who actually still believe the pseudo-science, find it convenient to corner a market they call &quot;whites&quot; (scoff scoff), who have no choice but to need endless deprogramming, given how deeply programmed (so-called &quot;privileged&quot;) these buggy bots have become.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Ethnic whites&quot; (invented for the purposes of this blog post) delude themselves into thinking it&#39;s all about them and their racist identity (ethnicity), and then they&#39;re supposed to suffer guilt about that, followed by transformative rebirth. As an ethnic Asian (self identified), I consider such &quot;whiteness&quot; rather callow and I&#39;m glad to not be an ethnic white in that sense, although I won&#39;t deny my skin has a pale rgb value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;DEI trainers are or were a type of deprogrammer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matt goes undercover, in the manner of &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/11/borat-movie-review.html&quot;&gt;a Borat&lt;/a&gt; (Sacha Baron Cohen) to infiltrate the DEI trainer universe, and mock it thoroughly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He concludes with his own over-the-top version of a training, which likely DiAngelo would call &quot;weird&quot;, just as was her own lucrative interaction with the guy pretty &quot;weird&quot; (the $30 race reparations incident).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m on board with mockumentaries as a genre, however if I wanted to mock racism (and I do), I&#39;d take &lt;a href=&quot;https://kirbyurner.medium.com/77af32830db7&quot;&gt;a different tack&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;d bring up all those websites about Noah and his spreading family after the flood, and how encoded the racial talk becomes in Bible studies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These different races really became more pronounced after the Tower of Babel incident though (we&#39;re still in Genesis here), when a lack of mutual understanding proved a godsend: peeps were no longer working lockstep on a fruitless, morally bankrupt project to &quot;reach god&quot; through the vertical dimension (the so-called 3rd dimension, i.e. depth).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Humans have continued confusing themselves with the word &quot;dimension&quot; ever since.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;God loves His little morons though, and wanted them to survive, and so confused their tongues this time (vs sending a flood). That started a clumping process whereby humans distilled into the five races we have today: black, white, red, yellow and brown. Everyone else is a mixture of these five.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s in the sapien branch of the hominid family. The Neanderthal and Denisovans were presumably racialized in different ways (we don&#39;t have all the data yet -- I&#39;m looking forward to the AI art).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I just don&#39;t sound mocking enough?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The literal Genesis story has been a dead horse for centuries, such that its skeleton was long ago back to sand. Only the symbolic meanings, as hinted at above, have any ongoing ethical or aesthetic value.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If we want literal history regarding a Great Flood, we should study Ballard et al and steer clear of theologically-minded spin doctors such as myself.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m interested in the dharmas, but when I want science, the Bible is not the first book I think of.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1173447271941228283'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1173447271941228283'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/09/am-i-racist-movie-review.html' title='Am I a Racist? (movie review)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8034553349587323268</id><published>2024-09-22T14:56:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-22T16:58:53.577-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Another Journal Entry</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;I was sorry to learn of Lowen&#39;s passing; this was the first I&#39;d heard. Now I see the announcement&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/2qi6jEf&quot;&gt;in the newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been somewhat peripheral to the life of the Meeting, as was driven home today during Peace and Justice committee meeting, in which I felt clueless about much of what was talked about.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which didn&#39;t keep me from opening my fat mouth a few times (I tried out &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/09/thursday-think-tank.html&quot;&gt;another joke&lt;/a&gt;: one thumbs up one down). The joke: my pronouns are in the possessive tense: &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;theirs&lt;/i&gt;. Hah hah?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joking aside, the most insidious of all pronouns is &quot;we&quot; but people rarely talk about that one, especially &quot;we white people&quot; (guffaw... barf). What &quot;we&quot; whiteman, right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kepper, Lowen&#39;s partner, made a telling point when talking about filling out Lowen&#39;s death certificate info and having to specify race. The clerk just assumed &quot;white&quot; but Kepper added &quot;he wasn&#39;t white until his twenties&quot; which of course the clerk couldn&#39;t process.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What she meant was: Lowen was born into the Jewish tradition and wasn&#39;t allowed even to caddy golf games except in Jewish clubs. The country club WASPs were that &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/08/homer-davenport-festival.html&quot;&gt;anti-semitic&lt;/a&gt;, even that recently. A good reminder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did we want an anti-racist trainer to come into the Meeting and catalyze a transformative experience for the attenders present? Friends have fallen a long way away from being leaders in the anti-racism campaign I gather. Now they need help, like any corporation (we are a corporation, not for profit). Color us IBM?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m saddened to see booji well-off people spending money on themselves to deprogram. Yes, racism is insidious. But isn&#39;t our faith and practice all about self deprogramming, to make more room for God&#39;s will (to use the archaic language)? Sad that we have so little faith in our faith that we need to heavily rely on outsiders, is how I was taking it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of my take on racism (old hat by now, with so much already here in my journals), here&#39;s the gist of my view, that a racist is someone who believes in races:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54014484393/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Screen Shot 2024-09-22 at 2.52.11 PM&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2024-09-22 at 2.52.11 PM&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54014484393_dd3effa041.jpg&quot; width=&quot;465&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/54008797653/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Syllabus Author&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Syllabus Author&quot; height=&quot;351&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/54008797653_44ff793a7c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8034553349587323268'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8034553349587323268'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/09/another-journal-entry.html' title='Another Journal Entry'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3592028010049910183</id><published>2024-09-18T19:06:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T21:33:54.628-07:00</updated><title type='text'>An Apple Story</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72157654417641521&quot; title=&quot;OCT / RU&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;OCT / RU&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/8724/17304234311_97eb61604c_w.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I mention my Mac Pro died? I was typing mid-sentence when the whole computer froze, nothing I could do but hard reboot, at which point it went to a rectangular icon, not the Apple, and told me to contact Apple support.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tried the recovery utility options, downloading a RAM boot drive. It saw nothing to fix, meaning no storage. I was looking at a total loss of access, with no viable boot process.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was pretty demur (that word is going around) about it, not nonplussed, calm.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After all, I was on a beautiful Oregon farm in a luxury trailer with a loyal and happy dog. I was learning tractor skills.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And back home in Portland, I had the external drive TimeMachine on my desk. I didn&#39;t think it would help at all with the dead Mac, but if/when I got a new one, I&#39;d have access to the old files. I was proud of myself for taking it in stride, although I did reach out to friends and family with snippets of what was happening.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the more positive results, and I need to tell Terry about this at the Equinox gathering, since he gave it to me, was the Apple iPad turned out to be more capable than I&#39;d thought. No, I wouldn&#39;t use it to do my Python work, but in terms of telecommunications and staying organized, it held up under pressure. My skills improved.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Secret: when the GUI seems bonkers, rotate the screen 90 degrees as in &quot;long tall mode&quot; the GUI improves, even if the keyboard is then at the wrong angle (relatively).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once back in Portland, I resolved I&#39;d need to visit the Apple Genius Bar downtown and get a read on whether the Mac was repairable. But I took my time, pondering my options. What if I could get by without a powerful Mac. I have older computers, including an older slow joe Mac Pro. I wouldn&#39;t wanna teach my Python classes on the slow ones, but what if I wasn&#39;t gonna be teaching any Python classes soon?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That was the question: was the course in question (Python + Data Analysis + Data Visualization), for Clarusway, still a go? We hadn&#39;t touched base in awhile.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the beginning, it was considered contingent, based on getting the peeps, the students.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have the workflow sketched out in a generic fashion in my Code School Blueprints album, developed after some years working for a startup code school (within a bigger company). I&#39;ll embed those slides here, why not?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Faculty hangs out in a holding pattern, learning new skills, prepping, until a course is chartered (like a charter flight, instructor = pilot). I&#39;m in a holding pattern with respect to that particular course, while working on other projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve nudged the company with some queries and will likely hear back shortly, but then this happened: the dead Mac Pro sprang to life.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d plugged it in upstairs, in my office (a real office, declared on taxes some years, not a bedroom, except for the snake), and walked away, knowing it&#39;d get as far as the &quot;contact Apple support&quot; screen.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t check on it for at least two days.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But then it was time to feed Barry (the python) a mouse, so I walked to and from &lt;i&gt;Tropical Hut&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;on Divsion, across Chavez, around noon, and at some point decided to hit the spacebar. The Mac sprang to life, at the usual login screen. It had booted! It lived!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did was do another TimeMachine backup as the best I had was not entirely up to date.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever since, I&#39;ve been enjoying poking around in familiar territory, my working environment for the last two to three years. I feel like I&#39;m reunited with a country I&#39;d steeled myself to maybe never see again. She&#39;s been working ever since.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m hoping she won&#39;t go into a coma again, of course. Probably next time I visit that farm, I&#39;ll leave her here and just use the iPad. It does Zoom. I still had my meetups. Coding in Python can wait, when &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/09/movie-shoot.html&quot;&gt;tractors&lt;/a&gt; become the priority.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3592028010049910183'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3592028010049910183'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/09/an-apple-story.html' title='An Apple Story'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8339027493420672020</id><published>2024-09-12T05:33:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-12T06:47:10.602-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Soap Opera Summary (satire)</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;The news says NATO is about to give itself permission to amp up its invasion of the Russian homeland. The idea is to keep Ukraine out of NATO on technicalities but “for all intents and purposes” to use it as a military base, as had been happening under &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/09/invective.html&quot;&gt;President Blinken&lt;/a&gt; and Vice President Nuland for some time now.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wait, did I get the narrative wrong? Anyway, it’s time for NATO to get the show on the road.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back in knee jerk legacy media land, there’s probably some sense that people are following the action and are ready to jump into their roles as nationalist loyalist troopers, happy to march march march like the old people tell ‘em is necessary.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NATO geezers expect the allegiance of a younger generation not necessarily cut out to play hero in such a tawdry low class drama. Who wants to die for the knuckle draggers? “Why let those dinos live through me?” your average coder is thinking. “They don’t even know Python, most of ‘em (OK, Ada maybe).”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can’t think of anything more uncool than living in Virginia with parents slaved to &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2023/03/beltway-mafia.html&quot;&gt;Beltway Mafia&lt;/a&gt; politics. What an ugly childhood for so many. Shades of Laurel Canyon right? It’s the kids of privilege, like Washington and Jefferson, who are more likely to rebel against the parent company (East India in their case). The Doors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The frenzied media, MSNBC especially, need to do way more to whip up Russophobia (aka dementia russogenica). &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/08/code-of-conduct.html&quot;&gt;Rachel Maddow&lt;/a&gt;, help us out here. The needle hasn’t really budged in a while, as attention turns to the “states are no solution” drama in the so-called “Middle East” (snicker). Is it time for another novychok bedtime story? What airplane is parked next to what airplane?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;President Blinken needs to deliver some great oratory, before people forget the plot again. Help us remember how democracy is at stake. Tell us how authoritarians will never get a toehold in the USA at least. These people are just not psychologically ready yet. Not for Mafia brand theater. More snake oil kool-aid is needed. Pass the numbskull sauce.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let me help y’all out. Um.. um.. “My fellow Americans…”. Something like that. And knock it off with the Zionista thing, that’s too radical for our middle of the roaders (pet lovers, cat ladies) by several orders of magnitude. No one thinks that’s cool anymore. Let the Brits take over that whole show. You know, the guys who started it. Lawrence of Arabia and all that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8339027493420672020'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8339027493420672020'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/09/soap-opera-summary.html' title='Soap Opera Summary (satire)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-3266835300626333323</id><published>2024-09-06T13:51:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-07T12:11:08.048-07:00</updated><title type='text'>America: The Exceptional Nation</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Decrying &quot;exceptionalist&quot; as in &quot;spoiled brat&quot; is not the same as claiming someone or something is exceptional. Maybe it is, we don&#39;t know yet. Exceptionally bad smelling? Exceptionally expensive? So many dimensions exist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So for a segment here, if only to be contrarian (we have that right), I would argue for other reasons, let&#39;s yak about in what ways &quot;America&quot; (so much to say) is indeed &quot;exceptional&quot; (which it is).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One thing that&#39;s easy to observe is: a lot of the people who came here were underdogs, fighting some establishment back home and ending up with the short end of the stick, as some say. They then had to risk everything to start over here in the New World. And once they got here, they wanted one thing: revenge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of new Americans came here with a chip on their shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OK, I&#39;m being a little facetious, but America&#39;s shores do harbor a lot of ethnicities within which &quot;getting back&quot; at whomever, is high on the agenda.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given how America is a mighty place, and its control rooms appear open to anyone able to pay to play, why not seize those amazing military assets and extract from those enemies back home the price they deserve to pay (something high, obviously)? I mean, it&#39;s an obvious agenda to pursue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Examples come piling in: refugee Gulenists wanted by Turkish authorities; refugee Falun Gongists seeking revenge against Xi, Ukes who hate Russkies, Russkies who hate Ukes, back and forth like that a million times.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They each want to rule the world, or at least get Americans to rally around their cause. Obviously I skipped over more obvious examples. The list goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think in that sense America is indeed exceptional. A huge number of its citizens came here with axes to grind, scores to settle, plans to get even.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many, it was a maybe simple story of succeeding at the personal level, in spite of all odds, and having news get back home that so-and-so was no small town idiot after all. These stories are often heartwarming. For others, the story is more civilizational, about &quot;the people&quot; (or &quot;pueblo&quot;) more generally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Critics who want to play counterpoint will insist we remember all the people already here, before the floodgates were opened to colonization, by the invention of mass ocean going vessels.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Mayflower was no Carnival cruise ship, we know that, but it was at least a step in that direction. People indulging in &quot;religious convictions&quot; could finally afford to book passage, and not have to help with crewing the ship or memorizing constellations (considered a pagan fixation by many).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;True, Turtle Island was already festooned with stellar cultures, spread out and not forced into interpersonal violence on the scale of say Napoleon&#39;s people. Europe was far more densely populated, had more lethal weaponry, and exploited horses. The &quot;Indians&quot; had a lot to learn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Napoleon decided to sell much of America to those Washington, DC people (a revolutionary avantgard), because he needed his troops to stay in the fight for the long haul. He needed to pay their salaries.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Louisiana Purchase helped keep his struggling Empire going against England&#39;s. Not so long before, the USA had fought the same foe. The USA kept expanding west, fighting over slavery as it did so, with the industrial revolution more on the side of &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2014/10/a-quaker-arc.html&quot;&gt;the Quakers&lt;/a&gt; in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nothing regarding America&#39;s exceptional nature, as a platform for diaspora nations to consolidate and pass on culture, is contradicted by its original network nations, going back to Inca, Mayan, and Aztec to name a few -- the people we tend to call &quot;Hispanic&quot; today, for lack of a more intelligent word.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My narrative is more designed to switch attention from &quot;melting pot&quot; shibboleths (which I also use) and point out how &quot;preserving ethnicity&quot; was never an &quot;unAmerican&quot; goal.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re allowed to keep practicing those rituals and rites, whatever they may be, and public schooling is not about countermanding your family&#39;s values on that score, as long as you don&#39;t interfere with the rights of others to perform otherwise, ritualistically and/or costume-wise (cosmetics, jewelry... we don&#39;t all share the same tastes, all right?&amp;nbsp; Welcome to Walmart).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3266835300626333323'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/3266835300626333323'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/09/america-exceptional-nation.html' title='America: The Exceptional Nation'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-768505475376111990</id><published>2024-09-01T06:49:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-01T06:52:30.615-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Explaining my Workflow: from 2D to 3D</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/53963426335/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;From 2D to 3D&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;From 2D to 3D&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53963426335_aefb9eaf8b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;363&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;
  :: reintroducing myself on X... ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/53962969391/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Screen Shot 2024-09-01 at 5.50.54 AM&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2024-09-01 at 5.50.54 AM&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53962969391_1162a5b7d5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;456&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;
  :: ... as a political cartoonist ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/768505475376111990'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/768505475376111990'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/09/explaining-my-workflow-from-2d-to-3d.html' title='Explaining my Workflow: from 2D to 3D'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5650303698860064481</id><published>2024-08-26T11:04:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-27T08:45:22.780-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Late August Weekend</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72177720319788214&quot; title=&quot;Hawthorne Street Fair 2024&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Hawthorne Street Fair 2024&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53948062693_e3940f0ac9_w.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what was my weekend like? As you know, I like to study, and that &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/07/a-multimodal-adventure.html&quot;&gt;includes adventures&lt;/a&gt; into the environment, such as taking Springwater Corridor to Sellwood and over the bicycle bridge to the Sellwood-Tacoma Max station. Ride Orange Line back to OMSI stop, transfer to FX2 to within blocks from home. That&#39;s work-study time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Sunday it was walk by Terry (ISEPP prez) and a consultant working on finding homes for left behind office furniture and supplies. I gather &lt;a href=&quot;https://floatworks.com/journal/john-c-lilly-the-pioneer-of-floating&quot;&gt;the John C. Lilly group&lt;/a&gt; has moved to other digs. Onward to Stark Street Meetinghouse (&lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2005/09/planting-seeds-in-silicon-forest.html&quot;&gt;formerly ESI&lt;/a&gt;, before that Jantzen) where the testimony was about &quot;sangha&quot; (community) -- although no one actually used that Buddhist word (but many were maybe thinking it, given our demographics (I know I was)).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That night I watched Kubrick&#39;s &lt;i&gt;Eyes Wide Shut&lt;/i&gt;, believe it or not for the first time, although having seen clips over the years, it felt familiar in places. I&#39;d checked &lt;i&gt;Movie Madness&lt;/i&gt; for it before, and imagined it was rented out, not realizing their Kubrick shelf wrapped around and down. I&#39;m illiterate in so many dimensions I&#39;ve lost count. Talked with fam through Verizon on my iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Quakers, I met up with Dr. Carl Abbott over snacks and thanked him for his excellent presentation on Portland history for Humanists of Greater Portland (HGP), to which I&#39;d been party over Zoom (not the first time I&#39;d caught one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/pKMMTe&quot;&gt;his &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/pKMMTe&quot;&gt;talks&lt;/a&gt;). Urban Studies, PSU. I caught up with Leslie, back from California.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, Megge suggested I join up with Peace &amp;amp; Justice (as it&#39;s now called -- did I get that right?). Quakers revolve through a finite set of management committees, learning to see a shared business from the inside, from many angles. Good experience building social and supervisory skills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m just hitting some of the highlights. Weekends don&#39;t stand out that much at the moment. I do have a work schedule in the queue, with Clarusway again, but that&#39;s always contingent on other outcomes, per some &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gantt_chart&quot;&gt;cosmic Gantt chart&lt;/a&gt; I&#39;m not privy to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Clarusway, this morning (Monday) I posted to edu-sig, a Python org Mailman group of longstanding, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mail.python.org/archives/list/edu-sig@python.org/message/EBZYLOWGIE6FYWB7N6U6GS3SNPDW7AZL/&quot;&gt;regarding digital roots&lt;/a&gt; (or &quot;indigs&quot; as some&#39;ve called them).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hawthorne Street Fair!&amp;nbsp; Slides above.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5650303698860064481'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5650303698860064481'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/08/last-august-weekend.html' title='Late August Weekend'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8493148096419012891</id><published>2024-08-15T06:46:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-21T07:09:53.961-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Posting From Cyberia</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjbG46TTg2INJ5R3kAbXjO00M79eELmBbTZZsWG4B2zTZ9QrlWGYvLO2g6sThvMNYIEXwDR6tdH6ne_W-97N2Pe7zAl8lgUKhNAaMAZrOnxXdNILrWvMiDIHc68daMtIkRytDquhJ1GyqsYDvsUIgBrTdJ3n1zS_BiHsnTRl2bsVQkgZZfgkyXh/s1536/BN_in_his_bunker.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1536&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1536&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjbG46TTg2INJ5R3kAbXjO00M79eELmBbTZZsWG4B2zTZ9QrlWGYvLO2g6sThvMNYIEXwDR6tdH6ne_W-97N2Pe7zAl8lgUKhNAaMAZrOnxXdNILrWvMiDIHc68daMtIkRytDquhJ1GyqsYDvsUIgBrTdJ3n1zS_BiHsnTRl2bsVQkgZZfgkyXh/w400-h400/BN_in_his_bunker.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;d like to get it to the point where arsonists in their bunkers, trying to start conflagrations, get treated more as psychiatric patients than as so-called &quot;world leaders&quot;. This has to do with my Spaceship Earth imagery (inherited) morphing into Global University (GU) imagery, meaning &quot;teaching hospital&quot; and a lot of&amp;nbsp; psy-stuff.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Faculty is working on curricula that turn out students with higher quotients in whatever respects higher quotients are needed. Perhaps we&#39;re sufficiently intelligent but insufficiently developed in other directions. What&#39;s our consistency score?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I&#39;m back to trucking and dirty jobs. The path to a PhD is through extensive practice with toolsets and skillsets. The medical doctor shares a lot of these same &quot;I can learn anything&quot; traits, which leads to some percentage crashing their single or even twin engine planes (&quot;Too Gung Ho&quot; on the tombstone).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think of it though: to swap long haul driving work with a counterpart, to ride as a sidekick, to take in the language and customs and bring that back. Then study more if you want to and join that same fleet as a driver next time, and repeat.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Airline pilots know what I mean. There&#39;s that inner circle that flies in and out of Hong Kong, or Rangoon or whatever (I had a bouncy ride into Rangoon once, as a passenger, on a DC3 or one of those).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The yahoos in their bunkers, trying to start wars, are already in rubber room approximators, so we shift attention to curbing enthusiasm for short term fireworks. Crushing obsolete institutions is actually a more rewarding exercise, and outward war as we know it has been seeing sunset for quite awhile now.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We still fight psychologically. That&#39;s actually a more even playing field, and we can get back to Victorian values like &quot;fairness&quot; as we talk about it in sports. You know: honor.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just blasting zoomorphic creatures from an Apache helicopter is better shifted to simulator, to computer game. Acted out, it&#39;s schizo nutso, by horror film Poindexters, except not confined to film.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve always been a fan of the global network at the city mayor level. Mayors meet and discuss issues. I&#39;m told Portland has gotten better an learning from others, versus letting its earlier fame and glory go to its head. Then came a fall.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But saying the fall of Portland was independent of seismic shifts shaking up the collective psyche more generally would be like wearing blinders, perhaps intentionally (confining attention to the &quot;Markov blanket&quot; is a systems technique).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Portland might be talking to Shiraz for all I know (I don&#39;t claim to be privy to all that mayoral type chatter).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Denizens of Cyberia, enjoying more overview than ever before in history, have an angle on the arsonists now that everything&#39;s out in the open.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transparency in government was given lip service as an ideal, but now that we approach a bar that leaves behind legacy media, showing it from the back side (in the rear view mirror), the political process snaps into clearer focus.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those who would profit from more slaughter on the battlefield are filmed hyping slaughter to their stakeholders, in pure Hunger Games fashion. Doctors without borders see how capitalism can make you cuckoo, in addition to highly paid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However shooting mental patients was never considered much of a cure outside of quack circles, wherein the sickly witch hunters seek scapegoats for bounty (or merely mob approval). The first step is to disconnect psychopaths from their agentic dashboards, such as by unplugging the latter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s nothing cowardly about not jumping in the cage with the rabid dog and having it out. For what purpose would one do that?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let the dog rage at the cage itself, and think about euthanasia as a kind of putting to rest some core concerns, such as where do we have to draw the borders ultimately. Virtual states have boundaries too, if not contiguous.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reputed ignorance, of Americans, of political geography, might turn out to be a good thing, as we go soft focus on these older maps. The global university comes with new floorplans.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8493148096419012891'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8493148096419012891'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/08/posting-from-cyberia.html' title='Posting From Cyberia'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjbG46TTg2INJ5R3kAbXjO00M79eELmBbTZZsWG4B2zTZ9QrlWGYvLO2g6sThvMNYIEXwDR6tdH6ne_W-97N2Pe7zAl8lgUKhNAaMAZrOnxXdNILrWvMiDIHc68daMtIkRytDquhJ1GyqsYDvsUIgBrTdJ3n1zS_BiHsnTRl2bsVQkgZZfgkyXh/s72-w400-h400-c/BN_in_his_bunker.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4112633086439096721</id><published>2024-08-07T06:56:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-07T16:15:47.572-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Contra Insanity</title><content type='html'>

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/albums/72177720319381227&quot; title=&quot;Hiroshima  / Nagasaki Memorial Ceremony 2024&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Hiroshima  / Nagasaki Memorial Ceremony 2024&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53909194908_a562803ef8_w.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/53906418296/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;End the Insanity&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;End the Insanity&quot; height=&quot;261&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53906418296_926887f92b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/53907973871/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;doomsday&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;doomsday&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53907973871_49c9eb717a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4112633086439096721'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4112633086439096721'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/08/contra-insanity.html' title='Contra Insanity'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5559766284756119095</id><published>2024-07-31T16:11:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-07-31T16:36:10.006-07:00</updated><title type='text'>A Last Straw</title><content type='html'>&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1536&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1536&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgihs6ygeZgPjBH5Zh3RdCMd3oQccXscemdNyGMuq2dNEBAMwdf1Yaoo43iPPv6lFbr9GgIQa6QccyIcAfAdcqmDdkA9qRvQmyDXa_F7ZgjRkKgOI0IaXZg-cn3O-iOgQ9ln1IC_mKCtc0tOcpuWSV1WpdWPGf0l2Ryp-suTXGkI8suU6R4ua1o/s400/camel_straw.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;:: before ::&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some ways, &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2024/07/working-out.html&quot;&gt;Working Out&lt;/a&gt; would make more sense here, in &lt;i&gt;BizMo Diaries&lt;/i&gt;, as it&#39;s about physical body stuff, and the &quot;business mobile&quot; (peripatetic action studio) works for a stand-in, metaphor-wise.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Likewise, this post, &lt;a href=&quot;https://grunch.net/synergetics/gst1.html&quot;&gt;about Cybernetics&lt;/a&gt;, would make more sense in &lt;i&gt;Control Room&lt;/i&gt;, just going by the relevant memes i.e. a &quot;control room&quot; is like a &quot;bridge&quot; or place to make things happen. Another type of &quot;action studio&quot; really (what isn&#39;t?), but relatively stationary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s now turn to this meme of &quot;last straw&quot;, which is also, presumably, the one which broke that poor camel&#39;s back. The camel was already laden with straw, one imagines, and was holding up. But that one last straw proved the tipping point and, snap, the camel&#39;s back lost structural integrity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We tend to empathize with the camel, or in any case, if a beast of burden, now we have no animal to bear our load. Like a car broken down by the side of the road, the connotations are mostly negative, in the direction of increasing entropy. May the tow truck make it all better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what about critical &quot;last straws&quot; that, when added, open doors or otherwise lead to positive developments. What&#39;s the English language opposite of &quot;catastrophe&quot; and if none comes to mind, isn&#39;t that a symptom of something, about English. I&#39;ve heard &quot;benestrophe&quot; suggested. I must&#39;ve already added it to my dictionary, as so far my spell checker hasn&#39;t complained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;To cyber&quot; means &quot;to steer&quot; i.e. &quot;cybering&quot; is a matter of rotating a rudder, thereby repointing the craft. That may sound like a simple process but sometimes so much inertia is involved that even the rudder needs a rudder, which reminds us which principle (leverage) is involved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s say you turn hard to starboard or port, and manage to miss the iceberg this time, because you had better intelligence ahead of time. You had more time to react.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Optimal responses may require cool headed thinking, and lots of it, however if that time is not now, then the usual strategy is to substitute a reflex as a next best reaction, a proxy action, an approximation, perhaps not well-thought out, but at least in the repertoire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you escape catastrophe, that in itself is a benestrophe. In ages past, the king or queen might have a monument, perhaps an entire church or temple, in gratitude to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/06/just-use-it.html&quot;&gt;whatever generalized principles&lt;/a&gt; allowed for a freakishly and unexpectedly positive outcome, what we call &quot;a miracle&quot; in the vernacular.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, we need to remain open minded with regard to even more positive positives, which are not about surmounting the relatively low bar of narrowly avoiding tragedy. These high bar events may be likewise triggered by feather-light tiny deltas, fourth derivative actions, as it were, as insignificant as the fluttering wings of a butterfly.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5559766284756119095'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5559766284756119095'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/07/a-last-straw.html' title='A Last Straw'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgihs6ygeZgPjBH5Zh3RdCMd3oQccXscemdNyGMuq2dNEBAMwdf1Yaoo43iPPv6lFbr9GgIQa6QccyIcAfAdcqmDdkA9qRvQmyDXa_F7ZgjRkKgOI0IaXZg-cn3O-iOgQ9ln1IC_mKCtc0tOcpuWSV1WpdWPGf0l2Ryp-suTXGkI8suU6R4ua1o/s72-c/camel_straw.png" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-506482231161937936</id><published>2024-07-27T08:58:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-07-28T07:58:52.922-07:00</updated><title type='text'>SimCity Thinking</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/53885901628/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Fun Simulation Game&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/53885901628_501820534b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Fun Simulation Game&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to admit my admiration for Uber&#39;s clever follow-up offer after my finally getting around to using their app and service:&amp;nbsp; free meal delivered on us, $45 value; then a week later: $25 if you use it now. The sight of a shrinking asset provokes action, although in my case I&#39;m resistant, and it helps that if I follow their offer I&#39;m back in Atlanta (which I&#39;m not, at the moment).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think a lot about the delivery economy but maybe not with enough inputs, as I&#39;m not a business consultant so much as a skills trainer in a working class ecosystem. I&#39;ll show you how pandas will give your data visualizations that professional zing that makes your cubicle a hub in whatever network you&#39;re in. I&#39;ve never worked for Amazon directly, although my code school was subsidized by its outreach programs that summer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2023/08/back-to-school.html&quot;&gt;as I recall&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the idea of fleets of flexibly routed vans delivering in high volume, versus browsers showing up in parking lots in private cars, leaves me thinking we&#39;re likely economizing in shrinking the mall culture. Yes, the web took the place of storefronts in large degree. That&#39;s ephemeralization at work, meaning as a species we&#39;re under pressure to economize, even when we&#39;d prefer to make a lifestyle more permanent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Derek and I were in agreement, in recent living room conversation, that better infrastructure, extending camping, for a nomadic lifestyle, perhaps on wheels, as a multimodal adventurer or whatever, would answer a need in some of our subcultures to &quot;live outdoors&quot; in some essential way. Dense urban living is too claustrophobic for them, or too stationary.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A nomadic lifestyle doesn&#39;t have to mean in a tent. A yurt with ample floor space in some hexagonal grid pattern (&lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2019/03/systems-science.html&quot;&gt;random lake shaped&lt;/a&gt;) would be an improvement over a phone booth shaped tiny house in my view. Electric ATVs come to mind. You might book a yurt for some months or weeks and move on to a next one, with variations in make and model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of boomers hope to retire to a mildly active lifestyle, recreational in nature, like in Florida.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had the privilege of retiring in my teens, while going to high school while based in a mobile home park for retirees. The homeowner association might&#39;ve frowned on our extended stay (me and my sister) which is why mom flew back to Bradenton and moved us into a roach motel (not that the trailer -- er mobile home -- didn&#39;t have &quot;palmetto bugs&quot;).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, absent Yurt Villages (high tech), the Florida option still seems a good deal, not that I&#39;m the expert or share that plan for myself. Like I said: been there done that. I&#39;m &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; dissing that lifestyle, which is pretty comfortable I admit, but I&#39;d use my stays in that trailer (I&#39;d be back) to reinvent myself, perhaps into an airport manager (that book was interesting but I wasn&#39;t sure how to break in).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I ended up finishing high school in Manila, dad having scored a gig with UNDP. We had UN passports for the whole family. I proudly display a UN flag as part of my living room decor to this day. I also keep flags of Bhutan, Lesotho, and Republic of South Africa, right here on my desk; places I&#39;ve come to feel some allegiance to and fondness for, in addition to these various states in North America (Oregon being my home base nowadays -- I&#39;d like to explore them more, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2023/09/museum-floors.html&quot;&gt;Birmingham&lt;/a&gt;, Alabama was fun).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another city older folks retire to is Las Vegas, which markets itself as a destination for recreational living in general. The new MSG Sphere is open, and showing &lt;i&gt;Grateful Dead&lt;/i&gt;, a live performance with giant screen backup. I talk about that in &lt;a href=&quot;https://coffeeshopsnet.blogspot.com/2024/07/more-synergetic-weirdness.html&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; (in my philosophy blog), which is actually a YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/506482231161937936'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/506482231161937936'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/07/simcity-thinking.html' title='SimCity Thinking'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5761851792784212183</id><published>2024-07-25T06:09:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-07-25T06:14:03.192-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Sharing in Meeting</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/8529524037/in/album-72157632938589642/&quot; title=&quot;Quakers Gather&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Quakers Gather&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/8371/8529524037_8c92c9541f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember standing up in Meeting once, a big Meeting in Philadelphia, where AFSC corporation members and directors had convened, and sharing something philosophical-sounding, and also arguably dualistic. &quot;The bodies&quot; I was saying &quot;are innocent of any wrongdoing, yet it&#39;s them that we punish&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My point was that of George Fox when he said you can&#39;t kill the devil with a gun or a sword or something to that effect. Ideologies circulate like viruses, independently of the animal bodies they haunt (infect, control). To counter an ideology effectively should not involve torturing the animals (the human animals) that express this ideology.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My view is somewhat that of medical science and its practitioners who take the Hippocratic Oath (do they do that anymore?). Treating human bodies is distinct from psychotherapy although they&#39;re intertwined. An anxious psyche is more likely to run a body into the ground by overdosing it with stress hormones. How mind and body interweave is the kind of problem Oliver Sacks liked to study.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The use of physical torture, such as by bombing and/or deliberately starving, is an expression of our weakness in the psychological realm. We have less success than we would like countering an ideology, and so take up arms against it, and attack its adherents (the infected, the blessed). Outward war, according to Quakerism, is somewhat beside the point, as what we&#39;re really trying to accomplish is metaphysical (psychological), not physical (physiological).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Don&#39;t blame the meat puppets for crazy beliefs and the strings they pull&quot; might be another way of saying it, &quot;but do work on curing craziness by inward means&quot;. In Quaker jargon, &quot;inward&quot; is versus &quot;outward&quot;. &quot;Inward&quot; is the world of psychological modeling and processing. &quot;Outward&quot; is the world of sticks and stones and broken bones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outward wars are misplaced (in the sense of inept) attempts to avoid dealing more directly with inward wars.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5761851792784212183'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5761851792784212183'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/07/sharing-in-meeting.html' title='Sharing in Meeting'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8471447657168287492</id><published>2024-07-08T20:50:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T21:08:06.312-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Bat Cave</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Does &lt;a href=&quot;https://radio-octopus.org&quot;&gt;Radio Octopus&lt;/a&gt; only play tracks of creature noises? I just tuned in for the first time. Now we&#39;re on to bird sounds with piano. Somewhere &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/06/the-french-connection.html&quot;&gt;in France&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found myself explaining, to a newcomer at our Solstice Gathering, how Wanderers, in my book, includes the nonhumans. I&#39;m not saying all of them. I circled &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/01/recruiting-new-wanderer.html&quot;&gt;Keiko&lt;/a&gt; in particular, better known as Willy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a morning &quot;about town&quot; I&#39;m in my &quot;bat cave&quot; for the most part, occasionally bouncing upstairs to use the office. The outside temperature is down to 92 degrees Fahrenheit, was 98 earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just heard from Kerry Butson, after so many years since our co-worker days. She&#39;s in Illinois. We were both employees of a code school in California, she before me. I was brought in by Steve Holden, author of their Python course.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since those days, I&#39;ve continued to work in Python. Just today I was hacking on my Google slides &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1ynde13tnMAu7EelfVuQVTFDUWGYBcRDRmtkMu4LIUFw/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;about Quadrays&lt;/a&gt;, an XYZ-like coordinate system. I&#39;ve been introducing them to UC Davis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2018/04/wanderers-2018425.html&quot;&gt;Dr. DiNucci&lt;/a&gt; gifted me with an air conditioner last year, when the original customer discovered she was disallowed such equipment by her Homeowner Association. She surrendered the unit in disgust and gave it to David to give away. It ended up in my living room.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of Portlanders have traditionally gone without air conditioning, preferring to tough it out through the few truly hot days every summer. I was in that category until life made it really easy to add this perk.&amp;nbsp; Central air for the whole house would make the upstairs more habitable. The ball python doesn&#39;t seem to mind the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From my bat cave, I monitor local and global conditions. I also network and telecommute. The &quot;bat mobile&quot; in the driveway has &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2024/07/fast-and-efficient.html&quot;&gt;proved serviceable&lt;/a&gt; lately.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8471447657168287492'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8471447657168287492'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2024/07/bat-cave.html' title='Bat Cave'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>