<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211</id><updated>2025-02-27T06:25:58.543-08:00</updated><category term="clojure python REPL ide"/><title type='text'>BizMo Diaries</title><subtitle type='html'>On the road with Global Data</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=201'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='previous' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=176&amp;max-results=25'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default?start-index=226&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1905</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>201</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-108982004582905208</id><published>2022-01-28T06:30:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-28T06:30:54.106-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Churning</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;For every thing there is a season, churn churn...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m pretty much in agreement with Glenn Greenwald regarding the neocons having conned the liberals into being neoliberals, or something along those lines.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more vocal pro-war pundits of the recent past, have been elevated on defense contractor TV, and made to sing those pro-war songs even louder, as folk music for liberals driving to work, listening to NPR.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However there&#39;s a two-way disconnect between the political grid of mayors and governors, and the Wall Street casino with arms bazaar roots.&amp;nbsp; The mayors create sister city relationships and compare notes on street camping, while the District of Columbia goes off the deep end into fighting a Qanon interpretation of world events.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not saying Qanon is winning (or whatever big lie theory), only that the general public has long since ceased to follow.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s no real logic to it, so change channels.&amp;nbsp; Leave DC to fight its own inner demons.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then what happened was: oligarchies like in the soap opera &lt;i&gt;Dallas&lt;/i&gt;, continued their battles over tax havens and business jurisdictions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Europe is somewhat afraid to compete with Russian capitalism and is using a protectionist NATO to keep the old dead horse narratives alive.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is it working?&amp;nbsp; Will the people believe? So far it is not.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fear drums over Eurasia and the rush of action, merely advertises the willingness of these people to lavish money on their own melodramas, and neglect our more serious concerns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The disconnect seems to be permanent, which doesn&#39;t preclude a somewhat business as usual attitude on the part of city governments.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Work with the truckers and universities to make life more livable for people on the city campus.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reach out to rural areas for local supply agreements.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pass the torch to a next generation, regarding agriculture, mass production, and life long learning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/108982004582905208'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/108982004582905208'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/01/churning.html' title='Churning'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8535804096442568158</id><published>2022-01-18T09:59:00.005-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-18T10:02:18.576-08:00</updated><title type='text'>MLK / FBI</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;The title refers to a new movie, which we rented from Movie Madness and watched on MLK day (yesterday).&amp;nbsp; The movie focuses on the FBI&#39;s surveillance of Martin Luther King and his associates, in connection with the former&#39;s paranoia regarding communism, a memeplex deemed controlled by the Soviet Union.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The military industrial memeplex embraced the threat of communism as its nuclear material, that which would justify all that followed, by fueling fears.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;MLK was a product of his time and not really in a position to counter the psychosis of the over-simplifiers and their HUAC.&amp;nbsp; Weak thinkers such as Nixon would later make it clear how little structure or historical information really went into this toxic blend.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One might blame Hegel in some ways.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Americans just didn&#39;t know how to deal with their own European heritage and could barely help themselves when it came to staying out of elective wars they had no real business joining.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Germany was seized with a virulent nationalism focused on a &quot;manifest destiny&quot; sensibility just as surely as any expansionist power.&amp;nbsp; When ideological ambitions express themselves in the form of contiguous landmasses called &quot;nations&quot; (to be drawn and redrawn) we get that political data layer the Fuller Projection tends to dismiss as irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The upshot is a conquered people, with Americans these days subjugated by Eastern philosophy, as much as the neo-Roman religion (heavily nationalist).&amp;nbsp; By Americans I of course as much mean the peoples of the Americas, the West.&amp;nbsp; I don&#39;t mean Anglo-Euros who carry these meme viruses and have succumbed to them, becoming creatures of the soulless corporations (animated by law).&amp;nbsp; Some of them seek enlightenment and liberation, but most seem content with their programming.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8535804096442568158'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8535804096442568158'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/01/mlk-fbi.html' title='MLK / FBI'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2223458770209292346</id><published>2022-01-10T10:54:00.003-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-10T12:45:11.248-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Four Directions</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/2f/Medicine_Wheel.png/600px-Medicine_Wheel.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/2f/Medicine_Wheel.png/600px-Medicine_Wheel.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of bellyaching goes on with regards to this concept of &quot;cultural appropriation&quot;. I do agree that one culture may seize upon the memes of another, and from the standpoint of the originator, the new uses may come across as abuses.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Are they mocking us?&quot;&amp;nbsp; Maybe.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not denying the &quot;reality&quot; of &quot;culture wars&quot; per se.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my ethnicity, we have this idea of &quot;class extends&quot; as in Java.&amp;nbsp; The equivalent notion of &quot;subclass&quot; gives rise to different mental pictures.&amp;nbsp; The &quot;extend&quot; is to expand into a wide open space, it seems, wheres &quot;to subclass&quot; since like going inward to create yet a more specialized version of something.&amp;nbsp; Both connotations have their echo in actual computer programming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having done the Wy&#39;East Lakota-based training, with sweat lodges, talking sticks, other accoutrements, especially the Medicine Wheel, I&#39;m thinking to extend it (not steal it) to mean what it already means:&amp;nbsp; the four directions.&amp;nbsp; This is not a new thought for me, but perhaps &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.io/g/synergeo/message/913&quot;&gt;my powers to propagate&lt;/a&gt; have amplified over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By &quot;four directions&quot; though, I mean &quot;in space&quot;.&amp;nbsp; Paint the four faces of a tetrahedron:&amp;nbsp; yellow, white, black, red.&amp;nbsp; Four faces face the fullness of space by dividing it into four quadrants.&amp;nbsp; We might call this &quot;the arrowhead&quot; and its four points are likewise four pointers, indicative of space&#39;s 4Dness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wherever three face colors meet, the vertex might be of the missing color.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If made of stretched skin or hide, you&#39;ll have the connotation of &quot;drum&quot; and also &quot;resonance&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2223458770209292346'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2223458770209292346'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2022/01/four-directions.html' title='Four Directions'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-582237701708052566</id><published>2021-12-20T21:09:00.010-08:00</published><updated>2021-12-20T21:23:40.753-08:00</updated><title type='text'>New Circuit Designs</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjlA5q7y9MqWcv3IePFmOqDKKTwlhqk7mxd2wCP-hxF6qnTES3dLmfMC_ajvZfPPFsbclcroqnGlFU8c6x5LLfXw9CQA_RhaBf3QWd2a8sFwtY7ZWAs7h8r0dsGrOi8tEzbXyRuczKWO2p9J8MVd4rafc3D2OOL7Hm9cf2tOZJBCIAR8CDIUA=s180&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;180&quot; data-original-width=&quot;180&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjlA5q7y9MqWcv3IePFmOqDKKTwlhqk7mxd2wCP-hxF6qnTES3dLmfMC_ajvZfPPFsbclcroqnGlFU8c6x5LLfXw9CQA_RhaBf3QWd2a8sFwtY7ZWAs7h8r0dsGrOi8tEzbXyRuczKWO2p9J8MVd4rafc3D2OOL7Hm9cf2tOZJBCIAR8CDIUA&quot; width=&quot;180&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&amp;nbsp;Here&#39;s the deal:&amp;nbsp; the core geometry in the Bucky stuff was baked enough to go mainline forty years ago and nothing much has changed on that score.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However the context is not &quot;Bucky was right about everything&quot; but &quot;this is what the guy thought, a mover and shaker in this world.&quot;&amp;nbsp; Then we look at what &quot;mover and shaker&quot; meant in his case, and the thoughts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Linus Pauling:&amp;nbsp; to have great ideas, have a lot of ideas.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lots of historical data connects to his bio; he made it easy for us to cast his foreground (private sky) against a shared backdrop (world history as theater).&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We could start with World&#39;s Fairs (Expos) and talk about &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/U_l6dVP0lFI&quot;&gt;how the Congress opted out&lt;/a&gt; of hosting any more of them within the USA.&amp;nbsp; I was taking in another Youtube on that around 3 AM last night.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We might want one in the Shire anyway, no need for Mordor to get involved (we speak in code?).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We could start with the capsomere counts in the viral nucleocapsid, should it have an icosahedral one.&amp;nbsp; Sars-2 doesn&#39;t, as many do not.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However the main thing is not to stop at domes and spheres, but to dive into the straight edged (hard nosed) concentric of polyhedrons as he conceived them, in a language game of his own devising.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was all ready to go mainline forty years ago (as already mentioned).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Said core geometry is Platonic and requires one major breakthrough insight, that our modeling of 2nd and 3rd powering didn&#39;t have to be expressed with squares and cubes.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not that the right angle choice was wrong, as if Synergetics &quot;disproves&quot; our practice.&amp;nbsp; Practices weave into forms of life, and what proves them seaworthy is the test of time, which of course involves stresses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;High school minus any Bucky stuff is not really American enough for my taste.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d expect our sprawling network to keep passing the torch, whatever that looks like.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/582237701708052566'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/582237701708052566'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/12/new-circuit-designs.html' title='New Circuit Designs'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjlA5q7y9MqWcv3IePFmOqDKKTwlhqk7mxd2wCP-hxF6qnTES3dLmfMC_ajvZfPPFsbclcroqnGlFU8c6x5LLfXw9CQA_RhaBf3QWd2a8sFwtY7ZWAs7h8r0dsGrOi8tEzbXyRuczKWO2p9J8MVd4rafc3D2OOL7Hm9cf2tOZJBCIAR8CDIUA=s72-c" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8200995769008307061</id><published>2021-11-26T08:22:00.002-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-26T08:22:17.789-08:00</updated><title type='text'>TG 2021</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been playing the Quaker card a lot more, being hellbent on pumping out some signature curriculum to my vast network of Quakerish schools, a global network, in the future.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I might be long gone, a sort of psycho-historian (parsed through Asimov&#39;s Foundation).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we had an authentic n8v American presiding, in a classic nuclear family setting.&amp;nbsp; Carol and I were the visitors.&amp;nbsp; She was able to climb the front steps on her own.&amp;nbsp; Both directions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Urners are into dogs too.&amp;nbsp; Carol has some fear of pythons, which both families also have.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8200995769008307061'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8200995769008307061'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/11/tg-2021.html' title='TG 2021'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-747740487001196687</id><published>2021-11-24T22:22:00.012-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-25T12:25:06.220-08:00</updated><title type='text'>More Quaker History</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/51677972563/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Watch Party&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Watch Party&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/51677972563_238e3ac016.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been fussing around in /cryptography lately, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/4dsolutions/elite_school/blob/master/Crypto.ipynb&quot;&gt;eliteschool/Crypto&lt;/a&gt;, the Jupyter Notebook, was not clear on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AKS_primality_test&quot;&gt;AKS primality test&lt;/a&gt;, what it is.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s still not entirely clear on that, but more because it talks about something else, relevant to primes and composites, that I take to be relevant to the proof of AKS also.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But really we&#39;re focused on Pascal&#39;s Triangle (PT), as always in &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2006/09/focal-points.html&quot;&gt;our Gnu Math curriculum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That PT property is one you likely know, if you&#39;ve been &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/HvMSRWTE2mI&quot;&gt;following Numberphile&lt;/a&gt; and other &quot;keep us current&quot; mathological type channels.&amp;nbsp; Category Theory...&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That the row number of PT evenly divides the members (other than 1 of course) on that row, if an only if that number is prime.&amp;nbsp; Skipping 1 of course.&amp;nbsp; We talk about -1 elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like row 3, 1 3 3 1 defines the prime 3, whereas 1 4 6 4 1 fails the test (row number 4 fails to divide 6 without remainder).&amp;nbsp; The Jupyter Notebook features a PT generator, written in Python, and this test as a sieve or filter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OK, that winds up my warmup. We were talking about /Crypto, where prime versus composite reigns supreme (as a distinction), so now lets segue to Elizebeth Friedman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She fell in with Shakespeare early in her career, where she sharpened her code skills and met her future husband.&amp;nbsp; They and their sponsor climbed a steep learning curve ladder and ended up becoming like another Bletchley Park eventually.&amp;nbsp; Elizebeth faced her own enigmas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my Quakerish curriculum we&#39;re linking her to Prohibition and to the early Bucky who socialized with Al Capone.&amp;nbsp; That helps sync up the timelines for for these several protagonists we&#39;ll be following.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tie-back to Shakespeare is convenient, given our Memory Palace focus (&quot;the urb it orbs&quot;).&amp;nbsp; Globe Theater architecture was about the microcosm, as well as the play within the play.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I notice Github decided to break Jupyter Notebooks linking back to their own repo as the default option.&amp;nbsp; The benefits of cloning and owning the repo locally, versus viewing it online, has just increased.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/747740487001196687'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/747740487001196687'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/11/more-quaker-history.html' title='More Quaker History'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2040135658788923203</id><published>2021-11-23T11:44:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-23T11:44:10.291-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Urbit Urbus</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/51701042574/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Urbit is Urbiquitous&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/51701042574_371209bedb_o.jpg&quot; width=&quot;471&quot; height=&quot;482&quot; alt=&quot;Urbit is Urbiquitous&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2040135658788923203'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2040135658788923203'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/11/urbit-urbus.html' title='Urbit Urbus'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6226638046068062019</id><published>2021-11-17T21:24:00.004-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-17T21:37:43.880-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Fake School</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/51684641366/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Cosmic Fishing&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Cosmic Fishing&quot; height=&quot;307&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/51684641366_36e9b5bda1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Way back in the WayBack [tm], I was saying the Clintonistas were underestimating Qanon, precisely because it went to the concerns of younger netizens, too young to vote&amp;nbsp; in fact, about predatory adult practices I needn&#39;t get into with a sophisticated audience like this one.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Yes I&#39;m talking &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2016/12/pizzagate-debate.html&quot;&gt;about Pizzagate&lt;/a&gt; and so on, you may scroll back in my blogs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These days though, and also in support of the kids, I&#39;m mocking the Q folks for the shallowness of their research at the end of the day.&amp;nbsp; From our chat session on Zoom last Saturday:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: courier; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: courier; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;10:39:45 From Kirby Urner to Everyone:&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Re conspiracy theories: The Qanons always boasted about doing their own research, following breadcrumbs, but were manifestly not good at doing that.&amp;nbsp; Even a cursory search on the web links their much vaunted “Mockingbird” to Ed Applewhite.&amp;nbsp; They don’t go there.&amp;nbsp; They’d find us. They’d lose control.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What am I talking about &quot;They&#39;d find us.&quot;?&amp;nbsp; Simply that Qanon pumps up Mockingbird as one of their dots to connect, but then fails to connect it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;C&#39;mon kids, don&#39;t be as dense as your parents, my contemporaries.&amp;nbsp; Get a clue and study more of your heritage.&amp;nbsp; The Applewhite guy retired and went on to collaborate with his boyhood hero.&amp;nbsp; Who was that again?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;C&#39;mon kids, if you&#39;re not getting time with the bash shell, ask your doctor if that&#39;s good for you.&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;In the Beginning was the Command Line&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Read it yet?&amp;nbsp; If you&#39;re in high school, has any math teacher mentioned RSA (public key crypto, but also the Republic of South Africa matters too)?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes?&amp;nbsp; Congratulations, there&#39;s hope for your high school.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seriously, in this Internet Age, you have Net right there staring you in the face, all day every day. So if your school isn&#39;t talking Graph Theory, as in nodes &amp;amp; edges, as in V + F = E + 2, then maybe stop calling it that?&amp;nbsp; Why would you call that &quot;school&quot;?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2021/11/back-to-day-camp.html&quot;&gt;Fake school&lt;/a&gt; is as real as fake news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/51685563618/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Recursive Python&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Recursive Python&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/51685563618_27440fe647.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6226638046068062019'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6226638046068062019'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/11/fake-school.html' title='Fake School'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4685377593360707443</id><published>2021-11-15T09:38:00.004-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-15T09:38:56.844-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Imported Tweet</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I would encourage Facebook and Google to leave the country before subsidizing irresponsible posers in DC and no I&amp;#39;m not talking about the recent election. So far Google hasn&amp;#39;t use WMDs &amp;quot;by mistake&amp;quot;. Whatever socially responsible investing it does, let it not be thru a faux USA.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Kirby Urner (@4DsolutionsPDX) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/4DsolutionsPDX/status/1460300463480270851?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;November 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4685377593360707443'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4685377593360707443'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/11/imported-tweet.html' title='Imported Tweet'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-417071202278469412</id><published>2021-11-06T11:06:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2021-11-06T11:13:46.265-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Revaluation of Values</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;What did Nietzsche mean by a &quot;revaluation of values&quot;?&amp;nbsp; He didn&#39;t mean we should sit around passively awaiting the new code of conduct or whatever.&amp;nbsp; The work is a personal interior undertaking, the kind of work no one seems to get paid for, yet desperately needs to get on with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take &quot;empathy&quot; for example, sometimes defined as &quot;putting oneself in an other&#39;s shoes&quot;. Normally this is seen as a positive, whereas &quot;jealousy&quot; is the name of a sin, not a virtue.&amp;nbsp; To bring &quot;empathy&quot; and &quot;jealousy&quot; closer together might seem more like opposing proton beams, bashing the grammar.&amp;nbsp; Precisely. Philosophical investigations resemble the work of CERN at some wavelengths.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For me to really wish for your lifestyle, I need to imagine it.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m jealous of your shoes, more comfortable, more durable than mine.&amp;nbsp; You have stuff that I want for myself.&amp;nbsp; I can imagine myself going through the day as you, happier and more satisfied than I am in my own life.&amp;nbsp; That all sounds like empathy to me i.e. I&#39;m putting myself in your shoes to the point of wishing I were more like you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now we might trace all the caveat neutrinos emanating from this opposition.&amp;nbsp; Lustfully imagining oneself as another, directing that much libido into a fantasy life, is a root symptom of so many pathologies, whereas working on developing empathy and compassion is more generally seen as a cure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lets define narcissism as deep empathy with one&#39;s self.&amp;nbsp; You have a lot of compassion for yourself, and in a &quot;me against the world&quot; model, this is as it should be.&amp;nbsp; The healthy ego basks in its own source of warmth and doesn&#39;t need the company of others to stay strong.&amp;nbsp; However this also sounds a lot like the description of an egoless person, if such exist.&amp;nbsp; Is your classic narcissist on the verge of enlightenment, needing only to see self sufficiency as a divine duo, a state of grace?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, mixing &quot;good&quot; with &quot;evil&quot; values in your investigations, exploring the new polarities and tensions that result, is the form of exercise.&amp;nbsp; Consider it character building.&amp;nbsp; Consider keeping a journal, perhaps even online.&amp;nbsp; Quakerism traces to some of the same roots as Emersonianism, which I speculate would be found in a Mithraic context, pre-Christianity.&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Thus Spake Zarathustra&lt;/i&gt; suggests such uber points of view.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/417071202278469412'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/417071202278469412'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/11/revaluation-of-values.html' title='Revaluation of Values'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7278855382143781545</id><published>2021-10-26T14:39:00.005-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-26T14:59:46.566-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Musings on Theme Park Planet</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;I was surfing in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/10/just-say-space.html&quot;&gt;Jungian Space&lt;/a&gt; yesterday evening, out for dinner with some heavy hitters I know or was getting to know.&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Dwaraka&lt;/i&gt; was open for indoor seating, per our current zip code protocol (not that protocols are defined at the zip code level -- I refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2015/01/expanding-radius.html&quot;&gt;Asylum District&lt;/a&gt;, here along Hawthorne Boulevard, 97214).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lets pause for a moment to cite Ken Kesey and &lt;i&gt;One Flew Over the Cuckoo&#39;s Nest&lt;/i&gt;, his novel and later a movie Ken &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2010/08/source-to-sea-columbia-river-swim-movie.html&quot;&gt;didn&#39;t much care for&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; That novel put Oregon in the map nonetheless, as thematically about mental health and/or the lack thereof.&amp;nbsp; Asylum State.&amp;nbsp; With the double-meaning of &quot;asylum&quot; as &quot;sanctuary&quot; and/or &quot;hangout&quot; and/or &quot;safe space&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What might asylum mean today?&amp;nbsp; Where might you enjoy an outdoor concert while tripping in some way, without fear of arrest, but in potential need of medical attention? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m tempted to go on about Portland&#39;s particular place in PsyWar Space (the business of the &quot;intelli-seers&quot;) but at this point lets talk about the space of meetups, newly facilitated by Zoomer culture, and also Meetup the website.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The catalysis of online meetup culture, thanks to covid and people staying at home more, trading First Life (more driving and flying) for Second Life (more virtual) conventions, has sparked an acceleration in the conversation.&amp;nbsp; New equilibria get established through communities comparing notes, and not just through owner-controlled mass social media.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m thinking here of ISEPP Wanderers meetups &lt;i&gt;52 Thinking Ideas&lt;/i&gt;, with &lt;i&gt;Thinking Society of Philadelphia&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Humanists of Greater Portland&lt;/i&gt; as supporting actors.&amp;nbsp; This was happening in my backyard, but also through related listservs and emails.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Humanists were already studying the job of ship crew worker, several weeks back.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve been looking at &lt;a href=&quot;https://controlroom.blogspot.com/2021/10/trucker-nation.html&quot;&gt;the truck driver role&lt;/a&gt; for several years myself, not as a driver myself, but as a role play designer (call it &quot;cosplay&quot; if you must).&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea here is to apply &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/jylee_sidlab/dt2015-class02&quot;&gt;design principles&lt;/a&gt; (ala &lt;i&gt;The Design Way&lt;/i&gt;) to lifestyle design, wherein lifestyles contain their workflows, such as truck driving, heavy equipment operating, jet engine development and so on.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The so-called &quot;dirty jobs&quot; are not outside academic experience, per the polytechnical institute model.&amp;nbsp; Include housework in the above.&amp;nbsp; The focus of Fuller&#39;s Dymaxion House was its unique particularity along one dimension, but its function in family life along another:&amp;nbsp; as shelter against the mortgage holders and the related slave driver regimen of both parents working (or lose your home), kids abandoned (to daycare shelters).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In place of polytechnic, think polymathic just as readily.&amp;nbsp; The &quot;maths&quot; in &quot;polymath&quot; come from &quot;mowings&quot; etymologyically, i.e. the condensed harvest from any &quot;field&quot;.&amp;nbsp; The Silicon Forest is polymathic and its curricula are designed accordingly.&amp;nbsp; Like check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikieducator.org/Digital_Math&quot;&gt;mine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How this all connects around on Planet Jung is &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2021/10/the-design-way-and-dissipation.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Design Way&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Harold Nelson and &lt;span class=&quot;a-size-large&quot; id=&quot;formatSelectorHeader&quot;&gt;Erik Stolterman
        &lt;/span&gt;invokes James Hillman and other Jungians, and dwells on the importance of the unconscious in creating &quot;organic&quot; solutions that are &quot;with the grain&quot; of a situation.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A commitment to comprehensivity (polymathy) gets the ball rolling, providing a wholesome starting context, with experienced judgement suggesting when to transition from analysis to implementation. &quot;Analysis paralysis&quot; is a stalling out to avoid, although maybe not in sciences wherein simply describing the status quo is the final objective. &quot;Paralysis&quot; might mean &quot;arrived at the station&quot; in that case (mission accomplished).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harold Nelson doesn&#39;t use the term &quot;Feng Shui&quot; that I could find, but I&#39;m sure many of his followers do.&amp;nbsp; On Planet Jung (in the space of depth psychology) we permit Alchemy, Feng Shui and Astrology (interconnected &quot;failed paradigms&quot; and/or &quot;pseudo-sciences&quot; to some), to perpetuate some of their ideals, not as scientific truths, but as intentional associations and mnemonic systemic structures of potential value upon selective amplification.&amp;nbsp; We live as players, not as cogs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Design Way&lt;/i&gt; posits Truths, Realities, Ideals as orthogonal axes.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ideals must be served by Truths in the long run, and the Realities provide the necessary feedback, without which steering would not occur.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Are we leaving the ideal path because our truths are wrong, or because we have been lazy in updating our truth tables?&quot;&amp;nbsp; We sometimes get behind in telling the truth.&amp;nbsp; Reality overtakes our storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, if you don&#39;t bother to have at least these three independent axes in your model, you may more easily become disoriented, as you&#39;ll confuse ideals with facts in need of proof, or special case realities, with what&#39;s true in general.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whatever the case, keep in mind your worldview is (a) yours to keep designing and (b) never finished.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What would Disneyland be without all the &quot;fairy tales&quot; it weaves together using some of the highest tech of the day?&amp;nbsp; Even &quot;humans making a success of themselves&quot; (Fuller) is but a fairy tale we may embrace, or laugh off as somehow beneath or beyond our ken.&amp;nbsp; Did we have some better story in mind then?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does choosing to remain oblivious make us devils?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Humanity bereft of any cause for hope might pass for the subhuman-tormented, as lost souls, in some dark novel (science fiction?) about mental illness.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Ill to the point of losing our humanity&quot; reminds us of the benefits of getting our collective mental health back.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Humanity&quot; still registers as a positive, even if, as creatures (monsters), we abandon our ideals and reconcile ourselves to cruelty and inhumanity as our lot.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Will the pendulum now swing the other way then?&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s always the hope that these dystopian moods are but cyclic.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7278855382143781545'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7278855382143781545'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/10/musings-on-theme-park-planet.html' title='Musings on Theme Park Planet'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1435930080832191939</id><published>2021-10-18T10:30:00.006-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-18T10:30:36.637-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Just Say Space</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Should I write a memo or something?  I just had a realization in marketing space.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;CMO here, Chief Marketing Officer for CSN (Coffee Shops Network). So why don&#39;t I post on that blog instead?  Isn&#39;t this company business?  Yes and no.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The realization is this:  our marketing is being done for us when it comes to &quot;namespaces&quot; (pointing back to PSF Python, see below), in that the pros are just saying &quot;space&quot; and &quot;spaces&quot; and have been for some time.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&#39;s OK to drop the &quot;name&quot; in front.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&quot;I work in the space of advertising&quot; sounds about right.  As a phrase in the new vernacular, and also what I do in CMO mode.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I promulgate the idea of (design a space for) playing games for charity, stealing the acceptability of church bingo and drawing from casino space for some of my aesthetics, not to mention video lottery games.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You choose where the money goes, from a menu of options.  Build a profile in the process.  Be a hero.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Actually that&#39;s more spelling out a business model, but leaving out the circuit diagrams I&#39;ve buried at the CSN blog, to keep patent trolls at bay.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There&#39;s a bigger picture around designer giving, the strategic application of funds to specific scenes in the various movies we&#39;re making.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now I&#39;m starting to wear my Asylum City hat, which is not that different when it comes to emphasizing prototyping.  Asylum City draws experience from refugee camps, outdoor music venues (sound stages), the Oregon Country Fair, and even Occupy Portland (OPDX). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So that&#39;s the memo: just saying space is OK in this space i.e. when we&#39;re talking about the various namespaces we&#39;re operating with or within.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;=== &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: courier;&quot;&gt;(base) Kirbys-MacBook-Pro:elite_school mac$ python -m this&lt;br /&gt;The Zen of Python, by Tim Peters&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Beautiful is better than ugly.&lt;br /&gt;Explicit is better than implicit.&lt;br /&gt;Simple is better than complex.&lt;br /&gt;Complex is better than complicated.&lt;br /&gt;Flat is better than nested.&lt;br /&gt;Sparse is better than dense.&lt;br /&gt;Readability counts.&lt;br /&gt;Special cases aren&#39;t special enough to break the rules.&lt;br /&gt;Although practicality beats purity.&lt;br /&gt;Errors should never pass silently.&lt;br /&gt;Unless explicitly silenced.&lt;br /&gt;In the face of ambiguity, refuse the temptation to guess.&lt;br /&gt;There should be one-- and preferably only one --obvious way to do it.&lt;br /&gt;Although that way may not be obvious at first unless you&#39;re Dutch.&lt;br /&gt;Now is better than never.&lt;br /&gt;Although never is often better than *right* now.&lt;br /&gt;If the implementation is hard to explain, it&#39;s a bad idea.&lt;br /&gt;If the implementation is easy to explain, it may be a good idea.&lt;br /&gt;Namespaces are one honking great idea -- let&#39;s do more of those!&lt;br /&gt;(base) Kirbys-MacBook-Pro:elite_school mac$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1435930080832191939'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1435930080832191939'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/10/just-say-space.html' title='Just Say Space'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2479421234476756118</id><published>2021-10-14T14:38:00.008-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-14T15:05:09.279-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Trucking and Social Media</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/x8k8k1Mia2I&quot; style=&quot;background-image: url(https://i.ytimg.com/vi/x8k8k1Mia2I/hqdefault.jpg);&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Some readers might be surprised to learn that I&#39;ve long used the cab of the long hauler truck as my paradigm PWS (personal workspace) &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2021/06/tiktok-meets-gst.html&quot;&gt;in GST&lt;/a&gt;, even more than the cubicle.&amp;nbsp; The cab of a truck is a work-study space, and driving may take fierce concentration.&amp;nbsp; You may also sleep in your study carrel.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The Trucker Exchange Program is a meme more than a program, even if I&#39;ve taken inspiration from such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2013/01/thirsters-gather.html&quot;&gt;Bob Textor&lt;/a&gt;, whom I didn&#39;t know well, but I joined his drinking party anyway.&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Thirsters&lt;/i&gt; at McMenamins.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;He had to do with sensitizing the budding Peace Corps to the importance of Anthropology (the A in STEAM says no one but me).&amp;nbsp; In terms of diplomatic corps, State Department types, I knew my dad of course, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2009/03/chauffeur-duty.html&quot;&gt;James Lambert&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Since I&#39;m &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2018/05/truckers-for-peace.html&quot;&gt;propagating memes&lt;/a&gt; more than I&#39;m administering program, I don&#39;t have to worry about taking credit for the rising self esteem among truckers, where &quot;self&quot; stands for &quot;role&quot; i.e. &quot;job&quot;.&amp;nbsp; The idea of a &quot;role&quot; is more appealing I think.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Theater is it.&amp;nbsp; World Game.&amp;nbsp; A play within a play within a play... Disney beat me to it, with cast members instead of employees. We see that holds all the way up, to Top Mouse.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The romance of &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/bLJ_KgSEFtU&quot;&gt;the trucking lifestyle&lt;/a&gt;, if only as a glimmer in the Eye of Possibilities, is enough to keep the would-be future trucker generations circling.&amp;nbsp; Let&#39;s make it a reality while we can. Like while we&#39;re not truckers, in my case, but active truckers may join us too.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;m some member of the movie crew in one scenario, following some experienced long haulers doing OBOR (Silk Road) or something in Africa, or Texas, or in Oregon or Australia.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I help with curriculum around trucking, to provide continuity, helping to design a global exchange regarding work-study opportunities.&amp;nbsp; The job (role) involves more tourism and diplomacy.&amp;nbsp; We depend on truckers to work things out.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2479421234476756118'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2479421234476756118'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/10/trucking-and-social-media.html' title='Trucking and Social Media'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/x8k8k1Mia2I/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-8392593971605780494</id><published>2021-10-12T09:12:00.005-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-12T09:21:13.142-07:00</updated><title type='text'>A Battle for Market Share</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;The joke about 5G is that &quot;it isn&#39;t about mind control&quot; whereas of course it is.&amp;nbsp; Not in a tin foil hat sense, but in a marketing sense. The FCC needs you to be OK with 5G, as does Qualcomm, and really, what&#39;s your problem with it?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you intend to obstruct the right of free peoples to make use of those frequencies?&amp;nbsp; We already use them, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newenglandhistoricalsociety.com/percy-spencer-melts-chocolate-bar-invents-microwave-oven/&quot;&gt;for cooking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PR maze makes it look like the anti-5Gers have a problem understanding the difference between nuclear bomb type fallout radiation, and the kind we all use to listen to the BBC on FM.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;5G is way down below the visible spectrum with radar, microwave, and other ice cream melting frequencies.&amp;nbsp; 5G has nothing to do with gamma rays.&amp;nbsp; The G does &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; stand for Gamma, you sillies.&amp;nbsp; You conspiracy theorists who think people haven&#39;t done their homework.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That other animals besides humans might already be making use of invisible frequencies is in many circles considered balderdash, except in the sense that loud sonar or rocket blasts could break the hearing and peace of mind, to the point of self destruction, of various species.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If SpaceX blasts the surrounding turtle space with trauma and drama, it&#39;s not a given the sacred species will &quot;bounce back&quot;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The science will tell us, if and when, but by then it may be too late.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Research seems to show that animals brought up in the presence of 5G suffer no ill effects presuming just a trickle of power.&amp;nbsp; Blasting power through devices not meant to handle it, usually causes damage, to phones and IoT devices included, not just nervous systems (wiring is wiring).&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ear drums get damaged when subjected to 2G rock and roll (when the giant amps and speakers made their debut, and kids stood right up next to &#39;em).&amp;nbsp; Stand right in front of a radar at the wrong time, and you&#39;re &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/news-room/q-a-detail/radiation-radar&quot;&gt;asking for trouble&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But are all the concerns around next generation telecommunications owing to concerns about brains in a radio frequencies ocean?&amp;nbsp; Not at all.&amp;nbsp; Other paranoias run just as deep if not deeper.&amp;nbsp; Stay tuned.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8392593971605780494'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/8392593971605780494'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/10/a-battle-for-market-share.html' title='A Battle for Market Share'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-6625915930513056356</id><published>2021-10-09T09:33:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-09T10:21:56.997-07:00</updated><title type='text'>City of Transients</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/51513793233/in/album-72157719899262313/&quot; title=&quot;Alpha Helix&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Alpha Helix&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/51513793233_4ae544458a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the ordinary English I inherited from birth, a &quot;transient&quot; is someone who hangs out around the Greyhound bus station, not really from around here, and soon to move on (with our encouragement, &quot;we&quot; being the people who live here).&amp;nbsp; You could use &quot;transient&quot; interchangeably with &quot;undesirable&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The revenge of the &quot;transients&quot; came with &quot;tourists&quot; who would come through laden with the gift of a hard currency. One&#39;s role in life was now to be authentic, loyal to one&#39;s traditions, so the outsiders could gawk at one&#39;s behaving so quaintly. The Amish could set up a roadside gift shop, and get the hard cash needed to procure from &quot;the grid&quot; (or &quot;the English&quot; in their jargon).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Transient City&quot; is more fun than just a giant dreary Greyhound bus station, however I admire the Greyhound brand and so wouldn&#39;t mind working it in.&amp;nbsp; &quot;Disneyland for Bums&quot; doesn&#39;t get it right either, because a Wanderer is possibly a college professor, someone else skilled, serious, hard working.&amp;nbsp; Among the bums be anti-bums. The quantum physics of &quot;particles in transit&quot; includes a representative percentage of every human variety (even the rare types).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m fine with working backward from the scandalized of the future.&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/i&gt; (Spielberg) does this with the anti-AI circus, wherein the anti-AI bash the AIs (the robots). My time-tunnel scenario was through the 1960s and &lt;i&gt;Woodstock&lt;/i&gt;. Harlem had a blow-out around the same time (a giant party).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Music is core to Asylum City, as is the willing participation of government agencies ala Oregon&#39;s &lt;i&gt;Vortex 1&lt;/i&gt; festival, brought to my attention by Alan Potkin and tracked by me ever since.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;i&gt;Oregon Country Fair&lt;/i&gt; in Eugene, Oregon is another model.&amp;nbsp; Expand that to include a whole suburb of a larger City, with sound stages and FM radio bubbles, and lots of internet with storefront gamer shops.&amp;nbsp; Wait, didn&#39;t I just describe the 1990s?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where are the sports stadia and intramural events?&amp;nbsp; At the schools of course.&amp;nbsp; Scholars and athletes are encouraged to cavort, and even be the same persons if possible (a Greek ideal).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The transient nature of tourists coming here, to live awhile, then move on, based on new connections and situations, leads to a camaraderie one finds among tourists.&amp;nbsp; Some are too full of stories to ever shut up about and are hard to be with, especially if one is bursting with stories as well.&amp;nbsp; Others have an endless supply of travel tips and whet the appetite of Asylum seekers to get out, to see the world, to quit the venue of Wanderers, Flaneurs, Tourists and rejoin a more static community, a Terminus (station, placement).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not all my visions of Asylum City are this sprawling.&amp;nbsp; As I write, I find myself picturing current situations, the shanty towns, the refugee camps, stretching for miles.&amp;nbsp; How do we shape these into more festival centric &quot;tourist traps&quot; destined to drain, eventually, of those truly wishing to move away for awhile (they deserve a vacation), while serving as strange attractors for others.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those who leave, may return (e.g. to Gaza), to see how a steady flow of tourism may shape a place that&#39;s ideal for transients.&amp;nbsp; Airport transit lounges provide a clay for our imaginative play.&amp;nbsp; Ambient Music for Airports.&amp;nbsp; Hello Brian Eno.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6625915930513056356'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/6625915930513056356'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/10/city-of-transients.html' title='City of Transients'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5656793100777971735</id><published>2021-10-03T14:41:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-03T14:41:50.310-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Scheherazad Numbers</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;On the Zoom call yesterday, with simultaneous chat (text dialog), I found myself weighing in on what I thought Bucky Fuller was up to with these uber-composite numbers, pregnant with prime factors, and going for a large number of digits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re used to large digit integers from cryptography these days, and the idea of a &quot;wrap around&quot; gear wherein our composite is the modulus for totatives, co-primes to N.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Scheherazad Numbers would have those too, but maybe not as many as we&#39;d expect (depending who &quot;we&quot; are), given their size.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Flash to the Antikythera mechanism, reconstructed from ancient blueprints (a rusted specimen, subjected to X-ray analysis), and we find a gearworks up to tracking local astrophysical phenomena.&amp;nbsp; Integers can do it pretty well, if at high enough frequency.&amp;nbsp; So could a computerized Antikythera with&amp;nbsp;Scheherazad Number limits to precision, hold its own?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The theory includes trig tables and all manner of digital operation, within the confines of this high frequency integer space, however expressed as a decimal.&amp;nbsp; The Numbers provide a degree of resolution, without dictating a specific scale, much as RGB provides &quot;millions of colors&quot; and no more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Buckyverse we have this &quot;nature is not using pi&quot; trope, which stands for the whole phenomenological argument over whether pi has trillions of digits of significance in any future physics, or does Planck insure a limit on precision / certainty (Heisenberg too)?&amp;nbsp; Bucky comes down on the side of uber-precision being attainable, but infinite precision being the fetish of infinitists, a school of thought he&#39;s pitted against.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, nature gets through the day without needing our trillion digits computer generated versions of &quot;pi in theory&quot;, as fun as this target is to reach for.&amp;nbsp; Incommensurability is a real phenomenon sure enough. I don&#39;t think of Synergetics as &quot;in denial&quot; vs-a-vis what Euclid proved:&amp;nbsp; that the 2nd root of two could never fully resolve as some p/q with p, q integers.&amp;nbsp; Rationals have their limited exactitude, but then what doesn&#39;t in phenomenological space and time?&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5656793100777971735'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5656793100777971735'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/10/scheherazad-numbers.html' title='Scheherazad Numbers'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-7265822523638542032</id><published>2021-09-26T14:54:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-26T16:18:33.994-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Front Burner / Back Burner</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/51520520838/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Figurate Numbers in Julia&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Figurate Numbers in Julia&quot; height=&quot;368&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/51520520838_4d94854e7c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;replit with Julia and OEIS number sequences&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My pedagogy around teaching any computer language is to have the target language e.g. Python on the front burner but then compare and contrast with one or more back burner languages e.g. Julia, Clojure...&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://replit.com/@EliteSchool/Sequence-City-Julia#main.jl&quot;&gt;Replit makes it easy&lt;/a&gt; to walk my talk in this respect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m eager to demonstrate starting a new Jupyter Notebook and having a choice among languages. Ju for Julia, Pyt for Python, Er for R.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The focus is ball packing:  triangular and square numbers (figurate on a plain (plane)); tetrahedral and &lt;a href=&quot;https://oeis.org/A005901&quot;&gt;cuboctahedral&lt;/a&gt; (= icosahedral) in space.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A student is co-developing a lexical skill (coding language) with a graphical skill (visualizing balls packing in space).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg9O2CxL7sCPSWzwnJokpj_fTCdalc9WOFuZavdQRaFmoefmU1sQDT3s2fkA-AAdfXRO7tj1reKCJ-6bpcHvrEFXx4PB_RUACKBvCEVPS_FyrXfSOulvFNcZhce4axI8d9uv-uY/s1373/cuboid_project_replit2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;755&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1373&quot; height=&quot;220&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg9O2CxL7sCPSWzwnJokpj_fTCdalc9WOFuZavdQRaFmoefmU1sQDT3s2fkA-AAdfXRO7tj1reKCJ-6bpcHvrEFXx4PB_RUACKBvCEVPS_FyrXfSOulvFNcZhce4axI8d9uv-uY/w400-h220/cuboid_project_replit2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Python replit and &lt;a href=&quot;https://oeis.org/A005901&quot;&gt;OEIS A005901&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg4iBbgygjre5YA-SRBJJz7MHie3M1Ll0frY9CotFfvxW0xb9qJjUlc8wpiClrXDv-jNKBIGGf5khcPiXcGn2-KTuKnhJHge4gDQtcDBUA6QZ3v5I8XF_8rI6A0Fivxfel6u-se/s225/cubanim.gif&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;210&quot; data-original-width=&quot;225&quot; height=&quot;210&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg4iBbgygjre5YA-SRBJJz7MHie3M1Ll0frY9CotFfvxW0xb9qJjUlc8wpiClrXDv-jNKBIGGf5khcPiXcGn2-KTuKnhJHge4gDQtcDBUA6QZ3v5I8XF_8rI6A0Fivxfel6u-se/s0/cubanim.gif&quot; width=&quot;225&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This way we get &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grunch.net/synergetics/octet.html&quot;&gt;an algebra-geometry bridge&lt;/a&gt; before (independently of) a coordinate system (which comes next).&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7265822523638542032'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/7265822523638542032'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/09/front-burner-back-burner.html' title='Front Burner / Back Burner'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg9O2CxL7sCPSWzwnJokpj_fTCdalc9WOFuZavdQRaFmoefmU1sQDT3s2fkA-AAdfXRO7tj1reKCJ-6bpcHvrEFXx4PB_RUACKBvCEVPS_FyrXfSOulvFNcZhce4axI8d9uv-uY/s72-w400-h220-c/cuboid_project_replit2.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-1176889123710679517</id><published>2021-09-14T16:35:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-14T16:40:01.422-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Bizmo Redesign</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgWFsiRpoemHEAtrln-QmibrXdBo6mnRAzGC7v5i8mzhrB9ZY1AnXXydTMdfK4s0oHHeVMSPrEOycbwHgXrarlSH51rFHzQdJfXqVayscaPZ8OPL2Xtk9jhJi0WGB2UAN2Hk9Wf/s838/bizmo_uhaul_design.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;838&quot; data-original-width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgWFsiRpoemHEAtrln-QmibrXdBo6mnRAzGC7v5i8mzhrB9ZY1AnXXydTMdfK4s0oHHeVMSPrEOycbwHgXrarlSH51rFHzQdJfXqVayscaPZ8OPL2Xtk9jhJi0WGB2UAN2Hk9Wf/w344-h400/bizmo_uhaul_design.jpg&quot; width=&quot;344&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, humorous.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1176889123710679517'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/1176889123710679517'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/09/bizmo-redesign.html' title='Bizmo Redesign'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgWFsiRpoemHEAtrln-QmibrXdBo6mnRAzGC7v5i8mzhrB9ZY1AnXXydTMdfK4s0oHHeVMSPrEOycbwHgXrarlSH51rFHzQdJfXqVayscaPZ8OPL2Xtk9jhJi0WGB2UAN2Hk9Wf/s72-w344-h400-c/bizmo_uhaul_design.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-426700350279844984</id><published>2021-09-08T13:25:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-08T13:25:41.434-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Critical Path</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/dq6gAULKstU&quot; style=&quot;background-image: url(https://i.ytimg.com/vi/dq6gAULKstU/hqdefault.jpg);&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We discussed &lt;a href=&quot;https://englishrussia.com/2016/03/09/the-mysterious-story-of-russian-rogue-typhoon-submarine-aircraft-carrier/&quot;&gt;this silly story&lt;/a&gt;: science fiction about a rogue Soviet branch of the KGB that leaked about its rogue activities to Bucky, who shared them in &lt;i&gt;Critical Path&lt;/i&gt;, during our meetup the other day.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just kidding. Bucky has a similar weapon, a submarine aircraft carrier, but not quite like we see in this toy design.&amp;nbsp; Bucky is an experienced cold warrior and gives Russian intelligence a level of credibility.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/426700350279844984'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/426700350279844984'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/09/critical-path.html' title='Critical Path'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/dq6gAULKstU/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-4367706169844592559</id><published>2021-08-22T12:57:00.001-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-22T12:57:32.114-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Americana</title><content type='html'>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEj74eyBgePUXVOiy5L9OaSLQCu_ZVUqOMw9ziLXObUdbt3CPhZ_lLG-5BI_H_PAGN_NO44lfYWiPEXMswlHXOwa9i81am2C5briOZTKNNJ1zNLcoCTTip_LzhWyPZ7LUkdexm-R/s474/bell_kite_flying.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;359&quot; data-original-width=&quot;474&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEj74eyBgePUXVOiy5L9OaSLQCu_ZVUqOMw9ziLXObUdbt3CPhZ_lLG-5BI_H_PAGN_NO44lfYWiPEXMswlHXOwa9i81am2C5briOZTKNNJ1zNLcoCTTip_LzhWyPZ7LUkdexm-R/s16000/bell_kite_flying.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/36414328814/in/album-72157686718676603/&quot; title=&quot;C6XTY Aloft&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/4339/36414328814_f218834e5e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;C6XTY Aloft&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4367706169844592559'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/4367706169844592559'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/08/americana.html' title='Americana'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEj74eyBgePUXVOiy5L9OaSLQCu_ZVUqOMw9ziLXObUdbt3CPhZ_lLG-5BI_H_PAGN_NO44lfYWiPEXMswlHXOwa9i81am2C5briOZTKNNJ1zNLcoCTTip_LzhWyPZ7LUkdexm-R/s72-c/bell_kite_flying.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-2582803627209816475</id><published>2021-08-15T10:57:00.008-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-15T11:22:32.839-07:00</updated><title type='text'>The Lobbyist</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyurner/5646223789/in/photolist-9ARms9-drcjLw-9AWnC2&quot; title=&quot;Making Math&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Making Math&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/5029/5646223789_2b76020951.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
I used to blog about myself as a &quot;lobbyist&quot; which probably conjures images of living the high life and lunching with high level mucky mucks. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As it turns out, I did have a consulting gig with Associated Oregon Industries (AOI), directly across from the legislature in Salem. They want the rule makers to know: &quot;we&#39;re watching you like a hawk&quot; (paraphrase). Me? I was a lowly application developer, writing Visual FoxPro for their LAN.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyway, as a lobbyist I was in league with those pushing &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wikieducator.org/Digital_Math&quot;&gt;digital mathematics&lt;/a&gt;&quot; as an alternative way to fulfill math requirements. The Silicon Forest economy is all about bits and bytes, so the idea was to convert an old and rotting vocational track, into a more computer science like track, and let students opt out of college prep calculus and go through something more like engineering (cue Terry). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What really happened is the code school economy grew up between high schools and universities. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After the 20- and 30-somethings decide they&#39;re sick of low pay grunt work, they raise their sights to more computer skills for better income, the trophy being &quot;full stack engineer&quot;. The industry itself (picture old Chamber of Commerce) will certify you&#39;re job-ready, no need for an expensive four year degree from some dot ee dee yu.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If we think of life as a game of &lt;i&gt;Snakes &amp;amp; Ladders&lt;/i&gt;, we know it&#39;s good to find ladders and climb them. The snakes have a way of sneaking up and providing themselves. No work necessary, to ride a slide.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fast forward to today and I have a bevy of pre high school kids, on the brink of high school, and I&#39;m bagging up all of high school math, as I learned it, and mixing it up with more discrete / digital / computer science type stuff, per my former &quot;career&quot; as a lobbyist, and feeding it back to them. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;JupyterLab, Python, crypto, group and number theory... I call it &quot;lambda calc&quot; (with real lambda calc a core logic) in contrast with the &quot;delta calc&quot; of Leibniz and Newton. They&#39;re both math tracks through high school, per my chalkboard diagrams of the curriculum.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m accelerating at high speed into what I see as a bright future for schools that don&#39;t have to compromise as much, when it comes to their certifications.  I picture those Quaker boarding schools, but add much higher tech (electric ATVs) and better animals (like we have here in Oregon).</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2582803627209816475'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/2582803627209816475'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/08/the-lobbyist.html' title='The Lobbyist'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5889734672510361793</id><published>2021-07-31T18:54:00.005-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-01T10:54:28.797-07:00</updated><title type='text'>From My Outbox</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span face=&quot;arial, helvetica, sans-serif&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Here&#39;s an exercise.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll do two exhibits (think of World Game Museum), one connecting Bucky into the Humanities, the other bridging to Sciences more, pursuant to your question. I&#39;ll try to keep it pithy.&amp;nbsp; Anyone might do this exercise, thereby strengthening the IVM Bridge.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Humanities&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Allegra liked&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Pound Era&lt;/i&gt;, she told me.&amp;nbsp; I think in the early days we all thought what we needed was a next Hugh Kenner, someone of high literary caliber.&amp;nbsp; Ed expressed strong affinity for Kenner as well, and maybe tried to be the missing literary figure in writing&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Paradise Mislaid&lt;/i&gt;, tackling that biggest question: what is life exactly?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;However, before closing the book on these connections, we should remember the circumstances of Pound&#39;s era:&amp;nbsp; he was repatriated in shackles having been caged by the US Army for his joining the Italian fascists and broadcasting their worldview on radio.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;He faced the death penalty, but so many of his friends were in high places and they managed to get him committed to a mental hospital instead.&amp;nbsp; For like twelve years.&amp;nbsp; After which he went back to Italy, from when we get that&amp;nbsp;&lt;a data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://static01.nyt.com/images/2013/07/24/t-magazine/24rupani-spoleto-slide-IZEO/24rupani-spoleto-slide-IZEO-superJumbo.jpg&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1627857298623000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNETfQOM0wZFJWDZEK5N5QYLWA7QTw&quot; href=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2013/07/24/t-magazine/24rupani-spoleto-slide-IZEO/24rupani-spoleto-slide-IZEO-superJumbo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;color: #1155cc;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;famous Bucky-Ezra picture&lt;/a&gt;, Noguchi there too.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;I&#39;ve speculated that one of &quot;those in high places&quot; who helped keep Ezra&#39;s living situation at St. Elizabeth&#39;s remain livable all those years, was cold warrior James Jesus Angleton.&amp;nbsp; Ezra was allowed to entertain, and did.&amp;nbsp; James &lt;a href=&quot;https://collections.library.yale.edu/catalog/17122519&quot;&gt;in his younger days&lt;/a&gt; had traveled to Italy and met Ezra then, before Mussolini and all that rot. Angleton then published a poetry mag,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.theoccidentalobserver.net/2010/04/29/james-angleton-and-ezra-pound/&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1627857298623000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEYdGWyLcSkk3Bgqr8nZXmsqywItg&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theoccidentalobserver.net/2010/04/29/james-angleton-and-ezra-pound/&quot; style=&quot;color: #1155cc;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;named&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Furioso&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, with Ezra&#39;s input.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;A lot in the Angleton file is still under wraps I&amp;nbsp;gather, as an&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Intercept&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;reporter discovered recently, hoping to score a story.&amp;nbsp; Georgetown University had the papers by then.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://theintercept.com/2016/04/25/how-the-cia-writes-history/&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1627857298623000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHaMxW-anuppR_orAIybI8KdmMM9Q&quot; href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2016/04/25/how-the-cia-writes-history/&quot; style=&quot;color: #1155cc;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The article says&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;they were originally curated by another CIA guy, by the name of Ed Applewhite.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;I uncovered and shared in my Youtube channel how the CIA has&amp;nbsp;&lt;a data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.cia.gov/static/a0c34085dfe487b73cc90c8a92bb077d/oss-ho-chi-minh.pdf&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1627857298623000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEC3MLIs-KJ0RWtz-aX2weLr5ok3w&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cia.gov/static/a0c34085dfe487b73cc90c8a92bb077d/oss-ho-chi-minh.pdf&quot; style=&quot;color: #1155cc;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a document on file&lt;/a&gt;, with Buckminster Fuller in a footnote, for having recommended for service a British journalist.&amp;nbsp; Mission: contact Ho Chi Minh and secure his cooperation against the Japanese.&amp;nbsp; This was before the great betrayal, as some would see it, which made HCM public enemy number one.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;gmail_quote&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; border-left: 1px solid rgb(204, 204, 204); color: #222222; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small; margin: 0px 0px 0px 0.8ex; padding-left: 1ex;&quot;&gt;“Fenn’s was the only name [Gordon] would agree to.” Charles Fenn, born in the United Kingdom, emigrated to the United States in his early twenties. He became a news photographer and journalist; joined the Associated Press in 1941; and covered the war in North Africa and Asia, including the Japanese invasion of Burma. In 1943, in New York, Buckminster Fuller,&amp;nbsp;an advisor to OSS, recruited him. He was commissioned as a Marine lieutenant and sent to Burma to run MO operations, in which he excelled. In June 1944, he was sent to China, where his duties expanded to include intelligence collection operations under the cover of AGFRTS.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; face=&quot;arial, helvetica, sans-serif&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;Source: Bartholomew-Feis, The OSS and Ho Chi Minh, 96&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Sciences&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Why was C60 named &quot;buckminsterfullerene&quot;?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Sir Harold Kroto, who shares a Nobel Prize for its discovery, tells the story&amp;nbsp;&lt;a data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/08/hp4e-continued.html&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1627857298623000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFvq5kjnXRbr-Ultd3xAkeiVfddFQ&quot; href=&quot;https://worldgame.blogspot.com/2016/08/hp4e-continued.html&quot; style=&quot;color: #1155cc;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;in my blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_default&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;[ blog post snipped ]&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5889734672510361793'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5889734672510361793'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/07/from-my-outbox.html' title='From My Outbox'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5460947792710296667</id><published>2021-07-23T21:06:00.002-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-23T21:06:20.254-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Orientation for New Recruits (School of Tomorrow)</title><content type='html'>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/aQrfXgtOHXg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5460947792710296667'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5460947792710296667'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/07/orientation-for-new-recruits-school-of.html' title='Orientation for New Recruits (School of Tomorrow)'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/aQrfXgtOHXg/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-5119723976151150407</id><published>2021-07-20T09:43:00.004-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-20T10:10:54.445-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Rules of the Road</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;In our day and age, it&#39;s push&lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot;&gt;​-​&lt;/span&gt;button simple to &lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot;&gt;​&quot;​&lt;/span&gt;hit record&lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot;&gt;​&quot;​&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;and, without anyone else on the call &lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot;&gt;​being notified&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot;&gt;​and ​&lt;/span&gt;the video meetup gets saved to storage media.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;I&#39;m not necessarily talking about the host or moderator making a recording, in which case others might see a pulsing red dot or other signifier, reminding them a recording is happening.&amp;nbsp; On the contrary, when any random person on the call hits record, that person gets a copy of the screen action, without raising any flags.&amp;nbsp; What happens to the recording after that?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Grateful Dead&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;were well aware of this issue at their concerts.&amp;nbsp; Anyone could tape the event, with the new devices.&amp;nbsp; Their policy was &quot;go ahead&quot; rather than to try policing and even punishing those creating, and even selling, &quot;bootleg&quot; tapes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;We have the same situation with television.&amp;nbsp; I have the ability to record whatever is coming over the &quot;telly&quot; (UK) or &quot;TV&quot; (USA).&amp;nbsp; I still have older VHS equipment able to do this.&amp;nbsp; Nowadays more people use DVR.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;One motivation for recording TV shows is &quot;time shifting&quot; i.e. the programs get broadcast at time X, but you&#39;d rather watch them at time Y.&amp;nbsp; You may also wish to watch them more than once.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;​Another motivation is mashups.&amp;nbsp; With raw material from several sources, an editor might cobble together overview reviews of specific online conferences, each with multiple venues (channels, tracks).&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot;&gt;Perhaps the audio track is supplied by some narrator providing a personal view of the activities.&amp;nbsp; Videos from &lt;i&gt;Burning Man&lt;/i&gt; have this flavor.​ A chief attraction of &lt;i&gt;Burning Man&lt;/i&gt;, a major spectacle, is the opportunity to take and make videos.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;The awkward approach is to let these new technological superpowers go unacknowledged and then, after the fact, invent rules and policies designed to rein them in.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;Do others on the call have to promise not to record unofficially?&amp;nbsp; &lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot;&gt;​Must they sign an NDA (non-disclosure agreement)?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;Do we insist that only those with hosting privileges have the right to hit a record button?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;When do we grapple with such questions?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;The hosting body might reserve the right to produce the &quot;official&quot; version of the content, perhaps later edited, yet explain to participants, including invited guests, the possibility of &quot;unofficial&quot; taping by anyone on the call.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;The same hosting body might decide to release no official recording whatsoever.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;What if excerpts from unofficial recordings make it to public forums?&amp;nbsp; Is this a travesty, a transgression?&amp;nbsp; What were the rules ahead of time?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;In this day and age of rapidly evolving technology, it&#39;s a mistake to assume we all share the same codes of conduct and that it&#39;s OK to take for granted specific practices&lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot;&gt;​, as if we&#39;re all on the same page by default.​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: inherit;&quot;&gt;The past is&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;a sufficient guide to create the future, which is why explicit discussion and hammering out of the rules ahead of time is essential for any organization planning to wade into th&lt;span class=&quot;gmail_default&quot;&gt;​is new​&lt;/span&gt; set of realities I call Cyberia (cyberspace).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5119723976151150407'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/5119723976151150407'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/07/rules-of-road.html' title='Rules of the Road'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10416211.post-18224424122394995</id><published>2021-07-18T14:45:00.003-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-18T21:47:42.068-07:00</updated><title type='text'>On My Radar</title><content type='html'>&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Yes, in claiming to have a &quot;radar&quot; (not really a claim, more semantic heritage, an allowed metaphor) I&#39;m thinking of Krystal and Saager, whom have kept me company, unbeknownst to them of course, through a first chapter of Covid.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;North Americans called it &quot;lockdown&quot; and I thought that too extreme, as in most zip codes we were free to move about, albeit with fewer places to go.&amp;nbsp; More a &quot;lockout&quot; in that we were kept out of businesses (bars and restaurants, libraries, anywhere &quot;inessential&quot;).&amp;nbsp; Paris was more heavy handed than New York City by a long shot, or so was my impression.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Saager and Krystal were the stars of The Hill channel&#39;s &lt;i&gt;Rising&lt;/i&gt;, and then moved on, rather recently, to start their own channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Youtubers are the new rock stars, joining together and splitting up, just like the bands of old, and making music together, in duets, trios, perhaps in solo.&amp;nbsp; Hey, I&#39;m one of them, way off in the weeds somewhere and barely looked at, given the esoteric content of what&#39;s on my shelf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I spent the morning gawking at the floods in Belgium-Austria-Germany along those major river basins, all swollen with torrential rains.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m also following societal meltdowns (ostensibly state failures) in South Africa (Durban especially), Cuba, Lebanon and of course Haiti, where a foreign mercenary force murdered a president.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I&#39;m watching Boomers and Millennials debate about who&#39;s to blame for the falling living standards, if that&#39;s what&#39;s in the cards.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m tracking TYT breaking away from anti-imperialist channels (Jimmy Dore&#39;s a flagship), in the ongoing oligarch-funded think tank wars.&amp;nbsp; I catch excerpts of Joe Rogan from time to time.&amp;nbsp; I tune in debates about Critical Race Theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;For my day job, I continue hammering away at my example high school curriculum.&amp;nbsp; The feedback I got on NCTM Math Forum, at least from some corners, was the work that I do is terrible.&amp;nbsp; My detractors do not necessarily admire Jupyter Notebooks regardless of who is authoring them.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;But they also may have a beef about my content.&amp;nbsp; I keep hearkening back to a specific &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/04/the-algorithm.html&quot;&gt;Zen garden sculpture&lt;/a&gt;&quot; (one of my names for it), a set of nested polyhedrons, almost a logo for a School of Thought (invisible college), with its own relationship to the various think tanks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Back in the day, I used to express worry about the &quot;cannibalization&quot; of Synergetics.&amp;nbsp; The cookbook &lt;i&gt;Synergetic Stew&lt;/i&gt; had been disturbing on that score.&amp;nbsp; However as time went on, I came to see this sculpture (with moving mechanisms) as akin to a beating heart, which could be surgically disentangled from the rest of Synergetics and held aloft by an accomplished doctor.&amp;nbsp; I would try my hand in that role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I&#39;d tell the Millennials that Boomers were too quick to dismiss the Bucky stuff, nor are most Millennials passing that torch to the GenZers.&amp;nbsp; How many does it take, to pass it on?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Anthropologists know the pattern:&amp;nbsp; grandparents (an older generation) bond with the grandkids (a younger generation) while working parents, the middle generation, stay focussed on their careers.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Boomers are looking back, GenZers ahead, with Millennials mired in their own fleeting now moment, on the treadmill (referring to the gym or to work), racing in the maze (the &quot;rat race&quot; we&#39;ve called it).&lt;/p&gt;
</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/18224424122394995'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/10416211/posts/default/18224424122394995'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://mybizmo.blogspot.com/2021/07/on-my-radar.html' title='On My Radar'/><author><name>Kirby Urner</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12114860457655013242</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author></entry></feed>